<node>
  <doctext>This section of the FAQ answers questions about where to find source and documentation for Perl, support, and related matters. &lt;BR&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I do (anything)?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I use Perl interactively?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Is there a Perl shell?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I debug my Perl programs?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I profile my Perl programs?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I cross-reference my Perl programs?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Is there a pretty-printer (formatter) for Perl?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Is there a ctags for Perl?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Where can I get Perl macros for vi?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Where can I get perl-mode for emacs?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I use curses with Perl?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I use X or Tk with Perl?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I generate simple menus without using CGI or Tk?]&lt;BR&gt;
[What is undump?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I make my Perl program run faster?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I make my Perl program take less memory?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Is it unsafe to return a pointer to local data?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I free an array or hash so my program shrinks?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I make my CGI script more efficient?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I hide the source for my Perl program?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I compile my Perl program into byte code or C?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I get &lt;CODE&gt;#!perl&lt;/CODE&gt; to work on (MS-DOS,NT,...)?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Can I write useful perl programs on the command line?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Why don't perl one-liners work on my DOS/Mac/VMS system?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Where can I learn about CGI or Web programming in Perl?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Where can I learn about object-oriented Perl programming?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Where can I learn about linking C with Perl? (h2xs, xsubpp)]&lt;BR&gt;
[I've read perlembed, perlguts, etc., but I can't embed perl in my C program, what am I doing wrong?]&lt;BR&gt;
[When I tried to run my script, I got this message. What does it mean?]&lt;BR&gt;
[What's MakeMaker?]&lt;BR&gt;
</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>116</type_nodetype>
  <node_id>782</node_id>
  <author_user>113</author_user>
  <title>perlman:perlfaq3</title>
  <createtime>1999-10-12 22:34:38</createtime>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-15 02:08:38</nodeupdated>
</node>
