<node>
  <doctext>This section is surprisingly small because the rest of the FAQ is littered with answers involving regular expressions. For example, decoding a URL and checking whether something is a number
are handled with regular expressions, but those answers are found elsewhere in this document (in the section on Data and the Networking one on networking, to be precise). &lt;BR&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I hope to use regular expressions without creating illegible and unmaintainable code?]&lt;BR&gt;
[I'm having trouble matching over more than one line.  What's wrong?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I pull out lines between two patterns that are themselves on different lines?]&lt;BR&gt;
[I put a regular expression into $/ but it didn't work. What's wrong?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I substitute case insensitively on the LHS, but preserving case on the RHS?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I make &lt;CODE&gt;\w&lt;/CODE&gt; match national character sets?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I match a locale-smart version of &lt;CODE&gt;/[a-zA-Z]/&lt;/CODE&gt;?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I quote a variable to use in a regexp?]&lt;BR&gt;
[What is &lt;CODE&gt;/o&lt;/CODE&gt; really for?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I use a regular expression to strip C style comments from a file?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Can I use Perl regular expressions to match balanced text?]&lt;BR&gt;
[What does it mean that regexps are greedy?  How can I get around it?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I process each word on each line?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I print out a word-frequency or line-frequency summary?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I do approximate matching?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I efficiently match many regular expressions at once?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Why don't word-boundary searches with &lt;CODE&gt;\b&lt;/CODE&gt; work for me?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Why does using $&amp;, $`, or $' slow my program down?]&lt;BR&gt;
[What good is &lt;CODE&gt;\G&lt;/CODE&gt; in a regular expression?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Are Perl regexps DFAs or NFAs?  Are they POSIX compliant?]&lt;BR&gt;
[What's wrong with using grep or map in a void context?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I match strings with multibyte characters?]&lt;BR&gt;
</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>116</type_nodetype>
  <node_id>821</node_id>
  <author_user>113</author_user>
  <title>perlman:perlfaq6</title>
  <createtime>1999-10-12 23:52:42</createtime>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-12 22:47:38</nodeupdated>
</node>
