<node>
  <doctext>This section of the Perl FAQ covers questions involving operating system interaction. This involves interprocess communication (IPC), control over the user-interface (keyboard, screen and
pointing devices), and most anything else not related to data manipulation. 
&lt;BR&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
Read the FAQs and documentation specific to the port of perl to your operating system (eg, the perlvms manpage, the perlplan9 manpage, ...). These should contain more detailed information
on the vagaries of your perl. &lt;BR&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I find out which operating system I'm running under?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How come exec() doesn't return?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I do fancy stuff with the keyboard/screen/mouse?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I print something out in color?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I read just one key without waiting for a return key?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I check whether input is ready on the keyboard?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I clear the screen?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I get the screen size?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I ask the user for a password?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I read and write the serial port?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I decode encrypted password files?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I start a process in the background?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I trap control characters/signals?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I modify the shadow password file on a Unix system?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I set the time and date?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I sleep() or alarm() for under a second?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I measure time under a second?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I do an atexit() or setjmp()/longjmp()? (Exception handling)]&lt;BR&gt;
[Why doesn't my sockets program work under System V (Solaris)? What does the error message &quot;Protocol not supported&quot; mean?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I call my system's unique C functions from Perl?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Where do I get the include files to do ioctl() or syscall()?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Why do setuid perl scripts complain about kernel problems?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I open a pipe both to and from a command?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Why can't I get the output of a command with system()?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I capture STDERR from an external command?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Why doesn't open() return an error when a pipe open fails?]&lt;BR&gt;
[What's wrong with using backticks in a void context?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I call backticks without shell processing?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Why can't my script read from STDIN after I gave it EOF (^D on Unix, ^Z on MS-DOS)?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I convert my shell script to perl?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Can I use perl to run a telnet or ftp session?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I write expect in Perl?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Is there a way to hide perl's command line from programs such as &quot;ps&quot;?]&lt;BR&gt;
[I {changed directory, modified my environment} in a perl script.  How come the change disappeared when I exited the script?  How do I 
get my changes to be visible?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I close a process's filehandle without waiting for it to complete?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I fork a daemon process?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I make my program run with sh and csh?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I find out if I'm running interactively or not?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I timeout a slow event?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I set CPU limits?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I avoid zombies on a Unix system?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I use an SQL database?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I make a system() exit on control-C?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I open a file without blocking?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I install a CPAN module?]&lt;BR&gt;
[What's the difference between require and use?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I keep my own module/library directory?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I add the directory my program lives in to the module/library search path?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I add a directory to my include path at runtime?]&lt;BR&gt;
</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>116</type_nodetype>
  <node_id>826</node_id>
  <author_user>113</author_user>
  <title>perlman:perlfaq8</title>
  <createtime>1999-10-13 00:06:27</createtime>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-10 15:20:10</nodeupdated>
</node>
