<node>
  <doctext></doctext>
  <type_nodetype>119</type_nodetype>
  <name>&lt;P&gt;
ExtUtils::Install - install files from here to there

&lt;P&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
</name>
  <author_user>113</author_user>
  <description>&lt;P&gt;
Both 
&lt;CODE&gt;install()&lt;/CODE&gt; and 
&lt;CODE&gt;uninstall()&lt;/CODE&gt; are specific to the way ExtUtils::MakeMaker handles the installation and deinstallation of perl modules. They are not designed as general purpose tools.

&lt;P&gt;

&lt;CODE&gt;install()&lt;/CODE&gt; takes three arguments. 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;A&lt;/FONT&gt; reference to a hash, a verbose switch and a don't-really-do-it switch. The hash ref contains a mapping of directories: each key/value pair is a combination of directories to be copied. Key is a directory to copy from, value is a directory to copy to. The whole tree below the ``from'' directory will be copied preserving timestamps and permissions.

&lt;P&gt;
There are two keys with a special meaning in the hash: ``read'' and
``write''. After the copying is done, install will write the list of target
files to the file named by &lt;CODE&gt;$hashref-&amp;gt;{write}&lt;/CODE&gt;. If there is another file named by &lt;CODE&gt;$hashref-&amp;gt;{read}&lt;/CODE&gt;, the contents of this file will be merged into the written file. The read and the written file may be identical, but on 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;AFS&lt;/FONT&gt; it is quite likely, people are installing to a different directory than the one where the files later appear.

&lt;P&gt;

&lt;CODE&gt;install_default()&lt;/CODE&gt; takes one or less arguments. If no arguments are specified, it takes 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;$ARGV&amp;#091;0&amp;#093;&lt;/FONT&gt; as if it was specified as an argument. The argument is the value of MakeMaker's
 &lt;CODE&gt;FULLEXT&lt;/CODE&gt; key, like &lt;EM&gt;Tk/Canvas&lt;/EM&gt;. This function calls 
&lt;CODE&gt;install()&lt;/CODE&gt; with the same
arguments as the defaults the MakeMaker would use.

&lt;P&gt;
The argumement-less form is convenient for install scripts like

&lt;P&gt;
&lt;PRE&gt;  perl -MExtUtils::Install -e install_default Tk/Canvas
&lt;/PRE&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
Assuming this command is executed in a directory with populated &lt;EM&gt;blib&lt;/EM&gt; 
directory, it will proceed as if the &lt;EM&gt;blib&lt;/EM&gt; was build by MakeMaker on this machine. This is useful for binary
distributions.

&lt;P&gt;

&lt;CODE&gt;uninstall()&lt;/CODE&gt; takes as first
argument a file containing filenames to be unlinked. The second argument is
a verbose switch, the third is a no-don't-really-do-it-now switch.

&lt;P&gt;

&lt;CODE&gt;pm_to_blib()&lt;/CODE&gt; takes a
hashref as the first argument and copies all keys of the hash to the
corresponding values efficiently. Filenames with the extension pm are
autosplit. Second argument is the autosplit directory.

&lt;HR&gt;
</description>
  <createtime>1999-12-22 19:51:43</createtime>
  <node_id>1187</node_id>
  <synopsis>&lt;P&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;use ExtUtils::Install;&lt;/STRONG&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;install($hashref,$verbose,$nonono);&lt;/STRONG&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;uninstall($packlistfile,$verbose,$nonono);&lt;/STRONG&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;pm_to_blib($hashref);&lt;/STRONG&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
</synopsis>
  <title>perlman:ExtUtils::Install</title>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-10 16:31:41</nodeupdated>
</node>
