<node>
  <doctext></doctext>
  <type_nodetype>119</type_nodetype>
  <name>&lt;P&gt;
print - output a list to a filehandle

&lt;P&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
</name>
  <author_user>114</author_user>
  <description>&lt;P&gt;
Prints a string or a comma-separated list of strings. Returns 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;TRUE&lt;/FONT&gt; if successful. 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;FILEHANDLE&lt;/FONT&gt; may be a scalar variable name, in which case the variable contains the name of or a reference to the filehandle, thus introducing one level of indirection. 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;(NOTE:&lt;/FONT&gt; If 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;FILEHANDLE&lt;/FONT&gt; is a variable and the next token is a term, it may be misinterpreted as an operator unless you interpose a
 &lt;CODE&gt;+&lt;/CODE&gt; or put parentheses around the arguments.) If 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;FILEHANDLE&lt;/FONT&gt; is omitted, prints by default to standard
output (or to the last selected output channel--see [perlfunc:select|select]). If 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;LIST&lt;/FONT&gt; is also omitted, prints &lt;CODE&gt;$_&lt;/CODE&gt; to the currently selected output channel. To set the default output channel to something other than 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;STDOUT&lt;/FONT&gt; use the select operation. Note that, because print takes a 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;LIST,&lt;/FONT&gt; anything in the 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;LIST&lt;/FONT&gt; is evaluated in list context, and any subroutine that you call will have one or more of its expressions evaluated in list context. Also be careful not to follow the print keyword with a left parenthesis unless you want the corresponding right parenthesis to terminate the arguments to the print--interpose a
 &lt;CODE&gt;+&lt;/CODE&gt; or put parentheses around all the arguments.

&lt;P&gt;
Note that if you're storing 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;FILEHANDLES&lt;/FONT&gt; in an array or other expression, you will
have to use a block returning its value instead:

&lt;P&gt;
&lt;PRE&gt;    print { $files&amp;#091;$i&amp;#093; } &amp;quot;stuff\n&amp;quot;;
    print { $OK ? STDOUT : STDERR } &amp;quot;stuff\n&amp;quot;;
&lt;/PRE&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
</description>
  <createtime>1999-08-24 18:43:33</createtime>
  <node_id>349</node_id>
  <synopsis>&lt;P&gt;
print 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;FILEHANDLE&lt;/FONT&gt; 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;LIST&lt;/FONT&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
print 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;LIST&lt;/FONT&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
print

&lt;P&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
</synopsis>
  <title>perlfunc:print</title>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-14 09:03:00</nodeupdated>
</node>
