<node>
  <doctext></doctext>
  <type_nodetype>119</type_nodetype>
  <name>&lt;P&gt;
ExtUtils::Mksymlists - write linker options files for dynamic extension

&lt;P&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
</name>
  <author_user>113</author_user>
  <description>&lt;P&gt;
&lt;CODE&gt;ExtUtils::Mksymlists&lt;/CODE&gt; produces files used by the linker under some OSs during the creation of
shared libraries for dynamic extensions. It is normally called from a
MakeMaker-generated Makefile when the extension is built. The linker option
file is generated by calling the function
&lt;CODE&gt;Mksymlists&lt;/CODE&gt;, which is exported by default from &lt;CODE&gt;ExtUtils::Mksymlists&lt;/CODE&gt;. It takes one argument, a list of key-value pairs, in which the following
keys are recognized:

&lt;DL&gt;
&lt;DT&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A NAME=&quot;item_NAME&quot;&gt;NAME&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;P&gt;
&lt;DD&gt;
This gives the name of the extension (&lt;EM&gt;e.g.&lt;/EM&gt; Tk::Canvas) for which the linker option file will be produced.

&lt;P&gt;&lt;DT&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A NAME=&quot;item_DL_FUNCS&quot;&gt;DL_FUNCS&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;P&gt;
&lt;DD&gt;
This is identical to the 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;DL_FUNCS&lt;/FONT&gt; attribute available via MakeMaker, from which
it is usually taken. Its value is a reference to an associative array, in
which each key is the name of a package, and each value is an a reference
to an array of function names which should be exported by the extension.
For instance, one might say
&lt;CODE&gt;DL_FUNCS =&amp;gt; { Homer::Iliad   =&amp;gt; &amp;#091; qw(trojans greeks) &amp;#093;,
Homer::Odyssey =&amp;gt; &amp;#091; qw(travellers family suitors) &amp;#093; }&lt;/CODE&gt;. The function names should be identical to those in the 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;XSUB&lt;/FONT&gt; code;
&lt;CODE&gt;Mksymlists&lt;/CODE&gt; will alter the names written to the linker option file to match the changes
made by &lt;EM&gt;xsubpp&lt;/EM&gt;. In addition, if none of the functions in a list begin with the string &lt;STRONG&gt;boot_&lt;/STRONG&gt;,
&lt;CODE&gt;Mksymlists&lt;/CODE&gt; will add a bootstrap function for that package, just as xsubpp does. (If a &lt;STRONG&gt;boot_&amp;lt;pkg&amp;gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt; function is present in the list, it is passed through unchanged.) If 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;DL_FUNCS&lt;/FONT&gt; is not specified, it defaults to the bootstrap function for the extension specified in 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;NAME.&lt;/FONT&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;DT&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A NAME=&quot;item_DL_VARS&quot;&gt;DL_VARS&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;P&gt;
&lt;DD&gt;
This is identical to the 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;DL_VARS&lt;/FONT&gt; attribute available via MakeMaker, and, like 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;DL_FUNCS,&lt;/FONT&gt; it is usually specified via MakeMaker. Its value is a reference to an array of variable names which should be exported by the extension.

&lt;P&gt;&lt;DT&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A NAME=&quot;item_FILE&quot;&gt;FILE&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;P&gt;
&lt;DD&gt;
This key can be used to specify the name of the linker option file (minus the OS-specific extension), if for some reason you do not want to use the default value, which is the last word of the 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;NAME&lt;/FONT&gt; attribute (
&lt;EM&gt;e.g.&lt;/EM&gt; for Tk::Canvas, 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;FILE&lt;/FONT&gt; defaults to 'Canvas').

&lt;P&gt;&lt;DT&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A NAME=&quot;item_FUNCLIST&quot;&gt;FUNCLIST&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;P&gt;
&lt;DD&gt;
This provides an alternate means to specify function names to be exported
from the extension. Its value is a reference to an array of function names
to be exported by the extension. These names are passed through unaltered
to the linker options file.

&lt;P&gt;&lt;DT&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A NAME=&quot;item_DLBASE&quot;&gt;DLBASE&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;P&gt;
&lt;DD&gt;
This item specifies the name by which the linker knows the extension, which may be different from the name of the extension itself (for instance, some linkers add an '_' to the name of the extension). If it is not specified, it is derived from the 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;NAME&lt;/FONT&gt; attribute. It is presently used only by 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;OS2.&lt;/FONT&gt;

&lt;/DL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
When calling &lt;CODE&gt;Mksymlists&lt;/CODE&gt;, one should always specify the 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;NAME&lt;/FONT&gt; attribute. In most cases, this is all that's
necessary. In the case of unusual extensions, however, the other attributes
can be used to provide additional information to the linker.

&lt;P&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
&lt;H1&gt;&lt;A NAME=&quot;AUTHOR&quot;&gt;AUTHOR&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
Charles Bailey &lt;EM&gt;&amp;lt;bailey@genetics.upenn.edu&amp;gt;&lt;/EM&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
&lt;H1&gt;&lt;A NAME=&quot;REVISION&quot;&gt;REVISION&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
Last revised 14-Feb-1996, for Perl 5.002.
&lt;HR&gt;
</description>
  <createtime>1999-12-22 19:51:44</createtime>
  <node_id>1196</node_id>
  <synopsis>&lt;P&gt;
&lt;PRE&gt;    use ExtUtils::Mksymlists;
    Mksymlists({ NAME     =&amp;gt; $name ,
                 DL_VARS  =&amp;gt; &amp;#091; $var1, $var2, $var3 &amp;#093;,
                 DL_FUNCS =&amp;gt; { $pkg1 =&amp;gt; &amp;#091; $func1, $func2 &amp;#093;,
                               $</synopsis>
  <title>perlman:ExtUtils::Mksymlists</title>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-10 16:27:24</nodeupdated>
</node>
