<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="17404" title="Where is Perl function foo() documented?" created="2000-06-09 19:02:54" updated="2005-08-13 01:09:18">
<type id="17338">
sitefaqlet</type>
<author id="17342">
SiteDocClan</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;!--
2003-03-20 [boo_radley] crosslinked, added perl doc site
2003-05-24 [Mr. Muskrat] s/Perl Monks/PerlMonks/ &amp; changed to id link
2004-01-26 [jdporter] regularized
2006-03-15 [jdporter] retitled
--&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Where is Perl function &lt;i&gt;foo()&lt;/i&gt; documented?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
An excellent repository of Perl documentation exists at
[http://perldoc.perl.org/]. That's your one-stop shop.
&lt;small&gt;Also, [szabgab] has created this nice [http://www.szabgab.com/articles/perlindex.html|comprehensive perl index].&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Your local installation of Perl comes with a full set of documentation on the Perl language and the perl execution environment.
(This surprises a lot of people new to Perl.)
On UNIX and UNIX-like systems (such as Linux), it's all available via the &lt;code&gt;perldoc&lt;/code&gt; command.
For example, &lt;code&gt;perldoc perlfunc&lt;/code&gt; on UNIXy systems should give you the answer to the title question.

On other OSes, Perl provides the same documentation in various forms &amp;mdash; for example, in HTML &amp;mdash; and with only a little searching under perl's installation directory, you should be able to find everything you need for basic questions. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If you want to link to documentation for a function, either in a node or in the chatterbox, you can do it like this: 
&lt;b&gt;&lt;tt&gt;&amp;#91;doc://&lt;i&gt;foo&lt;/i&gt;]&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
where &lt;i&gt;foo&lt;/i&gt; is the function name in question. For example, &lt;c&gt;[doc://time]&lt;/c&gt; -&gt; [doc://time]. (Note that this also works for built-in perl variables, e.g. &lt;c&gt;[doc://@ARGV]&lt;/c&gt;)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you want to jump &lt;i&gt;immediately&lt;/i&gt; to such documentation in your browser, it's quite easy: simply type 
&lt;b&gt;&lt;tt&gt;doc://&lt;i&gt;foo&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (no square brackets) in the Search box at the top of any page. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
(To do a general search of the documentation at perldoc.perl.org, type
&lt;tt&gt;&lt;b&gt;perl&lt;/b&gt;doc://&lt;/tt&gt; rather than &lt;tt&gt;doc://&lt;/tt&gt;.)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If you happen to be viewing a PerlMonks node which contains code (such as entries in the [id://1747] or [id://1967]), and you happen to have your [id://590090|Function Nodelet] enabled, that nodelet will contain links to the documentation for every function used in the code displayed on the node.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Old On-site Docs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If you don't mind looking at an older version of the Perl documentation, there are a couple of handy ways:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For browsing, you can visit our dusty old [id://148]. &lt;!-- Library --&gt;
This has an index of all the perl docs, including, for example, the Perl FAQ. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you want info on a specific function or topic, you can type its name in the Search box at the top of any page.
This will take you directly to the corresponding page in the [id://148].
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Back to the [PerlMonks FAQ]&lt;/i&gt;
</field>
</data>
</node>
