<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="17642" title="Help for User Settings" created="2000-06-11 22:25:31" updated="2005-08-15 06:18:03">
<type id="17338">
sitefaqlet</type>
<author id="17342">
SiteDocClan</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">

&lt;p&gt;
Make changes on the [id://1072] page to alter
the way the site works for you.  Make sure to press 
the submit button at the bottom of the page to make
your changes take effect.  The [id://25185] are on a separate page.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Note that there is a link to [id://1072|your User Settings page]
at the top right of your [id://17639|home node] &amp;mdash; it's
labeled "Edit your: &lt;u&gt;Profile&lt;/u&gt;, [id://1072|Settings]".
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a name="frontpage"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;FrontPage Configuration&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
"FrontPage" is an alternative name (an alias) for [The Monastery Gates].
You can choose which sections of the Monastery will be shown to you there.
Simply check the box next to any that you do not wish to see.
The Maximum Entries column allows you to set the number of notes shown in
each section.
If you leave these fields blank, they will default to some sensible value.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a name="misc"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Miscellaneous Settings&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Show Unapproved Nodes:&lt;/b&gt; if checked, you can
see all content, not just those nodes which have been approved by
moderators. Note that [id://17645]s (and above) see unmoderated
content all the time anyway; so if you're a [id://17645] (or above),
you should turn off this option, or you will see unmoderated content
in duplicate!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Turn Hints Off:&lt;/b&gt; hints are scattered through the
site for the benefit of new users.  You may check this box
to get rid of them.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;!-- gone
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Scratch Pad Public:&lt;/b&gt; each user gets a scratch pad
area where they can keep notes, post code snippets, or keep
any other information they choose.  If this box is checked,
other users will be allowed to see the contents of your
scratchpad by entering your username in the [id://108949].&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
--&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;No Forced Preview:&lt;/b&gt; Checking this option will make it 
possible to submit a node without first previewing what you've 
written; in other words, without reminding you to check that your 
post looks the way you intended.  This is a bad idea except for 
those very wise in the ways of [id://674668] and then, only for 
those who never make typos or other mistakes. 
As [id://17558] notes, "Preview, Preview, Preview." For the same reason you faithfully&lt;br/&gt;&lt;c&gt;use strict; use warnings;&lt;/c&gt;, leave "No forced 
Preview" UNchecked.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Null vote:&lt;/b&gt; this only applies to members with
voting privileges.  If you have this on, then for each
post, the radio button for no-vote is selected.  If you
turn this off, then there are only two buttons, ++ and --,
and you will have to reload the page if you pick one and
then decide you don't want to vote after all.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Show Reputation Spread:&lt;/b&gt; See [id://453652] &lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Disable some JavaScript on homenodes:&lt;/b&gt; this setting
attempts to filter out JavaScript when you visit someone's
home node. The people who maintain the site don't use
JavaScript so you would be even safer by turning it off in
your browser.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;a name="homenodefilter"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Don't filter risky HTML from monks' homenodes:&lt;/b&gt;
By default, homenodes are subject to the same restrictions
of [id://29281|allowed HTML] as ordinary posts. However, some monks like to
jazz up their homenodes with images, CSS, and other gewgaws.
To view these, you'd need to ease up on the HTML restrictions.
That's what this flag does. However, be aware that such
things are potentially risky, in terms of making possible
some types of [wp://cross-site scripting] attack.
Therefore, it is recommended that this flag be used very
judiciously and only temporarily &amp;mdash; if at all.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
When filtering is &lt;i&gt;on&lt;/i&gt; (the default), unallowed 
HTML present in a homenode will be escaped, 
which means it will be appear as plain text.
&lt;br&gt;
See [id://29281] for the full list of what is
allowed in posts.  In addition to that set, the following are
also allowed in homenodes:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;c&gt;form&lt;/c&gt; tag: attribute &lt;c&gt;method&lt;/c&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;c&gt;input&lt;/c&gt; tag: attributes &lt;c&gt;name, type, value&lt;/c&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;c&gt;select&lt;/c&gt; tag: attribute &lt;c&gt;name&lt;/c&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;c&gt;option&lt;/c&gt; tag: attributes &lt;c&gt;selected, value&lt;/c&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;!-- info from [displaySingleVar] --&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
Note that even if you have this flag set, you can enable filtering
individual homenodes by
appending &lt;c&gt;;scrub=1&lt;/c&gt; to the URL.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Perl Monks User Search Default Length:&lt;/b&gt; sets the
default number of nodes to display when listing a user's
nodes at [id://6364].&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Search finds nodes I can't read:&lt;/b&gt; if this is set,
[id://3989] will list nodes that you might not be permitted
to see.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;a name="datetimes"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Format for date-times:&lt;/b&gt;
lets you set the format for how date-time strings are shown.
This format is used in most places on the site, wherever a longer
time format is reasonable.
&lt;br&gt;The default is &lt;c&gt;%b %d, %Y at %H:%M %Z&lt;/c&gt;.
See [id://727004] for a complete description of the format specification.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;small&gt;See [id://192415] for background detail.&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;a name="shortdatetimes"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abbreviated Format for date-times:&lt;/b&gt;
As above, but for a handful of places in PerlMonks where shorter date-time strings are needed &amp;mdash;
in particular, when a list of items (e.g. nodes) is shown with a date-time column.
Currently, this is in just two places: in a user writeups listing (e.g. [by://tye|tye's writeups]),
and in a user vote view listing (e.g. [href://?node_id=22609;displaytype=voteview|your votes on tye's nodes]).
&lt;br&gt;The default is &lt;c&gt;%Y-%m-%d %H:%M&lt;/c&gt;.
Again, see [id://727004] for a complete description of the format specification.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;No navigation menu under title bar:&lt;/b&gt; normally there
is a list of links that point to the various sections of the
monastery at the top of each page.  Checking this option will
cause pages to be generated without these links.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a name="note"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Note Configuration&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
These settings control the display of a single page view 
of a discussion thread. The &lt;em&gt;Replies header depth&lt;/em&gt; 
setting controls how many levels of node headers are 
displayed on a page. When replies in a thread are deeper 
than this level, a box appears with the text "Some notes 
below your chosen depth have not been shown here". 
To view a node below this depth, click on it (or on any 
of the lower level nodes in the thread of interest) to 
make it the top-level node on a new screen.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;em&gt;Replies text depth&lt;/em&gt; setting controls how 
many levels deep the node text is displayed on a single 
page. Nodes of which the level is deeper than set with 
&lt;em&gt;Replies text depth&lt;/em&gt; will be shown with just a 
header (title, author, date, link), and no body text. 
Of course, no nodes are shown deeper than the level set 
with &lt;em&gt;Replies header depth&lt;/em&gt;. To view the text of 
a node of which the text is not displayed, click on it 
(or on any of the lower level nodes in the thread of 
interest) to make it the top-level node on a new screen. 
By the way, the User Settings page allows you to set the 
&lt;em&gt;Replies header depth&lt;/em&gt; below the &lt;em&gt;Replies text 
depth&lt;/em&gt;, in which case the &lt;em&gt;Replies header depth&lt;/em&gt; 
takes precedence.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Example: &lt;em&gt;Replies header depth&lt;/em&gt; = 10 and 
&lt;em&gt;Replies text depth&lt;/em&gt; = 2: the discussion is shown 
10 levels deep, but only the first 2 levels show the 
actual text of the discussion; the next 8 levels only 
show the header information of the replies. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Note ordering:&lt;/i&gt; you may choose to see threads
either in chronological order or by their reputation.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Back to the [PerlMonks FAQ]&lt;/i&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;</field>
</data>
</node>
