<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="243881" title="About the Code Catacombs section" created="2003-03-17 23:28:51" updated="2005-08-11 07:37:15">
<type id="17338">
sitefaqlet</type>
<author id="17342">
SiteDocClan</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;p&gt;
[Code Catacombs] was an old section intended for the posting of substantial chunks of code (scripts, modules, etc.)
It was superceded by [Cool Uses For Perl], and subsequently put out to pasture (i.e. disabled).
All new code postings (other than obfu and poetry) should be done in [CUFP].
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;!-- OLD CONTENT:
&lt;p&gt;
The point of the [id://1747] is to &lt;b&gt;share code&lt;/b&gt;. As such, it is a place to post relatively large, relatively mature code components, such as applications, modules, and frameworks.  While it does support discussion ensuing from such posts, it is not really the best place to ask programming questions.  (Open-ended requests for feedback are fine, however.)  In some sense, it can be considered slightly redundant with [http://www.cpan.org/|CPAN].
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Posting in this section differs somewhat from posting in other sections.
For starters, you're supposed to provide data in three additional fields besides the title and code content &amp;mdash; namely: &lt;b&gt;Category&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Description&lt;/b&gt;, and &lt;b&gt;Contact info&lt;/b&gt;. (The last should be considered "very optional".)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Postings in this section are organized into categories. Therefore, you should indicate which category your code belongs in. New categories are almost never made; so you should visit the [id://1747] section page to see what categories already exist, and choose one of those.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The Description field is a short note for perl monks. Real &lt;i&gt;documentation&lt;/i&gt; should be embedded in the Code field somehow (e.g. in [doc://perlpod|POD]).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The [id://17688|approval/moderation process] &lt;b&gt;does not apply&lt;/b&gt; to nodes in this section.&lt;br/&gt;
You can search in this section using [id://3989].
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
[Code Catacombs sitedoclet]
&lt;/p&gt;
--&gt;
</field>
</data>
</node>
