<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="252754" title="What nodes should/should not be FrontPaged?" created="2003-04-23 23:25:13" updated="2005-08-15 14:58:26">
<type id="17338">
sitefaqlet</type>
<author id="17342">
SiteDocClan</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;!--
2003-04-23 [pfaut] new faqlet
2003-05-23 [Mr. Muskrat] link to FAQ by id
2004-02-05 [jdporter] added link to 227268
--&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;What nodes should/should not be FrontPaged?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The front page ([The Monastery Gates]) is most likely the first thing a newcomer will see when they come to PerlMonks. It should be representative of what transpires on PM.

&lt;p&gt;Many regular users also use the front page to find interesting new content on the site.  These users rely on others to select what nodes they will see.

&lt;p&gt;Lack of turnover on the front page makes the site look inactive to someone who hasn't figured out how the site works yet, and to our regulars who use the front page.

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Do&lt;/u&gt; frontpage a node if it:&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;contains something you want newcomers to see.
&lt;li&gt;represents the spirit of PerlMonks.
&lt;li&gt;asks a specific question but has received no replies. Frontpaging will make it more visible and may help it get answered.
&lt;li&gt;asks a common question that hasn't been asked recently or is asked in a new way.
&lt;li&gt;contains a good poem or obfuscation.  Each section of the site has its own section on
 the front page, so frontpaging an obfuscation will not push a question off the front page.
&lt;li&gt;has exceptional or insightful responses.
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Don't&lt;/u&gt; frontpage a node if it:&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;is ill formatted, or long without readmore tags. These nodes may be frontpaged after being considered and fixed by an editor.
&lt;li&gt;asks bad questions. These may be off topic, show no effort at finding an answer before posting, homework requests, etc.
&lt;li&gt;puts PerlMonks in a bad light by posting copyrighted information or pornographic material, etc.
&lt;li&gt;is a troll.
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Poor spelling or grammar should not disqualify a node from being frontpaged. 
Not everyone who uses the site uses English as their primary language. 
Don't be afraid to frontpage such a node as long as the poster is capable of 
getting his/her point across.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Please read&lt;/b&gt; [id://227268|this classic discussion]
for more extremely relevant and informative information and opinions from
some of the Monastery's wisest clerics.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Back to the [PerlMonks FAQ]&lt;/i&gt;
</field>
</data>
</node>
