<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="323419" title="Signatures and Node Templates" created="2004-01-22 22:08:30" updated="2005-08-13 14:05:33">
<type id="17338">
sitefaqlet</type>
<author id="17342">
SiteDocClan</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;p&gt;
You can configure the way your new posts look via [id://14444], which lets you define a &lt;i&gt;Node Template&lt;/i&gt; and a &lt;i&gt;Signature&lt;/i&gt;.
These two are combined when you start a new post (whether root or reply) so that you don't have to type so much.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name="Node Template"&gt;Node Template&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The node template is intended for content which would normally be part of a standard posting.
Some monks use it to pre-load tags for doing common things like quoting the
parent node, code tags, or character entities which they frequently forget.
You &lt;i&gt;should not&lt;/i&gt; use it for including quotes, or your name, or anything
other than node content or markup.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Node Signature&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This is the approved way to put a [wp://Signature block|signature] at the bottom of your posts.
Not only does this feature make it easier to include signatures, but it lets gives other
users a way to apply custom rendering to signatures (including hiding them entirely),
on both a site-wide and an individual basis, via [href://?node_id=786921#styles|custom CSS].
Any text you place in your signature will automatically be wrapped in special
&lt;code&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags so that users can selectively style your signature.
It's true you can edit this markup after the node has been created, but please don't;
it is a violation of site policy to tamper with that automatically added markup.
On the other hand, feel free to modify the &lt;i&gt;content&lt;/i&gt; of your signature at any time, as you see fit.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What is (in)appropriate to include in a signature?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[wp://Signature block]s should be small and unobtrusive.
Anything larger than a line or two is probably inappropriate and would be better suited to your home node.
If you have a huge signature but your post contents are small, you are wasting screen space and annoying people.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Also, keep in mind that many monks surf with custom CSS and non-standard color schemes.
If you use explicit colors in your signature, it may look groovy-cool with &lt;i&gt;your&lt;/i&gt; settings but be an obnoxious mess with &lt;i&gt;theirs&lt;/i&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How do I hide someone else's annoying signature?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Occassionally, a user may have a particularly annoying signature which you would rather not see,
or you may wish to disable the displaying of signature entirely,
or otherwise control the way user signatures are displayed.
To support this, the signatures are automatically wrapped with two DIV tags with special class names:
&lt;c&gt;&lt;div class="pmsig"&gt;&lt;/c&gt; and &lt;c&gt;&lt;div class="pmsig-USERID"&gt;&lt;/c&gt;, where the USERID is the author's numeric ID.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
By [href://?node_id=786921#styles|configuring the CSS] which the Monastery serves with every page,
you can cause these DIVs to not be displayed, or to be specially rendered (e.g. with toned-down colors or smaller fonts).
&lt;br&gt;
To hide a specific user's signature:
&lt;code&gt;
.pmsig-USERID { display: none; } // where USERID is the author's numeric ID
&lt;/code&gt;
This will hide all signatures:
&lt;code&gt;
.pmsig { display: none; }
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How do I deal with these DIV tags that keep appearing?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
PerlMonks automatically adds these tags around your signature if they are not &lt;i&gt;both&lt;/i&gt; already present in your signature text.
This is biting you if you keep seeing unexpected DIV tags above and below your signature.
To make this stop happening, delete &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; 
&lt;c&gt;&lt;div class="pmsig"&gt;&lt;/c&gt; and
&lt;c&gt;&lt;div class="pmsig-USERID"&gt;&lt;/c&gt; tags from your signature block.
Then PerlMonks will add the appropriate ones correctly.&lt;br&gt;
Also, if you do have these tags in your signature explicitly, make sure that they contain no unnecessary whitespace, as this will interfere with autodetection.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Remember that users use these DIV tags to &lt;i&gt;hide signatures&lt;/i&gt;, so be careful not to write your post's content inside these elements.
Otherwise users with signature hiding in their custom CSS won't see your post!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Example template:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;c&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;
  &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
     &amp;#91;  &amp;#93;
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;code&gt;
  &lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/c&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Example signature usage:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;div class="pmsig"&gt;
  -- PerlMonks: The Heart of the Perl Community &lt;br&gt;
&lt;div class="pmsig-USERID"&gt;
  -- [id://USERID] is a Perl God!
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Back to [PerlMonks FAQ]&lt;/i&gt;
</field>
</data>
</node>
