<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="409197" title="What is Reaping?" created="2004-11-19 20:19:46" updated="2005-08-12 20:02:51">
<type id="17338">
sitefaqlet</type>
<author id="17342">
SiteDocClan</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;!--
2004-11-19 jdporter Created, from text authored by [Arunbear]. Thanks, [Arunbear]!
--&gt;

&lt;a name="define"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is reaping?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Reaping is the process by which undesirable nodes are taken out of circulation. 
  When a node is reaped, [NodeReaper] claims the node as his own, i.e. he becomes 
  the new owner of the node. He places a link to a location where you can see 
  the old node and the reason it was considered for reaping (if one was provided). 
  He also informs the node's previous owner of the reapage.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
A reaped node can only come back from [NodeReaper]'s realm if it is resurrected by the [gods].
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a name="threshold"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
A node which has been [id://92975|considered] for reaping will be claimed by the 
[NodeReaper|Reaper] once all of the following conditions are met:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt; $reputation &amp;lt; 0 &lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt; $reap_votes &amp;gt; 4 &lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt; 2 * $keep_votes + $edit_votes &amp;lt; 4 &lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;!-- No point in mentioning this to Hoi Polloi:
&lt;p&gt;A node which doesn't meet the above criteria may still be reaped, but only through [gods|godly] intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Note, however, that these conditions are only checked (and possibly acted upon) when Moderation votes are registered, not when reputation votes are cast.
Therefore, the actual reapage of a node meeting the above conditions only happens on the casting of the critical moderation &lt;b&gt;reap&lt;/b&gt; vote, and &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; on the critical reputation downvote.
This is why it is possible, for example, for a node to accrue a reputation substantially lower than 0 before it is finally reaped.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Point #3 above bears some clarification. What it means is that 2 'keep' votes are sufficient to prevent a node from being reaped, as are 1 'keep' + 2 'edit', and 0 'keep' + 4 'edit'.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
See also: [id://92975]
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;HR/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Back to [PerlMonks FAQ]&lt;/i&gt;

</field>
</data>
</node>
