<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="419625" title="Using the Message Inbox" created="2005-01-05 09:29:58" updated="2005-08-12 18:05:07">
<type id="17338">
sitefaqlet</type>
<author id="17342">
SiteDocClan</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;!-- 2008-01-21 ww updated last section, "What is this nobody thing" per request, "ambrus says In Using the Message Inbox, there's a section "What's this 'Nobody' thing?", but 'Nobody' has since been changed to 'Do not send at all'. Could you fix that?" --&gt;

&lt;!-- 2005-01-05 jdporter Created, from draft by [szabgab]. --&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Using the Message Inbox&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Whenever someone sends you a new private message, it goes into your message inbox.  
There are two common ways to view and act upon your inbox.
One is through the Chatterbox nodelet, and the other is through the [Message Inbox] page.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
(For testing purposes, you can send a private message to yourself by typing 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;tt&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;/msg &lt;i&gt;your_username&lt;/i&gt; some text&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
in the Chatterbox.)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Private messages in the Chatterbox nodelet&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The current contents of your inbox are displayed in the upper section of the Chatterbox nodelet.
(The lower section is the public Chatterbox itself.)
Next to each private message listed there, you will see a checkbox.
If you'd like to delete one or more messages immediately, you can simply check their checkboxes and press the &lt;i&gt;talk&lt;/i&gt; button of Chatterbox.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There is a limit to the number of private messages the Chatterbox nodelet will display.
This parameter (and others) can be set in the &lt;b&gt;Private Message Settings&lt;/b&gt; section of your [id://1072].
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
See the [id://236794] for more info on how to use the Chatterbox.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Other actions (such as replying and archiving) are available on the [Message Inbox] page.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Accessing the Message Inbox&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
For your convenience, there are two links to the [Message Inbox] page just below your private messages in the Chatterbox nodelet &amp;mdash; that is, at the bottom of the upper section of the Chatterbox nodelet.  They will look something like this:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;And &lt;u&gt;21 more&lt;/u&gt;, &lt;u&gt;378 archived&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
If you click on a link you will be taken to one of the folders in your [id://48824]: your [href://?node=Message+Inbox;srch_folder=0|default folder], or your [href://?node=Message+Inbox;srch_folder=1|archived messages], respectively.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Message Inbox page&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Whenever you visit your [Message Inbox], you will see one line per message, with the following fields:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Delete&lt;/b&gt; - a checkbox&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Reply to&lt;/b&gt; - a radiobutton&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Message&lt;/b&gt; - the text of the message itself&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Archive&lt;/b&gt; - a checkbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Beneath these there is a line with the following fields:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a &lt;b&gt;Reply to&lt;/b&gt; radiobutton labeled 'Nobody'&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a &lt;b&gt;Message&lt;/b&gt; textbox labeled 'Reply text:'&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a Submit button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Below this is a section for "archived messages".  Archived messages are really
no different from the normal messages in your inbox; this just gives you one
simple level of organization.  It's rather like having two inboxes &amp;mdash; but
all incoming private messages go into the one; the other is called "archived".
Also note that archived messages will not be listed in your Chatterbox nodelet.
In general, PerlMonks clients can and do distinguish between normal and archived
message inboxes.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In the Archived Messages section, the field headings are slighly different:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Delete&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Reply to&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Archived Message&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Unarchive&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
When you press the Submit button, the following actions happen:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any messages whose &lt;b&gt;Delete&lt;/b&gt; checkbox is checked are deleted from your inbox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any messages whose &lt;b&gt;Archive&lt;/b&gt; checkbox is checked are moved into your archived messages section.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any messages whose &lt;b&gt;Unarchive&lt;/b&gt; checkbox is checked are moved into your (normal) messages section.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If any message has its &lt;b&gt;Reply to&lt;/b&gt; radiobutton checked, the text in the 'Reply text:' textbox is sent to the author of that message as a private message.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
(Note: There are actually two submit buttons on the page, but let that not confuse you.
They do the same thing.)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Here are the actions you can perform:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send a reply:
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Check the radio button next to the message to which you'd like to reply.
    &lt;li&gt;Type your reply in the text box.
    &lt;li&gt;Press one of the Submit buttons.
  &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
  You won't get a real confirmation that a message actually got sent,
  but at the bottom of the Chatterbox nodelet you'll get a message confirming your attempt.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Delete one or more messages without sending any reply:
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Check the relevant checkboxes in the first column (under &lt;b&gt;Delete&lt;/b&gt;).
    &lt;li&gt;Leave all of the "Reply to" radiobuttons unselected, or select the one under 'Nobody'.
    &lt;li&gt;Press one of the Submit buttons.
  &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Archive a message:
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Check the checkbox in the Archive column of the relevant message(s).
    &lt;li&gt;Leave all of the "Reply to" radiobuttons unselected, or select the one under 'Nobody'.
    &lt;li&gt;Press one of the Submit buttons.
  &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Unarchive a message:
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Check the checkbox in the Unarchive column of the relevant message(s).
    &lt;li&gt;Leave all of the "Reply to" radiobuttons unselected, or select the one under 'Nobody'.
    &lt;li&gt;Press one of the Submit buttons.
  &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The above actions can be combined in one operation, since
the message delete/archive and reply are essentially independent actions.
For example, you can reply to and delete a message in the same operation.
You can even reply to one message while at the same time deleting and archiving other messages.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There is a limit to the number of private messages the [Message Inbox] page will display.
You can set this parameter via the small form at the bottom of the [Message Inbox] page.
In addition, this parameter (and others) can be set in the &lt;b&gt;Private Message Settings&lt;/b&gt; section of your [id://1072].
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;What's this 'Do not send at all' thing?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Selecting &lt;i&gt;Do not send at all&lt;/i&gt; for the recipient of a reply message is the default.  It means that no message will be sent.
It allows you to Delete, Archive or Unarchive messages without sending a reply message at the same time.
Selecting &lt;i&gt;Do not send at all&lt;/i&gt; has the same effect as not selecting any radiobutton.
It's there in case you select a particular recipient and then change your mind.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;See related: [Message Outbox]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Back to [PerlMonks FAQ]&lt;/i&gt;
</field>
</data>
</node>
