<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="474389" title="How can I wipe every trace of myself from PerlMonks?" created="2005-07-12 17:03:52" updated="2011-07-11 16:17:13">
<type id="17338">
sitefaqlet</type>
<author id="17342">
SiteDocClan</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;
I want to delete my account and have all of my posts wiped as well.  How can I do this?
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So you wish to commit &lt;i&gt;[c2://wiki suicide]&lt;/i&gt;, eh?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The short answer is that you can't and we won't. But you're really asking about two somewhat distinct things.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Deleting Your Account&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Even though this is not possible, please think seriously about what it is you really want to achieve, and why. There are some remedies for most concerns.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you are concerned about &lt;b&gt;privacy&lt;/b&gt;, i.e. the ability of third parties to associate your activities here with your other presences on the web, you can take measures to &lt;b&gt;anonymize&lt;/b&gt; your account, such as [id://324084|changing your username] to something meaningless or [lucky://"picture is unrelated"|unrelated].
You should probably also blank out the "location", and "User bio" fields of your Profile, as well as the contents of your scratchpads, if any; and Remove your user Image. (You shouldn't blank out the "Email Address" field, which is never displayed, unless/until you disable account; see next.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you are &lt;b&gt;done with PerlMonks&lt;/b&gt; and wish to close your account to any further use, you can &lt;b&gt;disable&lt;/b&gt; your account. 
To do this, go to your homenode, click the link to Edit your Profile, and set your password to &lt;c&gt;0&lt;/c&gt; (zero).
Note: Once you submit that change, you will never be able to log into that account again, so be sure to make any other desired changes first!
You might consider saving out a copy of the contents of your message inbox. (There is no easy way to do this in bulk; sorry.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Disabling the account does not &lt;i&gt;delete&lt;/i&gt; it. The account will live on forever, as the owner of any content you ever posted here.
Also, the account's XP will remain and continue to grow/shrink in accordance with how people vote on the the nodes you posted.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You may, of course, do both (anonymize and then disable). This would make sense if you are paranoid about privacy, for example.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
See:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;[id://784702]&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;[id://798436]&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Deleting All Your Posts / Wiping All Your Content&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This is considered vandalism and is against site policy. It is not condoned and not enabled.  If you attempt to [c2://WikiSuicide|wipe] your nodes' contents (other than your homenode and scratchpads), efforts will be made to restore them when you're done. Similarly, requests to have your nodes reaped (except in the obvious cases of duplication or spam) will not be honored. 
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;The [gods|site admins] reserve the right to lock you out if they catch you in the act of wiping your content.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
See:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [id://913697] &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [id://181253] &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [id://17557] &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Some interesting relevant (at least tangentially) threads:&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [id://893819] &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [id://675888] &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [id://381446] &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;
</field>
</data>
</node>
