<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="555609" title="Can I get the PerlMonks source code?" created="2006-06-15 16:26:45" updated="2006-06-15 12:26:45">
<type id="17338">
sitefaqlet</type>
<author id="17342">
SiteDocClan</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;h1&gt;Can I get the PerlMonks source code?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Short answer:&lt;/i&gt; No.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Not so short answer:&lt;/i&gt; PerlMonks is based on a web site engine called [e2://Everything Engine|Everything], which was developed by some of the same people who built the original [http://slashdot.org/|Slashdot] engine. 
In Everything, all of the code and data lives in the database, except for a very small kernel of static perl modules and scripts. In order to replicate PerlMonks, you'd have to get not only those few files but also all of the code stored in the database, as well as the infrastructural data records (lookup tables and whatnot). This is not easy to do. Ordinary users don't have access to those records, and even members of [pmdev] don't have access to all of them. Only the [gods] do.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If your objective is merely to build a site like PerlMonks, you could start with the latest [e2://Everything Engine] code ([http://sourceforge.net/projects/everydevel/|from SourceForge]) and customize it your own way.
&lt;small&gt;(Alternatively, you could start with the [http://devel.everything2.org/ecore|version] used at [e2://|Everything2], which is older than the latest version but still somewhat newer than PerlMonks'. Rumor has it that you can in fact get &lt;i&gt;some&lt;/i&gt; of the database contents (called "nodeballs") if you start with the [e2://] [http://devel.everything2.org/ecore|baseline]. A smidge of info is available [e2://nodeball|over there].)&lt;/small&gt;

Note that the code base used in PerlMonks forked from Everything development over 10 years ago, and the two code bases have moved on significantly, in different directions, since then. A lot of the concepts will resonate between them, but implementation details will differ wildly.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If your objective is to contribute to the maintenance of the PerlMonks site itself, you can. You simply have to [id://238736|join] the [About the PmDev Group|pmdev] group. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Some previous discussions:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[id://318123]&lt;br/&gt;
[id://345757]&lt;br/&gt;
[id://279204]&lt;br/&gt;
[id://177277]&lt;br/&gt;

[pmdev://294759||]
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Back to [PerlMonks FAQ]&lt;/i&gt;
</field>
</data>
</node>
