<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="587754" title="Editing DocLists" created="2006-12-04 17:47:36" updated="2006-12-04 12:47:36">
<type id="17338">
sitefaqlet</type>
<author id="17342">
SiteDocClan</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;h1&gt;Editing DocLists&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[DocList] is a node type whose purpose is to contain a list of other nodes and some associated information. 
Technically, a doclist is a [c2://CompositePattern|composition] of:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; a list of node IDs (via the [id://887] db table) constituting the list itself; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; a text blob (via the [id://878] db table) associated with the list; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; a set of settings, &lt;i&gt;aka "vars"&lt;/i&gt; (via the [id://890] db table) for configuring the list's behavior/appearance. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
In this FAQlet, the [doclist] being viewed is called the "parent", and the nodes contained in its list are called "children".
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The [DocList] node type has [pmdev://519034|associated code] which allows a doclist instance to be represented in a variety of ways, so doclist editors have some flexibility in making each doclist most usable.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
There are two subclasses of [doclist]: [faqlist] and [tutlist]. Only these subclasses are ever instantiated, not [doclist]. (You can think of [doclist] as an [c2://abstract base class], although technically nothing prevents it from being instantiated.) The subclasses ([faqlist] and [tutlist]) are nearly identical in all respects; the main difference have to do with permissions: [SiteDocClan] have authority to edit [faqlist]s, and [Pedagogues] have authority to edit [tutlist]s.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How to Edit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The doclist edit page has three parts, contained in two HTML forms.
Be careful not to try to make changes in both forms at once, or 
you will be unhappy when you lose changes you thought you made.
&lt;li&gt;
The &lt;i&gt;upper form&lt;/i&gt; contains the text blob editor, with "preview" and "update" buttons below it. How to use this editor should be pretty obvious.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
The &lt;i&gt;lower form&lt;/i&gt; contains the doc list editor and the settings editor, with "submit" buttons both above and below.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Making changes to the doc list:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;To insert an item in the list:&lt;/b&gt; Select a new (unused) entry in the list, enter the item's node ID in the right-hand column  (the &lt;b&gt;Node ID&lt;/b&gt; field) and a non-zero list position in the left-hand column (the &lt;b&gt;Position&lt;/b&gt; field). &lt;i&gt;Note: enter only the ID number, e.g. &lt;c&gt;112233&lt;/c&gt;, &lt;b&gt;not&lt;/b&gt; markup like &lt;c&gt;[id://112233]&lt;/c&gt;!!!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;To change the position of an item in the list:&lt;/b&gt; edit the value in its &lt;b&gt;Position&lt;/b&gt; field. You'll have to mentally predict what the resulting order will be.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;To delete an item from the list:&lt;/b&gt; Change the value in its &lt;b&gt;Position&lt;/b&gt; field to 0 (zero).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
For info on making changes to the settings, see the next section.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
When done with your edits to the doc list and/or settings, click either the "Submit below" button above the doc list or the "Submit" button below the Settings.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Settings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
When editing a [doclist], you'll see at the bottom a place to enter arbitrary Settings (name/value pairs). This is presented in a table with a header row like:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table width="50%"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Remove&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Setting&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Value&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Currently, all settings are &lt;b&gt;boolean&lt;/b&gt;: you should set them either to &lt;b&gt;&lt;tt&gt;0&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/b&gt; or to &lt;b&gt;&lt;tt&gt;1&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/b&gt;. Note that the default behavior for each setting (i.e. when not explicitly set) varies, and in some cases is context dependent.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Note that a [doclist]'s settings have no effect except when viewing the doclist &lt;i&gt;directly&lt;/i&gt;.
Any children which are doclists are shown using the parent doclist's settings.
That is: if A and B are both doclists with their own settings, and B is a child of A, then B will be rendered with B's settings when viewing B directly, but will be rendered, like A, with A's settings, when viewing A.
(I think we need to re-verify this. It doesn't quite sound right.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Currently available settings with behavior defined:&lt;/h4&gt; 
&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt; &lt;h4&gt;sections&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[Doclist]s have two &lt;i&gt;render modes&lt;/i&gt;: &lt;b&gt;tree&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;sections&lt;/b&gt;.
The default is &lt;b&gt;tree&lt;/b&gt; mode (sections=0). In this mode, child nodes are represented as &lt;i&gt;links to&lt;/i&gt; each node, (except &lt;a href="#strings"&gt;string&lt;/a&gt; nodes which are expanded in place).
In &lt;b&gt;sections&lt;/b&gt; mode (sections=1), child doclist nodes are "expanded", or &lt;i&gt;embedded&lt;/i&gt;; and a table of contents, with links to the embedded nodes, is shown at the top. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;"Embedding"&lt;/i&gt; means that when the parent doclist is displayed, the &lt;i&gt;contents&lt;/i&gt; of its child nodes will be shown as well. This has two specific, distinct, effects, depending on whether the child node is another [doclist]-type node or a "regular" node (e.g. a [Tutorials|tutorial] or [sitefaqlet]):
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Child node &lt;b&gt;IS&lt;/b&gt; a [doclist]: child node appears as a sub-list and the text associated with it displayed in place. This is how the tutorials page is handled. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Child node IS &lt;b&gt;NOT&lt;/b&gt; a [doclist]: document content of child node is displayed. 
&lt;i&gt;(This needs to be checked, i dont remember that -[demerphq])&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
When this setting is off, child nodes will be shown simply as links, regardless of their node type.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Bottom line:&lt;/b&gt; You should normally only set &lt;tt&gt;sections=1&lt;/tt&gt; for upper-level lists in a hierarchy, where only other lists are linked. Lower-level lists which link to content nodes should not (normally) have &lt;tt&gt;sections&lt;/tt&gt; set.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;recurse&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt; Default = ON! This setting is orthogonal to the tree/sections mode setting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;showauthor&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt; Shows author of linked non-list nodes. Default = ON for all tutlists, OFF otherwise. Only has effect in &lt;b&gt;tree&lt;/b&gt; mode (sections=0).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;showtext&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt; Show the doctext above the list. Default is OFF, but turned ON for the top-level [Tutorials].&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;showtype&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt; For each link, also show a link to its nodetype. Default = ON for users who can edit the doclist, OFF otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;no_string&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt; When ON, &lt;a href="#strings"&gt;string&lt;/a&gt; ([faqstring],[tutstring]) entries link to the actual string node. When OFF (the default), string entries link directly to the target of the string. Turn this on for debugging string links. Only has effect in &lt;b&gt;tree&lt;/b&gt; mode (sections=0). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;What about this &lt;b&gt;Show Auto&lt;/b&gt; checkbox?&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If turned on, an additional column is shown in the &lt;b&gt;Settings&lt;/b&gt; table: &lt;b&gt;Auto&amp;nbsp;Set&amp;nbsp;Value&lt;/b&gt;. It has something to do with nodeballs and other setting-related features. It is very rarely used, and in the context of [doclist]s it is utterly superfluous and should be ignored. But if you're a curious [pmdev|devil], start with [id://895].
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a name="strings"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About DocStrings ([tutstrings], [faqstrings])&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
A [docstring] has two parts: a &lt;b&gt;title&lt;/b&gt; and a &lt;b&gt;text&lt;/b&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;b&gt;title&lt;/b&gt; should not contain links/shortcuts, as it will be used as link text. It is really is the string node's title: monks can link to the string node by title using this value. Example: [SOPW|&lt;c&gt;[SOPW]&lt;/c&gt;]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;b&gt;text&lt;/b&gt; is free-form, and can contain links/shortcuts and other markup, as well as plain text.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When &lt;b&gt;editing&lt;/b&gt; a [docstring], you can edit the &lt;b&gt;title&lt;/b&gt; and the &lt;b&gt;text&lt;/b&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When &lt;b&gt;viewing&lt;/b&gt; a [docstring],
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;b&gt;page title&lt;/b&gt; is the &lt;b&gt;docstring title&lt;/b&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;b&gt;page content&lt;/b&gt; is the &lt;b&gt;docstring text&lt;/b&gt;, rendered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When &lt;b&gt;viewing&lt;/b&gt; a [doclist] which contains a [docstring],
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The entry appears as the docstring's &lt;b&gt;text&lt;/b&gt;, rendered. The docstring's &lt;b&gt;title&lt;/b&gt; is not visible at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When &lt;b&gt;editing&lt;/b&gt; a [doclist] which contains a [docstring],
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The entry is shown as a link whose&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;link text&lt;/b&gt; is the docstring's &lt;b&gt;title&lt;/b&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;link target&lt;/b&gt; is the docstring node itself (by ID).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To add a docstring node to a list, enter the docstring's &lt;b&gt;node ID&lt;/b&gt; &amp;mdash; just like any other doclist entry. (see above)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Bottom line:&lt;/b&gt; In the context of a [doclist], ordinary users will only ever see the docstring's &lt;b&gt;text&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
Even the authorized doclist editors will never see the child docstring's &lt;b&gt;title&lt;/b&gt;, except when viewing the doclist in Edit mode.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When linked as a node in normal situations (i.e. in the Chatterbox or in a post, rather than in a [doclist]), [docstring]s are not treated differently from other nodes. The link text is the docstring's &lt;b&gt;title&lt;/b&gt;, and the link links to the [docstring] node itself. No automatic redirection or anything like that occurs, and the docstring's &lt;b&gt;text&lt;/b&gt; is never used in the rendering of the link.
&lt;/p&gt;
</field>
</data>
</node>
