<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="92977" title="How does Nodes to Consider work?" created="2001-07-01 02:28:32" updated="2005-08-12 21:51:27">
<type id="17338">
sitefaqlet</type>
<author id="17342">
SiteDocClan</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;!--
2003-08-21 [jdporter] Changed title from "I've considered a node, now how does Nodes to Consider work?"; changed links to use id's
2005-07-10 [jdporter] added a little more detail
2005-09-07 [jdporter] "finished" the unfinished job. (but always, Work In Progress...)
2005-11-14 [VSarkiss] The approval nodelet now says "reap", so adjust accordingly.
--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
When a node has been requested for [id://92975|consideration], it appears on the list of [id://28877].  Each node is listed as it would appear on the [id://131|Front Page], with
the addition of the following between the title bar and the body of the node:&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; four radio buttons, labeled 'keep', 'edit', 'reap', and 'nada' (the default).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; the requestor and text of the consideration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
At the bottom of the page is a 'submit' button.
[id://17645]s (and above) can mark a vote on each consideration request.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Once you have voted on a consideration of a node, the radio buttons are replaced with
the current tally of 'keep', 'edit', and 'reap' votes, and you can no longer vote
on that consideration.  Note that submitting your ballot with 'nada' checked doesn't
count as a vote on that consideration.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Each request should be carefully considered.  This means actually reading the node!
If you are in doubt as the proper disposition of the consideration, check 'nada'.
Also reflect on whether you ought to recuse yourself from the vote (for example,
if you are the node author).  Remember, if you vote 'nada', you can always come back
and vote on the consideration later.  See [id://326922]
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If the voting on a consideration goes preponderantly toward &lt;b&gt;edit&lt;/b&gt; (according to a magical formula of the keep/edit/reap tally), the node gets added to the list of "nodes requiring editing"&lt;!--NRE is off limits to most: [id://59481]--&gt;.  This brings it to the attention of the [janitors], who may then take action, as described in [id://324820]. Remember, however, that [janitors] are &lt;i&gt;never&lt;/i&gt; obliged to perform the change, no matter how the voting goes!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If the voting on a consideration goes preponderantly toward &lt;b&gt;reap&lt;/b&gt; (again, according to a magical formula of the keep/edit/reap tally), the node will be &lt;b&gt;automatically&lt;/b&gt; reaped. Note, though, that the conditions under which this happens are quite stringent, the idea being that it's better to err on the side of not reaping a bad node, rather than reaping a good node. 
See [id://409197] for more detail.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Also see: [id://92975]
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Back to the [PerlMonks FAQ]&lt;/i&gt;

</field>
</data>
</node>
