<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="798" title="perlman:perlfaq5" created="1999-10-12 23:30:43" updated="2005-08-14 14:05:14">
<type id="116">
perlman</type>
<author id="113">
root</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
This section deals with I/O and the ``f'' issues: filehandles, flushing, formats, and footers. &lt;BR&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I flush/unbuffer an output filehandle?  Why must I do this?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I change one line in a file/delete a line in a file/insert a line in the middle of a file/append to the beginning of a file?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I count the number of lines in a file?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I make a temporary file name?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I manipulate fixed-record-length files?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I make a filehandle local to a subroutine?  How do I pass filehandles between subroutines?  How do I make an array of filehandles?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I use a filehandle indirectly?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I set up a footer format to be used with write()?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I write() into a string?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I output my numbers with commas added?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I translate tildes (~) in a filename?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How come when I open a file read-write it wipes it out?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Why do I sometimes get an &amp;quot;Argument list too long&amp;quot; when I use &amp;lt;&amp;#042;&amp;gt;?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Is there a leak/bug in glob()?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I open a file with a leading "Å¼çô¾" or trailing blanks?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I reliably rename a file?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I lock a file?]&lt;BR&gt;
[What can't I just open(FH, "&gt;file.lock")?]&lt;BR&gt;
[I still don't get locking.  I just want to increment the number in the file.  How can I do this?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I randomly update a binary file?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I get a file's timestamp in perl?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I set a file's timestamp in perl?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I print to more than one file at once?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I read in a file by paragraphs?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I read a single character from a file?  From the keyboard?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How can I tell if there's a character waiting on a filehandle?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I do a &lt;CODE&gt;tail -f&lt;/CODE&gt; in perl?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I dup() a filehandle in Perl?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I close a file descriptor by number?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Why can't I use "C:\temp\foo" in DOS paths?  What doesn't `C:\temp\foo.exe` work?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Why doesn't glob("*.*") get all the files?]&lt;BR&gt;
[Why does Perl let me delete read-only files?  Why does &lt;CODE&gt;-i&lt;/CODE&gt; clobber protected files?  Isn't this a bug in Perl?]&lt;BR&gt;
[How do I select a random line from a file?]&lt;BR&gt;
</field>
</data>
</node>
