<node>
  <doctext>&lt;p&gt;I loved the 1st edition of this book and couldn't wait to see this one when I fisrt saw that the authors, Joseph Hall, Joshua McAdams and Brian Foy were producing this 2nd edition.  It was billed as a significant update with lots of new material and it is, in my opinion, exacly that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This 2nd edition has a much more readable style (fonts, printing,etc, as well as style).  The examples are, it seems to me, much improved and easier to both understand and digest.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chapters on Unicode and on CPAN were especially interesting to me.  But topics such as the chapter on Regular Expressions were all greatly improved.  I especially like the chapter on Regular Expressions since it is a topic that has always been frustratingly opaque and obtuse to me...yet so often I have to try to use Regexs in my coding.  This book's coverage of regexs is not extensive (it is not, of course, meant to be a tutorial on any of the topics); but the authors somehow...I can't seem to put my finger one it...managed in a few short pages to bring transparency to regexes for me like noone and no other book has!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kudos to Hall, McAdams and Foy...Great job!  I am confident anyone reading this book will not be disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/b&gt; Corrected some typos and re-did the formatting.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;UPDATE 2:&lt;/b&gt; Corrected typos in &lt;i&gt;Review Synopsis&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>31670</type_nodetype>
  <author_user>638334</author_user>
  <createtime>2010-05-18 13:42:42</createtime>
  <itemdescription>A series of Iteminized Suggestions for improving one's Perl programming</itemdescription>
  <identifier>978-0-321-49694-2</identifier>
  <node_id>840554</node_id>
  <usercomment>Super book! Much improved over 1st ed.  Highly Recommend.</usercomment>
  <title>Effective Perl Programming: Ways to Write Better, More Idiomatic Perl 2nd ed.</title>
  <nodeupdated>2010-05-18 13:42:42</nodeupdated>
</node>
