<node>
  <doctext>&lt;h2&gt;potential readers:&lt;/h2&gt;
  Since it is in German, everyone that is more comfortable
  reading German than English, especially beginners and
  intermediate users of perl.

   &lt;h2&gt;contents:&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   compact introduction to Perl in terms of syntax, string
   manipulation, list manipulation, regex etc.&lt;br&gt;
   complete with examples &amp;amp; excercises
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   introduction to OO complete with examples &amp;amp; excercises
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   a chapter on modules and their use, especially:
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    LWP
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    NET::FTP
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    URI::URL
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    diverse HTML modules
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
    again complete with examples &amp;amp; exercises
    &lt;p&gt;
     a chapter on Perl/TK
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     information on installing Perl
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     a CD with the book containing a Perl as source, a binary for
     win32 (all slightly outdated by now in my edition) and all the examples from the book
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;3 stars out of 5&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;
    Fine to start out with. All examples and exercises are code that one might need in everyday computing. The auther even keeps an eye on security &lt;b&gt;-w&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;use strict&lt;/b&gt; are not only explained but also used in the examples.&lt;br&gt;
    But there will come a time in the live of a Perl adept, when he needs more in depth information than this book can give. [Programming Perl] is a must have.&lt;br&gt;
    Another problem with the first edition (the one I have) is the index. Wrong page numbers in an index are not acceptable in a book that you might also use just to look up a function. This problem might have been fixed in a newer edition.
  &lt;p&gt;I still use it alongside my [Programming Perl] (2nd) and [Perl Cookbook].&lt;/p&gt;

</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>31670</type_nodetype>
  <author_user>33990</author_user>
  <createtime>2000-10-18 16:01:00</createtime>
  <itemdescription>Disregarding the title, this book is actually a book written in German aimed at the beginner and intermediate</itemdescription>
  <identifier></identifier>
  <node_id>37343</node_id>
  <usercomment>Go to Perl 5&lt;br&gt;author: &lt;b&gt;Michael Schilli&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;publisher: &lt;b&gt;Addison-Wesley&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;ISBN: 3 273 1378 3</usercomment>
  <title>Go to Perl 5</title>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-10 16:41:22</nodeupdated>
</node>
