<node>
  <doctext>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I love O'reilly. But I also love Addison Wesley. Lincoln
D. Stein's newest title under Addison Wesley is a massive
collection of examples and explanations of the how's and
why's of network programming.
&lt;p&gt;
For the advanced network programmer, there is probably
not much to offer - although there is always some little
detail that even the most experienced guru will overlook.
Such is the nature of our trade. With so much information,
it's hard to learn it all - and especially if you are
an initiate, it seems impossible. This book manages to be
a great introduction AND a great reference book at the
same time - 650 pages total (not including appendices and
the index).
&lt;p&gt;
But for those who are not gurus in network
programming, this is the book to start with.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Network Programming With Perl&lt;/i&gt; starts off not with
networks, but instead with basic I/O. Stein shows how
a Perl script that reads from a socket is very similar
to one that reads from a local filehandle (actually, only one
line is different). The concepts of blocking and buffering
are covered within chapter 1 - pipes, signals, and 
forking are covered in chapter 2. Once these basic building
blocks are understood by the reader, the rest of the 
material in the book becomes much clearer.
&lt;p&gt;
Many useful CPAN modules are covered in this book:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IO::File, IO::Handle, IO::Socket,
&lt;li&gt;Socket
&lt;li&gt;Net::Ftp, Net::Telnet, Net::SMTP
&lt;li&gt;LWP
&lt;li&gt;HTML::Parser
&lt;li&gt;and many, many more
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The first four chapters are the basics, the next five
serve as a cookbook for writing various TCP/IP clients, such
as FTP, POP, and LWP user agents. Chapters 10 through 16
cover the meat and potatoes of server programming: forking
servers, daemons, inetd, some experimental 5.005 version
multi-threading, multiplexing with IO::Select, 
nonblocking I/O, and a whole chapter on 'bullet-proofing'
server code.
&lt;p&gt;
The last chapters cover more specialized areas, such as
UDP chat servers, broadcasting, and multicasting. I wish an example of
multicasting mp3's across a network would have been covered,
but with the infomation provided, coding such an application
should prove to be fairly simple.
&lt;p&gt;
The layout of the book is wonderful. There are many examples
of code, and I really like the way various function explanations
are presented. Platform independance is a goal in this book. 
Windows and Macintosh are covered as well as Unix, but
the last chapter is dedicated soley to Unix: Unix-Domain
sockets.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Network Programming With Perl&lt;/i&gt; covers some of the
same material that can be found in the &lt;i&gt;Perl Cookbook&lt;/i&gt;,
but it has a clear direction that will prove to be 
beneficial to anyone wishing to travel it.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>31670</type_nodetype>
  <author_user>18800</author_user>
  <createtime>2001-02-04 03:58:28</createtime>
  <itemdescription>Licoln D. Stein's book of wonders</itemdescription>
  <identifier>0201615711</identifier>
  <node_id>56273</node_id>
  <usercomment>Everything about network programming with Perl</usercomment>
  <title>Network Programming With Perl</title>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-15 03:10:51</nodeupdated>
</node>
