<node>
  <doctext>&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oreilly.com/catalog/perlcdbs/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.oreilly.com/catalog/covers/perlcdbs.s.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Perl CD Bookshelf&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
By O'Reilly &amp; Associates, Inc.
1st Edition July 1999
1-56592-462-2, Order Number: 4622
, $59.95 , Features CD-ROM
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capsule Review (a la [splinky])
&lt;p&gt;The most useful collection of perl books to date.  5 of 5
&lt;p&gt;For reviews of &lt;u&gt;The Perl Cookbook&lt;/u&gt; and &lt;u&gt;Advanced Perl Programming&lt;/u&gt;,
look at [splinky]'s &lt;a href=&quot;http://perlmonks.org/index.pl?node_id=21670&quot;&gt;
A Review of the Perl Cookbook&lt;/a&gt; and [gryng]'s &lt;a href=&quot;http://perlmonks.org/index.pl?node_id=21811&quot;&gt;
Advanced Perl Programming&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;Who should be interested?
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Any Perl programmer&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Anyone interested in perl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Full Review&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 6 books contained in this set are the ultimate references
and learning materials available for Perl.  These books are:
&lt;u&gt;Learning Perl&lt;/u&gt;, &lt;u&gt;Learning Perl on Win32&lt;/u&gt;, &lt;u&gt;Perl Cookbook&lt;/u&gt;,
&lt;u&gt;Advanced Perl Programming&lt;/u&gt;, &lt;u&gt;Programming Perl&lt;/u&gt;,and &lt;u&gt;Perl In a Nutshell&lt;/u&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;This CD set comes with a hardcopy of &lt;u&gt;Perl In a Nutshell&lt;/u&gt;, and online versions
of the six books listed above.  This set is ready to put on a webserver for your own
personal reference library available from anywhere in the world.  If you don't have a
webserver or wish to use just the CD, the search function for this set allows you to find terms used throughout the compendium
by just starting a Java applet and searching with the custom search page.
&lt;p&gt;It is, without a doubt, the most useful tool I have at my disposal as a Perl programmer.  I can read these books at 
my leisure, or search quickly and easily.  By logging into the restricted area of my webserver, I can use all 6 books from anywhere in the world, whether at work, at home, on business trip, or on vacation.  If you are lucky enough
to have a constant connection to the internet, this book set will save you from having
to lug all 6 books with you, and will save you money over the individual price.
&lt;p&gt;To all of you who hold value, usefulness, and just plain coolness, get this set,
put it on a webserver (don't forget to restrict access), and use it, use it, use it.


&lt;pre&gt;
J. J. Horner
Linux, Perl, Apache, Stronghold, Unix
jhorner@knoxlug.org http://www.knoxlug.org/
&lt;/pre&gt;</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>31670</type_nodetype>
  <author_user>6727</author_user>
  <createtime>2000-07-10 17:20:23</createtime>
  <itemdescription></itemdescription>
  <identifier></identifier>
  <node_id>22049</node_id>
  <usercomment></usercomment>
  <title>Perl CD Bookshelf</title>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-10 15:37:33</nodeupdated>
</node>
