<node>
  <doctext>Authors: Randy Kobes, Peter Wainwright, Shishir Gundavaram with Adrian Arva, Gavin Brown, Arthur Corliss, Joshua Ellis, Pancrazion de Mauro, Simon Oliver, Mark Wilcox. &lt;BR&gt;
Publisher: &lt;a href=&quot;www.wrox.com&quot;&gt;Wrox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
Availability: &lt;a href=&quot;http://search.barnesandnoble.com/booksearch/isbnInquiry.asp?userid=2VLLTM9BY3&amp;isbn=1861004389&amp;itm=2&quot;&gt;Barnesandnoble&lt;a&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
Price: $49.99&lt;P&gt;

After hashing through a few introductory texts, and purchasing &lt;a href =&quot;http://perlmonks.org/index.pl?node_id=169417&quot;&gt;Programming Perl&lt;/a&gt;. I decided to purchase 'Professional Perl Developement' after scanning through it and reading a couple of its pages in a shop. Its quite a large book, and I still have a long way to go before I've read it all. I found the CGI stuff well written, and a good introduction for me, so much so that I'm already writing some useful applications. I also found the LWP chapters very useful and well written. So a thumbs up for the web sections (from me anyhow). The Tk stuff was very good, the examples all worked for me, and I found it a great introduction. Its given me a taster for Tk, and I've just ordered &lt;a href=&quot;http://perlmonks.org/index.pl?node_id=144517&quot;&gt;Mastering Perl/Tk&lt;/A&gt; in the hopes that it can provide me with the higher level of detail that just couldn't be covered by the scope of this book.&lt;BR&gt;
Overall, well written, with good working examples, and a very useful edition in any Perl library. Maybe some other monk with more experience of databases, etc. would review some of the middle chapters that I'm missing out on. &lt;P&gt;
Plato</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>31670</type_nodetype>
  <author_user>262587</author_user>
  <createtime>2003-06-03 05:03:38</createtime>
  <itemdescription>Web server and client programming, Databases, LDAP, Network and distributed programming, Embedded Perl Scripting, XML, Mathematical and computational applications, Graphics, Perl/TK</itemdescription>
  <identifier>1-861004-38-9</identifier>
  <node_id>262599</node_id>
  <usercomment>Good text on some more advanced topics using Perl</usercomment>
  <title>Professional Perl Development</title>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-10 15:50:08</nodeupdated>
</node>
