<node>
  <doctext>This is not the original post!!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

 Published by Que in 1997, 384 pages long with CD-ROM
The book itself is divided into 16 chapters, all of which are simple, easy to understand, and concise and clear.(In my opinion)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The book is used in several college courses that I know of. The code used in the book is exactly how Perl is meant to be. It is very concise with no unecessary lines. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; I can not compare it to other books that I do not have. I believe that is the purpose of the review list, so that you can make the comparisons yourself.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

 This book will get readers quickly on the road to developing robust real-world applications. Various cutting-edge applications are presented. The book addresses the what, why and how behind each application in a very direct fashion so that programmers can begin producing applications immediately.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The book includes object-oriented programming in Perl, advanced CGI applications, security issues, databases, online forms, search engines, shopping carts, MIME documents and other topics. The book also references and makes use of CPAN.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 The CD-ROM contains sample scripts and modulas from the book, the entire Comprehensive Perl Archive Network archive, and pre-compiled ports of Perl for various platforms. The book is targeted at intermediate to advanced internet programmers.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
For those wondering about the author....Bill Middleton works as a computer scientist for Adobe Systems in San Jose, California. His primary duties include automated testing for Adobe products, for which he uses Perl extensively. He also has the privilege of working with some of the original movers and shakers of the computer era at Adobe. Prior to working at Adobe, he worked for Motorola as a UNIX systems administrator. In early 1991, Bill cofounded an Internet service provider in Dallas, Texas, one of the very first ISPs in the country, called Metronet. He holds a B.S. in math/stats, with a minor in Computer Science.
</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>31670</type_nodetype>
  <author_user>225811</author_user>
  <createtime>2003-01-13 12:33:05</createtime>
  <itemdescription>written by Bill Middleton, Brian Deng, &amp; Chris Kemp</itemdescription>
  <identifier></identifier>
  <node_id>226529</node_id>
  <usercomment>This is not my original review. I messed it up trying to reply.</usercomment>
  <title>Web Programming with Perl 5</title>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-10 16:37:49</nodeupdated>
</node>
