<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="603609" title="Searching Perl Documentation" created="2007-03-07 09:30:17" updated="2007-03-07 04:30:17">
<type id="956">
perltutorial</type>
<author id="409850">
blazar</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;h3&gt;Perldoc&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perl comes with its own documentation. The most straightforward and widely preferred way to read it is by means of the &lt;c&gt;perldoc&lt;/c&gt; command line utility. It will give access to specific perl manpages (e.g.: [doc://perlsyn] for Perl syntax or [doc://perlop] for Perl operators) as well as to the documentation for individual functions and faq entries: it supports a large number of command line switches that are described in its own documentation. To access the latter just issue the following command at your shell's prompt:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;[doc://perldoc|perldoc perldoc]&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some tips about where to look for some particular information, see [brian_d_foy]'s [id://408254] [tutorials|tutorial].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To put it briefly, however, most times you will want to use &lt;c&gt;perldoc&lt;/c&gt; as in one of the following examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[doc://perldata|perldoc perldata] - to read about Perl data types;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[doc://open|perldoc -f open] - to read about the &lt;c&gt;open()&lt;/c&gt; function;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;c&gt;perldoc -q "how do I do X"&lt;/c&gt; - to search the [doc://perlfaq|FAQ].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;HTML&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The language used by &lt;c&gt;perldoc&lt;/c&gt;, [doc://perlpod|POD] makes it easy to render the documentation in a variety of target formats, including HTML. Some Perl distributions, most notably [http://www.activestate.com/|ActiveState]'s [http://www.activestate.com/Products/ActivePerl/|ActivePerl], a very popular one under Windows, come with ready made HTML documentation, wich some find easier to read and walk through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An HTML version of the documentation is also available on the web at [http://perldoc.perl.org/] and some other locations. As such, it can be searched through with [http://www.google.com|Google] and the above mentioned [id://408254|tutorial] contains some specific examples about how to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A [id://352893|POD Quick Reference] is also available here, at the [href://?|Monastery], which provides a &lt;em&gt;categorized&lt;/em&gt; list of the most frequently used docs right in front of the reader for easy and intuitive access to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Grep&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people prefer to use a [wp://grep] or grep-like utility to search specific stuff in the POD documentation installed on their computers, and one can indeed use such an approach when everything else fails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under *NIX osen or [http://www.cygwin.com/|cygwin], several grep-like utilities are generally availabe out of the box. Under Windows one can use ports from the [http://unxutils.sourceforge.net/|UNXUTILS] or [http://gnuwin32.sourceforge.net/|GnuWin32] collections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other options include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the pure Perl [wp://grep|tcgrep] [http://search.cpan.org/dist/ppt/bin/grep|implementation] from the [dist://ppt|Perl Power Tools] project;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the specialized [http://search.cpan.org/dist/pmtools/podgrep|podgrep] utility from the [dist://pmtools] distribution;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[zentara]'s [id://524324];&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[id://573020], which in turn borrows the pretty formatting of&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[petdance]'s [http://search.cpan.org/~petdance/ack/ack|ack].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Other options&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One additional possibility is to use the [http://search.cpan.org/~ulpfr/perlindex-1.502/perlindex.PL|perlindex] utility, which is &lt;em&gt;"a program to index and search the perl documentation."&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The [http://search.cpan.org/dist/Tk-Pod/tkpod|tkpod] standalone [mod://Tk] POD viewer from [mod://Tk::Pod] (which is a GUI for viewing and browsing Perl's POD documentation) also provides an interface to perlindex if it is installed, and its features additionally include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;support for single or multiple POD windows;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tree view of available PODs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet another alternative to perldoc is [mod://Pod::Webserver], a minimal web server which serves local Perl documentation: with it one can browse all the docs available on the machine it runs on with a web browser.&lt;/p&gt;
</field>
</data>
</node>
