<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="7940" title="Using can With Inheritance" created="2000-04-18 18:07:47" updated="2005-08-15 12:11:26">
<type id="956">
perltutorial</type>
<author id="2675">
btrott</author>
<data>
<keywords>
<keyword rating="">
can</keyword>
</keywords>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;h1&gt;Using can With Inheritance&lt;/h1&gt;

This started out as a Q &amp; A on using can, so that's how
it'll start.&lt;p&gt;

If you asked, "How can I determine whether a particular
object has a particular method?", an answer would be:&lt;p&gt;

Use the [can] method on your object. From [perlobj]:

&lt;code&gt;
    can(METHOD)

    can checks to see if its object has a method called METHOD. If it does
    then a reference to the sub is returned; if it does not then undef is
    returned.
&lt;/code&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;A Scenario&lt;/h2&gt;

This is relatively simple and straightforward. I found a
rather interesting use for it the other day, though.
Here was the scenario:&lt;p&gt;

I had created (basically) an abstract base class for
holding a tree-like data structure. The base class
contained all of the methods necessary to interact with
the data structure--to get data out, to put data in, etc.&lt;p&gt;

But the base class didn't have any notion of how to read
the data in from an external source; that was to be
provided by the subclasses.&lt;p&gt;

So I also defined two subclasses: one for processing XML
data and one for processing a different format.&lt;p&gt;

The base class also had a recurse method--supplied with a
callback method, it would recurse into the data structure
and call the callback for each node found in the tree. I
had defined some simple callbacks: one to pretty-print the
data to the screen; one to dump the data in HTML format
using unordered lists; and one to write the file to disk
in either XML or this other format. These callbacks were
"private" functions, though, so I also provided accessor
methods to return sub references to the callbacks.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;A Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

The problem, though, was that these accessor methods were
defined in my base class, and I wanted to allow for my
subclasses to override the callback methods. However, I
(obviously) wouldn't know whether or not they overrode
the methods until run-time, so I couldn't hard-code the
subclass name into my accessor functions.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;A Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

So I used can. When I defined a new object, it was blessed
into one of my subclasses; so, in my accessor methods,
I realized that I could call can with the callback method
name as the argument, and I'd get back the "correct"
version of the callback method.&lt;p&gt;

So, for example, here's a stripped-down version of my
base class:

&lt;code&gt;
    package A;

    # stuff taken out

    sub get_write_file_func {
        my $self = shift;
        return $self-&gt;can("_write_file");
    }
&lt;/code&gt;

The method "_write_file" is defined in my subclasses, so
here's an example one of those:

&lt;code&gt;
    package A::B;
    use A;

    use vars qw/@ISA/;
    @ISA = qw/A/;

    # stuff taken out

    sub _write_file {
        my($path, $val, $start) = @_;
        # ...
    }
&lt;/code&gt;</field>
<field name="reputation">
42</field>
</data>
</node>
