<node>
  <doctext>&lt;!--
2003-05-23 [Mr. Muskrat] added link back to the PerlMonks FAQ
2004-01-26 [jdporter] updated, regularized.
2004-07-25 Fixed a minor typo:  s/End the end/In the end/
2006-03-14 [jdporter] just try to answer the question head-on. moved the overly [gods]-centric content to 238736.
--&gt;

&lt;!-- This FAQlet was originally derived from [id://174035], which was written by [Petruchio] on 2002-06-12. --&gt;


&lt;h1&gt;Do I have privacy on PerlMonks?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
 The [gods] (the system administrators) have full access to the site's code, database, and logs. This is necessary in the course of site maintenance and development, as in any web-based discussion board/community. (Other [id://238736|special user groups], such as the [id://106850|developers] and [id://59438], have powers which can affect other users, but these powers are limited by constraints built into the site. The [gods] can have no such constraints.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 The [gods] use handy web-based tools for performing site maintenance tasks, and very few of these tools would be useful in user tracking. Provisions have been made to shield sensitive user information (such as passwords) from casual inspection, even by the gods. For example, the tool which allows a [gods|god] to look at a user's variables does not display the password.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 The [gods] and [power users] can temporarily silence users from trying to speak in the [Chatterbox]. This power is occasionally necessary when someone is being abusive, or (more rarely) when it is detected that one of the participants is, ehrm, not human (i.e. a 'bot).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 The [gods] and [janitors] have the ability to modify the content of posts.
 This happens on a regular basis, although it is far more often to correct minor errors of formatting than objectionable content. (See [id://92975] for more info.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 In terms of tracking users, the [gods] do perform some statistical analyses of records, which are devised to treat users in the aggregate, anonymously. These tools allow the [gods] to isolate individual users with unusual usage patterns, without having to expose their personal data.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 The [gods] have no interest in your voting record, and never collect or examine such stats.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 The [gods] adhere to an ethic which reflects the site's tradition of voluntary self-restraint and respect for others.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 However, there are simply no rock-solid safeguards for your personal information or your habits. You should understand this, and align your actions accordingly.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Back to [PerlMonks FAQ]&lt;/i&gt;
</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>17338</type_nodetype>
  <node_id>174053</node_id>
  <author_user>17342</author_user>
  <title>Do I have privacy on PerlMonks?</title>
  <createtime>2002-06-12 18:41:35</createtime>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-12 13:33:02</nodeupdated>
</node>
