<node>
  <doctext>&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;display&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Display Settings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Use [id://450961] to control how pages appear generally.
This covers not only HTML styling (CSS), but also various
PerlMonks-specific options, such as how &lt;c&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;/c&gt;, 
&lt;c&gt;&lt;readmore&gt;&lt;/c&gt;, and &lt;c&gt;&lt;spoiler&gt;&lt;/c&gt; tags are handled.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;tagopts&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Special Tag Options&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Override &lt;c&gt;&lt;readmore&gt;&lt;/c&gt; tags:&lt;/b&gt; users are requested
to insert a &lt;c&gt;&lt;readmore&gt;&lt;/c&gt; tag in a post that
contains a long code section. In order to keep page lengths
short in certain areas of the site, the remainder of the post
will be replaced by a link to the full content of the post.
Check this box if you would rather ignore the
&lt;c&gt;&lt;readmore&gt;&lt;/c&gt; tags and see the full text everywhere.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;render spoiler tags as&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Customize CPAN link options:&lt;/b&gt;
This modifies the effect of the &lt;c&gt;[cpan://...]&lt;/c&gt; [id://43037|shortcut] style.
If this variable is unset (empty), &lt;c&gt;[cpan://Foo]&lt;/c&gt; will render as the link
&lt;tt&gt;http://search.cpan.org/search?query=Foo&amp;&lt;b&gt;mode=module&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
If this variable is set, &lt;tt&gt;&lt;b&gt;mode=module&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/tt&gt; will be replaced with the
contents of this variable.
Possibilities for &lt;c&gt;mode&lt;/c&gt; are: &lt;c&gt;qw( all module dist author )&lt;/c&gt;.
Additionally, you can ask to get [cpan://] search results in XML form by
including
&lt;c&gt;format=xml&lt;/c&gt; in this setting. (Note, however, that this feature is 
[http://search.cpan.org/faq.html#Can_I_get_the_results_to_be_output_in_XML_format?|not supported].)
&lt;br/&gt;
Remember, &lt;i&gt;this setting affects how cpan:// links work for &lt;b&gt;you&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;HTML Related Options&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
As you know, PerlMonks allows only a restricted subset of HTML
to be used in posts.  (See [id://29281] for the list or [id://674668] 
for illustrations of usage and rendering.) This is enforced each time 
a node is rendered, not when the content is submitted by the poster.  
When a node is rendered, it is filtered through a process which escapes 
all the invalid markup &amp;mdash; whether invalid tags, or invalid attributes on
valid tags &amp;mdash; thus rendering the markup visible as plain text.
As an additional nicety, the same filter can &amp;mdash;
if you ask it to &amp;mdash; close unclosed tags as necessary to ensure
balanced tags.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you're curious about the operation of this filter on the nodes
you view, you can enable &quot;reporting&quot; to various degrees of verbosity.
That's what the following settings do.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Enforce proper nesting of HTML&lt;/b&gt; - 
If set, PerlMonks adds explicit closing tags in cases where an element was
&lt;i&gt;implicitly&lt;/i&gt; closed due to the ending of an outer element.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;HTML error reporting level&lt;/b&gt; - 
This controls how much you are told about what PerlMonks had to do
to a node's content to make it compliant with [id://29281].
By default, these little notes will be shown in a medium gray font. 
This can be customized with CSS:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markup which has been added will be in &lt;c&gt;&lt;font class=&quot;htmlinserted&quot;&gt;&lt;/c&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tags which have been escaped will be in &lt;c&gt;&lt;font class=&quot;htmlignored&quot;&gt;&lt;/c&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attributes which have been escaped will be in &lt;c&gt;&lt;font class=&quot;htmlattrib&quot;&gt;&lt;/c&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
Here's what the different levels mean:
&lt;ol start=0&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No reporting. All HTML filtering is completely &quot;silent&quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show when markup had to be added.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show when attributes had to be escaped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show when tags had to be escaped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show when tags had to be escaped, and also when there are unclosed &lt;c&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/c&gt; tags.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
The levels are cumulative: level 3 implies level 2, etc.&lt;br/&gt;
Note that level 4 is not an option for viewing nodes in general, since unclosed
&lt;c&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/c&gt; tags is an extremely minor sin which pretty much always be overlooked.
&lt;!--
 &quot;level 3 and above will likely eventually be disabled except for one's own nodes,&quot;
    saith [tye] in cb on 2007-05-14
--&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;A word from your [gods|sysadmins]:&lt;/i&gt; Harrassing other users for
the perceived low quality of their postings markup will not be tolerated.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;HTML error reporting during Preview&lt;/b&gt; - 
This setting is the same as above, but only pertains to the
Preview stage of the node posting process.
Note that you can't select any level lower than 3.
This is because we want you to post good, clean nodes!
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;titles&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Custom Node Title Definition&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You may customize the text that appears in your browser's title
bar here.  Use the tokens %T, %N, %D and %S to insert the current
node's title, node id, date, or section name. The section name
will only actually appear for base nodes.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Code Listing Settings&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Code Wrapping Off:&lt;/b&gt; by default, the site will
wrap all content that appears between &lt;c&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;/c&gt; tags at
70 columns.  you can turn that off if you wish, but it can
be difficult to read the site as unwrapped code will be
rendered at the full width.  This can mean a lot of
horizontal scrolling to see the right hand side of the
page.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Code Wrap Length:&lt;/b&gt; you may set the column at
which code will be wrapped.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Auto Code Wrapping:&lt;/b&gt; allows your browser to
perform code wrapping.  If this is set, the value in
&lt;b&gt;Code Wrap Length&lt;/b&gt; can be used to insert soft hyphens
in long runs of non-space characters.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;a name=&quot;code_prefix&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Code Prefix:&lt;/b&gt; whatever you enter here will be
used as a prefix for lines inside &lt;c&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;/c&gt; blocks. 
If you specify something that matches &lt;c&gt;/&amp;\d+;/&lt;/c&gt;,
then those digits will be incremented for each line of code.
Typically you would specify &lt;c&gt;&amp;001;: &lt;/c&gt; to have all code
lines numbered starting from 001. &lt;i&gt;Note - This is &lt;u&gt;not&lt;/u&gt;
an HTML entity, although it was meant to look like one.  
It is specially interpreted by the perlmonks engine.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Large Code Font:&lt;/b&gt; This setting increases 
the font size of everything posted within &lt;c&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/c&gt; tags (or
&lt;code&gt;&lt;c&gt;&lt;/c&gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags).  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Normally, when text in a fixed-pitch font (such as Courier) is shown
next to text in a variable-pitch font (such as Times) &lt;i&gt;in the same
size&lt;/i&gt;, (e.g. 12 point), the fixed-width text appears noticeably larger.
To compensate for this and achieve a more equal-looking text size,
PerlMonks normally decreases the size of code text by one point, by
enclosing it in &lt;tt&gt;&amp;lt;font&amp;nbsp;size=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;/tt&gt; tags.
If you wish to disable this feature, you should check this setting checkbox.
You would do this, for example, if you are handling your own font sizing
in CSS. Block-level code blocks are wrapped in
&lt;tt&gt;&amp;lt;tt&amp;nbsp;class=&quot;codetext&quot;&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;
and in-line code blocks are wrapped in
&lt;tt&gt;&amp;lt;tt&amp;nbsp;class=&quot;inlinecode&quot;&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;.
In CSS, you'd define styles using &lt;tt&gt;tt.codetext&lt;/tt&gt; and
&lt;tt&gt;tt.inlinecode&lt;/tt&gt; respectively.
However, you may simply wish to set all &lt;c&gt;&lt;tt&gt;&lt;/c&gt; segments
to one point size smaller, via &lt;code&gt;
tt { font-size: smaller; }
&lt;/code&gt;
in your custom CSS.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;theme&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Theme Configuration&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The appearance of the PerlMonks site can be changed by
choosing from one of several themes.  You can stay with the
default or pick a specialized theme.  The dark theme
exists for the people who prefer light text on dark
backgrounds.  Choosing a theme other than the default makes
it easy to remember if you are logged in or not.  &quot;Monk
pictures off&quot; turns off the random monk picture in the top
right corner of every page, while &quot;Monk quips off&quot; turns off
the pithy quotes on the top left.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;styles&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[href://?node_id=450961#Stylesheet-Settings|Stylesheet Settings]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In addition to the themes above, you can alter the
appearance of the PerlMonks site with your own custom
CSS stylesheets.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Link to external CSS stylesheet:&lt;/i&gt; You can link
to a stylesheet you maintain on another webserver by
entering the stylesheet's URL here.  This stylesheet will be loaded
after any stylesheets specified for your selected theme.
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;On-Site CSS Markup:&lt;/i&gt; Any CSS code you enter here
will be inserted into all pages you view.
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Link to CSS stylesheet for print display type:&lt;/i&gt;
At the top of each page just under the title are two
links labeled &quot;print&quot; and &quot;xml&quot;.  The print link causes
the current page to be redisplayed in a format suitable
for printing.  You can alter this format by specifying a
stylesheet to use for print display type.
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Back to the [PerlMonks FAQ]&lt;/i&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>17338</type_nodetype>
  <node_id>786921</node_id>
  <author_user>17342</author_user>
  <title>Help for Display Settings</title>
  <createtime>2009-08-07 16:47:13</createtime>
  <nodeupdated>2009-08-07 16:47:13</nodeupdated>
</node>
