<node>
  <doctext>&lt;!--
2001-02    [turnstep] added sopwify item
2003-05-22 [Mr. Muskrat] s/Perl Monks/PerlMonks/
2004-01-28 [jdporter] major upgrade
2004-03-20 [davido] Multiple markup cleanups. commented out QA approval text for later deletion; the q/a approval feature is only available to gods.
2004-06-21 [jdporter] For editing replies, pointed reader at docs on Consideration, instead of recommending /msg janitors.
--&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;How does editing work in the Q&amp;A section?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The [id://11732|QandAEditors] maintain the [id://1843|Categorized Questions and Answers]
section of the site, which is meant to be a local, living Perl FAQ database.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Only monks of at least [id://198665] can submit questions to this section.
All registered monks can submit answers.
The nodes which get created for the questions and answers can only be
edited by [id://11732|QandAEditors].
(Even so, the contributor of the question/answer gets credit for any XP generated by the
node getting up-/down-voted.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The [id://11732|QandAEditors] have complete liberty to create, modify, and delete [id://1843|QandA]
nodes as they see fit.  
They endeavor to ensure that all the information in that section is factually correct and
concise. However, since [QandAEditors] aren't always the greatest Perl gurus in the world,
they are expected to rely on feedback from the PerlMonks community to keep QandA quality
high.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[id://11732|QandAEditors] respond to requests for action in the [id://1843|QandA] section.
If you would like them to do something, such as improve the wording of a question,
or remove a bad answer, send your request via &lt;tt&gt;[msg://QandAEditors]&lt;/tt&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[id://11732|QandAEditors] have few constraints on what they can do in the [id://1843|QandA] section.
But one thing thing they &lt;i&gt;can't&lt;/i&gt; do is edit or delete replies to answers. Replies are ordinary
[id://11]-type nodes, and thus not technically &quot;in&quot; the [id://1843] section. 
If such an action is needed, [id://92975|flag the node for consideration].
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;small&gt;
&lt;b&gt;A note about [id://11]s and threads:&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
When viewing a CatQ, the CatA's, if any, are listed below it. This is not a thread in the usual sense, as it does not display anything below the CatA's (that is, replies of CatA's).
Similarly, when viewing a CatA, it shows at the top which CatQ it is an answer to, and which Category it's in; but it does not say &quot;in reply to&quot; and &quot;in thread&quot;, as is done for normal [id://11]-type replies. 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
On the other hand, a CatA &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a thread root in the usual sense (like a root post in [SoPW], for example), in terms of displaying its replies.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
However, the similarity is superficial.  In normal sections, the &lt;c&gt;root&lt;/c&gt; field of each reply points to the root post of the thread.
In CatQ&amp;amp;A, the &lt;c&gt;root&lt;/c&gt; field of each reply points not to the CatA to which it is a reply, but to the &lt;i&gt;category&lt;/i&gt; (a [id://1823] node) containing the CatQ!
&lt;br/&gt;
Therefore, when you use [id://3989], you won't be able to find CatA replies using the section selector: there is no checkbox for [id://1823].
&lt;br/&gt;
Actually, if you try it, you will get some hits, but these are from the very early days, when CatA replies had their &lt;c&gt;root&lt;/c&gt; field set to the CatA itself, rather than to the category node.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
CatA replies can be found by SuperSearching for [href://?node_id=3989;xr=1;pa=QandAEditors|replies to nodes owned by QandAEditors].&lt;br/&gt;
Where the right-most column of the results says &lt;tt&gt;Re:[SoPW]&lt;/tt&gt;, those are threads (some? all?) which have been [id://46722|SoPWified].&lt;br/&gt;
Where the right-most column says &lt;tt&gt;Re:[CatA]&lt;/tt&gt;, those are the old threads which have their 'root' field set to the CatA (as mentioned above), rather than to the category (the [id://1823] node).&lt;br&gt;
[href://?node_id=3989;xr=1;pa=QandAEditors;CA;Wi;CQ|This search] finds just those two classes of replies.

&lt;!--

Note (:-) that [categorized question] and [categorized answer] are, strictly speaking, subclasses of [note]!
[QandASection] is simply a [node], and thus does not have 'parent' and 'root' fields.


Parent field:

	Set just as in a normal thread, with the root of the thread being the QA section, for all types (CatQ, CatA, replies)

	QASection &gt; CatQ &gt; CatA &gt; reply &gt; reply.

Root field:

	CatQ: 0 (zero)
	CatA: 0 (zero) 

	Replies: Section, or the actual thread root if SoPWified. But some old CatA replies have root set incorrectly to the CatA.

In SS, if you search for replies of CatQ &amp; CatA, you will
only find notes which have their root set INCORRECTLY.
E.g. 349211, which has its root = its parent, the CatA.

--&gt;

&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
Another power [id://11732|QandAEditors] notably lack is the ability to affect the approval 
of a [id://1843|QandA] node, which is what determines whether the question/answer is displayed high or low on the list. 
Approval is granted by [id://17645]s and above, and since
most, if not all, [id://11732|QandAEditors] will be in this range, they should be able to approve.
However, &lt;i&gt;un&lt;/i&gt;-approving is a power reserved for the [janitors].
See [id://17688] for more detail.
&lt;/p&gt;
--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[id://11732|QandAEditors] can convert a [id://1843|QandA] submission into a [id://479|SoPW] post,
at their own discretion. (There is no mechanism for the reverse transformation, however.)
&lt;br/&gt;
Note that this does not require the node to be in an unapproved state -- unlike the 'Move node to another section' [id://17688|moderation] power which [id://17645]s have.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In general, the [id://11732|QandAEditors] are good at keeping up with the maintenance
of the [id://1843|Categorized Questions and Answers] section. On the off-chance
that you see something which requires their attention, you can &lt;tt&gt;[msg://QandAEditors]&lt;/tt&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Related: [id://162297|Why are categorized questions and answers displayed separately from the rest of my writeups?]
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;H3&gt;Things QandAEditors Can Do&lt;/H3&gt;

&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Respond to requests to have Questions/Answers cleaned up
&lt;LI&gt;&quot;SoPWify&quot; Questions/Answers which ought to be in the [Seekers of Perl Wisdom] section
&lt;li&gt;Make question titles more descriptive
&lt;li&gt;Remove/rework questions which aren't general enough for this section
&lt;LI&gt;Remove repeat answers
&lt;LI&gt;Remove wrong answers
&lt;LI&gt;Remove answers which aren't answers
&lt;LI&gt;Add links where appropriate
&lt;LI&gt;Clean up any bad/missing &lt;code&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags
&lt;/UL&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
They have the [id://133122], which they use to plan and coordinate their activities.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;H3&gt;The mechanics of editing&lt;/H3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Things work a little bit differently for questions and for answers.
We'll talk about questions first, then answers.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;

&lt;dt&gt; &lt;p&gt;To edit a question: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	When viewing a question, you can edit the title in the box labeled 'Title' and the body in the box labeled 'Optional&amp;nbsp;Description'. (It's &quot;optional&quot; because it is at least theoretically possible to phrase the entire question in the title.) &lt;br/&gt;
	You can also set the category. For this, there is a pulldown menu right above the 'Title' box.&lt;br/&gt;
	When you're done, press the 'Submit' button.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt; &lt;p&gt;To remove a question: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;i&gt;First&lt;/i&gt;, be sure to &lt;b&gt;Delete all of the question's answers&lt;/b&gt;, if any!&lt;br/&gt;
	&lt;i&gt;Then&lt;/i&gt; click the &lt;u&gt;delete&lt;/u&gt; link which is right at the top of the node.&lt;br/&gt;
(Note: this convenience link requires javascript to function. If you don't have javascript enabled, you can simply add &lt;code&gt;;op=nuke&lt;/code&gt; to the node's basic URL.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt; &lt;p&gt;To move a question out of CatQA into SoPW:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Find the &lt;u&gt;SOPWify!&lt;/u&gt; link, immediately below the body of the question (above the category pulldown menu). Click it.&lt;br/&gt;
(As above, this simply re-fetches the node with &lt;code&gt;op=sopwify&lt;/code&gt; added to the URL.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt; &lt;p&gt;To edit an answer: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	For this, you must be viewing the answer's node. (From the parent question node, click the &quot;Answer:&amp;nbsp;...&quot; title link of the answer you wish to edit.)&lt;br/&gt;
	Scroll to the bottom and edit the title and/or text.&lt;br/&gt;
	Click the 'update' button when done.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;To remove an answer:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	For this, you must be viewing the parent question's thread, &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; the answer's node.&lt;br/&gt;
	You may remove any number of answers in one submission (so please exercise caution).
	Use the 'submit' button located immediately below the question, i.e. above the list of answers.&lt;br/&gt;
	In the header above each question, there are two checkboxes: 'delete' and 'kill'.
	They have identical effects, except that 'kill' also deducts 1 [id://5938|XP] from the answer's author.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Edits to categorized questions and answers do not produce entries in the
[id://434853|janitation log].
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Note that nothing special is shown in the QandAEditors&amp;nbsp;Nodelet when viewing a categorized question or answer. Neither is the Moderation&amp;nbsp;Nodelet displayed.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
When viewing a Categorized&amp;nbsp;Question, the name of the original
poster is shown with the Question and each Answer.&lt;br/&gt;
However, when viewing a Categorized&amp;nbsp;Answer, this info is not
displayed.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The ID of the user who posted a Cat Q or A is stored in the node's
&lt;tt&gt;original_author&lt;/tt&gt; field.&lt;br/&gt;
If you're a [pmdev]il, you can click the [id://153451|Dump Fields] link
in the PmDev Nodelet to see this (and other) fields.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Back to the [PerlMonks FAQ]&lt;/i&gt;</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>17338</type_nodetype>
  <node_id>20059</node_id>
  <author_user>17342</author_user>
  <title>How does editing work in the Q&amp;A section?</title>
  <createtime>2000-06-27 19:23:26</createtime>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-14 18:48:43</nodeupdated>
</node>
