<node>
  <doctext>&lt;!-- 2004-01-03 jdporter Created --&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;How do I work with Scratchpads?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Viewing another monk's scratchpad&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If you know the name of the monk whose scratchpad you'd like to see,
you can first navigate to their home node (by e.g. clicking on their
name in the chatterbox), then click on the 'View' link next to the 
word &lt;b&gt;Scratchpad:&lt;/b&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If you are in a place for typing monastery
content (such as a node or the chatterbox), you can enter 
&lt;tt&gt;&amp;#91;pad://&lt;i&gt;username&lt;/i&gt;]&lt;/tt&gt; and this will rendered as a
link directly to their scratchpad.  For example, &lt;code&gt;[pad://vroom]&lt;/code&gt;
results in [pad://vroom].
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Alternatively, there is one node which allows access to any 
scratchpad by username: the [id://108949].
You can go there and type in a monk's name.
Or, if you're making a URL, you can write
&lt;tt&gt;?node_id=108949;user=&lt;i&gt;username&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;
(If the link is for use off-site, be sure to include
the &lt;tt&gt;http://perlmonks.org/&lt;/tt&gt; part. ;-)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Viewing your own scratchpad&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Same as above (using your own username, of course).
But in addition, if you type &lt;tt&gt;&amp;#91;pad://]&lt;/tt&gt;,
it results in a link that says &lt;u&gt;my scratchpad&lt;/u&gt;.
However, this works only in the PerlMonks messaging system (private messages and chatterbox),
not on nodes.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Editing your scratchpad&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
You actually have two scratchpads: a public one and a private one.
The above discussion relates to public scratchpads only.
Private scratchpads are hidden from mere mortal monks (i.e. [gods]
can see them, because they see all).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Editing your public and private scratchpads is done all on one page.
You can update one or both in one submission.
To get there, simply go to your home node and click 'Edit' next to
the word &lt;b&gt;Scratchpad:&lt;/b&gt;.  (The 'Edit' link takes you to the same node
as the 'View' link, but the scratchpads are ready for editing; this
is controlled by the addition of &lt;i&gt;&lt;code&gt;displaytype=edit&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
in the URL.)
If you're already viewing your scratchpads, you can enter edit mode by
clicking the 'Edit' link which appears just above the current public
scratchpad content. When you're done editing, click the 'Submit' button.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now, there are a few more tricks.  
If you have your [id://786931|Personal Nodelet] enabled, 
there will be a couple of links at the bottom of that nodelet, saying
&quot;Add&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;&lt;u&gt;public&lt;/u&gt;&amp;nbsp;/&amp;nbsp;&lt;u&gt;private&lt;/u&gt;&amp;nbsp;pad&quot;.
If you click one of these links,
it inserts a link &lt;i&gt;the current node&lt;/i&gt; (whatever you're viewing at the time)
at the bottom of your public or private scratchpad, respectively.
This can be handy if you like to use your scratchpad for maintaining lists of bookmarks.
&lt;br/&gt;
(Go to [id://25185] to enable your Personal Nodelet.)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related Discussion&lt;/h3&gt;

See [id://366368].

&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Back to [PerlMonks FAQ]&lt;/i&gt;
</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>17338</type_nodetype>
  <node_id>418988</node_id>
  <author_user>17342</author_user>
  <title>How do I work with Scratchpads?</title>
  <createtime>2005-01-03 12:14:20</createtime>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-12 13:44:32</nodeupdated>
</node>
