<node>
  <doctext>&lt;h1&gt;How does 'Select Code to Download' Work?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The 'Select Code to Download' feature is available via a link labeled &lt;b&gt;Select&lt;/b&gt; in a bar immediately below a node containing multiple &lt;c&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;/c&gt; blocks.  It appears in a line which looks like the following:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; cellpadding=&quot;2&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;?displaytype=selectcode;node_id=131&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Select&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
or
&lt;a href=&quot;?displaytype=displaycode;node_id=131&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Download&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Code
&amp;mdash;
&lt;a href=&quot;?node_id=131;sendto=Paco;replytotext=&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Send private /msg&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
to Paco
&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Note, again, that the &lt;b&gt;Select&lt;/b&gt; link only appears if the node being displayed contains more than one &lt;c&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;/c&gt; block.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
When you click on the &lt;b&gt;Select&lt;/b&gt; link, you are taken to a page which allows you to select one or more of the code blocks from the source node.  Each code block has a checkbox next to it. You check all the ones you want to download in one operation, then click the 'Download Selected Code' button. The result is plain text page ([wp://MIME] type &lt;c&gt;text/plain&lt;/c&gt;) containing the text of all the code blocks you selected.  If you selected more than one, they will be separated in the resulting page by lines of the following text:
&lt;c&gt;

##&lt;/code&gt;&lt;code&gt;##

&lt;/c&gt;
Note: if you click the button with &lt;i&gt;none&lt;/i&gt; of the checkboxes checked, it will be the same as if you had &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; of the checkboxes checked.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Each code block also has a link next to it, &lt;c&gt;&quot;download this&quot;&lt;/c&gt;, which is just like the &lt;c&gt;[download]&lt;/c&gt; links which appear on the main node display beneath each code block.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Show inline code blocks?  What's that about?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The effect of setting this setting is that &quot;inline&quot; code strings will also be included in the list of code blocks available for download in this page.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This is a sticky user configuration setting.  That is, when you check or clear the checkbox and click 'stumbit', PerlMonks remembers the setting.
&lt;/p&gt;

</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>17338</type_nodetype>
  <node_id>626918</node_id>
  <author_user>17342</author_user>
  <title>How does 'Select Code to Download' Work?</title>
  <createtime>2007-07-16 16:32:25</createtime>
  <nodeupdated>2007-07-16 12:32:25</nodeupdated>
</node>
