<node>
  <doctext>&lt;!--
2003-03-17 [boo_radley] created placeholder
2003-09-19 [Mr. Muskrat] (alpha) content graciously provided by phydeauxarff
2003-10-28 [Mr. Muskrat] (Beta) nitpicking copyediting, added space between sentences, removed contractions, etc...
2004-04-17 [Mr. Muskrat] no content changes, updated status to 'Stable'
2004-06-05 [Mr. Muskrat] changed version number to 1.0, should have done that back in 2004-04
--&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;I need help!  Who can help me?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If you are seeking enlightenment regarding the use of Perl, then you are in the right place.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
First, you will want to create a user account on PerlMonks.  See the section [id://156908|Creating an account on PerlMonks] for more detail concerning how and why you will want to do this but the short answer is that you will be able to easily find your question and see replies even if your question is not [id://17688|approved].
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But more importantly, creating a user allows you to more fully participate and gain the most benefit from The Monastery.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Now you need to decide where to post your plea for assistance.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Most likely if you have a question that is of any significant length or requires the inclusion of source code, you will want to post it to [id://479] (Seekers of Perl Wisdom) but before you do, be sure to read [id://483077] in the [PerlMonks FAQ] for guidance on how to properly format your question for the greatest effect.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If your question is a quick snippet that can be answered in a line or two, you can often post it in the Chatterbox and the Monks who are hanging around at the time will offer guidance and assistance as they are able.  Before doing this you will want to be sure to check out the [id://236794|Chatterbox FAQ] for information on CB etiquette and alternate clients that can make your experience more rewarding.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Back to the [PerlMonks FAQ]&lt;/i&gt;</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>17338</type_nodetype>
  <node_id>243873</node_id>
  <author_user>17342</author_user>
  <title>I need help! Who can help me?</title>
  <createtime>2003-03-17 23:22:43</createtime>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-15 12:52:46</nodeupdated>
</node>
