<node>
  <doctext>&lt;!-- 
[Corion] Created from text written by [castaway]. All formatting errors and stuff are belong to me thusly
2005-07-23 [Arunbear] more formatting improvements
2005-07-28 [davido] A few tidbits added regarding janitorial attribution, retitling protocol, unconsidering without action
2005-08-01 [davido] Moved &quot;Moving posts&quot; information out of [What is Consideration] into [Janitors Guidelines].
--&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Janitors' Guidelines&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;a name=&quot;why&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is janitoring (editing)? Why are we here?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 The unfortunate fact is that many posts are made improperly, by people who
 either don't (yet) understand the spirit or machinery of the site, or are deliberately
 trying to subvert it.
 The [janitors]' mission is to hold the line against utter chaos, to keep
 PerlMonks tidy and usable.
 &quot;Tidy&quot; means nodes are in their proper sections. (For junk (troll) posts, this
 means &quot;the bit bucket&quot;.)
 &quot;Usable&quot; means nodes have meaningful, searchable names, and render readably
 in the most common browsers.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Note that PerlMonks' janitorial philosophy, while generally conservative, has evolved somewhat over time. To fully appreciate the nuances of current janitorial thinking, [janitors] should read the [id://74283], preferably in chronological order, understanding that what comes later takes precendence of what went before.  Furthermore, understand that [janitors] serve at the pleasure of the [gods], who ultimately determine site policy. All [janitors] should think first, ask and discuss second, and act third.  And remember that [janitors] &lt;i&gt;never&lt;/i&gt; have a &quot;mandate&quot; from the Monks at large.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a name=&quot;how&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How do we fulfill that mission?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 Mostly, it's about using your judgement; for example, much advice for
 [janitors] talks about &quot;reasonable&quot;, &quot;significant number&quot;, and so on.
 Even though these guidelines attempt to outline the janitorial site policies
 that have evolved, ultimately it is up to the current cadre of active
 [janitors] to act as they see fit, with PerlMonks' best interests at heart.
 To be successful in this, [janitors] must be users with a deep and broad
 understanding of the history and workings of PerlMonks, and must have an
 unimpeachable respect both for the author of each individual node, and for
 the PerlMonks user populace as a whole (including [Anonymous Monk]s).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 In most cases, haste is not a virtue. (See below for exceptions.)
 If you feel
 uncomfortable about changing a node according to a consideration, then just
 leave it for someone else to judge.  Considerations don't expire.
 Leaving something alone is always one of the choices!
 You can also raise the issue in the [id://236794|chatterbox] or the
 [id://74283], and solicit the advice of others.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a name=&quot;what&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What do we do?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;a name=&quot;edit_content&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 The watchword is: keep your impact low.
 If a node needs corrective action on its formatting (i.e. HTML tags), do just
 enough to make the node render readably, in accordance with
 the original poster's probable intention.  This means, mostly, just adding
 &lt;c&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/c&gt; and/or &lt;c&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/c&gt; tags in cases where the poster didn't realize
 that the content would be interpreted as HTML rather than plain text.
 (You can go into the 'edit' view of the node to look at its raw content,
 and that should give you a good idea of what the original poster was aiming for.)
 Other types of edits that are occasionally required include adding, moving,
 or removing &lt;c&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;/c&gt; tags or &lt;c&gt;&lt;readmore&gt;&lt;/c&gt; tags.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;edit_titles&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 Unlike node &lt;i&gt;content&lt;/i&gt;, node &lt;i&gt;titles&lt;/i&gt; are &quot;property&quot; of both the node
 author and the site itself, in the sense that title quality has a substantial
 impact on the usability of the site.  Therefore, [janitors] have considerably
 more license with titles than with content.
 Note that when retitling a node, you should retitle all of its children having
 the same title (modulo any &quot;Re:&quot; part); whereas in cases where the author of
 a reply has explicitly changed its title to something else, that should not be
 affected by the retitling action.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;move_nodes&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 Then [janitors|janitor]'s job sometimes also involves moving nodes between sections,
 when they &lt;u&gt;clearly&lt;/u&gt; do not belong in the section they were originally posted in.
 [id://92975] lists which sections a node can be moved between (by [janitors]).
 The list of sections and their purposes should already be known by all,
 but as a refresher, here are the &quot;big three&quot;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt; [id://1040] - Topics about PM itself, only. &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt; [id://479] - Questions about Perl (and occasionally, other things vaguely related to Perl.)&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt; [id://480] - Nodes that contain insights, information, opinions, and not programming questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[id://480] serves an important role as a place for authors to post RFCs and similar draft documents which may ultimately be destined for other sections, most notably the [Tutorials] section.  If someone has posted a [Tutorials|tutorial] which is clearly not &quot;ready for prime time&quot;, [janitors] should consider moving it into [id://480].
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;unconsider&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 [Janitors] may also &lt;b&gt;unconsider&lt;/b&gt; nodes. If a node has been considered, for whatever 
 reason, and there is a significant number of 'keep' votes (meaning &quot;keep the 
 node as it is&quot;), then there is nothing the janitor needs to do, except to remove 
 the consideration. This also applies to other situations in which there appears to 
 be no useful consensus.  One situation in which unconsideration action is mandatory
 is when a node has been considered for [id://409197|reapage], but it has 
 a reputation high enough to prevent automatic reaping. There are also times when the
 consensus of the [Janitors] is to leave a node unchanged despite an affirmitive
 vote.  It's generally advisable to discuss such nodes in the [id://74283].
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a name=&quot;methods&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How do we do it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
 We keep an eye on [id://28877] and [id://59481] (linked
 as [id://28877|ntc] and [id://59481|nre], respectively, in the Editors Nodelet). 
 Any nodes which
 are considered for editing and have a significant amount of edit votes (and no
 or few 'keep' votes), we change as appropriate. Judgement is required here,
 whether a thing should be changed immediately, or whether one should wait for
 a general consensus to form.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 Exceptions to the &quot;easy does it&quot; rule:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;
 Posts which have no formatting whatsoever (and appear to need it). If the
 output looks just like a block of text, with intermixed code, and data
 examples. Clicking 'edit' will probably show that the author used newlines
 and indents, but failed to check the preview. Here it is best to replace
 consecutive newlines with p-tags, and surround code/data with code-tags.
 Make sure to /msg the author (using the msg box provided upon updating the
 node), and point them to [id://17558].
 &lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
 Posts which are &lt;u&gt;clearly&lt;/u&gt; offensive and not in the slightest Perl or PerlMonks related.
 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
 When changing a post, it is considered a good idea to add a note to the end of
 it, noting who did the edit, when, and what/why. This usually goes something
 along the following lines (this is just an example):
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;i&gt;2013-12-11 [vroom] Added code tags&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 Just a brief description will do. When retitling a post, it's nice to put
 the previous title here, so people/the author figures out whats happened.
 If an entire thread is retitled, we only place a janitorial attribution
 in the base node being retitled. 
 See [id://477713] for some sample janitorial attributions.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 Please keep these janitorial attributions neutral in connotation.
 We shouldn't be using our powers to attach commentary to a post which might
 influence how others feel about the post.
 We simply do our job, mark that we've been there, and quietly leave.
 It is also customary, when unconsidering a node that required no action,
 to attribute who considered it, why, and what the final vote was, along with
 who unconsidered it, and why.
 This is done not to deface a node, but to keep a record of what's been done
 (or not done).
 As much as possible, keep it concise.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 When we edit a node we should also /msg the author to explain briefly what
 we did and why.  For example:
 &lt;em&gt;/msg [davido] &quot;Help Please!&quot; has been retitled to &quot;How do I execute a Perl script?&quot; to promote searchability.  Please see [id://341118] for more info.&lt;/em&gt;
 Doing so will educate the author so that hopefully the same mistake isn't
 repeated.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;When do we do it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
 When we're dead sure that something needs to be changed for its own good
 (i.e. so that people can actually read it, or find it later). 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 This bears repeating: There is also the possibility to &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; do something!
 If you're unsure about a proper action, leave it for someone else.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What &lt;i&gt;don't&lt;/i&gt; we do?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Don't change actual post content!&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
 It's considered very poor taste to change the actual text of a post, even if
 the bad spelling/grammar is niggling at you. Our aim is to try and present 
 the post as the author originally meant/wrote it. So please &lt;em&gt;don't&lt;/em&gt;: 
 correct spelling, grammar, move things around, delete pieces etc. 
 &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
 &lt;strong&gt;Exception:&lt;/strong&gt; Occasionally, a node will be considered to be 
 edited to &quot;remove what seem to be actual persons names/addresses/email
 addresses, passwords&quot; etc. The author of this faqlet is in two minds as to
 whether this should be done. Replacing these in code snippets where the
 author has apparently just imported a local copy of their code, without
 checking first, would seem to be the only place this should be done.
&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Don't act hastily!&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;
 This means, specifically, don't edit a node just because someone considered it.
 &lt;i&gt;Never&lt;/i&gt; edit a node without reading it and its replies, and taking into
 account any votes already cast.
&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;a name=&quot;moving&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Moving posts&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
 If a node has been approved into a section, you should unapprove it before moving it.
 &quot;Unapprove&quot; appears as a link in the Editors Nodelet.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Note that you must never attempt to move and approve a node in the same step! Or even two steps!
You must follow this sequence very carefully:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Move the node (change its assigned section, and submit). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;b&gt;Reload the page&lt;/b&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Approve the node.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h3&gt;Further reading:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;[id://180874]&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;[Nodes To Consider]&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;[Nodes Requiring Editing]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;b&gt;See also: [id://475618].&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>17338</type_nodetype>
  <node_id>324056</node_id>
  <author_user>17342</author_user>
  <title>Janitors' Guidelines</title>
  <createtime>2004-01-25 21:20:29</createtime>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-12 23:03:25</nodeupdated>
</node>
