<node>
  <doctext>&lt;h1&gt;Logging in&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
To [id://109|log in], follow the link in the email you've received, or enter your username and password in the box near the top right corner of the page. Click &quot;login&quot;. If you check the &quot;remember me&quot; checkbox, a cookie will be set so that you do not need to log in every time you visit PerlMonks.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Logging in &quot;Cloaked&quot;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Normally, when you're logged in, other monks can tell you're around in a couple ways: you're listed in the [id://590099|Other Users nodelet], and your 'last here' time (shown on your home node) is updated. If you'd prefer to log in &quot;stealthily&quot;, so as not to appear in the Other Users list and not update your 'last here' time, you can 
[href://?node=login;ticker=yes|log in with this link]. This is sometimes referred to as being &quot;cloaked&quot;. For example, if you log in this way, then the &quot;talk&quot; button in your Chatterbox Nodelet is labeled &quot;decloak&quot;.  If you then send a [id://17434|public chatter message], your presence will be registered (&lt;i&gt;for that transaction&lt;/i&gt;) so your 'last here' time will be updated, and you will be listed in Other Users, at least for a few minutes.  (Note, only public talking will have this decloaking effect.  Sending [href://?node_id=236794#use|commands] such as [/msg] and [/ignore], and sending nothing at all, do not have this effect, the button label not withstanding.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Another effect of being &quot;cloaked&quot; is that the [href://?node_id=5938#When_do_I_get_my_votes|daily vote dispenser] is not triggered. If you &quot;decloak&quot;, you are no longer hidden from the 
[href://?node_id=5938#When_do_I_get_my_votes|vote fairy], and you will get a refresher of votes, if there are any coming to you.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;
[vroom]'s original announcement: [id://114864]
&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Back to the [PerlMonks FAQ]&lt;/i&gt;
</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>17338</type_nodetype>
  <node_id>156909</node_id>
  <author_user>17342</author_user>
  <title>Logging on to PerlMonks</title>
  <createtime>2002-04-05 08:47:08</createtime>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-12 10:50:45</nodeupdated>
</node>
