<node>
  <doctext>&lt;!-- 
2004-01-28 [jdporter] created
2005-07-30 [jdporter] changed title from &quot;How does editing work? (Or, What do Editors do?)&quot;
2005-07-30 [jdporter] remove (comment) stuff about editor nuke.
2005-12-20 [jdporter] overhaul
--&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;What do Janitors do?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This document is for non-janitor monks who are curious about what this shadowy cabal known as [janitors] actually do.  If you are a janitor yourself, please read [id://324056] and [id://475618] for instructions on how to do your job.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The [id://59438] (who are also, in some docs, called &quot;editors&quot;) can:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Edit the title and content of any user-created, non-homenode node. That is,
     all types of nodes displayed in [Newest Nodes] (except user home nodes).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Move mis-posted nodes to the correct section. &lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;li&gt; Re-parent [pmdev://note|replie]s. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Convert [pmdev://note|replie]s into root nodes. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Unapprove root nodes. (See [id://17688] for info on Approval.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Unconsider a node if it has 2 edit votes or 4 keep votes. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
Execution of these janitorial functions 
is usually (but not always) &quot;derived from a mandate from the masses[http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0071853/quotes|&quot;],
through a process we call &quot;consideration&quot;. ([id://92975])&lt;br&gt;
[Janitors] can (and generally do) keep a watchful eye on the site, 
taking note of problematic situations as they arise and taking necessary action on a preemptive basis. 
However, the self-moderating nature of PerlMonks works because everyone is vigilant. 
If you find a node needing some clean-up, you should &quot;[id://92975|consider]&quot; it for action.
(Note: you need to be at least a [Friar] to do this. 
If you are not, just discuss the problem node publicly in the [Chatterbox FAQ|Chatterbox].)
&lt;!-- There's also [Editor Requests], but its use is discouraged. --&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Node Titles&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
One of the main thing [Janitors] are entrusted to do is ensure that node titles are meaningful and useful for the site. (See [id://341118]) &quot;In a very real and legally binding sense,&quot; node &lt;i&gt;titles&lt;/i&gt; have a dual ownership between the node author and the site [janitors], unlike node content.

A poorly written title can greatly hinder site navigation. For example, one-word titles tend to be a problem, since they can look like keywords and usernames; and misspellings grossly impair searchability.  [Janitors] are authorized to fix any such problems as they see fit, while respecting, to the extent possible, the intentions of the author.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Node Content&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
[Janitors] can edit the actual content of a node, but in general, they will only use this power to clean up formatting problems that cause the node to fail to render usefully in most browsers. Modifying otherwise usable markup to make it compliant with some standard (such as HTML 4.01) is &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; in their charter.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[Janitors] are specifically directed &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; to use their power to fix typos, add or delete information, or correct factual errors.  In general, you should also not ask them to linkify URLs.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
They &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; licensed to delete email addresses and passwords.
When a post contains material of an objectionable nature, such as incendiary troll trash or links to pirated material, the entire post is usually considered for reapage and that process does the job.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;What about crappily formatted postings?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
...for example, when someone puts the whole post inside &lt;c&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;/c&gt; tags.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
That's really the janitor's judgement call.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
On the one hand, it could be left to the author to fix, and
 a &lt;tt&gt;[/msg]&lt;/tt&gt; to the author is therefore the best course
 of action.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
On the other hand, a janitor may feel that cleaning up a poorly
 formatted node, as a service to those who have to &lt;i&gt;read&lt;/i&gt;
 such a node, and as a way of illustrating how nodes ought to
 be formatted, is reasonable. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And if the node's author is [Anonymous Monk], it can't be fixed
by the author, so if it's going to be fixed at all, it's got to
be done by [janitors].
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Janitor Reap may be a reality in the future - Please don't delete the following. --&gt;

&lt;!--

&lt;h4&gt;Janitor Reaping&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The [janitors] have the power to force the reaping of a node.
This essentially overrides the [id://409197|automatic reaping] process, which depends on popular concensus. This &lt;b&gt;editor reap&lt;/b&gt; power is generally used only in extreme cases  where reaping is deemed necessary, but perhaps before the monks-at-large have had a chance to raise a consideration or vote on it, or the voting tally is preventing automatic reap.
&lt;/p&gt;

--&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Logging&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The changes that [janitors] make are automatically logged by the PerlMonks engine. 
All Monks can view the changes by clicking &lt;i&gt;&lt;u&gt;node history&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/i&gt; in the &lt;i&gt;&lt;u&gt;Approval Nodelet&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/i&gt;. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Cautionary Note&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The [janitors] don't necessarily all agree on the exact scope of their priorities and prerogatives.

Each one tries to do what seems right and proper and best for the Monastery, within the constraints of conscience and tools.

If you have questions or issues, you can raise them in the [id://236794|chatterbox]; there are usually a few [janitors] and [gods] around.  You can also post in [id://1040].
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Back to the [PerlMonks FAQ].&lt;/i&gt;
</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>17338</type_nodetype>
  <node_id>324820</node_id>
  <author_user>17342</author_user>
  <title>What do Janitors do?</title>
  <createtime>2004-01-28 17:45:32</createtime>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-12 07:53:57</nodeupdated>
</node>
