<node>
  <doctext>&lt;!-- here's another idea: a page like this one, which lists special monks, e.g. vroom,
nodereaper, etc. --&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;What are PerlMonks Orders?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
PerlMonks is made up of many people from many places with many interests. 
Some of these people have come together to form 'orders' (groups) within the Monastery. 
Members of these groups do not get [id://5938|XP] for their efforts, nor do they get free coffee from [http://www.StarBucks.com/|Starbucks]*. 
The only reward for their (sometimes quite considerable) trouble is satisfaction and positive [wp://karma].
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;* This is only a presumption. As far as we know, no one has ever tried to get free coffee from Starbucks by claiming to be a member of a PerlMonks Order. If you try and succeed, please let [cabal|us] know. :-)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What Orders exist?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
See [id://483087] for descriptions of what order performs what services.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;sitedocmanagers&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;developers&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;
The following groups exist but are not actually used for anything anymore: 
SiteDocManagers,
Developers.
&lt;!--
&lt;p&gt;
At some point in the past, [id://47075] were in charge of maintaining the [id://483101] list. 
This responsibility now belongs to the &lt;a href=&quot;#sitedocclan&quot;&gt;SiteDocClan&lt;/a&gt;,
so [SiteDocManagers] is obsolete.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The [id://929] group exists out-of-the-box in each Everything installation. It serves as the owner of certain infrastructural nodes, but otherwise is unused. Its only member is [root].  (By the way &amp;mdash; [root] is a special user which, like [developers], automatically exists in [http://everydevel.com|everything]. In the past, it was used by the [gods] to perform certain privileged operations. Nowadays it is mostly unused.)
&lt;/p&gt;
--&gt;
&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;So You'd Like To Join An Order&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If you'd like to join one of the PerlMonks user groups, you will need three things &amp;mdash; yea, four things must thou have in order to gain the tassel and the golden key &amp;mdash; namely:

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Substantial experience and understanding of PerlMonks. In lieu of a written test, the [gods] require that you be at least a [Friar].&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consent of a plurality of the existing members of the order you desire membership in.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formal blessing of the [gods] on high.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And last, but not least: a burning desire to contribute countless hours in devotion to keeping PerlMonks clean and happy, with no more thanks than the occasional pat on the back.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

Ready? Then [/msg] the [gods] and make your supplication.
Be prepared to argue your justification before their tribunal.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And remember that the answer isn't always 'yes'.
&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Back to the [PerlMonks FAQ]&lt;/i&gt;
</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>17338</type_nodetype>
  <node_id>238736</node_id>
  <author_user>17342</author_user>
  <title>What are PerlMonks Orders?</title>
  <createtime>2003-02-26 06:34:06</createtime>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-15 11:08:19</nodeupdated>
</node>
