<node>
  <doctext>&lt;!-- 2004-02-02 - jdporter - changed title from &quot;Can't see your post?&quot;;
     reworked &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;; added &lt;/dt&gt;,&lt;/dd&gt; --&gt;
&lt;!-- 2003-09-03 - Louis_Wu - changed title for clarity; added 174053 to add'l reading --&gt;
&lt;!-- 2003-09-02 - Louis_Wu - advance to stable --&gt;
&lt;!-- 2003-08-25 - Louis_Wu - changed wording to clarify --&gt;
&lt;!-- 2003-08-25 - jdporter - changed to dl/dt/dd q&amp;a format --&gt;
&lt;!-- 2003-08-25 - Louis_Wu - advance to beta --&gt;
&lt;!-- 2003-05-16 - Louis_Wu - create faq --&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Why can't I see my post?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Posts which start new discussions go through a 
quick review process, where members 
of good standing check posts for anything inappropriate.  
Until that speedy check is done, Anonymous Monks can't
see those posts on the [Newest Nodes] page.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Inappropriate?  Are you people prudes or something?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
We consider this site to be a home away from home, 
so we treat it as such.  We have some standards, 
and we try to keep our home clean according 
to those standards.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;OK, so what kind of standards do you have?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The post should be understandable, both in language 
and formatting. 
This doesn't mean that your post will disappear into 
the ether if it doesn't fully satisfy our sky-high 
standards.  But if we don't place the goal high, how 
will you learn to jump?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Could you put a numeric value to &quot;speedy&quot;?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Approval usually comes in 30 or 40 minutes.  If you 
don't see it by then, and the site seems active (the 
[Newest Nodes] page is adding several new Notes every 
time you refresh the page), you might have had a 
submission problem. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;What do I do now?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
There are a few options for you.
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Type the title of your node into the Search box at
    the top of the page.  If your node title is unique, 
    you'll go straight to it.  However, if the title is not 
    unique, you'll arrive at a search results page which will 
    (hopefully) contain a link to your question.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Go to &lt;a href=&quot;/index.pl?node_id=6364&amp;user=anonymous+monk&quot;&gt;Anonymous
    Monk nodes&lt;/a&gt; and look for yours.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Wait a bit, someone will probably approve your post soon.  
    Soon is usually 30 minutes.  Get some lunch, take another
    whack at your problem, and you'll likely see your 
    question when you get back.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Log in. :)  
    We don't require a registered account, but we encourage it.  
    Users can customize the actions and appearance of PM, in 
    addition to enjoying a bit of community.  You'll find some
    registering help in these FAQs.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;[id://156908]&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;[id://156912]&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;[id://156909]&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;[id://174053]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [id://174051] -- A good primer on getting your question answered. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [id://17558] -- Recommendations on how to make your post look good. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [id://17688] -- More information on what moderation is. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Back to the [PerlMonks FAQ]&lt;/i&gt;

</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>17338</type_nodetype>
  <node_id>258824</node_id>
  <author_user>17342</author_user>
  <title>Why can't I see my post?</title>
  <createtime>2003-05-16 23:10:02</createtime>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-15 10:54:56</nodeupdated>
</node>
