<node>
  <doctext>&lt;!-- 2004-01-28 - jdporter - update, regularize --&gt;
&lt;!-- 2003-05-22 - Mr. Muskrat - added link back to PerlMonks FAQ --&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why are Categorized Questions and Answers displayed separately from the rest of my writeups?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
It may seem strange, but it is actually a very natural consequence of the
way the PerlMonks database is arranged. You see,
the [id://1843] are &quot;owned&quot; by [QandAEditors],
regardless of who actually wrote the text.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Consequently, to show you the [id://1843|Q&amp;amp;A] nodes you wrote, the PerlMonks engine 
has to scan for nodes owned by [QandAEditors]* but written by you; whereas, to
show you all your other nodes, the engine simply scans for nodes owned
by you.  Written separately, the two queries are simple and fast.
If they had to be combined, it would result in an ugly, inefficient mess.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So, in a nutshell, it is done this way because it is better for PerlMonks,
even if not better for &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt;.  Sorry!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
See also: [id://656697]
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;
* (Having [id://1843] &quot;owned&quot; by [QandAEditors]
gives them the editorial control over that section that they really need.
See [id://20059])
&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- previous content:
&lt;p&gt;
The short answer is &quot;Because displaying them separately requires a small
fraction of the resources that would be required to display them together&quot;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If we used separate queries to display both sets of your write-ups
in a single view, then the web process would have to fetch both
full lists, merge the two sorted lists together, and then select
the subset to be displayed on the current page.  This would be
much less efficient than using mySQL's &quot;LIMIT&quot; keyword to have
the database return only the information to be displayed
(which is what we do).
&lt;/p&gt;
--&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Back to the [PerlMonks FAQ]&lt;/i&gt;
</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>17338</type_nodetype>
  <node_id>162297</node_id>
  <author_user>17342</author_user>
  <title>Why are categorized questions and answers displayed separately from the rest of my writeups?</title>
  <createtime>2002-04-26 11:11:05</createtime>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-15 07:07:44</nodeupdated>
</node>
