<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="223106" title="Slurp" created="2002-12-30 12:55:46" updated="2005-08-15 01:26:03">
<type id="31663">
modulereview</type>
<author id="132236">
Juerd</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;p&gt;
During my daily [http://search.cpan.org/recent] ritual, I came across a new module called [cpan://Slurp].
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Slurp provides three functions: &lt;tt&gt;slurp&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt&gt;to_array&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;to_scalar&lt;/tt&gt;. &lt;tt&gt;slurp&lt;/tt&gt; is exported by default, the other two can be exported too.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Object orientation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Again, fake object orientation. You can use either &lt;tt&gt;slurp($filename)&lt;/tt&gt; or &lt;tt&gt;Slurp-&gt;slurp($filename)&lt;/tt&gt; to do exactly the same thing. I fail to see how &lt;tt&gt;Slurp-&gt;to_array&lt;/tt&gt; is any better than &lt;tt&gt;Slurp::to_array&lt;/tt&gt;. Both can be used.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Naming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This module handles files, so it should be in the File:: namespace. It is, however, just called Slurp. A much better name would be File::Slurp. But that module already exists.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;File::Slurp&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[cpan://File::Slurp] provides exactly the same functionality, plus some extra handy functions. It has been around since 1996 and is does its job well. Slurp has no advantage over File::Slurp. The author clearly didn't search CPAN, or wants to compete.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The only positive sound about this module you'll hear from me is: nice documentation! Every function is docmented in detail.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Slurp does what it is supposed to do and is documented quite well. However, it should not be on CPAN, for two reasons: it is not in the correct namespace and another module already provides the functionality. This module adds nothing to CPAN but needless confusion for people in search of a file slurping module.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I think it should be removed from CPAN, or at least be renamed to something in File::.
&lt;/p&gt;
</field>
<field name="itemdescription">
Slurp entire files into variables</field>
<field name="usercomment">
</field>
<field name="identifier">
</field>
</data>
</node>
