<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="233782" title="Data::ShowTable" created="2003-02-08 17:22:02" updated="2005-08-05 13:17:28">
<type id="31663">
modulereview</type>
<author id="20513">
markjugg</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;p&gt;
I found this module when I was looking for a solution to easily and intelligently format some data in text-based tables in an e-mail message. After a lot of wrestling, I'm here to report that Data::ShowTable was not a good choice for this. Here's why:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, It should have a clue that the module hasn't been updated since August, 1997. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; I noticed that several standard column types weren't supported that appeared to fit in with author's intended support of 
SQL character types in this capacity. The author's email address bounced when I sent a suggestion to update this area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The interface is at least partly broken. I was trying to use a syntax that was documented as valid, but was getting "not a CODE ref" errors, even though I wasn't using CODE refs. I switched to an equivalent syntax and it worked. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; My most substantial complaint against the module is that it insists on printing the results to STDOUT. In an era where using templates is common, this seems archiac to me. I hacked up support this to get my project done. A patch for this is &lt;a href="http://mark.stosberg.com/Tech/perl/data-showtable.diff"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, I've &lt;a href="/index.pl?node_id=199411"&gt;learned about&lt;/a&gt; a module named [cpan://Text::FormatTable]. If I need to address the same problem space instead, I'll try this module instead. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
To it's credit Data::ShowTable seems well written and has some decent features. However, after my various annoyances with it, I've come to feel it's no longer being developed by anyone because there is a better solution out there. 
&lt;/p&gt;</field>
<field name="itemdescription">
routines to display tabular data in several formats.</field>
<field name="usercomment">
</field>
<field name="identifier">
</field>
</data>
</node>
