<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="106868" title="pmdev wiki" created="2001-08-22 02:44:52" updated="2005-08-15 10:12:54">
<type id="68046">
wiki</type>
<author id="979">
vroom</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;table border=1 cellspacing=0 cellpadding=15 width="100%"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;If you want to have a discussion, please post in [Inner Scriptorium]&lt;/b&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;!-- ## PLEASE DON'T DELETE THIS TEMPLATE:

&lt;p&gt;&lt;wikihead&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

## Put your comment JUST below (new stuff at the top, even replies).
## Please leave some BLANK LINES below this header, above your comment.
## DON'T DELETE ANYTHING ABOVE HERE!!! --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jaybonci] I've posted a new discussion at [Everything2 github repository and being of value to perlmonks] regarding how perlmonks might be able to reuse E2's new development infrastructure. I'm generally interested in seeing if we can either re-converge on a shared engine or at least grow off of each other.  It'd be great if another site can get some additional leverage off of the renewed effort to move E2 forward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href="#2011-08-28 07:57:45" name="2011-08-28 07:57:45"&gt;[localtime://2011-08-28 07:57:45]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
On a completely different note, I've been rummaging through the
slow queries log and changing the SQL to not use functions on columns.
This mostly consists of changing stuff like

&lt;c&gt;
...
WHERE unix_timestamp(lasttime) &gt; (unix_timestamp(now())-3600*24*7)
&lt;/c&gt;
&lt;p&gt;into&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;c&gt;
where lasttime&gt;date_sub(now(), interval 7 day)
&lt;/c&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If a query uses a naked column, MySQL can use an index on that column. If we were using Pg, it could
also be using an index on the function of a column, but we aren't.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It's unlikely that my changes have a vast effect, because the situations
where I think adding a new index would really help are the situations where
creating that index takes longer than the 10 seconds a query is allowed to run.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[planetscape], &lt;a href="#2011-08-27 05:52:49" name="2011-08-27 05:52:49"&gt;[localtime://2011-08-27 05:52:49]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
What [ww] observed has been occurring intermittently for me for some time now (since January! where has the time gone?). I advised [jdporter] of the anomaly, and he suggested:
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;
Next time you notice that anomaly, do this: go to your homenode, and click "Dump Fields" in the PmDev Nodelet. Scroll down to the bottom and look at the various votes* fields.
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
I have done so, but I am afraid it has provided no enlightenment (for me, anyway).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ww], Glitch, ca 1640 EDT (US), 15 Aug: I had been reading [id://3628] with my XP nodelet showing "28 votes left today." Then, I clicked "I've checked all of these" and got a fresh copy of Newest Nodes with XP nodelet showing I "have 29 votes left today."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason, I suspect that's probably not the way it's s'posed to work (but I can't see any bug that would cause that).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[yitzchak], &lt;a href="#2011-06-05 14:28:04" name="2011-06-05 14:28:04"&gt;[localtime://2011-06-05 14:28:04]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
There've been a couple complaints from people who've either reset their password to 10 characters and had it not work or after a long absence requested their 10 character password by mail and and it not work.  Anything after the first 8 characters used to be ignored; are &gt; 8 character passwords now not working at all?  I'd appreciate it if someone could check.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[dhoss], &lt;a href="#2011-04-25 13:56:47" name="2011-04-25 13:56:47"&gt;[localtime://2011-04-25 13:56:47]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm afraid I've only got more ideas as opposed to solutions to add here for now but,what are the logistics of setting up an RSS feed for things here?  Truth be told i"m attempting to set up an overall "modern/not crap you get off google" search engine and I'd like to index perlmonks nodes.  RSS would be a very easy avenue to start down if I were to attempt to feed in data from PM.&lt;b&gt;UPDATE&lt;/b&gt; I see we have RSS in the works. Will keep up to date.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href="#2011-01-11 17:14:28" name="2011-01-11 17:14:28"&gt;[localtime://2011-01-11 17:14:28]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
[tinita] points out [http://perlpunks.de/deliver_html_as_text_plain.html|an analysis] which means
that (for IE), the "download code" parts of a node will render as HTML if they contain HTML. She suggests
adding &lt;c&gt;Content-Disposition: attachment&lt;/c&gt;, which will then &lt;i&gt;always&lt;/i&gt; download the content
as a file, instead of allowing for other handling (like having a mime extension set up for it).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This is a medium security hole, as &lt;i&gt;likely&lt;/i&gt; such malicious posts would be detected and edited
by a non-IE user, hopefully. Still, having a way around that would be nice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Potentially,
we should collect more input from the monks by posting this as an [Inner Scriptorium] so they can
propose how to handle things, especially with regard to how they currently use the "download" links.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[yitzchak], &lt;a href="#2010-12-21 13:10:48" name="2010-12-21 13:10:48"&gt;[localtime://2010-12-21 13:10:48]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Reminder: when patching, if there is no "Current" patch, please create one (typically with reason "Original state")
so the differences in your actual patch can be seen after it is applied.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[yitzchak], &lt;a href="#2010-11-25 21:00:50" name="2010-11-25 21:00:50"&gt;[localtime://2010-11-25 21:00:50]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
radio_group()s that should have nothing checked need to supply a default value that's not one of the value values.
I've made poll voting do this.  (Previously it was inconsistent depending on which webserver's CGI.pm was used.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href="#2010-08-13 09:15:16" name="2010-08-13 09:15:16"&gt;[localtime://2010-08-13 09:15:16]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
So far, I had to switch the &lt;c&gt;version&lt;/c&gt; table back to memory anyway because MySQL decided that the table "got full".
If we lost the current table values (due to a MySQL or &lt;c&gt;memcached&lt;/c&gt; restart), the webservers would think they
were out of date. But maybe that could be changed by having them not check whether the locally cached version is less than
but instead checking whether the local version is identical and otherwise reloading. That way, a reset to version 0
would "only" be problematic when there are two restarts of the node server between accesses from the web server(s) to it,
while other webservers changed the versions.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[dhoss], &lt;a href="#2010-08-08 14:06:56" name="2010-08-08 14:06:56"&gt;[localtime://2010-08-08 14:06:56]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
why redis? out of curiousity.  I've had great experience with memcached.  I'm not sure I can offer much to this discussion, but I'm curious about that.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], &lt;a href="#2010-08-01 22:04:43" name="2010-08-01 22:04:43"&gt;[localtime://2010-08-01 22:04:43]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I'd have to look at the node cache again, but I didn't think you could safely just lose the version table,
at least while the web servers were up.  And last I knew, the DB server was still restarting regularly.
[Corion], can you switch it back or examine the code and convince us that it is safe?  redis, maybe, instead
of memcached?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], &lt;a href="#2010-07-16 22:51:17" name="2010-07-16 22:51:17"&gt;[localtime://2010-07-16 22:51:17]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
So if the DB server is restarted, we lose all version information but the running web server processes still have lots of version numbers handy so we end up with a lot of updates not being immediately visible to a lot of processes?  I have no good guess at what "a lot" means percentage-wise.  But I thought the difficulty should be pointed out.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href="#2010-07-04 16:48:22" name="2010-07-04 16:48:22"&gt;[localtime://2010-07-04 16:48:22]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I've altered the [version] table to use &lt;c&gt;ENGINE=MEMORY&lt;/c&gt;. I'm not sure if/how
this will affect performance, but I presume it can't hurt as it is a cache table
anyway. Maybe it would be more beneficial to move this table into &lt;c&gt;memcached&lt;/c&gt;
instead, and I'm looking at how this can be done in a convenient way as well,
but this might be a quick win. Before I cleaned it, the
[version] table had 800k entries.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the server gets restarted, that table will likely get lost
and then be recreated automatically as an on-disk table again.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href="#2009-07-26 17:13:29" name="2009-07-26 17:13:29"&gt;[localtime://2009-07-26 17:13:29]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
On [http://qs1968.pair.com/~perl1/rss/], we now have a cron job running &lt;c&gt;genFeeds.pl&lt;/c&gt; every 5 minutes that creates RSS feeds for the threads that have changed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;between 0 and 10 minutes ago
&lt;li&gt;between 30 and 40 minutes ago
&lt;li&gt;changed between 120 and 130 minutes ago
&lt;li&gt;between 240 and 250 minutes ago
&lt;li&gt;between 1440 and 1450 minutes ago
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are available under &lt;tt&gt;http://qs1968.pair.com/~perl1/rss/&lt;i&gt;root_node&lt;/i&gt;.rss&lt;/tt&gt;. I haven't looked into how to best distribute these to the other webservers, and also haven't looked into a proper, unix-filesystem-friendly directory structure.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Another issue is that we'll need an Apache ErrorHandler to create the RSS on demand, if somebody creates a new thread and immediately wants to subscribe to it. As the last step, the appropriate &lt;c&gt;&lt;link&gt;&lt;/c&gt; tag needs to be embedded into [note display page] and the section root display pages so that the thread RSS feed is reachable from everywhere. Also, the
proper &lt;c&gt;Content-Type&lt;/c&gt; for &lt;c&gt;.rss&lt;/c&gt; files needs to be set up with Apache. I hope all these Apache specific things
can happen through the magic of &lt;c&gt;.htaccess&lt;/c&gt;. Otherwise, we'll have to turn &lt;c&gt;/rss&lt;/c&gt; into a script, but then, we'll have to deal with &lt;c&gt;304&lt;/c&gt; replies ourselves again.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Co-Rion], &lt;a href="#2009-07-26 16:32:19" name="2009-07-26 16:32:19"&gt;[localtime://2009-07-26 16:32:19]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
That assumption should be valid - at least the current incarnation checks that all (RSSed) nodes
also are readable by the current user. But RSS (IMO) only makes sense for stuff where replies tend to
get added, so I've limited it to the &lt;c&gt;nodetypes&lt;/c&gt; part of [Newest Nodes Setting], unless other
types get passed in.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2009-07-26 08:28:40" name="2009-07-26 08:28:40"&gt;[localtime://2009-07-26 08:28:40]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Ok, when you said "readable", I assumed (shame on me) that you meant "readable by the current user",
implying that the user's access rights would be respected.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href="#2009-07-26 07:51:16" name="2009-07-26 07:51:16"&gt;[localtime://2009-07-26 07:51:16]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I've renamed the node to "Writeup RSS Generator". In the long run, some code
will emerge that can be reused to generate RSS from other data structures and that
will then form the new basis, but currently, this is mainly targetted at things
that can have replies. Also, the RSS is supposed to get written to disk, so I'm
not sure how good it is to write the contents of inboxes into files, which don't have
our access control...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2009-07-26 07:22:03" name="2009-07-26 07:22:03"&gt;[localtime://2009-07-26 07:22:03]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
While I very much appreciate this functionality, and the work which 
went into it, I feel very... &lt;i&gt;adamantly&lt;/i&gt;... that any reference 
to it, including the
[href://?node_id=783225;displaytype=viewcode|function]'s title 
(currently"Node&amp;nbsp;RSS&amp;nbsp;Generator") make it very clear that 
this only feeds RSS for &lt;i&gt;postable node types&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;b&gt;not&lt;/b&gt;, 
as [Corion] said, "all (readable) nodes". 
It &lt;i&gt;does not work&lt;/i&gt; on, for example, [superdoc]s, such as 
[Newest Nodes|NN] and the sections, nor on [strangedoc]s such as 
[Message Inbox], nor on anything other than postable node types.
If the intent is for it ultimately to feed RSS for any (readable)
nodes in fact, then the current name and description are OK, but
a caveat could be added. Otherwise, perhaps just s#node#writeup#
in all of its descriptions and title will be sufficient.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href="#2009-07-25 17:50:25" name="2009-07-25 17:50:25"&gt;[localtime://2009-07-25 17:50:25]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
There is a preliminary general RSS generator at [id://783225]. It currently can
generate RSS for all (readable) nodes, but it doesn't encode/remove the contained HTML 
properly and does not have a size limit per post. If anybody wants to toy with it,
the general link format is [link://?node_id=783225;for_node=5349]. RSS knowledge
is needed by me, so if you know what tags are allowed in RSS, and what tags need to be removed, and what
the acceptable item size is, please chime in.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This will become the basis for static RSS files per thread. These will be
generated through a cron job. Please don't distribute this link outside
of [pmdev], as it has the potential of sending thundering herds of bots
against the site before we have set up static files.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href="#2009-06-20 06:27:05" name="2009-06-20 06:27:05"&gt;[localtime://2009-06-20 06:27:05]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Locked users (locked through [Lock user]) now have their &lt;c&gt;nick&lt;/c&gt; field set to &lt;c&gt;[NodeReaper]&lt;/c&gt;. This should allow you to filter them out from any lists conveniently.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[bobf], &lt;a href="#2009-05-14 23:59:20" name="2009-05-14 23:59:20"&gt;[localtime://2009-05-14 23:59:20]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I agree with [jdporter] that "talk" works for the cb but "say" might be marginally better.  I also prefer "send" for private messaging, especially since the UI (of the Message Inbox) clarifies the meaning:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;&amp;#91;Send&amp;#93;&lt;/tt&gt; &amp;#91;_____________________&amp;#93;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;To User:&lt;/tt&gt; &amp;#91;_____________&amp;#93;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I also agree with [tye] that "chat", "submit", or "deliver" could be confusing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I don't mind the send button in the inbox located prior to the input fields, but [tye] makes a good point wrt keyboard navigation.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
My crux of my comment was that the label "tell" didn't seem to fit the rest of the UI.  I find the Message Inbox UI (above) to be quite intuitive, but [tye]'s proposal ("&lt;tt&gt;Send Message: &amp;#91;__&amp;#93; To User: &amp;#91;__&amp;#93; &amp;#91;Deliver&amp;#93;&lt;/tt&gt;") would be no less understandable.  I would be fine with either and find both an improvement over the current UI of the Message Outbox ("&lt;tt&gt;Say: &amp;#91;__&amp;#93; To: &amp;#91;__&amp;#93; &amp;#91;Tell&amp;#93;&lt;/tt&gt;").
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Finally, I mentioned this because it is unlikely that users have already become accustomed to the UI of the outbox.  If this was not a new feature I would not have proposed a change, and it is for that reason that I do not feel a change is needed to the Inbox or cb UIs.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Sorry for posting this in the wiki rather than the [Inner Scriptorium].  Noted.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], &lt;a href="#2009-05-13 22:16:38" name="2009-05-13 22:16:38"&gt;[localtime://2009-05-13 22:16:38]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I find "talk" quite a bit better than "chat" since the former is more clearly "make this text appear" and not "launch the 'chat' application".
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
"Send" is fine for [Message Outbox], though it is so vague that it could mean anything.  Part of the reason we moved to more specific verbs was to reduce the frequency of people typing search terms into the chatterbox, etc.  You can "Send" the keywords that you want to search on to the site.  So "Send" can be seen as a synonym for "Submit" which is about as useful of a label as "Button" (if the user has used the web before).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
"Deliver" would be less vague, but perhaps less accepted.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Note that I still don't see [bobf]'s point.  The submit action should be a clear verb.  The labels for the input fields should be clear.  "To:" should probably be changed to note that a user's name is expected, actually.  And I'd leave the submit button 3rd in the tab order for us dinosaurs that can navigate via a keyboard and like to push the button rather hit Enter in some random input field.  I wonder if mouse-users would prefer the button directly under the input field (to reduce required sideways motion).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Perhaps better labels would be " Message:" and "For User:" (in isolation, "To User:" seems clearer, but perhaps not with "Message:").  At which point my first choice for button would still be "Tell".  The minor contrast enforces that the purpose of the form is the intersection of the words present.  I guess we could prepend "Send" so "To User:" seems natural:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;Send&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;Message: &lt;/tt&gt;&amp;#91;____________________________&amp;#93;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;To User: &lt;/tt&gt;&amp;#91;___________&amp;#93;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/tt&gt;&amp;#91;Deliver&amp;#93; (See also [Message Inbox])
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Note that I've changed this wiki's boiler plate from "If you want to say something lengthy/complex, please post in [Inner Scriptorium]" to "If you want to have a discussion, please post in [Inner Scriptorium]".  The latter more accurately covers what sucks about using a wiki, like what we are doing now.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2009-05-13 13:53:44" name="2009-05-13 13:53:44"&gt;[localtime://2009-05-13 13:53:44]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
My two cents...&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Infrastructurally, private messaging and public chatting are not related; and anyway, they're pretty different modes of communication: chat is real-time interactive; [/msg]ing is like email. (Body-less email.) &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;IMHO, "talk" is fairly adequate for the cb, although it's essentially the same as "chat" &amp;mdash; and the problem there is that "chatting" (or "talking") refers to one's ongoing involvement in the medium, vs. submitting a single line into the cb. A better word would be "say". &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;For private messaging, I think we can do no better than "send"; I believe that is what the vast majority of users think they are doing when they press that button.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], &lt;a href="#2009-05-13 02:56:49" name="2009-05-13 02:56:49"&gt;[localtime://2009-05-13 02:56:49]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I wouldn't be surprised if [Message Inbox] originally had the verb "Reply" on that submit button.  Later, we added the field for sending a private message to a named user not just in reply to another message.  Now the button might mean the verb "Reply" or "/tell" ("/tell" is identical to "/msg" in the CB) so it got the more vague "Send" label.  [Message Outbox] can't "Reply", it can only "/tell" so "Tell" seemed an appropriate verb.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So it was intentional but it also seems nearly trivial so I'm not dead set against changing it.  I have a preference for more specific verbs in hopes or making the interface just slightly clearer.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[bobf], &lt;a href="#2009-05-13 02:00:26" name="2009-05-13 02:00:26"&gt;[localtime://2009-05-13 02:00:26]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
There are at least four different ways to send a private message, but the UI to do so is not consistent.  Specifically,
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users &lt;i&gt;talk&lt;/i&gt; in the Chatterbox nodelet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users &lt;i&gt;talk&lt;/i&gt; in Fullpage Chat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users &lt;i&gt;send&lt;/i&gt; in the Message Inbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users &lt;i&gt;tell&lt;/i&gt; in the Message Outbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The first three haven't bothered me, since the button's label fits the UI.  The Message Outbox seems a bit different; its UI is set up as "say text to user" but the button is "tell".
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
One option would be to change the button's label to "send".  Another would be to change the UI so it matches the Message Inbox ("send text to user").  I'm sure there are countless others.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I'm willing to help make these changes (to both the code and the sitedoclets), but I wanted to get feedback and establish consensus on what should be done prior to submitting a bunch of misguided patches.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Co-Rion], &lt;a href="#2009-05-02 16:08:37" name="2009-05-02 16:08:37"&gt;[localtime://2009-05-02 16:08:37]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
[id://743706] is finally active after I've found the stupid typo that prevented it from working. I haven't announced this
in [Tidings] because it only affects new accounts.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2009-04-18 22:55:01" name="2009-04-18 22:55:01"&gt;[localtime://2009-04-18 22:55:01]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I believe that it is good practice, when a patch is to fix a bug which has been brought to our attention by a post (usually a PMD), or otherwise to implement a feature suggested in a post, to refer to that post in the 'reason' of the patch.  It appears that this practice is not universally followed, however.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2009-03-27 14:38:12" name="2009-03-27 14:38:12"&gt;[localtime://2009-03-27 14:38:12]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
That said... You might find how I fixed it somewhat edifying. I came at it from both ends:&lt;br&gt;
First, from [handlelinks settings], where the particular code for &lt;c&gt;pad://&lt;/c&gt; and &lt;c&gt;by://&lt;/c&gt; is defined; &lt;c&gt;$AUTHOR&lt;/c&gt; is clearly used there, would likely be the culprit, since the "Author" of [Message Inbox] is [developers], not the owner of the inbox.&lt;br&gt;
Then, from [href://?displaytype=viewcode;node_id=48824|the code of Message Inbox], the epicenter of the problem. (epicenter = that point on the &lt;i&gt;surface&lt;/i&gt; where a problem manifests.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[bobf], &lt;a href="#2009-03-27 12:29:39" name="2009-03-27 12:29:39"&gt;[localtime://2009-03-27 12:29:39]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
No problem at all.  Thanks. :-)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2009-03-27 11:58:43" name="2009-03-27 11:58:43"&gt;[localtime://2009-03-27 11:58:43]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I'm sorry. I beat you to it. :-)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[bobf], &lt;a href="#2009-03-27 11:43:33" name="2009-03-27 11:43:33"&gt;[localtime://2009-03-27 11:43:33]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
That was my thought as well (at the time of posting), but as you mention this could be tricky.  How might we handle a case where the message content is at max length, yet we need to expand the shortcut with the author's name?  That's why I started to look at patching the rendering routine, but that just didn't seem right.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2009-03-27 07:56:00" name="2009-03-27 07:56:00"&gt;[localtime://2009-03-27 07:56:00]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
It seems to me that this kind of shortcut should be resolved at the time of &lt;i&gt;posting&lt;/i&gt;, vs. at the time of rendering like the others. But that might be hard to do. &lt;br&gt;
Also note that the other shortcut type which ought to have the same problem, &lt;c&gt;[by://]&lt;/c&gt;, actually has a different problem: it renders fine in most places, but in a [Message Inbox], it is unrendered. That is, it appears simply as &amp;#91by://&amp;#93;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[bobf], &lt;a href="#2009-03-26 23:13:24" name="2009-03-26 23:13:24"&gt;[localtime://2009-03-26 23:13:24]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I was poking around the code in response to [id://753542].  The trouble is, I'm not sure where the fix should be made.  When the message is composed and submitted ([id://182567]) (consider implications with message length)?  When the link is handled ([id://43235])?  Some other place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If someone could provide a little direction, I could try to write a patch.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[yitzchak], &lt;a href="#2009-03-03 22:06:38" name="2009-03-03 22:06:38"&gt;[localtime://2009-03-03 22:06:38]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Welcome [dhoss] to [pmdev].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href="#2009-02-13 17:38:39" name="2009-02-13 17:38:39"&gt;[localtime://2009-02-13 17:38:39]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I've created [id://743706] to preset some saner default settings for new users, at least how I perceive them. Is this the correct place? Are there other settings or different settings that should be added?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Co-Rion], &lt;a href="#2008-12-31 11:14:02" name="2008-12-31 11:14:02"&gt;[localtime://2008-12-31 11:14:02]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The new webserver is ready. PM is running on mod_perl 2.0 there. Please test it or use it in the next few days, as we plan on taking it up into the load balancer rotation: [http://qs1969.pair.com/~perl2/].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is one known issue - it seems that the database connections don't always reconnect properly and so the server returns blank pages when you're the first one to use it after some inactivity. I see that as a minor problem though, because with enough usage, the problem will never occur.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2008-12-18 11:10:30" name="2008-12-18 11:10:30"&gt;[localtime://2008-12-18 11:10:30]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Ah, quite so. Thank you [Arunbear].&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So I take it that this means that [superdoc]s can contain any html, without restriction.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], &lt;a href="#2008-12-18 10:50:44" name="2008-12-18 10:50:44"&gt;[localtime://2008-12-18 10:50:44]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
[parsecode] passes &lt;c&gt;overridefilter=&gt;'override'&lt;/c&gt; to [ParseLinksInContent] which makes the latter skip the call to htmlScreen().
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2008-12-18 10:23:08" name="2008-12-18 10:23:08"&gt;[localtime://2008-12-18 10:23:08]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
For some reason, I feel like my pmdev fu is fading...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Could someone please help me out with something?  I'm trying to figure out how a [superdoc] can display images.
[superdoc] &amp;rArr; [parsecode] &amp;rArr; [ParseLinksInContent], which allows a parameter,
&lt;code&gt;
override =&gt; 'allowImg'
&lt;/code&gt;
the effect of which is to allow images. However, in the case of [superdoc], this parameter value is not passed.
(The only nodetypes which do pass this parameter value are [document] and [largedoc].)
However, notwithstanding, it's obvious that [superdoc]s do have images. (E.g. [id://17709])
So somehow, somewhere, &lt;c&gt;&lt;img&gt;&lt;/c&gt; tags in [superdoc]s are not being blocked.
What am I missing? Where should I be looking?  Thanks in advance...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], &lt;a href="#2008-11-17 23:23:55" name="2008-11-17 23:23:55"&gt;[localtime://2008-11-17 23:23:55]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The first test is against $parent's type, the second against $node's type.  $node certainly best not be one of the types you list, as that isn't supported.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2008-11-17 08:53:06" name="2008-11-17 08:53:06"&gt;[localtime://2008-11-17 08:53:06]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I am confused about something in [href://?displaytype=viewcode;node_id=60309|ehomat].&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
An array &lt;c&gt;@toplevel&lt;/c&gt; of the node types which can be the new parent is defined at line 74. A first-level check is done at line 88, but here, five more nodetypes are added to the set. Later, at line 100, another check is done against just &lt;c&gt;@toplevel&lt;/c&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
My question is, why doesn't &lt;c&gt;@toplevel&lt;/c&gt; simply contain all the nodetypes which can be the new parent?  Essentially, it looks like if the new parent is one of &lt;c&gt;qw( bookreview modulereview snippet sourcecode )&lt;/c&gt;, nothing will be done!  What am I missing?&lt;br&gt;
Thanks.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href="#2008-10-04 16:45:43" name="2008-10-04 16:45:43"&gt;[localtime://2008-10-04 16:45:43]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The dev instance is currently reachable via [http://web6.p15138201.pureserver.info/]. As the machine will be shut down during the next two months, I cannot guarantee that the changes you still have in there will survive the move to the new machine. So please keep a local backup of the things.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It's my plan to automate the generation of a (cleaned/randomized) SQLite database so you can have your own private PM for testing and to have one pmdev instance on which you can try the changes and how they interact. But currently I don't have the time necessary to set all of this up properly.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href="#2008-09-28 05:27:52" name="2008-09-28 05:27:52"&gt;[localtime://2008-09-28 05:27:52]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/ &gt;
The SQL has converted to plain JOINs where there were "comma" JOINs before.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[demerphq], &lt;a href="#2008-09-26 20:43:07" name="2008-09-26 20:43:07"&gt;[localtime://2008-09-26 20:43:07]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Corion, about the xml ticker, i think i meant what i was calling "grunt" GRand UNified Ticker. [id://145597], i remember i wrote up some stuff on it, but i havent managed to find where yet. Likely in an older dev-wiki. I dont recall why i never released it. (Heh, took me only a year to reply :-)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[demerphq], &lt;a href="#2008-09-26 20:28:31" name="2008-09-26 20:28:31"&gt;[localtime://2008-09-26 20:28:31]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Yep both mine. *blush*. Sorry. :-)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[demerphq], &lt;a href="#2008-09-26 20:24:19" name="2008-09-26 20:24:19"&gt;[localtime://2008-09-26 20:24:19]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Well those arent so weird actually. They are perfectly valid sql. Granted they arent beautiful, and i probably shouldnt have done that but anyway. The correct reformulation is to make the implicit joins be straight and not left. 

So 
&lt;code&gt;
SELECT ...
  FROM node baz, note bar
  LEFT JOIN htmlcode h ON h.htmlcode_id = baz.node_id
  WHERE baz.node_id = note.note_id
&lt;/code&gt;
Means, give me all the records from node and note where the node_id=note_id, (meaning dont show ones where either is NULL) and given me any corresponding htmlcode records that match as well, if they exist. Thus you want:
&lt;code&gt;
SELECT ...
  FROM node baz JOIN note bar ON baz.node_id = note.note_id
  LEFT JOIN htmlcode h ON h.htmlcode_id = baz.node_id
&lt;/code&gt;
See http://dev.mysql.com/doc/refman/5.0/en/join.html, which as far as i can tell explains this issue as being one of a parser change to be more ANSI compliant. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Odds are high that this was my bad. A Sybase 11 side effect :-) My apologies.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[yitzchak], &lt;a href="#2008-09-21 00:19:25" name="2008-09-21 00:19:25"&gt;[localtime://2008-09-21 00:19:25]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I experienced this at a former job in a MySQL 4 to 5 transition, wherever there were implicit and
explicit joins in the same statement.  AFAIK, there's nothing to do about it but try to divine the
original intent and convert it to explicit joins.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href="#2008-09-20 05:08:45" name="2008-09-20 05:08:45"&gt;[localtime://2008-09-20 05:08:45]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ambrus] has found the following problems on the [http://qs343.pair.com/~monkperl/beta.cgi?node=Corion|beta.cgi]:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
The link to the common css file and to the favicon seem to be broken
&lt;li&gt;RAT gives me a server error if I set it to a date where there are threads
&lt;li&gt;the patch lister doesn't work on the beta server either -- though unlike last time that's happened now you can at least view the table of patches for any single node
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think 2. and 3. likely are related. At least [Patch Lister] creates some SQL that MySQL 5 doesn't seem to like (fixed? by [id://712726]), and I guess the same happens for [Recently Active Threads] (fixed by [id://712728]). In both cases, MySQL5 choked on SQL like this nonsensical example:
&lt;c&gt;
SELECT ...
  FROM node baz, note bar
  LEFT JOIN htmlcode h ON h.htmlcode_id = baz.node_id
  WHERE baz.node_id = note.note_id
  ...
&lt;/c&gt;
which I converted into
&lt;c&gt;
SELECT ...
       FROM node baz
  LEFT JOIN note bar ON baz.node_id = note.note_id
  LEFT JOIN htmlcode h ON h.htmlcode_id = baz.node_id
      WHERE ...
&lt;/c&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;



&lt;p&gt;[McDarren],  [localtime://]&lt;br/&gt;
It seems to me that [Janitor Signatures] would be a useful additon to the [59490|Editors Nodelet], so I've submitted a patch. My very first patch, so I hope I didn't break anything ;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2008-02-11 13:00:43" name="2008-02-11 13:00:43"&gt;[localtime://2008-02-11 13:00:43]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
So, I'm looking at &lt;c&gt;%HTMLVARS&lt;/c&gt; and [system settings], and [set_htmlvars]... And the picture which emerges is that certain parameters from [system settings] used in [id://165672] were renamed; for example, &lt;c&gt;permissionDenied_node&lt;/c&gt; is copied to a new &lt;c&gt;%HTMLVARS&lt;/c&gt; entry, &lt;c&gt;permission_denied&lt;/c&gt;. This renaming is done in [set_htmlvars]. Subsequently, [id://165672] was modified to use the new names. The old names now &lt;i&gt;only&lt;/i&gt; occur in [system settings], where they're defined, and in [set_htmlvars], where they're copied to new names.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Question: Why was this done, rather than simply continuing to use the old names?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Now, it seems to me that we can improve clarity and performance by defining the new parameters directly in [system settings]; then we don't need [set_htmlvars] to copy anything. Is there any reason we shouldn't do this?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Co-Rion], &lt;a href="#2008-02-03 10:45:50" name="2008-02-03 10:45:50"&gt;[localtime://2008-02-03 10:45:50]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Welcome [suaveant] in the ranks of [pmdev]ils!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[bobf], &lt;a href="#2007-09-26 00:06:46" name="2007-09-26 00:06:46"&gt;[localtime://2007-09-26 00:06:46]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
On Sept 24 [blokhead] sent the following msg to [pmdev]:
&lt;blockquote&gt;
[blokhead] says I think there is a bug with [showotherusers] and/or the "Last here" reporting on some homenodes.. I have a bit of a more of a description at the top of [pad://blokhead]
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
After not finding anything on his scratchpad about this, I followed up with him off-line and he sent me this:
&lt;blockquote&gt;
[blokhead] says yeah, it was resolved.. sorry, it was a silly thing actually
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
As a result, I moved his message from the inbox into the "Processed" folder.  Please let me know if there is something else I should do to tag that comment as "solved".
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href="#2007-09-13 02:41:18" name="2007-09-13 02:41:18"&gt;[localtime://2007-09-13 02:41:18]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
No - I haven't looked at the [node query xml generator], but the name sounds as if I just duplicated that functionality, badly. I'll look at that, thanks!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[demerphq], &lt;a href="#2007-09-12 17:19:23" name="2007-09-12 17:19:23"&gt;[localtime://2007-09-12 17:19:23]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Corion, just curious, have you looked at the node query xml generator?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href="#2007-09-08 12:57:34" name="2007-09-08 12:57:34"&gt;[localtime://2007-09-08 12:57:34]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I've spun off half the code from [id://30175] into [id://637848], which now also is used by [id://637849], which is the (generalized) other half of [id://30175]. That split was for adding RSS to the separate sections, which needs RSS for different sets of nodes. The code seems to work (on pmdev) but I have a problem - I have no idea how the RSS should look and what users might expect. FireFox displays the results as XML (and not as some funky-formatted RSS), so maybe someone can recommend an RSS reader. Even better would be if somebody actually knew what to expect and would tell if [http://pmdev.flux8.com/index.pl?node=section_rss;section=perlquestion] looks what they expect. Otherwise, I could ask that more in public...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
One day [id://30175] should be cleaned up to use the two other nodes.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], &lt;a href="#2007-07-10 09:21:48" name="2007-07-10 09:21:48"&gt;[localtime://2007-07-10 09:21:48]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
nodegroups and nodetypes cache information about related nodegroups and nodetypes so one nodegroup changing means all nodegroups need to be reloaded.  So those statements are adding a version number for tracking any nodetype-wide or nodegroup-wide updates.  I think I also made it so that only the global version number is checked, reducing round-trips per page hit.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], &lt;a href="#2007-07-10 03:47:26" name="2007-07-10 03:47:26"&gt;[localtime://2007-07-10 03:47:26]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
What are these doing?&lt;c&gt;
&gt; INSERT INTO version (version,version_id) VALUES( '1', '-1' )
...
&gt; INSERT INTO version (version,version_id) VALUES( '1', '-16' )
&lt;/c&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], &lt;a href="#2007-07-09 23:42:48" name="2007-07-09 23:42:48"&gt;[localtime://2007-07-09 23:42:48]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
[href:///nncro/] is a read-only version of the site using the new node cache.  At the bottom of each page you'll see all of the SQL update statements that didn't get run.  Please test it a bit.  If nobody turns up any problems, I'll probably be deploying it to production in a week or so.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thanks! 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2007-05-24 12:29:16" name="2007-05-24 12:29:16"&gt;[localtime://2007-05-24 12:29:16]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
What is the appropriate way to tickle the [gods] about 
[wp://Warnock's Dilemma|unapplied patches]?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2007-05-21 12:48:18" name="2007-05-21 12:48:18"&gt;[localtime://2007-05-21 12:48:18]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Unlike [note|replies], root posts have no parent nor root.

However, it would be convenient, in some situations, for every node in a
thread, including the root itself, to have a parent and root. 
In these situations, I think it would make sense for the root post 
to be &lt;i&gt;its own&lt;/i&gt; parent and root.
I'm thinking in particular of the [id://590089|Free Nodelet]
[id://454955|expansion code].  Any thoughts, before I go ahead and
write the [id://454955] patch?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], &lt;a href="#2007-04-30 16:07:07" name="2007-04-30 16:07:07"&gt;[localtime://2007-04-30 16:07:07]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
[ambrus] &lt;i&gt;says&lt;/i&gt; It seems that replies to the poll ideas quest don't show up in RAT, even though they show up in NN. Also, the bracketed reply link besides quests on the Quests page are broken.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[shmem], &lt;a href="#2007-04-28 16:17:25" name="2007-04-25 08:48:36"&gt;[localtime://2007-04-25 08:48:36]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Why, of course. But would this be a good or a bad thing to happen?

&lt;p&gt;[yitzchak], &lt;a href="#2007-04-25 22:31:24" name="2007-04-25 22:31:24"&gt;[localtime://2007-04-25 22:31:24]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Adding additional filters means the sort-by-reputation becomes even more revealing of node reputations than at present.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[shmem], &lt;a href="#2007-04-25 16:17:25" name="2007-04-25 16:17:25"&gt;[localtime://2007-04-25 16:17:25]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I think being able to constrain a User search is a reasonable shortcut. The $showtype and %types stuff is in [id://6364] anyways, so why not make it available, keeping the default as "All Types"? Should I ask in the [Inner Scriptorium]? If you do not object to the general idea, that would be the next step.

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2007-04-25 09:16:34" name="2007-04-25 09:16:34"&gt;[localtime://2007-04-25 09:16:34]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
[shmem], I think the idea is that "if you want a more full-featured search,

you know where to find [Super Search|it]." But I could be wrong.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[shmem], &lt;a href="#2007-04-25 06:04:34" name="2007-04-25 06:04:34"&gt;[localtime://2007-04-25 06:04:34]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Is there a reason why [id://6364] doesn't have a combo box with node types to select from? If it is "just because
nobody did it", I've got the patch ready.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], &lt;a href="#2007-04-24 12:45:19" name="2007-04-24 12:45:19"&gt;[localtime://2007-04-24 12:45:19]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I reused "user_superdoc" to create [reaped_snippet] as an ugly hack to make [snippets section] show a few snippets instead of just a list of reaped snippets in the short term.  Fixing [snippets section] to skip reaped nodes (based on a user setting) is a better fix.  Steps to prevent spam postings would also be good.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[bobf], &lt;a href="#2007-04-11 15:24:17" name="2007-04-11 15:24:17"&gt;[localtime://2007-04-11 15:24:17]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
/me sighs.  I guess that's what happens when I post before I have time to investigate things more thoroughly.  Now that I reread the wiki, I remember that discussion.  Thanks for the info re: display settings.  Apparently I didn't notice it (or, more likely, I didn't remember it) when I tested them all out to find one I liked.  Sorry for the clutter.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2007-04-11 12:15:51" name="2007-04-11 12:15:51"&gt;[localtime://2007-04-11 12:15:51]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Hi, [bobf].&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Please see discussion in the wiki below, from 2007-01-11 to 2007-01-13.
There is a patch on the dev server which would allow the (viewing) user to
decide how far down the SIOB list goes (though never lower than level 13). 
Not the same as paginating; an alternative. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; It's not that you have to &lt;i&gt;submit&lt;/i&gt; twice; you submit once, then (re)load
the/a page.  I believe the cause is that the theme for the current page render is
loaded before the update of that field is written to the database in the current
page fetch operation.  I don't believe there's any way around this, given the
Everything architecture. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[bobf], &lt;a href="#2007-04-11 11:37:53" name="2007-04-11 11:37:53"&gt;[localtime://2007-04-11 11:37:53]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Two ideas while I'm thinking about them:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've noticed that [id://3559] loads slowly.  As that list grows, perhaps we should think about paginating it so the results are displayed in groups of 100 (for example).  Then again, if that page isn't hit often (only 122 hits yesterday) and/or the server time isn't an issue, this could be premature optimization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yesterday I was showing someone how to change their theme in [id://450961] and the results were a bit odd.  Specifically, the display changed only after two clicks of the submit button.  For example, if the display was set to the default and we changed it to "green web safe" and hit submit, the page refreshed with the default theme.  Hitting submit again changed it to the green theme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
I haven't had a chance to follow up on either of these yet, but I wanted to get them down before I forgot about them.  I looked around (briefly) to see if the idea of paginating the Saints page has been discussed before but I didn't find anything.  I haven't had time to search for patches that may have affected the display settings.  Thoughts?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2007-04-06 14:04:29" name="2007-04-06 14:04:29"&gt;[localtime://2007-04-06 14:04:29]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I'd love to!  In fact, I've often thought that it would be nice to be
able to get any arbitrary nodelet in fullpage form.  Or XML. :-)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], &lt;a href="#2007-03-30 20:49:34" name="2007-03-30 20:49:34"&gt;[localtime://2007-03-30 20:49:34]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
[jdporter] Perhaps you'd like to create a [fullpage] version of the
[Free Nodelet]?  ("Free Nodelet sidebar"? "free sidebar"?)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2007-03-30 16:06:26" name="2007-03-30 16:06:26"&gt;[localtime://2007-03-30 16:06:26]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
These days I'm running perlmonks with All Nodelets Off.
I find that it makes a &lt;b&gt;huge&lt;/b&gt; difference in page load time.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], &lt;a href="#2007-03-21 15:58:28" name="2007-03-21 15:58:28"&gt;[localtime://2007-03-21 15:58:28]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I actually found them /all/ useless /here/.  The inbox, wiki, and patches links I almost never follow unless they show a "new info" indicator which these links would never show so I'd never use them.  Of the remaining, the only one I've used recently is code search, which I have in a nodelet where I know to find it and where I use it every time rather than having it multiple places that change depending on which nodes I'm on.  BTW, I'd have been a lot happier if you had simply not pasted links that you personally find useless.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2007-03-21 15:03:05" name="2007-03-21 15:03:05"&gt;[localtime://2007-03-21 15:03:05]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I'd have been a lot happier if you had simply removed the links you think
are useless. (I'd probably have agreed with you.)&lt;br/&gt;
And using the 'Recent Edits' function has always seemed pretty natural to me...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], &lt;a href="#2007-03-21 14:27:32" name="2007-03-21 14:27:32"&gt;[localtime://2007-03-21 14:27:32]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
[jdporter], please add a note when you change the wiki so we don't have to wonder what changed, go look up the list of recent edits, yadda yadda.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you want those links, put them in your free nodelet.  I don't want them and I really don't want to scroll over them every time I go to edit this wiki.  I already have those links where they aren't in the way.  Even with the newlines removed, the place to insert comments would still require scrolling.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I've &lt;del&gt;re&lt;/del&gt;moved them for now.  If others find them extremely useful to be /here/ (some of them I've found very little use for anyway) and they can be made to take up much less space in the textarea, then add them back in.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Here are the links that were inserted above by [jdporter]:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
[href://?recipient=106850;node_id=48824|inbox] 
| [id://222493|to-do wiki] 
| [id://461491|how-to wiki] 
| [id://322009] 
| [id://386578] 
| [id://106927] 
| [id://160975] 
| [id://157620] 
| [http://everydevel.com/index.pl?node=The%20Everything%20Bible| The&amp;nbsp;Everything&amp;nbsp;Bible] 
| [http://everydevel.com/index.pl?node=chromatic|chromatic's library] 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2007-02-27 23:15:03]&lt;br/&gt;
I fixed two places; there's another in Everything.pm.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2007-02-27 20:39:29]&lt;br/&gt;
Due to a surprise upgrade, the 'B' web server has a newer version of DBD::mysql and code that tries to use placeholders with LIMIT ("LIMIT ?") will fail on the 'B' web server.  This is why 1/2 of the time there is a server error in Other Users.  Anyone finding time to make a patch to replace such usages (and/or search for other cases of such usages) would be appreciated.  Thanks.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[bobf], [localtime://2007-01-14 23:30:52]&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;[yitzchak]: How about being able to select root only/replies only/both?&lt;/blockquote&gt;
I like that idea.  OTOH, the more it looks like the [SuperSearch] page the more I wonder if we need the redundancy.  Would it be sufficient to add a note to [id://6364] that reminds users that [SuperSearch] can be used to perform more complicated searches (and possibly provide examples of such searches), or is the intent to provide a simplified [SuperSearch] page?
&lt;blockquote&gt;[yitzchak]: Though I'm not sure how it would work combined with CatQ&amp;amp;A; is a categorized answer a reply or not?&lt;/blockquote&gt;
I guess it depends on how we define "reply". :-)  Since [id://1843] are owned by [QandAEditors], one could argue that categorized answers are not replies in the usual sense.  However, I would probably define "reply" as "something written in response to and in the same thread as another node", so I would consider a categorized answer a reply in this sense.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[yitzchak], [localtime://2007-01-14 21:16:44]&lt;br/&gt;
How about being able to select root only/replies only/both?
&lt;p&gt;
Though I'm not sure how it would work combined with CatQ&amp;amp;A; is a categorized answer a reply or not?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[mcdarren], [localtime://]&lt;br/&gt;
WRT to [id://594651], I'm wondering how difficult it would be to add a "Show Root Nodes Only" feature to the [id://6364] page? I think that would be quite a useful feature. I'd be willing to have a go at writing a patch for it myself, but I think I'd need a bit of hand-holding - at least to get started.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2007-01-13 23:00:03]&lt;br/&gt;
Looks to me like the default continues to be 3000 XP.  It would be easier for some to see this if the patch were moved here.  Re: anonymous monk,
it doesn't let hir change the setting, but still displays the text and button: [http://anon.pmdev.flux8.com/?node=saints%20in%20our%20book].
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strike&gt;BTW, I made (and applied) another patch to SIOB (both here and on the test server).&lt;/strike&gt; And then regretted it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ChemBoy], [localtime://2007-01-13 20:51:19]&lt;br/&gt;
It's not so much the &lt;i&gt;time&lt;/i&gt; I was lacking yesterday as the ability to focus my eyes on a computer monitor without suffering a somewhat distracting amount of pain.  Today I have a bit more of both, so I'll make an attempt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of [Saints in our Book], as I understand it, is to publicly recognize the "best" (I'll let those quotes stand on their own) members of the site.  By its nature, such recognition is valuable (if it has value at all) because it can be seen by &lt;i&gt;other people&lt;/i&gt;.  What [demerphq] proposed was to change what would be seen, by default, by a random monk or passer-by going to view that page.  Hence, the "value" of being listed on [Saints in our Book], for those Curates, Priests and other formers Saints who are not above [demerphq]'s cutoff, would be changed: either you are a "Saint in our Book", or you are a "Saint in a conveniently available appendix to our book that you can see if you really want to, isn't that nice for you?"  If you think nobody would notice or care about that perceived demotion, then I can only say that I believe you are mistaken.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people reading this will probably disbelieve this (feel free), but I honestly wouldn't care all that much personally if the criteria for Book-sainthood were changed such as to exclude me&amp;mdash;I'm not a [id://244022|Saint] on my homenode any more either, after all, and I've fallen as far as I have down the list  because I don't contribute much any more.  I would, however, be somewhat upset if I popped into the chatterbox next week and found another pointless and entirely avoidable shitstorm over administrative issues drowning out all the technical and social conversations.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may argue, and you may well be right, that it wouldn't be that big a deal.  It's fairly unlikely that you will actually get another 30-post thread in PMD on this one, for example.  But you would annoy a bunch of people, and I still don't "get" &lt;i&gt;what the hell useful purpose this change would serve&lt;/i&gt;.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In sum, I argue that this change would: 1) materially benefit an unknown number of people I have no reason to believe greater than zero; 2) annoy a number of people that I argue, with what I think are not unreasonable assumptions, is likely to be significantly more than zero.  Assuming I'm even remotely close to right, what earthly reason is there to go forward with it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2007-01-13 17:18:09]&lt;br/&gt;
If someone becomes annoyed at finding themselves no longer listed in SaintsIOB, then they'll have to be annoyed at themselves because they would be the one who made the change.  So if they want to ignore themselves when they tell themselves that they shouldn't be annoyed that they've removed themselves from SaintsIOB, then that might be unpleasant for them.  How that is a problem for anyone else I guess [ChemBoy] will have to eventually find the time to explain, at least if he'd like me to "get it", because I don't. :)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ChemBoy], [localtime://2007-01-12 17:53:47]&lt;br/&gt;
Oddly enough, many people fail to be pacified by being told they &lt;i&gt;shouldn't&lt;/i&gt; be annoyed by something.  You may have noticed a trend this way during the past week or so.  (Or if you haven't, God help you.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this a serious performance issue?  Or is it just an issue of tidiness?  Because if the latter, really guys, I don't think it's a bright idea.  (I would attempt to explain in more detail, but I can't right now; instead I will attempt to communicate my seriousness by explaining that I checked in and said this much despite not going to work today because I find it painful to focus on a computer screen for any noticeable length of time.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[demerphq], [localtime://2007-01-12 05:57:30]&lt;br/&gt;
[McDarren], i guess [tye] mean that anonymonk doesnt have user settings, or rather that they are shared amongst all anon users.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Regarding the inbox ill try to track down the problem one of these days. Im a little busy with p5p stuff rght now tho.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[mcdarren], [localtime://]&lt;br/&gt;
Looks pretty good to me. Just one comment - assuming that you make the default Level 13, then I expect people will want to be able to make that a user setting. Otherwise, they'll need to load the page once, then load again with the desired setting - which sortof defeats the purpose of [demerphq]'s suggestion, no?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I don't really understand [tye]'s comment 'degrade well for anonymonk')
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2007-01-11 21:59:35]&lt;br/&gt;
It doesn't degrade well for anonymonk.  I don't have my DEV password handy so I haven't looked at it beyond that yet.  I hope others will.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2007-01-11 16:13:23]&lt;br/&gt;
I disagree with the view (re. [ChemBoy]'s comment, below) that the proposed change to [Saints in our Book] would be dropping people from lists they expect to be on. Specifically, the proposal is to let the &lt;i&gt;viewing user&lt;/i&gt; select where the list cuts off. I think that's fair. No one suggested that the site administrators would make the decision to change the cutoff level for everyone.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
To that end, I've made a [http://pmdev.flux8.com/index.pl?node_id=325174|patch] for [http://pmdev.flux8.com/index.pl?node_id=3559|Saints in our Book]; please check it out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;readmore&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Note that this does a little dance to account for the differences in the available levels between DEV and the production server.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
On PM, we want to show levels no lower than 13, whereas on DEV the levels only go as high as 10.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So on DEV, the menu shows only 9 and 10, whereas on PM the menu should show 13 and up.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/readmore&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2007-01-11 14:21:07]&lt;br/&gt;
There is a problem with messages being shown in the reverse order in the message inbox.  It causes lots of breaks.  You can work around it by going into inbox settings and fiddling.  I have done that with [tye] but not with [tye&amp;nbsp;].  [bart]'s patch fixed move/archive being broken if you haven't made your inbox go back to not being backwards.  However, other things are still broken for [tye&amp;nbsp;] and anyone else who hasn't puzzledly gone and fiddled with their settings.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In particular, going to a group inbox shows you the oldest messages not the new ones you went to see.  However, the group inbox flag in the nodelet is only updated if you go into the inbox looking at the oldest messages, not if you actually look at the new messages.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And then there is the long-standing confusion over wanting message shown newest-first vs oldest-first compare with wanting to see only your oldest messages vs only your newest messages.  I'm fine with not supporting "only show me my oldest messages" and think that would be the best short-term fix; making sure that any settings that impact message display order to /not/ cause only the oldest message to be shown, especially in the [message inbox].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This breakage was introduced months ago.  I tried to look for the patch to blame but failed to find it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[shmem], [localtime://2007-01-11 12:19:08]&lt;br/&gt;
[id://592021] from 2006-12-28 (by [bart], applied by [Co-rion]) fixed
the &lt;i&gt;Move&lt;/i&gt; error I had reported.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ChemBoy], [localtime://2007-01-11 11:57:48]&lt;br/&gt;
Oh God, haven't we had enough noise this week about people not being on lists that they expected to be on?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[demerphq], [localtime://2007-01-11 10:21:27]&lt;br/&gt;
[Saints in our Book] is getting long. There should probably be an select box that controls how many people it shows, probably defaulting to 250 or something. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Also regarding the message box behaviour, ive not been able to replicate any of the bugs that ive seen reported here. Im wondering if there is some kind of user setting mismatch responsible.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[belg4mit], [localtime://2006-12-25 21:44:36]&lt;br/&gt;
[id://419625] states:
&lt;blockquote&gt;When you press the Submit button, the following actions happen:&lt;br&gt;
1. Any messages whose Delete checkbox is checked are deleted from your inbox.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Yet, when I check a few boxes and click submit, *every* messages goes bye-bye.
&lt;b&gt;UPDATE&lt;/b&gt; [shmem]'s /msg to pmdev might be related?
&lt;blockquote&gt;
shmem says Message Inbox: Move (all but) selected to Archive doesn't work anymore after the ordering changed. I'd fix it if I could :-)
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2006-12-13 13:07:16]&lt;br/&gt;
Trying to think of a reasonable resolution to the issue discussed in [id://589124|this subthread].  One idea I have is to use [docstring]-type nodes as redirectors. We'd have a [docstring] node for each page on perldoc; i.e. [perlreftut] would be a [docstring], and it would lead to [doc://perlreftut].
Existing hurdle is that the code for automatically following such references is in the [doclist display code] (actually [render_doclist_group]), so it only works when the [docstring] is in a [doclist]; this code would have to be added/moved to someplace more generic. Of course, whether to automatically follow should be user-controllable, perhaps via a user setting. (There's already an opt for it, &lt;tt&gt;no_string&lt;/tt&gt;, in [doclist] code.)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
That's not even addressing the issue of whether we should have a slew of one-word-titled nodes for the perl docs. But whether we do or not, this capability would be really handy.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;small&gt;
Note &amp;mdash; the similarity of this to the previous (below) is only coincidental. Although... &lt;i&gt;There are no accidents&lt;/i&gt;, right?&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


[id://591498]













































































































































































































</field>
</data>
</node>
