<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="157365" title="pmdev wiki through 2002-04-07" created="2002-04-08 01:37:54" updated="2005-08-02 09:33:09">
<type id="68046">
wiki</type>
<author id="8948">
ar0n</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
Continued from [id://166549]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[jaybonci], 2002-04-06&lt;/p&gt;
See below. I patched monkbar2001 to do the same thing as the [showad] patch. Thanks.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Also minor buglet, I can diplaytype=edit a patch, but whenever I submit it, it gives me "tough beans". It'd be helpful if we could change the patch to fix minor silly things post submission.
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-04-04&lt;br/&gt;
[vroom] is.  Yes, I got used to the old AND.  I'd at least like a line drawn
to separate the perfect matches from the rest.  Also note that doing a super search for things like "number", "list", and/or "string" can (still) lock up the DB for minutes which explains some recent site brown-outs (please! don't try this unless you have access to kill threads in the DB server and are already connected and ready to do so -- yes, this is enough to make me consider disabling it again, tho I'll probably just implement "auto kill" for such threads soon instead).  Searching for "code significant update" will not tie up the DB but will never return (probably some error that the Everything error checker can't catch).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
An idea has been forming in my mind to do something similar to MySQL's "fulltextsearch" (which is what the new [super search] uses) but implemented ourselves so that we can do searches on short words like TCP but not on overly common words like "number" unless you also include at least one less common word.  Though I probably don't have time to do this so I don't know why my mind bothers thinking about it. (:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[dws], 2002-04-02&lt;br/&gt;
Who is working on Super Search? And is there any intent to make search term work as conjunctions (ANDs) rather than disjunctions (ORs)? I'm getting flooded with spurious hits, and am finding it really hard to find things.
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-04-01&lt;br /&gt;
We don't use [showad].  See [monkbar2001] instead.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[jaybonci]: (March 30, 2002) I patched the code in [showad] to be up to speed with what E2 has.  Currently the floating layer like that causes a bug in Omniweb that would make searching (to name one thing) impossible. It mutes out all of the controls that would normally bubble through in other browsers. There was some HTML junk in there that I'm not sure if you need or not, but it is left in there to be display compatible with the current banner layout. &lt;a href="http://devedge.netscape.com/evangelism/docs/articles/updating-dhtml-web-pages/TAGtests/matrixRunner.html"&gt;Netscape suggests&lt;/a&gt; the method implemented for cross-browser iframe/ilayer consideration.  Thanks.
&lt;hr&gt;
[Russ] (Latecomer to the pmdev party :-) asks on Sat Mar 30 01:19:26 CST 2002:&lt;br&gt;
&amp;lt;UPDATE&amp;gt; was just learning how to use the [id://106927]. Remainder of post (including [Chady]'s help) removed for brevity&amp;lt;/UPDATE&amp;gt;&lt;br&gt;
[id://155911|Patch] submitted
&lt;p&gt;
Next dumb question: "What now? /msg vroom, mention it here, sit patiently?"

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[grinder] 2002-03-28 13:58 UTC&lt;br&gt;

Seeing that user images can now be uploaded, I thought about uploading a new pic. I prepared an image, saved it in PNG format and uploaded. Silly me! The image was 200Kb and was rejected. Checked my home node. Old image still there. Saved the file in JPG format. Checked it, 37Kb. Pressed the back, back to get back to the edit page. I know, that's probably naughty. Edited the extention to .jpg. Stumbitted.

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;cite&gt;
&lt;font color="red"&gt;Server Error (Error Id 5396287)!&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

An error has occured. Please contact the site administrator with the Error Id. Thank you. Received 37054 bytes.
&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few moments later... checked my home node again and the new picture is now in place. Oh well...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[grinder] 2002-03-26 15:58 UTC&lt;br&gt;
Umm, I have no &lt;code&gt;[talk]&lt;/code&gt; button on &lt;i&gt;any&lt;/i&gt; node. Then again, there is no "All is quiet" or any chatter, so I suppose something is clearly borked. &lt;b&gt;update:&lt;/b&gt; fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
[tye] 2002-03-25&lt;br&gt;
[ar0n] fixed it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[myocom] 2002-03-25 - Seems to work now, at least for me...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 [Petruchio] Mon Mar 18 18:36:50 UTC 2002 -
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 Bug report:  I cannot speak to the chatterbox from [Nodes to Consider].
 Neither can [ar0n], nor could one other person I heard complain of it.
 [tye], on the other hand, can.  No clue as to why, just now, though I 
 mean to investigate further.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[vroom] 2002-03-02&lt;BR&gt;
Should be fixed now. %2d and %02d are not created equal when it comes to sprintf.
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2002-03-02&lt;br&gt;
[tilly] asks: BTW is there a reason that we no longer seem to get changes to home nodes in "Recently Updated Home Nodes"?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[demerphq] 28/02/02 20:07 GMT+1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ive submitted a patch to the showhint function.  Since its just as easy to show what it would ouput I wont bother describing it, except to say that I did reword a few things from the passive to the assertive and removed the italics, both with the intention of having people read it. (Small italics are often overlooked IMO) instead here it is....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- UPDATED SHOWHINT OUTPUT STARTS--&gt;
Actually for space reasons ive moved it into a PMD thread [id://148351|here] .
&lt;!-- UPDATED SHOWHINT OUTPUT ENDS--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
With a bit of luck this should reduce the number of poorly formatted posts and thus the work load on the [Editors] and [Janitors]. Feel free to sneer at me if this anathema. ;-)&lt;p&gt;
Heres the link to the patch:[id://148332]
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[dws] Tues Feb 26 21:01:00 PST 2002:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Got a wierd one here. [id://147763|this node] is visible in SoPW, but not visible in [Newest Nodes]. At first, I thought there might be a problem with the original title (Apache::MP3), since it conflicted with another post in a different section, but changing the title had no effect. (That may be superstitious behavior on my part.) In the CB, a few people mentioned that they'd noticed the same behavior (post visible in SoPW but not in Newest Nodes) several times today. Database corruption? Cosmic Rays? Elvis in the building?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;reply&lt;/b&gt;
[vroom] I changed something with Newest Nodes to order by ucreatetime which is allows that to be indexed and consequentially a faster query.  The code for inserting the unix_timestamp for createtime in ucreatetime is apparently broken.  Perhaps on both servers perhaps on the additional server added to rotation today.  For the time being there is a cron job that sets ucreatetime once a minute for nodes on which it isn't defined.  I'll look at that more tomorrow.
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 [Petruchio] Thu Feb 21 23:50:19 UTC 2002:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 Our banner ad is presently handled by both iframe and layer tags; the
 redundancy, I'm guessing, is for browser compatibility reasons. There are 
 drawbacks to this. First, these do not, as far as I know, comply with HTML 
 standards... and they certainly have no place in XHTML, which seems to be
 (much to my satisfaction) the standard towards which we're moving. Second,
 there's this troublesome CSS snippet from our creative peanut gallery:
 &lt;code&gt;layer, iframe { display: none }&lt;/code&gt; Seems to me that blocking the
 ads should be more challenging than that. :-)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I do not understand the purpose of the iframe and layer elements, so I
 would not venture to simply replace them (in [showad]). When I asked in
 IRC, someone suggested that their purpose might be to load the href link
 dynamically. This seemed pretty reasonable; however the person who said
 it couldn't quite remember whether he'd been smoking crack recently. ;-)
 Anyway, it's something I think deserves a bit of discussion. How should
 we handle this?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
[grinder] 2002-02-15 10:51:32 Z&lt;br /&gt;
I just posted [id://145655] so as to advise people of the problem, but I daresay the culprit is a pmdever. I traced the problem to a response I made in the node "Asbestos clear &amp;amp; present danger", one of the post-9/11 off-topic threads. When I changed the &amp;amp; to &amp;amp;amp; the problem went away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

[tye] 2002-02-12&lt;br&gt;
As part of changing ?random=NNN to ?updated=20020212072345 in the user image URL, I also changed the scratch pad link text from "Link" to "View it".

&lt;p&gt;[grinder] 2002-02-13 10:33 Z
&lt;p&gt;I like it. Which begs the question, is there any way of deleting or withdrawing a patch? Because my patch on that issue is therefore redundant. Similarly, I goofed in a recent patch... can I edit the patch node?
&lt;p&gt;[tye] I cut your post apart so that I could reply to this part, hope you don't mind.
&lt;hr&gt;
[tye] 2002-02-12&lt;br&gt;
[editors] can now viewcode (and patch) 'fullpage' nodes (mostly the XML tickers) by appending &amp;amp;displaytype=viewcode to the URL by hand.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[tye] 2002-02-11&lt;br&gt;
The navigation links in [Node Lister] have never worked.  I just fixed them.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[tye] 2002-02-11&lt;br&gt;
I noticed that user images have ?random=NNN in their URL.  So now I have a separate copy of each user image in my cache for each time I hit the same home node.  This also makes it more likely that a home node will render incorrectly because the image size isn't in the IMG tag.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I don't think we need to be playing such tricks to disable caching of home node images.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
 [Petruchio] Sun Feb 10 10:08:33 UTC 2002:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I have made A Discovery &amp;trade;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I really wasn't familiar with [crazyinsomniac|crazy]'s custom title
 patch before I looked at the code itself.  It's actually pretty neat;
 I've often been vexed by not knowing the section something was in, or
 what its node id was.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 However, allowing arbitrary text into the head of every document onsite
 can lead to unexpected effects.  I invite you to try this as a custom
 title string:
&lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;code&gt;%T (%S  ID: %N) - %D &lt;/title&gt;&lt;link rel="stylesheet" href="http://www.brinzer.net/css/PerlMonks.css" type="text/css" /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 Yes, you can sneak custom stylesheets onto the site this way. My question
 is, is this unintended use a potential problem?  After all, it only 
 changes the site for the user, not for anyone else.  I cannot think of a
 serious abuse which would make use of this.  I must admit, I'm
 dying to post and tell everyone how to do this... but it seems the sort
 of thing that should be blessed by a Higher Authority first.  Please
 let me know what you think.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[grinder] 2002-02-10 10:58:07 ZULU&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I think it's a nifty hack, and should be permitted, much like the way you can add additional &lt;code&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/code&gt; elements in the Location: field on homenodes. I am a happy user of crazy's patch. It's nice to see the node id easily in the title. Helps with replying, especially using Mozilla's tabbed interface.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[jcwren] 2002-02-10 15:44:00 GMT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Perhaps we could consider adding a %C option that would allow pointing to an offset style sheet, and not require the user worry about specify the link tags and such.  I don't know what all the security issues would be, but perhaps even consider permitting the ability of a user to upload a style sheet, much like a monk picture (since not everyone has a server they can point to).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 [Petruchio] Sun Feb 10 17:32:37 UTC 2002:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I entirely agree, [jcwren|jc]; I would prefer some formal mechanism
 for allowing offsite stylesheets.  And I think the hack is small enough
 that a separate mechanism is reasonable... I daresay I could cook up
 something proper with its own entry in the [User Settings] in a half
 hour or so.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 And actually, this gets to the root of my misgivings about announcing
 this hack to the teeming masses.  I want stylesheets; always have.
 And I think it's just incredibly cool looking at my own warped monastery
 as I write this.  But it's not my site, and I've not been given the
 go-ahead to add such a feature.  Even though this is merely a discovery,
 and not a real action on my part, I don't feel it's quite right to just
 go ahead and sneak them in by exploiting a bug, and then tell everyone
 how they can do it, too.  At the moment, it's still fun and games; if I
 post, that's different.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 This behavior can stopped very easily by adding a filter to
 [crazyinsomniac]'s code, swapping &amp;amp;lt; and &amp;amp;gt; for &amp;lt;
 and &amp;gt.  I will be happy, with [jcwren]'s assistance, to take
 care of this... or, naturally, to let someone else do so, if that's
 desired.  I'll also be happy to code up the capacity for a stylesheet
 link, if that is deemed good.  I'm also willing to simply write a post
 on what I've discovered, or keep my public mouth shut indefinitely on
 the subject and ignore the whole thing (and until I've been given
 instruction on the matter, I'll do the latter).  Sorry to lay another
 decision at your door, [vroom], but you're the man.  Speak, and it shall
 be done.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  [Petruchio] Sat Feb  9 15:08:44 UTC 2002:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 [ar0n] and I have been writing some patches; mostly cleanup of both perl
 and HTML. Two of these have been applied by [jcwren]:  [ar0n]'s
 [user display page] and my [basichead] (in which some of the code I
 modified was [crazyinsomniac]'s, though I did not change its function).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 Besides writing to document our actions, I would like to invite comment
 on our work.  It's important, after all, that we be accountable and 
 constructive; if we could have done these things better, or should have
 thought better of doing them, please let us know.  Otherwise, we're
 liable to do it again. ;-)  For my part, I'm pleased and excited.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
[vroom] Jan 31&lt;p&gt;
I figure this is as good of place as any to log things that are broken
on the new server&lt;p&gt;
Add node_id, title, or nodelet and any actions that may have prompted the error.
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;ERRORS&amp;gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[crazyinsomniac] - Wed Feb  6 08:57:15 2002&lt;BR&gt;
[Node Lister], the [pmdev]ers [Gigantic Node Lister] is broke.
In particular, it is a call to an htmlcode to generate the drop down menu.
Server Error (Error Id 6790071)!&lt;BR&gt;
A current workaround is to list nodes of type nodetype(1), and then
whatever nodetype you're interested in.  The nodetype is the node_id.&lt;BR&gt;
[http://perlmonks.org/index.pl?node_id=106927;whichtype=1;] - nodetype&lt;BR&gt;
[http://perlmonks.org/index.pl?node_id=106927;whichtype=3545;] - opcode&lt;BR&gt;
[grinder] 2002-02-11 11:04:17 ZULU&lt;br /&gt;
Hmm. When I try to access node 106927 all I get is tough beans. Can someone give
my account the necessary privs to view it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VSarkiss] Mon Feb 11 16:33:53 2002 GMT&lt;br /&gt;
May be a cookie thing, [grinder].  I had to change it to "www.perlmonks.org", or it would look like I got logged out.  I don't know how to add parameters to a square-bracket &lt;code&gt;[id://106927]&lt;/code&gt; type link, but if I could, that would probably fix the problem for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr width="50%" align="center" /&gt;
[grinder] 2002-02-10 14:56:32 ZULU&lt;br /&gt;
The "9 Replies" element at the head of a thread is really whacked out, like, much more than usual :). For instance, [id://144745] says 50 replies, but I count only 31. Note that in my user settings I have set the reply number to be the count of all nodes, not just the direct children of the node.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know it used to suffer from off by one errors, but it's seriously overestimating things. I'll try to understand why, although an expert may find teh cause faster than I could
&lt;HR width="50%" align="center"&gt; 
[Kanji] is a bishop with more than 50 nodes, however his homenode says he only has 1 write up ... this is not true ...
&lt;BR&gt;
[user display page] ....&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;CODE&gt;my $count = htmlcode('displaySingleVar','numwriteups') || 0;&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
It is my belief that numwriteups got corrputed (it's a key in kanji's $NODE, and everybody elses for that matter)
&lt;BR&gt;[crazyinsomniac] - Fri Feb 22 08:02:17 2002 GMT&lt;BR&gt;
Kanji is not the only one affected.... one of the [gods] ought to write a little maintenance script or what have you to go and check everybody with a "questionable" number of nodes, recalculate, and update the attribute.

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&amp;lt;/ERRORS&amp;gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR /&gt;
[dws] Tue Jan 15 23:00:00 GMT 2002&lt;p&gt;
The [Quests] page is emitted invalid HTML. I'm not able to (or don't know how to) get at the source code to see what's going wrong.
&lt;p&gt;
[vroom] Fri Jan 18&lt;p&gt;
fixed quests page&lt;P&gt;
[VSarkiss] Fri Jan 18 21:23:16 GMT 2002&lt;br /&gt;
It looks like the code and the [newlistapproved] htmlcode haven't changed, so I'm guessing it was the container you had to fix.  I couldn't figure out which container it was using.  Is there a way to do &lt;code&gt;containers=show&lt;/code&gt; in the monastery?  Typing it into the URL doesn't work. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
[crazyinsomniac] - Wed Jan 23 20:25:03 2002 GMT &lt;BR /&gt;
What are you talking about? Please explain yourself. (and folks please do keep in style of the wiki, &lt;CODE&gt;&lt;P&gt;[user] ~~gmtime GMT &lt;BR&gt;stuff&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[user] ~~gmtime GMT &lt;BR&gt;stuff&lt;/P&gt; &lt;HR&gt; different topic...&lt;/CODE&gt;
&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VSarkiss] Thu Jan 24 15:51:38 2002 GMT &lt;br /&gt;
Originally, [vroom] put his "fixed quests page" note above [dws]'s, so I put my question below his.  Then [vroom] moved his note, and mine was "dangling" at the top.  I've moved mine (and yours ;-) to make the flow clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As to the question itself, I was trying to figure out what [vroom] changed.  The [Quests] node and the underlying htmlcode haven't changed, so I presumed he changed the container, but I couldn't figure out which container the node is using.  In Everything, [root] can pass a &lt;code&gt;containers=show&lt;/code&gt; parameter to see what the containers are on the page, and I was wondering if [vroom] had added something to PM so mere mortals could do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
[dws] Mon Jan 14 19:00:00 GMT 2002&lt;p&gt;
If you turn on "Monk Pictures Off" in your personal settings, the table
at the top of each page still sets &lt;code&gt;height="75"&lt;/code&gt; for what is now
a set of empty cells. You save a small amount of download overhead, but no screen real-estate.
&lt;p&gt;
Perhaps someone who has the necessary skill and access can take a crack at
setting the height based on &lt;code&gt;[{checkvar:monkpicsoff}]&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[ar0n] 2002-01-14 16:45 EST
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There's a patch for it [id://138744|here]. It's not exactly legible (mainly because I cleaned up the html a bit, too), but you might be able to make something out of it. I'll notify [vroom|El Presidente] of the patch.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[dws] Thu Jan 16 14:00:00 PST&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D'oh! I must have hit this at a time when there was no banner ad up. The 75 pixels can only be reclaimed if (a) monk pictures is disabled, and (b) there is no banner ad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[blakem] Sat Jan  5 02:06:58 GMT 2002&lt;P&gt;
I've been away for a couple weeks, and while attempting to catch up I stumbled across some nodes in the 'patch' category.  For instance, [135486|here is crazy working on customizable titles].  The patch nodes are readable by [pmdev] but rather difficult to find... [super search] wont list them, and you have to use the rather obscure "search for '[patch asdf]'" trick to get regular search to list them.&lt;P&gt;
I'm wondering if there is a list of patches available to [pmdev]ers and if not, should I make one?  Would people be interested in seeing a list of submitted patches?
&lt;P&gt;
-Blake
&lt;P&gt;[crazyinsomniac] - Thu Jan 10 17:17:20 2002 GMT&lt;BR&gt;
First &lt;CODE&gt;&lt;P&gt;[crazyinsomniac] - perl -e'print ~~gmtime' GMT &lt;BR&gt; ... &lt;/P&gt;&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
Now, the [Node Lister] is a hacked up version of the [Gigantic Node Lister] which [pmdev]ers can access.&lt;P&gt;
you can go to [http://perlmonks.org/index.pl?node_id=106927;whichtype=112733;]
to see all the patches.  BTW - it is true that the [id://106927] needs patching at the moment, but only gods can do it
&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ar0n] 2002-01-04&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
(moved from pmdev /msg's)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[tilly] says:
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;
Something I think a good idea was raised at [id://134592]. Why not have a chatter announcement whenever a node is frontpaged? That is worthy information, and not too much added noise to chatter.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
To which [crazyinsomniac] replies:
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;i&gt;a patch is in the works&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
After which he then says:
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;i&gt;one question, who would get the announcment? everybody? everybody level 5+?&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
and
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;i&gt;should editors( or maybe power users) get the message, since they're the only ones who can change frontpage status? I vote editors for sure&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ar0n] 2002-01-04&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There's now a patch for it [id://136277|here]. I opted to send out the message to all as I don't really see a reason not to (other than perhaps flooding the CB with messages, which I don't expect to happen). If anything, it'll add greater visibility to the work of the editors. Remember, "there is no editor cabal".
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[crazyinsomniac] - Fri Jan  4 13:59:19 2002 &lt;BR&gt;
That patch seems kind of "odd".  I had something like the following in mind:
&lt;CODE&gt;                   updateLinks($curid,$frontpageid,$frontpagelinktype);
                   updateLinks($curid,$nodeid,$lt_id);
##### message editors on frontpage update patch
$DB-&gt;sqlInsert("message",
{ msgtext =&gt; "[editors] announcement -- Hi everybody, I just frontpaged [$$NODE{node_id}].  This announcement is involuntary.",
  author_user =&gt; $$USER{node_id},
  for_user =&gt; 59438,# editors is 59438
  });
&lt;/CODE&gt;
&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[pr0n] 2002-01-04 9:05 EST&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Like I said, I really don't see why only editors should be able to see it. If a 'low-level' user disagrees with the frontpaging of a node, shouldn't he/she be able to comment on it as well?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[crazyinsomniac] perl -e"print ~~gmtime" Fri Jan  4 14:12:58 2002 GMT&lt;BR&gt;
Because only [editors] can change the status.  What's the point of notifying every schmoe, even the thousands which never logged in, if they can never do anything about it except whine to an [editor], which they can do on their own.  EEditors are the only people who need to know.  To everyone else, it's just clutter.
&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;p&gt; [tilly] 2002-01-04&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There may be a misunderstanding about what I mean by "announcement".  I meant
a public chatter where people present could see it, and discuss.  If the
change is obviously bad, people will comment and an editor will get to it.
If it is good then the message is unobtrusive.  A /msg to everyone on the site,
including people who rarely login, seems .. extreme.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;UPDATE&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Another point that may not be obvious.  It is &lt;i&gt;good&lt;/i&gt; for everyone to be
able to participate since the most important part of the process is for the
people who can frontpage nodes to get visible feedback.  Appropriate actions
that can be taken include discussion in chatter, private /msgs, downvoting
people you think are being XP whores, and so on.  These are more effective in
most cases than simple removal of offending nodes, and virtually anyone can
do them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[boo_radley] 04JAN2002&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
in regards to "who gets to see this?", I would suggest making it an option in user settings.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ar0n] 2002-01-04 17:26 EST&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[tilly] appears to have been misunderstanding the code. It actually &lt;i&gt;does&lt;/i&gt; send the message to the chatterbox, not as a private message. &lt;code&gt;for_user =&gt; 0&lt;/code&gt; is [vroom]'s way of saying it's for everyone to see (the chatterbox). If you want to see more about how the chatterbox works, see [Chatterbox|this node].
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[larsen] - Wed Nov 14 2001&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've found a problem regarding user scratchpad. When you put a link
on it using "add to scratchpad" in the "personal nodelet", the
link produced can have the side-effect to logout you from PM.
Here the relevant code from [addtoscratchpad]:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
my $str="&lt;BR&gt;&lt;A HREF=\"http://perlmonks.org/index.pl?node_id=$$N{node_id}\"&gt;$$N{title}&lt;/A&gt;";
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As noted by [Petruchio] on IRC, the problem is that
I've not a cookie for perlmonks.org, but only for www.perlmonks.org.
I think others could have the same problem, considered that
PM uses three different domains. [OeufMayo] proposed a simple
patch:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
my $str=qq( &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="/index.pl?node_id=$$N{node_id}"&gt;$$N{title}&lt;/a&gt; );
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;qq()&lt;/code&gt; notation is better&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
--
&lt;p&gt;[grinder] Thu Dec 27 13:57:26 2001 UTC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone just pointed out in the CB that scratchpad's should have a "d/l code" link. I'm not sure how one would go about that for the moment, but I record the question in case I forget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[footpad] - Mon Nov 12 05:26:29 2001 (UTC)&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Um, is anyone else having problems sending email to [vroom|TFL]?  I've tried the blockstackers addy, as well as the older one.  Both bounce.  Anyone care to update the link in the footer of every page?  (I don't mind not having my work incorporated, but I do mind not being able to find out whether it's because it's simply too lame for words or for other other reasons.  Rather not do that confirmation publically, if you catch my drift.)&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;B&gt;Update&lt;/B&gt;: Seems to be working again.  Must've been that DNS problem someone mentioned.  *shrug*&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[blakem] Sat Oct 27 00:24:23 UTC 2001&lt;BR&gt;
What's up with perlmonks DNS?&lt;BR&gt;
From my point of view, I see:&lt;BR&gt;
(www.)?perlmonks.com =&gt; 206.170.14.76  --  BROKEN&lt;BR&gt;
(www.)?perlmonks.net =&gt; 206.170.14.76  --  BROKEN&amp;lt;BR&gt;
(www.)?perlmonks.org =&gt; 63.150.14.148  --  works&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;FONT SIZE=1&gt;* yes, it should be '(www\.)?' but that seemed silly&lt;/FONT&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[vroom] 2001-10-25 13:09:49 UTC&lt;br&gt;
If you were responsible for making banners disappear for a piece today please /msg me before I get some time to 
search some logs and/or get truly annoyed.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;update: err nevermind, I think&lt;/B&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[grinder] 2001-10-02 10:26 UTC&lt;br&gt;
Don't know who's hacking on the [new user settings] but I would just like to point out that it ate my personal nodelet. Fortunately I was able to recover by backing up in Mozilla, but [virtualsue] says via CB that she lost the lot and didn't notice. There should be a red splash warning of this possibility, until it moves out of beta.&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[vroom] 2001-09-26&lt;BR&gt;
some of you may have noticed changes have been slow in getting checked in from my end.  I'm busy and often lazy and or tired... occasionally I feel like a slasker.  Hopefully once I get the patch apply and undo/redo capabilities added in it will make checking things in and checking whether they work much easier.  I've added a list on my homenode of the things
I expect to do and the current order I expect to do them in.

&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2001-09-21&lt;br&gt;
Where do I find the source code for linkNode()?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[crazyinsomniac] Wed Sep 26 07:22:16 2001 GMT&lt;BR&gt;
It's found in Everything::HTML (good question).
Lets please not have anymore questions like this in the [pmdev wiki].  Every pm developer should go to [http://www.everydevel.com/] and download the e-core and other goodies, and super search everydevel (or search your own local Everything*.pm's) for answers to these type questions.  Also, don't forget about chromatic on everydevel (excellent info), and his Everything Bible.  And you can always drop me line (if you can catch me in non-ho mode).
&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
[vroom] Sun Sep 16 17:54:13 UTC 2001&lt;P&gt;
New exciting feature stolen from E2.  Now you should be able to submit patches wherever you can see code listed.  The patch is then displayed showing the diffs between the current node state and the patch.  Now if I build functionality to apply a patch along with a history nodetype I can apply changes and then undo and redo with impunity.
&lt;HR&gt;
[blakem] Sun Sep 16 02:32:08 PDT 2001&lt;P&gt;
Can we setup a mailing-list for pmdev?  I see a lot of good ideas being presented here and people willing to work on them... However, it doen't seem
like the process is moving forward very smoothly... I think a pmdev listserv would be an easy step in the right direction.
&lt;HR&gt;
[blakem] Mon Sep 10 15:15:30 PDT 2001&lt;P&gt;
It looks like my idea at [id://111410] has received overwhelmingly positive
response from the community (no one complained about it revealing a slight amount of rep info before actually voting on a node)  So, how do I go about developing this.   Others have 
posted similiar questions below (i.e. How do I get started) but I don't see
any real answers.  Other than 'viewcode' and this wiki, what tools/environments are available to me as a developer?&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Update:&lt;/B&gt; I combined some code from Best Nodes and the 'next entries' links from the sections.  The [http://www.blakem.com/~blakem/bestnodes.txt|resulting code] is available, though I don't even know if it will compile (let alone work properly)... Is there anyway I can test this out somewhere?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[grinder] 2001/09/14 09:15 UTC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am pretty much against the idea of revealing the reputation of nodes you haven't voted on. Even in best/worst nodes, although I can live with that. But revealing a whole lot more, I don't like the idea. Display the list, yes, but don't display the reps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is just like viewing threads sorted by best first. You have to vote to find out what a node is "worth".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;HR&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
[vroom] Thu Sep 6 sometime after work has ended for the day
&lt;p&gt;
I hope to get some stuff done this weekend.  [crazyinsomniac] sent me an alternative opcode called tickerlogin to prevent people from showing up
on other users.  The ignore for private messages is a good one although
I think the shortcut should happen before insert into the db.  [OeufMayo]
sent me a slew of html cleanups.  On my first attempt at inserting them
I broke the site pretty badly at some point and had to reload the old
nodes from a db dump.  I also need to set up a devel PM for checking
changes into first.  Also pmdevtasks and task lister need to be made more
functional so the users in this group can use them.  A note type that other
users can't see would be nice for people to comment on given development
tasks.
&lt;p&gt;[grinder] 2001/09/07 16:31:16 UTC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you mean that we can check changes into ourselves, and then you can
pick and choose what you like to load up on the production site? Right now
I'm a little puzzled... I can edit code, but how do I test it? Am I supposed
to install MySQL, E 0.8, and the PM nodeball on a server of my own? Call me
unclear on the concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[crazyinsomniac] - Thu Nov 22 08:43:56 2001 GMT&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/BR&gt;
Well on perlmonks you can't exactly test it.  Best you can do is give any of the gods a holler and bother them (might not be considered nice), or call me and ask me to look at it (and I might even test it on JJ if it's generic enough).  Honestly, as long as you're not doing anything major, and your syntaxt is right (you should check with perl -Mstrict -wc) you should be ok.  And anyway, vroom picks and chooses which patches to apply, as "we", the [pmdev]elopers cannot create new nodes, only fix bugs and submit improvements (as of now).
&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 [Petruchio] Fri Aug 31 13:44:14 UTC 2001:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I thought I'd point out a [Regarding the Chatterbox|relevant discussion]
 on the topic of ignoring private messages. No opposition, but ideas and
 slight diversity of opinion regarding implementation. It is from the height 
 of troll war paranoia, by the way.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 Another thing... and I'm forcing myself to bring this up... are we going
 to establish any coding standards?  The place where this actually interests
 me is HTML cleanup; if we're going to make things pretty, there's a sense
 in establishing what we think is pretty.  I'm much less keen on the idea
 for actual Perl coding, but that's because I'm a geek, and my own style
 is obviously perfect. :-)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[OeufMayo] Fri Aug 31 22:16:00 UTC 2001: As far as HTML is concerned, I think
that [http://www.w3.org/people/Ragget/Tidy|HTML Tidy] does a pretty good job at
reformating the HTML. I usually filter all the HTML doc through it. And the same
goes with [http://perltidy.sourceforge.net|perltidy] for my perl code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FWIW, I made the code I've rewritten so far available on my site: [http://briac.dyndns.org/pmcode/]&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;hr /&gt;

[grinder] 2001/08/30 21:55 UTC
&lt;p&gt;Here's a thing, [deprecated] complained about the fact that when you
/ignore a user [id://108995|you still receive their private messages]. So
the task I'd like to set myself would be to change the /ignore functionality
to also ignore private messages. I don't think it's worthwhile introducing a
new /verb to differentiate between ignore the public and private messages of a user. If you are sufficiently annoyed to be forced to employ /ignore I doubt you care. So the question is, is/can it be put in the [pmdev task lister]?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ar0n] 2001-08-30 23:33 UTC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Actually, I just finished that and sent it to [vroom]. See [http://ar0n.dyndns.org/private.txt]. Sorry ;)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
[jlp] Thu Aug 30 19:16:51 UTC 2001
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;
One thing from the now-defunct [http://obiwan.blockstackers.com/~pythonmonk/|PythonMonks] project that I would like to see make it into PM is the most excellent [http://obiwan.blockstackers.com/~pythonmonk/index.pl?node_id=26205|Green Theme], created by [neshura]. I know there have been threads where people requested a green theme for PM, and I would love to have it for my own use, as well. Some of the images would need to be altered for PM use, and somebody with actual graphics skill (I'm looking at you, [OeufMayo|Oeuf] :)) would need to do that, since I suck. And once again, all credit for this to [neshura]; she did all the hard work, I'm just handling some of the legwork on getting it to PM.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;grinder likes the green theme :)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;myocom does too!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aug 31 21:36:18 2001 GMT - [oeufmayo]: This green them sure looks good! I'm okay to do some graphics
stuff for it, so if anyone knows the font used for the top banner and the main
section, just let me know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;[chromatic] 2001-08-29 00:03 UTC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you do figure things out, please leave copious comments in your new version.  There are a few tricky things with Everything, along with several common idioms and workarounds.  In addition, keep an eye out for weird stuff, like localized subs and repeated code that might be best abstracted out into htmlcode (supplementary functions).
&lt;/p&gt;
[grinder] 2001-08-30 8:59 UTC
&lt;p&gt;Umm... how exactly do we go about writing new code? What's the general plan? So far all I have done is &lt;code&gt;[viewcode]&lt;/code&gt;. As for writing new stuff, I'm unclear on the concept. (Just realised I'm supposed to add comments below the root) &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;P&gt;
[crazyinsomniac] Mon Dec 17 07:35:25 2001
&lt;BR&gt;
As of now you do not.  [pmdev]ers can only alter existing nodes, well, submit patches for vroom to approve, which will eventually, if approved, alter existing nodes.  Only [gods] can create new nodes, so if you have new code, and it's not controvertial, I sugguest you solicit a god and persuade him to create the node.  If it is controversial, it's off to discussion to discuss.
&lt;BR&gt;
Serisouly guys, how hard is it to type &lt;TT&gt;perl -e"print ~~gmtime"&lt;/TT&gt;
&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ar0n] - 2001-08-29 23:34 UTC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I agree. Since it's a group of developers now, and not just a single developer, readability/maintainability would be a nice thing (not that I'm complaining :)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[grinder] - 2001-08-29 23:08 UTC&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been merrily viewing code left, right and center and have at last resolved why the [Perl Monks User Search] displays certain monk names and not others if you bounce on the CB Talk button for a while...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, I've come across all sorts of code that just screams out to be tidied up. For instance TMG contains the following:
&lt;code&gt;
   8:      my $sopwnum=$$VARS{fp_max_sopw};

   9:      my $mednum=$$VARS{fp_max_med};
  10:      my $craftnum=$$VARS{fp_max_craft};
[...]
  15:      $sopwnum||=4;
  16:      $craftnum||=2;
  17:      $cufpnum||=2;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that's just begging to be rewritten as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
   8:      my $sopwnum  = $VARS-&gt;{fp_max_sopw}  || 4;
   9:      my $mednum   = $VARS-&gt;{fp_max_med}   || 2;
  10:      my $craftnum = $VARS-&gt;{fp_max_craft} || 2;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it ain't broke notwithstanding, writing this more concisely doesn't
serve any visible purpose but it might make it easier to read. Are we to
bother about this sort of thing or not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[ar0n], a wee bit later -- the [preview page] code isn't viewable, because it's a [strangedoc].
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] - 2001-08-29&lt;br&gt;
[vroom] just fixed the nodelet display code so that it now shows the source code that generates the nodelet.  Thanks, [vroom]!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Another small bug is that node titles get truncated at quote characters by the preview code.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[vroom] - 2001-08-28&lt;br&gt;
I'm currently working on a way of adding a nodetype for development tasks.  These
items will have a piece of text describing the change or feature.  The item will
have a status which will be new, in development, and completed.  There will also be a priority field with a number between 1 and 10.  There will also be a field
for the lead developer on a given item.  /msg me if you have any other ideas
for information that would be useful to manage these tasks.
&lt;p&gt;See: [pmdev task lister]
&lt;p&gt;[tye] - 2001-08-28&lt;br&gt;
If anyone wants a good starter task, the [editors] could really use [id://60309] but it isn't acceptably useful right now.  It doesn't update the moved reply's "thread".  If moved to be a reply to a root node, it doesn't update the number of replies on that root node (and likewise doesn't decrement the number of replies for the previous parent).  Of course, it doesn't move entire threads.  It also can't be used to turn a root node into a reply.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
For an even smaller starter task, the "SOPWify" link for Cat Q+A (which is just &lt;code&gt;?op=sopwify&amp;node_id=...&lt;/code&gt; mostly works but leaves the count of replies to the newly-created root node at 0.  It also has a race condition of allowing a previously-started reply to get created as a Cat A that is a reply to a SoPW, though I'm sure that is much harder to fix.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[chromatic] - 2001-08-23 around 4:40 pm GMT&lt;/p&gt;
Everything allows for code to be modified on the fly, even code that's considered part of node objects or node display.  Unfortunately, it's optimized for the uncommon case, checking to see if the code needs to be recompiled on every hit.  As reads are much, much more common than writes (at least 100 to 1), that's a big performance penalty.
&lt;p&gt;
What makes things worse is that there's no good way to share memory between mod_perl child processes.  They'll get further and further out of sync.  If there are five kids, and I modify an htmlpage in one kid, the other four will each have to recompile and to cache it.
&lt;p&gt;
My potential solution is to rework the forking slightly.  Instead of allowing Apache to prefork several children, we'll limit it to one kid.  That'll be the new parent.  It will receive new requests and fork off children on its own.  The difference is, each child will report back to the parent any modified nodes that need to be recompiled.  The parent will then recompile the node, install the new code in the appropriate stash for the object or wherever, and cache the new node.
&lt;p&gt;
The next child to be forked off will use the same memory pages as the parent.  It'll be much more up to date and ought to use less memory.  We can remove a lot of redundant "is this updated?" checks in the children.  Moving nodetypes to first-class objects can also give us a speed win, if we avoid AUTOLOAD in Everything::HTML.
&lt;p&gt;
I have a small, non-Apache proof of concept already.  
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[oakbox] - 2001-08-23 &lt;/p&gt;
[chromatic] said:&lt;i&gt;"Brian Aker gave me an idea on how to speed this up, though, by abusing
  mod_perl. It's worth considering. "&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt; I would love to hear what that suggestion is, [chromatic].  Our new installation at javajunkies.org can be painfully slow, even after upgrading to 256Mb ram.&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2001-08-22&lt;br /&gt;
[id://891] (the dbtable) fails (server error) if you have privilege to view it.  Perhaps we should replace the nice new reaper page for such errors with something more like "fatals to browser" if you are a pmdev?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;P&gt; [footpad] 22 Aug 01, ~6:50 am (PDT) &lt;BR /&gt;
Thanks.  I think we should track what's needed and who's working on what.  this way, we know things get done and we don't duplicate effort.  I'll happily track that if you like.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;

&lt;p&gt; [jlp] Wed Aug 22 08:06:43 2001 GMT:
&lt;br&gt;
This seems kind of messy. Why a wiki, exactly? Why not an actual site section (it shouldn't be in the titlebar or the sections nodelet or anything, since that would contribute to section clutter, which is already pretty bad), where we could have real threading, which seems like it would lend itself more easily to the task(s) at hand.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[zdog] Wed Aug 22 ~9:20 2001 PDT:&lt;br&gt;
But it's so much more fun this way!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 [Petruchio] Wed Aug 22 06:56:56 2001 GMT:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I think posting continuously in one direction is strongly preferable to 
 adding root nodes in one direction and replies in the other. I suggest 
 moving upwards, as with the editors' wiki.  Adding timestamps is also a 
 good thing; [crazyinsomniac] suggests using GMT.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I'm honored to have been chosen for the group. This should be fun.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;

[chromatic]'s &lt;strong&gt;Thoughts on Everything 0.8x and Everything 1.0&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;p&gt;

My completely impractical, more work for vroom and nate  and maybe CowboyNeal suggestion is to think about migrating PM to the Everything 1.0 codebase. Part of that is pragmatic. I know Everything 0.9x and 1.0, and I can work with 0.8, but it's not documented. There have been several impressive feature enhancements (code caching, API improvements, Form Objects!), and there's even a manual.
&lt;p&gt;
Of course, it tends to be slower (though I have a nasty mod_perl idea to fix that for good), and there are a lot of existing nodes that will have to be converted.
&lt;p&gt;
The bulk of the PM database made up of general questions and answers, in the message nodeball. vroom 's produced a version of this that runs on 1.0. I don't know if there are any schema changes, but translating nodes between versions is straightforward.
&lt;p&gt;
The big work will be translating superdocs, htmlpages, and just about any other site construct that uses things that have changed in the API. There are probably a couple hundred of them. vroom's probably the only guy who understands them at this point, but they can't be too hard to decipher.
&lt;p&gt;
If there are a handful of people in pmdev with the time and the inclination, perhaps someone could set up a 1.0 site and vroom could make some of these nodes available, for porting purposes. If everything can be updated to take advantage of Everything 1.0, it might be easier to port the entire site.
&lt;p&gt;
Of course, this is just my opinion. It's a bit of work, and it's not my call whether or not vroom 's even interested in such a project. Also, the rough consensus among Everything developers is that 1.0 is slower than 0.8, which is why Everything 2 isn't running the latest and greatest code. Brian Aker gave me an idea on how to speed this up, though, by abusing mod_perl. It's worth considering.
&lt;p&gt;
[zdog] Last Night GMT: I wuf you chromatic! I'll gladly jump into the pool of porters since this has been a long time dream of mine :-). And in theory, during the process of porting all the bug-fixing and hole-patching can be going on. And since this is an offsite thing, there is little chance that the developers can do any direct damage.
&lt;HR&gt;
[vroom]
There are definitely loads of things that would be a lot-easier to do in 1.0.  Also there are lots of kludgey workarounds in PM and E2 which led to a better
way of doing things in 1.0.  I'm not against an effort to do so.  If nothing
else it'd be cool to have a distribution or nodeball for 1.0 which contained
basic PM-Like functionality for other people that wanted to start similar 
sites.  One other difficulty with translation of data is all of the embedded
node_id's in posts which could be stolen by system nodes in the core system.
A script to translate these on import would probably not be exceedingly difficult but it is another thing to think about.
&lt;P&gt;
I would think that at the least with a small group of developers a distribution
with PM-like functionality would be quite doable.  Perhaps we could get PM
there one day too.
&lt;P&gt;&lt;B&gt;Also where are we adding new posts? at the top or bottom?&lt;/B&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Yesterday GMT: I'm thinking new "root posts" at the top. Responses below them. -Z
&lt;hr&gt;
First Post!  --Chris</field>
</data>
</node>
