<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="166549" title="pmdev wiki through 2002-05-10" created="2002-05-14 15:29:53" updated="2005-08-09 09:21:31">
<type id="68046">
wiki</type>
<author id="142755">
tye&amp;nbsp;</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
(continues in [id://178924]...)
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2002-05-10&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I'm proud to announce that [pmdev]ers can now view the source code to the &lt;a href="/?node_id=106927&amp;whichtype=118397&amp;sexisgood=submit"&gt;modules&lt;/a&gt; used by Perl Monks.  I'll eventually fix [search internal code] to also search those.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[demerphq], that first IP address works fine for me.  You need to traceroute (or tracert for Win32) to it and see where your connectivity problem is.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[JayBonci], I'll be getting the info you need to you soon.  Thanks.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; [demerphq] 2002-05-10 ~3pm GMT&lt;br&gt;
Not sure if this is the right venue (itsnot really a dev matter I dont think) but a lot of people have been reporting "cannot find server" errors today.  A check of my DNS settings says that perlmonks is resolving to
&lt;code&gt; 
24   110 ms   125 ms   140 ms  ads.perlmonks.org [66.39.54.27]
&lt;/code&gt;
which seems to be wrong as I cant get anything if I use that as an url.  But if I do a DNS flush I get the same result as [jeffa] did
&lt;code&gt;
 24   125 ms   125 ms   125 ms  perlmonks.pair.com [209.197.123.153]
&lt;/code&gt;
Which if I use it as the address works fine.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;UPDATE&lt;/STRONG&gt;It appears that these both work now. Sigh. :-)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[jaybonci|jb] 5-9-02&lt;br /&gt;
More of the same... [showprivatemessages2 - (patch)] by me secures two otherwise insecure parameters at the top of the node. Same basic stuff as the previous patches applied by [Tye].

Also, Tye, where is the functionality for [QandAEditors]? Do they use op=nuke, or some other marking / deletion method (such as [consider]). Lemme know, and I'll look into that, and the "can't update" wiki thing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2002-05-08&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, [super search] produces server errors, just like it says on the page.  Yes, [pmdev] members get the "full error" for server errors now.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
BTW, the server errors happen when super search has probably locked up PM for quite a few seconds and a daemon has canceled its query out from under it.  I'd love to remove it, but that wouldn't be popular.  I'd love more to replace it, but none of the potential replacements are ready yet. /:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[demerphq] 2002-05-08&lt;br /&gt;
Actually [tye] I believe the ISO 8904 (??) says that both / and - as well as nothing are legal. :-)&lt;br /&gt;
Is this a "server error" from SuperSearch:
&lt;code&gt;
 DBD::mysql::st fetchrow_hashref failed: fetch() without execute() at (eval 3117) line 75.
# Lots removed by tye
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;   
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-05-08&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
ISO dates use "-" not "/", [demerphq]. (:&lt;br /&gt;
[jaybonci|jb], applied your patch.  Thanks!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[crazyinsomniac], I'm highly doubtful of the multiple-ops patch having anything to do with your bug.  The patch was pretty trivial and I've heard of this problem in the past.  Unfortunately, I have no clue where to look, just like for the "[QandAEditors] can't nuke" bug that appears to be related to some other problems (like wiki updates saying they failed when they didn't). /:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
BTW, the latter involves updates happening twice such that the second update fails.  For the "can't nuke" problem, the node-to-be-nuked is inserted into the "morgue" and then a second insert fails and results in HTTP 500 error.  For wiki updates, it says "didn't update 'description' because it had changed" but the change was the update &lt;b&gt;I&lt;/b&gt; am making.  [vroom], [jaybonci|jb], or others with more experience with Everything, any clues?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[belg4mit], I didn't apply [id://164453] because I don't find the results more compact and I don't like having to use both the keyboard and the mouse in order to select multiple items.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[crazyinsomniac] Wed May  8 14:16:51 2002 &lt;br /&gt;
When posting a few of my latest nodes (last 10+), I have on occasion, while previewing, been taken to a page of search results (regular search).  I didn't get no server errors, and I have no clue how it happened (I did click on preview for sure).  This could potentially have something to do with the recent multiple ops patch.  I haven't been able to replicate this on demand.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[demerphq] 2002/05/08 : I know its a trivial thing but could we try to use ISO compliant date stamps in the wiki (YYYY/MM/DD)? Mixing different date formats, especially the unusual American style ones (even the US Army doesn't use them) can be really quite confusing. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[jaybonci|jb] 5/7/2002: Patched unchecked input in &amp;numdays= parameter in [nodesWithinDays - (patch)]. That's the only unchecked / non-secure parameter in that superdoc. It's in the style of tye's mod to the last patch.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-05-07&lt;br /&gt;
Patch applied (w/ minor mods).  Someone else already opened access to maintenances.
&lt;p&gt;
[jaybonci|jb]: Two things, patch for unchecked input in [Node Lister], also, please add pmdev to authorized readers for maintenances, I'd like to see some of the enginey parts of the system if that's cool with you all. Thanks, and have a good night.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-05-07&lt;br /&gt;
Fixed.  Author was -1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[jaybonci|jb]: 05/07/02 still happening: Do you get a normal node display? Is there more than one pm webhead?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  [demerphq] 2002/05/06:&lt;br /&gt; 
As myself I get the same error as [jaybonci|jb] does.&lt;br /&gt;
As AM I get "Access is denied.".&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  [ar0n], 2002-05-06
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  No problem here.  Not even as AM.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[jaybonci|jb]: node_id 5771 [vote settings] tosses a 500 whenever I go to it... probably corrupted.  You might want to take a look at it. I don't know if it's vital to the system, but you might want to look at it 
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Chady] Fri May  3 12:23:55 2002&lt;br /&gt;
am I the only one who gets broken images after logging in from the [minilogin]?
I believe the problem is the trailing / in the action:
&lt;code&gt;
&lt;form method="post" action="/index.pl/" enctype="application/x-www-form-urlencoded"&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
aren't the error logs being filled up with HTTP404 errors?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[jaybonci|jb] adds: Gotta love newer CGI libs. This also plagues willowisp over on E2. The basic fix is to add -action =&gt; $query-&gt;script_name() to the form creation and that usually fixes it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VSarkiss] Fri May  3 02:39:42 2002 UTC&lt;br /&gt;
Kudos to whomever that patched [Perl Monks User Search].  It looks wonderful, and I can't find you in [Patch Lister] or any other way I know of.  Thank you, thank you, thank you. :)
&lt;br /&gt;[Demerphq] agrees absolutely. Its muuuuch better now!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2002-04-28&lt;br /&gt;
A user was only partially created such that their 'owner' was -1.  The NNXG doesn't handle that case.  I nuked the user and that fixed it.  Making NNXG more robust would be a reasonable task for someone.  I plan to update server errors such that [pmdev] members get the details just like [gods] do now.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; [blakem] 2002-04-28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Newest Nodes XML Generator] is broken (Error Id 6557772a10454)&lt;BR&gt;
Has anyone done anything to it in the past 24 hours?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2002-04-28&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks.  Applied.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; [JayBonci] &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minor cosmetic patch for [Nodes to consider] at [Nodes to consider - (patch)]. It makes it easier to consider nodes that are further down in the list&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 [blakem]  2002-04-23
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Oddly enough, when submitting a reply to a Q&amp;A Answer a 'Permission Denied' error
occurs.  This leaves an empty node and a rather broken user experience.
I tried doing this as both as anonymonk and as myself with the same result.  Note, this only occurs when replying to an already supplied Answer, not when replying to the original Question.  The two empty nodes I created are: [161236] and [161239].  I stumbled over this issue after noticing several empty nodes
with titles starting with "Re: Answer ..."&lt;br&gt; 
The query string that lead to the Permission Denied error was:
&lt;blockquote&gt;
index.pl?&lt;br&gt;
parent=161040&amp;&lt;br&gt;
title=Answer%3A%20How%20do%20i%20force%20the&lt;br&gt;
%20user%20to%20download%20my%20content%3F&amp;&lt;br&gt;
lastnode_id=161040&amp;&lt;br&gt;
displaytype=display&amp;&lt;br&gt;
type=superdoc&amp;&lt;br&gt;
node=Comment%20on&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
After tracking down the nodeid I was able to edit my empty node, but that's not
really a satisfactory solution.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For no real good reason I have corrected the date typos in [Petruchio] and [Belg4mit]'s posts below.  It is still April after all...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 [Petruchio] 2002-04-21
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 No, &lt;tt&gt;px&lt;/tt&gt; is good, insofar as our present purpose is concerned.
 Citing authority is not particularly useful, either, here.  I run at
 1600x1200, and I disagree.  The whole point of CSS is to separate content,
 and the structure of the content, from presentation details.  It is not 
 to hobble one's ability to provide specific presentation details at all.
 The default should indeed be generally useful... and let me tell you, I
 have empirical evidence that this is not the case using &lt;tt&gt;smaller&lt;/tt&gt;
 or &lt;tt&gt;pt&lt;/tt&gt;.  Browser settings have everything to do with this; the 
 major reason for &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; defining an absolute size is to attempt to
 accomodate individuals' browser settings.  The fact that users may change
 the style information themselves renders this consideration mostly 
 unimportant.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 The plain fact is, setting the font size in the fashion you suggest
 causes very different results on NS4, IE, Opera and the Mozilla family.
 Results which are, as it turns out, very unpleasant to at least some
 large group of users whichever way you cut it.  Now, hypothetically,
 this is okay; they simply need to set 'small' to whatever pleases them.
 Then, with 'small', 'medium' and 'large' arranged to their tastes, all
 sites should be able to employ these relative terms, to the great satisfaction
 of the user.  In practice, however, the vast majority of people do not
 customize their browsers... and the defaults for the major browsers differ
 greatly.  As you point out, the default should be useable. Experience has
 made plain that using 'smaller' or a pt setting does not accomplish this
 goal by a long shot.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 Feel free to prove me wrong, and come up with a more abstract solution which
 &lt;i&gt;actually&lt;/i&gt; provides a better default.  However don't think I haven't tried
 what you've suggested thus far.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 [belg4mit]  2002-04-21
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;px&lt;/tt&gt; is bad. I thought W3C agreed, but cannot find anything to back me up. Try setting your video mode up to 1200x1024,
then disagree. The whole point of CSS is to be vague
in a specific way. Individual users may setup a style sheet,
but the default should be generally useable. Browser setting
have nothing to do this (exclusing user-defined style sheets which very few support). Defining an absolute size makes any
browser setting irrelevant. Additionaly it is my understanding
px has issues across platforms/devices since it relies upon DPI;
could be wrong on this bit though.
&lt;p&gt;
 [Petruchio] 2002-04-21
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 No, &lt;tt&gt;px&lt;/tt&gt; is considered to be good; &lt;tt&gt;pt&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;smaller&lt;/tt&gt;
 are considered to be not merely harmful, but dangerous to life and limb.
 We &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; attempting to give a very specific, concrete description of
 presentation.  Having the IE users scream because the fonts are too large, 
 or the Mozilla users wail because they're too small, is a Bad Thing&amp;trade;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 To separate presentation details from document structure is reasonable, 
 but the quest to reduce all presentation directives to the level of 
 vague, unquantifiable suggestions is not one I approve of.  There is
 a need to offer documents with distinct layouts, and markup should serve
 this need.  In any case, all style information on the site may be 
 overridden by the user at the source, so there is very little need
 to accomodate unusual browser settings.  There is, however, a strong
 need to give users a consistent default appearance.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[belg4mit] 2002-04-20
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Hello, still poking around all this stuff.
With respect to the recent style sheet modifications,
&lt;tt&gt;px&lt;/tt&gt; is considered harmful, it is used in
the nodelet body definition. Any other unit is preferable to &lt;tt&gt;px&lt;/tt&gt;.
Perhaps &lt;tt&gt;pt&lt;/tt&gt; was meant? Either way in this case
&lt;tt&gt;smaller&lt;/tt&gt; is probably a better choice.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 [Petruchio] 2002-04-21
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 Now, rather than the two links atop the nodelet stack, there is a [PM Dev Nodelet].  You'll find it in
 your [user settings], as you would any other nodelet.  I hope you find it useful.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-04-18&lt;br /&gt;
Fixed.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[demerphq], 2002/04/18&lt;br /&gt;
There seems to be a bug in the snippets section.  It seems that for some reason the code is not being displayed correctly. Each snippets code section seems to consist of only a 
&lt;code&gt;
&lt;TR&gt;&lt;TD colspan=2&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;tt&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/TD&gt;&lt;/TR&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
This doesnt seem to affect any other node than a top level snippet.&lt;p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-04-15&lt;br /&gt;
OK, I made some moderately major updates to Everything::HTML including duplicating [ar0n]'s changes (which most notably get rid of lastnode_id) to the second web server (grrr).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Anyway, the main motivation for this was to fix a problem with htmlcode.  Prior to the change, you used htmlcode nodes by 1) embedding &lt;code&gt;[{textarea:fieldname,10,80}]&lt;/code&gt; into HTML template code or 2) calling &lt;code&gt;htmlcode('textare','fieldname,10,80')&lt;/code&gt; from Perl code.  Although (2) is still supported, you should now instead use &lt;code&gt;htmlcode('textarea','','fieldname',10,80)&lt;/code&gt; &amp;#91;note the empty second argument, &lt;code&gt;''&lt;/code&gt;, which is required&amp;#93;.  &amp;#91;You can even mix the two: &lt;code&gt;htmlcode('textarea','fieldname,10',80,'virtual')&lt;/code&gt;.&amp;#93;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The major motivation for allowing the above is to fix calls to [parselinksinstring] to avoid using a global (which can cause very strange things when two different bits of code both want to use that function).  So code that used to read:
&lt;code&gt;    $HTMLVARS{embed_node}{doctext} = $U-&gt;{scratchpad};
    return htmlcode( 'parselinksinstring', '0' );
&lt;/code&gt;
should be changed to:
&lt;code&gt;    return htmlcode( 'parselinksinstring', '',
      0, '', $U-&gt;{scratchpad}
    );
&lt;/code&gt;
where [parselinksinstring] takes 3 arguments, 1) whether or not to process &lt;code&gt;&lt;readmore&gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags, 2) the ID of the node the readmore link should go to, 3) the text of the node.  If (3) is missing, then &lt;code&gt;$HTMLVARS{embed_node}{doctext}&lt;/code&gt; is used (for backward compatability).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Also, &lt;code&gt;&lt;/readmore&gt;&lt;/code&gt; is now supported so you can put
&lt;code&gt;    Really interesting description
    &lt;readmore&gt;
    Boring details
    &lt;/readmore&gt;
    Your signature
&lt;/code&gt;
in a node and have your signature appear after the "Read more..." link.  You can even have multiple groups of &lt;code&gt;&lt;readmore&gt;...&lt;/readmore&gt;&lt;/code&gt; that each become &lt;code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="..."&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Similar nodes like [parsetimeinstring] should also be fixed to support not using a global to pass in arguments, but I haven't done that yet.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-04-15&lt;br /&gt;
As noted in the change log in [pm-port wiki], I've updated "view code" to work on 'pmdevsuperdoc' nodes (thanks for [N-Wing] for requesting this).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[crazyinsomniac] - Sun Apr 21 11:38:08 2002&lt;BR&gt;
Not bad, althought I think this'd would've been better discussed in [Perl Monks Discussion].  I suggest [Other Tutorials] for the section ;)
&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[vroom], 2002-04-15&lt;br /&gt;
The related information section in tutorials sounds like a good idea to me.  [footpad] feel free to pursue this.

&lt;P&gt;[footpad], Mon Apr 15 15:41:57 2002 (GMT)&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;P&gt;In [id://159188|this thread], two people suggested a Related Information section in Tutorials.  (The idea being a collector of stuff that you should know, but may not be directly "Perl" related.)  We can do this fairly easily.  What do you think?  &lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;I'm more than happy to do the actual work, but wanted to get some more feedback before going off with my markup half-cached.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-04-13&lt;br /&gt;
fixed
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[demerphq], 2002/04/11 11:00 (GMT+1)&lt;br /&gt;
I've found a minor bug in the new CB markup.  Which [tye] has now kindly fixed.. So I removed the rest of the report...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;P&gt;[footpad], Tue Apr  9 20:22:55 2002 (GMT)&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Look like we need to update the handling of the &amp;#091;isbn://&amp;#093; tag, as Barnes and Noble has finally gotten around to assimilating fatbrain's site.  I can do this (and am perfectly willing to), however, it looks like they're also mangled with the Affliliates program somewhat.  So, before we actually change the isbn tag, would someone in the know please see if a) our old Affiliate ID still works and b) if not, please provide the new parameter needed?&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Note that you have to got to &lt;a href"http://bn.com"&gt;bn.com&lt;/a&gt; to get to the Affiliate program.  Also, BN does have an ISBN search, but they've placed it on their advanced search page.  *Sigh*&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;Small&gt;And thanks to whoever archived the wiki; I was just about to ask for that.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-04-09&lt;br /&gt;
I added [search internal code].  Hope others find it useful.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  [ar0n], 2002-04-0&amp;#91;78&amp;#93;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Err, I, well, I deleted it.  I did not mean to, but while deleting a node I had 
  created, I accidentally nuked the [Visit Reaped Nodes] page, not the node 
  itself. I restored it from backup, but rewrote it, since I did not 
  like what I saw.  Anyhoo, it's fixed.  And remember, "It's [ar0n]'s fault."
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VSarkiss], Mon Apr  8 02:59:20 2002 UTC&lt;br /&gt;
[Visit reaped nodes] appears to be gone.  At least I haven't been able to bring it up since yesterday.  Thus, I can't follow the "for more information see [this]" link in any reaped node.  I'm really curious about what happened to it since I can't seem to track it down in any of the ways I know about....
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
Backed up to [id://157365].</field>
</data>
</node>
