<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="168299" title="editors' wiki though 2002-05-06" created="2002-05-21 18:15:52" updated="2005-08-02 09:34:26">
<type id="68046">
wiki</type>
<author id="142755">
tye&amp;nbsp;</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;Continued in [id://200924]...&lt;/I&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  [ar0n], 2002-05-06
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I removed [nodes to reparent], as [kudra] has taken care of all of them.  From 
  now on they'll be in [nodes requiring editing]
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[kudra]&lt;br&gt;
Thanks!  That was pretty quick.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[kudra], 2002-05-06&lt;br&gt;
It seems to work nicely. 
Would you consider adding an editable /msg line to the bottom like
the one you get with edit?  I think when we start using this realtime
instead of on the backlog people would find it nice to know about the moves.
I was thinking of something along the lines of:
'/msg foo I've reparented &amp;#091;id://&amp;#093; under &amp;#091;id://&amp;#093;'.
&lt;p&gt;
  [ar0n], 2002-05-05
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  [nodes to reparent] is a wiki, and all editors should be able to edit it.
  The &lt;tt&gt;ehomat&lt;/tt&gt; link on the editors nodelet now links to [id://60309].
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[corion], 2002-05-05&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;++ to [ar0n], and ++ to whoever came up with "does this look right", because it didn't on my first try &lt;tt&gt;:-)&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I reparented the first node, [id://94907], but how do I remove it from the list from the [nodes to reparent] ?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  [ar0n], 2002-05-05 (happy liberation day, dutchies)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  [id://60309] is now in service.  It chops, slices and reparents your favorite 
  nodes, all in a matter of seconds!  You can have this amazing feat of
  technology for only $9.99!  And that's not all folks:  if you call now, we'll 
  throw in a FREE [nodes to reparent] list.  Order now! (We accept VISA)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;small&gt;
    Standard disclaimer applies.  We are not responsible for any lost nodes,
    mutilations, or dismemberments.  Only capable of reparenting [note]s, [monkdiscuss], [perlquestion], or [perlmeditation] nodes.  
  &lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-05-04&lt;br /&gt;
Sure.  If you consider the replies so they can be found later, then purging the parent is OK by me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[kudra], 2002-05-04&lt;br&gt;
What if the node is a duplicate, and you (or someone else) has submitted
the replies for reparenting under the non-duplicate node?  Until 
the rest of us can reparent that does leave parentless nodes, but it
seems nicer to leave them alive for eventual adoption.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-05-03&lt;br /&gt;
Please, don't cast "editor delete" votes on nodes with replies unless you have already case such on all of the replies (which implies that you think all of the replies should be purged).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[kudra], 2002-05-01&lt;br&gt;
One small problem I've noted is that the approval nodelet is showing
up right underneath the XP nodelet, even if it isn't set as the top
nodelet in user settings.  I haven't performed an extensive test, I
just verified that the approval nodelet isn't the top item in
my settings (I prefer the editor nodelet above it).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[kudra], 2002-04-30&lt;br&gt;
The new changes are very nice.  I still would prefer to be able to
unconsider as I submit the edit, but just having the button on the
same page is already a huge improvement.  In general the site changes
are very welcome and I appreciate the job you're doing.
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[dvergin], 2002-04-29&lt;br/&gt;
This is terRIFic. Check it out folks. These last changes really streamline the editing process for current items. (We'll still need to visit NRE to catch older items that have not been resolved.) Thank you, thank you...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-04-29&lt;br/&gt;
[editors|We] can now "unconsider" a node directly from the approval nodelet (presumably after [editors|we]'ve fixed what was broken with it or noticed that someone else did) if the node has gotten at least 2 "edit" votes or at least 4 "keep" votes.  Not quite what was asked for (requires an extra click), but useful, I hope.  Although a single "keep" vote is (currently) enough to prevent a node from being reaped, 4 "keep" votes are required before unconsidering in order to give the community time to vote.  The analogous changes have not (yet) been made to [Nodes To Consider].
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;kudra, 2002-04-28&lt;br&gt;
I also use the delete, but only when I think the node should be deleted,
which leaves out quite a few that are considered for deletion.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
On the topic of changes, I like that I can now see that a node was
considered when I view it (and I hope others can see that too, to reduce
replies to considered duplicates).  Other changes I hope will be considered
include &lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;supplying a 'done' checkbox in the same page as the edit, so that
a node can be removed from nre and edited in a single step;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;have nre
display 'keep' votes as well as edit votes to make it easier to see
if people prefer an editing change to take place or disagree with it; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;give editors a way to remove nodes from ntc even without the 2 edit
votes needed to get them on nre (for example, nodes submitted for deletion
which have too many keep votes).
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Corion], 2002-04-27&lt;br&gt;
I'm also a regular delete button user - duplicates and other "clear" (empty, "delete me") nodes get a click from me wherever I see them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[dvergin], 2002-04-26
&lt;br&gt;Count me as another delete button user. If it's a judgement call, I just post to ntc. If it seems clear, I click the button and if I'm only the first or second, I also post to ntc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[boo_radley], 2002-04-26&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, too, use the delete button. Nicer than letting the reaper run amok sometimes.&lt;br/&gt;
I also suggested a change to [ar0n] regarding putting a set of NTC radio buttons alongside the voting radio buttons in order to encourage participation in the administrative portion of consideration. See my homenode for an example.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[dws], 2002-04-26&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suspect that the edit votes get cleaned out a lot quicker, leaving the nodes that delete votes but some keep or edit. I use the "Delete" button a few times a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Ovid], 2002-04-26&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do we still need the "Delete" button on nodes?  As far as I can tell, no one is using it and [nodes to consider] is being used exclusively for delete votes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;P&gt;[Footpad], ~Thu Apr 25 04:32:38 2002 (GMT)&lt;BR /&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Three things:&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;OL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Out of respect for the main people involved, I've limited my remarks on the HTML entity issue to suggestions that those who choose to use them use the numeric entities instead of the character entities, primarily for cross browser support.  Some of you may not care about NS4.x, however, certain titles in [Newest nodes|NN] start with the phrase &amp;bull in that browser.  (Personally, I'm not certain that's necessarily the first phrase I'd like to be associated with my remarks.) IME, numeric entities enjoy broader cross-browser support than character ones; in this case &lt;code&gt;&amp;#8226;&lt;/code&gt; may be more effective.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;

&lt;P&gt;(And, yes, there's a reason why I sign my nodes with &lt;code&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;--f&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/code&gt; rather than &lt;code&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;&amp;#402;&amp;#8212;&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/code&gt;.  I'd rather make my sig accessible to as many as possible rather than coerce people into submitting to my design choices.  Again, YMMV.)&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;I agree with [dws].  It's all well and good to incorporate more CSS into the site.  That will, after all, make use more W3C compliant.  However, please take time to at least preview the results in browsers are are known for not supporting CSS well and code accordingly.  (The latest changes aren't, um, attractive without CSS support.)&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;If you don't wish to cross test, then please: either enlist people you know are using those browsers and elicit their feedback &lt;I&gt;OR&lt;/I&gt; stop mucking about.  A cardinal rule of effective development is "if you can't take the time to test properly, you don't have time to code it properly."&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Along the same vein, I'm peridocally getting DNS errors from pm.org, using IE (recent) and NS (not so).  I don't know why, but it's only started in the last little while.  Those of you making checkins may wish to review your edits for corner cases.  I'll add more if I figure it out, however, I've not seen this before so it may take a bit for me to isolate by myself.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;

&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Would whoever did whatever to the &lt;code&gt;isbn://&lt;/code&gt; tag *please* weigh in on the subject?  If it's working, then please post a node in [id://161385|this thread]?  I didn't do anything and I'm not comfortable with people giving me credit for things I didn't do.  &lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;I realize we're a team and all, but...I don't like taking credit that I don't deserve.  (True, I may not get any after that, however....)&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;(And while we're on the subject, I note that the new version doesn't seem to have an affiliate ID.  This was the sort of implementation I didn't want to see, since it means that YAS, [vroom|TFL], or whoever won't be getting that small kickback.  Do we need a new ID or what?)&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;

&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;We need another archive of this wiki for those of us unfortunates who still refuse to use 30MB browsers.  TIA...&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;

&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;As far as editing style, I've almost always a) Placed a &amp;lt;small&amp;gt; comment reporting the update, b) Used &amp;!-- foo --&amp;gt; to gently describe the change, c) /msg'd the poster to let them know, and d) immediately returned to [nodes requiring editing|nre] to clear the node.  AFAIKT, some folks are still editing without the follow up.  I may be wrong though.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;

&lt;P&gt;OK. 6 things. I lied.  Sorry.  I'm in a snit.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;HR /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[kudra] 2002-04-04&lt;br /&gt;
Just an example of some changes which I think are needed but which
might not be obvious from just looking at the page:  adding a readmore,
and replacing tt/br with code.  Of course not all changes require that,
but most (except title changes) require at least going to the node in
question.  That's not a problem if the server's okay, but it's still
pointless effort for the second editor.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2002-03-28&lt;br /&gt;
I have no problem with the details of the update being in HTML comments (if that is your preference).  But you should append a visible notice that the node was editted (to avoid confusion, perhaps even arguments).  I prefer to include "&lt;code&gt;[tye]&lt;/code&gt;" in this information so that if there is an issue with the edit, they know who to blame/contact/etc.  This can be alleviated by getting a "view editors' change log" feature working.  I also usually submit the "I changed..." /msg for non-AnonyMonk nodes (if you submit it for AnonyMonk nodes, then ppl using some chatter clients w/o logging in will see the /msg -- until we fix that bug).  This is also why I usually include a visible description sumarizing what or why I changed: I don't want to enter the information twice and don't want a reply of "What did you change?".
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As for details from those who submit the node for consideration, see [What is Consideration?] for more on this.  In particular "title of 'help' should be changed" is a pretty bad example in my book.  "Change title to 'specific title suggestion goes here'" is what I want to see.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[turnstep] Mar 27 2002&lt;br /&gt;
To play devil's advocate against kudra's comment below: shouldn't viewing 
the source be unnecessary as the change should be obvious by looking at 
the node itself? If the change is not obvious, then perhaps it did not need 
editing in the first place! :) Ideally, the nominators should give as much 
detail as possible e.g. "title of 'help' should be changed" or "needs 
code tags in first paragraph." I like the unobtrusiveness of a simple HTML 
comment myself. Perhaps the engine could automatically add a small 
"this node has been edited" note somewhere? Or perhaps just putting a 
&lt;code&gt;&lt;small&gt;Edited&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/code&gt; at the bottom and put the details 
(who, what, when) inside a comment?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[merlyn] Mar 21 2002&lt;br /&gt;
I've been just adding an HTML comment.. should we always make it visible instead?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[chromatic] Sun Mar  3 21:03:46 UTC 2002&lt;br /&gt;
I don't follow the reasoning behind reaping [id://148987|this node].  How is asking if there's a Perl module for doing something &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; about Perl?  Granted, it's an XYZ question, but I think several someones jumped the gun here.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[kudra] 2002-03-01&lt;br&gt;
Not to mention that if the node isn't also removed from nre (not enough
edit votes yet, for instance), the next editor needs to view the source
to see if the changes were made (sometimes) instead of just noting it was
already done.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2002-02-28&lt;br&gt;
I'd like to encourage everyone to note when they edit a node with the "standard" &lt;code&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Edit by [tye] (optional reason)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/code&gt; at the bottom of the node.  The exact format is very much not important (I like the way &lt;code&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;/code&gt; helps the line not "stand out").  But the presense of the line is very important.  I've noticed several nodes recently that got an edit without a tag being added.  This can lead to confusion and even arguments where someone complains or comments on the appearance of the node and later readers wonder what the heck they are talking about.  It also leads to people feeling like secret things are happening behind their back.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thank you for your attention. (:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Ovid] 2002-02-28&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, I think I've got it, now.  Removing the special characters is a waste of energy.  Some like the characters, so they'll be unhappy.  You &lt;strong&gt;can't&lt;/strong&gt; please everyone.  No matter which way we turn, someone will scream "your other left, dummy!"  So, I won't remove those characters -- it's a non-issue, I think.  However, if we can improve the searches to return the author along with the node title, I won't even be including &lt;tt&gt;(Ovid)&lt;/tt&gt; in my titles as that will obviate the need for it, as was mentioned below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's my story and I'm sticking to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2002-02-28&lt;br&gt;
I weigh in [id://148337|here].
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[dvergin] 2002-02-28&lt;br&gt;
This seems like an idea that starts out looking helpful but doesn't scale well. I don't see a way to make this work for more than a limited number of folk. Lose 'em. (The markers, not the folk.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree with [kudra]'s specific statement and the general drift of others that this indicates a need for one or more enhancements in the way titles are displayed. Like [kudra] I would appreciate seeing authors with search results. But I am not sure that would resolve all the issues that have given rise to this practice.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[kudra] 2002-02-28&lt;br&gt;
I don't really care for the entities, which remind me of about 50% of
the spam I get, but I'll just continue ignoring them if they stay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As I think I've said before, (kudra) isn't about vanity, it's about identifying
the author from a search.  I'd rather that information be provided
(optionally?) from the search.  If it were, I would stop putting my name
on my posts and would probably even go over my old posts to remove it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If that inspires anyone to start mucking around in the code, please
add some threading support as well &lt;tt&gt;:)&lt;/tt&gt;.  
Then titles could be changed when the subject changes without loosing
context (or requiring that the old title be attached somehow).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[chipmunk] 2002-02-28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I say ban them.  They're distracting and platform dependent.  (I don't care so much about labelling a node with one's username, although I don't see much point in it myself.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
P.S.  Please remember to add new entries at the very top of the wiki, so that they'll be in the right order.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[chromatic] Thu Feb 28 00:32:39 UTC 2002&lt;br /&gt;
I'm opposed to removing them before sufficient discussion.  They're annoying, but they don't seem to be dangerous.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[merlyn] 2002-02-27&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm fine with uniformly banning anything like it.  I disliked (Ovid) and (Tye), and when I discovered
that I could do something as obnoxious as &amp;bull;, I started doing it just so that we'd have this discussion
and conclude that &lt;b&gt;all&lt;/b&gt; such "non-re" prefixes should be banned.
&lt;p&gt;So, let's ban any vanity labeling of threads, and make it publicly known and supported by the monks-who-are-in-charge.

&lt;p&gt;[Ovid] 2002-02-27&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can't say that I'm wild about them as identifiers.  They're kind of a limited commodity and if everyone starts following [merlyn|merlyn's] lead, I can just see a title like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;#128; &amp;#135; &amp;#149; &amp;sect; &amp;ordm; re: are globals a bad thing?&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see it stifling comprehension.  On the other hand, so what?  Does it really matter who posts a node or who's in the thread?  It &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; add character, but some could object to trying to memorize all of those symbols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we decide to keep 'em, I might just call dibs on &amp;oslash;. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incidentally, the first character in my "title" above is the Euro symbol.  Many should be aware that different browsers will display that differently.  Some versions of Netscape, IIRC, display it as a dot.  It could be misread as [merlyn].  Hmmm...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[dws] Wed Feb 27 2002&lt;/p&gt;
Editors: I invite you to let me know whether I'm out of line in unilateraly editing out the typographic dingbats that some Anonymous poster(s) have starting using in node titles. (There's a public discussion [id://148090|here].)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2002-02-27&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Please&lt;/b&gt;, keep conversations in the wiki and not via "/msg editors" (as previously requested).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The "reparent" tool is very unlikely to be available in the next couple of days, so moving the majority of those requests out of NTC makes perfect sense to me.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thanks, [kudra].
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[kudra] Wed Feb 27 10:08:39 GMT+1 2002&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Update 19/4: added the new crop&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I suggested making a list of nodes which require reparenting and removing
them from nre, to make it easier to pick out things we can edit from nre.
Here is a list of the nodes where a specific parent is named, cut directly
out of nre (I'll wait a while before marking these as resolved to see
if there are any objections).

(moved to [nodes to reparent] by [ar0n])

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[chromatic] Thu Jan 17 03:52:40 UTC 2002&lt;br /&gt;
That makes sense, but would it require a finer-grained consideration system than we have in place now?  We have a system where one consideration can be active on a node at a time.  Even when that's purged, the votes aren't regenerated.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I'm getting the impression I'll have to write an event queueing system for Everything to satisfy my desire to write finer-grained tools.  Anyone want to pay me to get pre1 to release status?  (Hey, I got Regexp::English out the door.  ;)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2002-01-15&lt;br&gt;
I'm for changing consideration so that, when a node has been considered, the reason for consideration shows up in the "approval" nodelet &lt;b&gt;even if you don't have that nodelet turned on and even if you aren't level 6 yet&lt;/b&gt;.  In addition, if you have the nodelet turned on (and are level 6), you still get the "consider" form elements so you can consider it again with a different/better/opposing explanation, which will show up in the "approval" nodelet for all to see and will show on [nodes to consider].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Perhaps to make "rude" remarks easy to hide quickly, only the most recent reason would show in the "approval" nodelet.  And [nodes requiring editing] still provides the final purge for those.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[kudra] 2002-01-10&lt;br&gt;
Ooh, I want the power of bop!  
Seriously, I would like an official way of informing a consideree when
the consideration is inadequate.  I can message them, but as I'm just
a random person that has little effect.  
&lt;!-- Save me from having to write a nagging discussion post on the topic! --&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[chromatic] 2002-01-07&lt;br /&gt;
Meta-consideration?  An editor-specific widget next to each considered node that resets the count, bops the consideree on the noggin, and says, "This is a malformed consideration, try harder?"  I like that in some ways and hate it in others.  Maybe it's the feedback to the consideree that's appealing.  Maybe there could be an automatic note to the consideree when the consideration is finally handled.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[kudra] 2002-01-04&lt;br&gt;
Is there anything that can be done with considered nodes?  Looking at the
current crop, I see 5 out of 5 nodes considered for deletion on the grounds
of duplicate don't refer to any other node.  This means that each person
has to search for her/himself to find the duplicate, ignore the post, or
make a blind vote.  I have tried msging people, but it's becoming too large
a task and it also feels a lot like nagging.  I think part of the problem
is that people who just get the power to submit nodes aren't really aware
that they really ought to provide more information.
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[kudra] 2002-01-04&lt;br&gt;
I'd go one step further and say there's no need to even msg about new
wiki content.  If this is used for a lot of discussions, checking it
will become another common stop, like ntc and nre.  The only uses I
see for msging editors are vroom-wide announcements and problems which
need to be dealt with at the time (and in the second case, msging only
editors currently online would be better).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Masem] 2002-01-02&lt;br&gt;
*ahem* Me too.  I came back from lack-of-significant-net-access for 5 days to find a huge stack of editors messages in the CB, and as the CB only displays the first 10 or so non-archived private messages, I had to clear those out to see several messages directed towards me.  Initiated the thread in msg is necessary to alert editors, but further discussion should be moved here.
&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[jcwren] 2002-01-02&lt;br&gt;
I agree with [tye].  Especially since I've managed to lose track of which thread it is that [chromatic] is talking about.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
On another note, don't forget to update the [Nodes Requiring Editing] list, where applicable.  I've seen a lot of things taken care of by editors, but still outstanding on the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2002-01-02&lt;br&gt;
I'd prefer much more use of [editors' wiki] and much less "/msg editors".  I don't mind a "/msg editors" in order to start a discussion, but I'd really, really prefer that any follow-up go here.  I'd like to encourage [editors] to update this and then simply "/msg editors [editors' wiki|wiki update]" in order to encourage ensuing comments/discussion to end up here.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[dvergin] Tuesday 2001-12-06&lt;br&gt;
Thanks to [vroom] for making [Editor Requests] editable. Posting a status line
in each request as it is resolved
makes it easier to keep track of what's been done. 
But diving for still-pending requests farther and farther down the list
quickly becomes cumbersome.
&lt;p&gt;
Next step would be to 
enable consideration or unilateral deleting of these items (consideration 
would probably be 'safer'). 
Ultimately [Editor Requests] should probably have a form-based tool like the one for [nodes requiring editing]. (Or just integrate the two lists.)

&lt;p&gt;[vroom]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;made editor requests, editor editable&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jcwren] Wednesday 2001-12-05 06:34 GMT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If 'nodes' is deliberate, it's a good one.  If it was a typo, it's even better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[dvergin] Tuesday 2001-12-04&lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;...the new-comer nodes respectfully to the assembly and takes courage to venture an observation and a suggestion:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greetings, all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've checked the editor docs and with several editors and it appears that there is not a mechanism for marking items in [Editor Requests] as resolved. [tye] (we can call him Tye) explains that this tool pre-dates the editor clan and was designed for use by vroom. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we regard these individual requests as transient (no longer needed once acted upon) in the same way that entries in [nodes requiring editing] are, &lt;strike&gt;it would appear that we might retire items in [Editor Requests] by simply deleting the individual request node&lt;/strike&gt;. This handles the matter without requiring further coding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would be glad for any clarification, support, correction, or a pointer to the relevant info.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Update:&lt;/b&gt; Attempting to edit one of the [Editor Requests] (to mark it done) brings up "&lt;i&gt;Not an editor editable type&lt;/i&gt;". So the delete option appears to be out for now. Same for editing them to mark them done. Ditto for reparenting them by hand to a new "Completed Editor Requests" node.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;HR /&gt;

&lt;P&gt;[footpad], ~Tue Nov 27 05:37:48 2001 (GMT)&lt;BR /&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Re: [kudra]'s thoughts on self-immolation: I agree with her.  You posted it, you suffer the consequences.  We've previously argued to keep the archives extant; I say, "Let's continue to do so. If Perl can be a bit messy, so can we."&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;And now for the segue.  I'll be the first to admit that I'm the closest we seem to have to &lt;a href="http://www.xfiles.com/infobase/bios/characters/index.html"&gt;Spooky&lt;/a&gt;.  I'm the suspicious one.  Paranoid.  (My server's been hacked; I have a reason.)&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;B&gt;Update&lt;/B&gt;:  &lt;strike&gt;That said, is this a *reasonable* node?&lt;/strike&gt;  Never mind, someone else brought it up and it was promptly removed, which confirms my earlier suspicion.  &lt;strike&gt;H&lt;/strike&gt;Cracking tools aren't welcome.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;HR /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2001-10-21&lt;br&gt;
I left [id://119980] as I felt it seemed a reasonable Q+A (short and likely to be asked again).  BTW, any single member of [QandAEditors] can delete any Q or A w/o any other involvement.  For cases like this, if it isn't a good Q+A question, then it should be SoPWified.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Yes, lots of editting in Q+A would be a good thing.  I'm not sure what structural changes you are considering.  I don't see how spotty editting would be worse than no editting.  I think [QandAEditors] can even move questions between sections and make new sections, etc., though I haven't tried recently so I'm not completely sure.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 [Petruchio] Sat Oct 20 01:59:12 UTC 2001:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I got a request from [crazyinsomniac] to delete [119980], as being 
 inappropriate for Q&amp;A.  Q&amp;A nodes cannot, of course, be considered, 
 nor can a lone editor delete a node, so I told him I'd bring it to
 the attention of the editors generally.  In any case, I'm uncertain
 as to what qualifies as a good Q for the section.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 A /msg would have been enough for that, but I'm left with other
 questions about our vision for Q&amp;A.  Pardon me if I've missed a 
 relevant discussion of the topic; I sometimes fall behind the times.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I think the Q&amp;A section is potentially one of our most valuable, 
 but that it's presently not all it could be.  It's developed ad
 hoc, and it remains mostly as it's created.  Do we wish to keep
 things this way?  It could benefit a great deal by aggressive 
 editing, which seems far more appropriate there than elsewhere.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 On the other hand, cleaning things up would be a good deal of work, 
 and we've got plenty already.  And to do so effectively might
 turn out to require structural changes, which are always a compromise,
 as they place a burden on the higher powers.  And uneven editing
 could be as bad or worse than none; a model or standard ought probably
 be adopted, and creating one is yet more work.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 What think ye?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[kudra] 2001-10-17&lt;br&gt;
Today I was cleaning out nre and I have one request and one question.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The request is that people mark nodes as 'resolved' in nre after editing
them.  I know that nodes are often edited before they have enough edit
votes to appear in nre, but the number of already edited nodes lingering
in nre makes me think that people are also forgetting.  (If anyone who
edits the code has some time, it might be nice to have a 'resolved' button
already checked at the bottom of the edit page, so nodes can be resolved
with editing.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The question is whether it is appropriate use of nre to use this to
delete your own nodes.  Nitsuj (and I think someone else earlier this
week) has considered a few nodes which I don't think were originally
accidental postings (although I can't tell, since the original content
has been changed to 'Delete me! Already in the negatives').  If these
are just nodes the author no longer likes because they went negative,
my inclination is to let them stay...but with their changed contents
they are of no use to the site whatsoever.  
Is it our job to help people clean up history a little
more throughly, or do we leave these contentless nodes as markers of
the author's cleaning? (The nodes, btw, were 35547, 100711 and 96625).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
[Masem] 2001-10-03&lt;BR&gt;
[kudra]* discovered that [id://116400|this node] was causing major formatting problems on the SoPW page; namely (before I edited it), it was cutting out text from right before where the words 'username password' were href'ed, down to 3 posts later at the start of a code block in [id://116371].  The display of the node by itself showed no problems.  Initially, the "username password" phrase was manually a href'ed, but even moving it into the bracketed form caused the same problem.  When I moved the a href off those words and into a new word (in this case, the 'here' that follows in the present version), everything was fixed.
&lt;P&gt;
I would guess that there's something about 'username' or 'password' that is causing a problem on the node display system; exactly what, I'm not sure.  A possible bug in the E code?
&lt;P&gt;
* [kudra]'s addition, 2001-10-04:  
I can't take credit for finding it.  The author of the post that contained the username/password contacted me about it and asked if s/he'd
broken anything.  My 'edit' message on the 3rd post down was the next bit
of text on the page, so it probably looked like I had something to do with
it.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
[Masem] 2001-09-19&lt;/BR&gt;
While an automatic system would be nice, it would still not catch what happened today , where the user was doing slight edits between submissions.  You could catch on title only, but again, that might cause problems if people are trying to include 'special' characters that have given node title problems before.  Again, I doubt that the user today was doing this malciously, but this situation could easily happen again by a newer user.
&lt;p&gt;
[kudra] 2001-09-19&lt;br&gt;
For non-malicious users, I'd rather see a system which doesn't involve
editor intervention.  An example of this might be to check each new post
against any posts by anon monk and the user made in the last five minutes,
and to not make the new post if the previous one exists.  Still, I would like to
see a reduction in duplicate posts however it is done.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
To deal with a malicious person, I don't think this is adequate.  The
person could easily create a program that would log new users and use
them to post random garbage (so that each post would differ in content
and user).  To block this sort of thing something like a 'no new accounts'
mode or a 'no posting' mode (where either all posting or all posts by anon
and users &amp;lt;1 month in age would be unable to post) which could be turned
on as needed.  However, if we get to the point of needing such tools much
of the fun may have already vanished.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt;[Masem] 2001-09-19, ~8:30 CDT
&lt;P&gt;
A good number of us editors just got finishing up cleaning a mess that a user ([Juo], in this case), made when they tried to repost their question several times, trying to obviously post-edit the formating after submission.  That user ended up posting about 18 copies of the same question within 10 minutes.  I doubt that it was meant to be malicious, but it did have us editors running ragged.
&lt;P&gt;
I've got a suggestion that might help in the future; Only a power for editors and possibly Level 10's, however.  Upon visiting a user's node page, the "consideration nodelet" would be available and have a form for "Block this user" with a reason.  Just like Nodes to Consider, this would be recorded somewhere with the person that initiated the block.  When blocked, the target user can not post for some time (4 hrs seems reasonable), at which point the block is automatically removed.  The user should also be told he is blocked for the message given by the upper-level person.  If the user has to be blocked again, the block should be in place until it is removed manually by Vroom or some other upper level monk.  Possibly a third block means loss of the PM account, but this is debatable if we need to go this far.
&lt;P&gt;
Obviously, there's potental for abuse here, which is why the power must be limited.  In addition, the person that places the block must be accountable for why the block was in place, and any abuse can be dealt with on a case-by-case basis. (I don't expect that to happen, but we have that outlet to justify it).
It should only be used in a case like today, when a user is posting too many duplicates of the same question, as I can easily see that being extended to someone maliciously doing a DOS attack on PM.  It should NOT be used to stop someone putting their foot in their mouth such as in the sierrathedog04 "Surprised by Reality" thread, at least, IMO.
&lt;P&gt;
It's probably not critical, but it should be a strong consideration on the to-do list.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 [Petruchio] Mon Sep 17 01:35:08 UTC 2001
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I see.  My misapprehension.  I sometimes get confused on the nature of 
 'recent' features... the approval system, for instance, having been 
 created only after I was already of reasonably high level.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2001-09-10&lt;br&gt;
[Petruchio], I don't know what you are referring to about "relegated to monks who have reached level 6".  Any monk can see [Newest Nodes], all but AnonyMonk can check "Show Unmoderated Content" in [User Settings] so, to me, leaving a node unapproved forever just means that it was not appropriate for that (nor any) section.  It would only "hide" it from the most casual of observers, the type of people who wouldn't get this joke anyway.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
That said, I'm not unapproving it.  I'll err on the side of laziness. (:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 [Petruchio] Sat Sep  8 23:30:37 UTC 2001
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 For nearly 24 hours, [111091|Anti. Paco.] has remained unapproved in 
 [Perl Monks Discussion].  Its rep is, as I write, -14.  I'm told 
 that in ntc, the vote is split 8/8 between keeping and deleting.
 No editors have tried to delete it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 At first I avoided the situation, because I have mixed feelings. 
 It's obviously meant in humor; one need only be familiar with

 [paco]'s lone post, its outrageous reputation, and [Ovid]'s
 humorous reply to get the joke.  On the other hand, it's a 
 joke with a trollish voice.  It's not the sort of thing I'd like
 to see more of on the site.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 But since no decisive action has been taken, I am now Ok-ing the 
 post.  Given a division of sentiment, I see no reason to err on 
 the side of censorship; nor do I see good reason that this post 
 should be relegated to monks who have reached level 6.  It does 
 not seem good to me that the Unapproved bin should hold noded 
 indefinitely.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I mention this because it's no doubt a controversial action, and
 one I'd prefer to make public.  I'd also like to draw attention
 to the post.  If you feel you need to take some action, do so.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[Masem], 2001-08-30&lt;br&gt;
I think kudra's right in that our ability to handle the editing duties on the site is limited more by node moving than our numbers.  I remember when I and the other more recent editors were added was when ntc was around 130-150 nodes, as opposed to the 40 or 50 we've been floating around now.  Shortly after that, the nodes dropped down to 20ish.  So we're still out there, but just with hands tied.
&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[kudra], 2001-08-30&lt;br&gt;
Searching for delete duplicate seems to turn up a lot of reaped nodes.
These aren't listed in nre, which is the only place I typically look
for stuff requiring editors.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Looking at the nre list, almost everything I see is a reparent request.
Those that aren't could easily be getting lost in the pile.  Couldn't we
perhaps make a list of things that can't be done soon and stick it
somewhere else, just to clear out nre to manageable proportions?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2001-08-29&lt;br&gt;
I'm ready to recruit more [editors].  Or do we all just need a good kick in the butt? ;)  If anyone feels like exercising their power, [delete duplicate] finds lots of things.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[Petruchio], I'm aware of few practical differences.  Nodes posted to [Tutorials] are flagged as being of node type "Tutorial", which means they could be displayed differently, etc.  So the original author probably loses the ability to update tutorials that are really tutorials but can still edit other types of nodes that end up being referenced from [Tutorials].  I'm somewhat for having tutorials be tutorials, for no really good reasons.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I've asked [pmdev] to fix our node mover in hopes that we'll be able to clean up the biggest cause for remaining [Nodes to consider] sooner rather than later.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 [Petruchio] Sun Aug 26 13:37:26 UTC 2001:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 What, exactly, is the practical difference between having a node in 
 [tutorials], and a link in [tutorials]?  Each may be voted upon, commented 
 upon, edited by the author, and so on.  The only important distinction I 
 see is a practical matter... a node originally posted to [Meditations] is 
 more likely to receive a higher rep.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 That's a good thing.  Not only does it bring worthy nodes the attention they 
 deserve, it provides a sort of popular mandate before something winds up in 
 [tutorials].
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 Am I missing some important factor here?  This seems to me less an awkward
 case than the ideal case.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Ovid] 2001-08-16&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At [tye|tye's] suggestion, I have edited tutorials and added a link to the node.  However, rather than copy the node to tutorials, I left the link where it

&lt;!-- Edited by turnstep (added content to top) *grin* --&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
Earlier content moved to [id://96695]</field>
</data>
</node>
