<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="178924" title="pmdev wiki through 2002-06-28" created="2001-08-22 02:44:52" updated="2005-08-02 09:35:54">
<type id="68046">
wiki</type>
<author id="979">
vroom</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
Continued from [id://218593]...
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-06-28&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, I certainly have plans for the "wiki" links showing whether the wiki has been updated since you last "viewed"; it will &lt;code&gt;&lt;blink&gt;&lt;/code&gt; if there is new content ;).  I like the idea of making wiki updates easier.  A chatterbox "/wiki pmdev ..." would be cool for very short updates.  And a user-set "signature" that gets prepended when you "edit" would be cool except it needs to fill in the current date.  &lt;b&gt;I'd&lt;/b&gt; probably just hard-code prepending of &lt;code&gt;"&lt;p&gt;[$USER-&gt;{title}], ".getYYYY_MM_DD()."&lt;br /&gt;\n&lt;/p&gt;\n"&lt;/code&gt; except that it squelches innovation.  So we'd probably need a "wiki sig" and some template that gets replaced by the date.  I'm prone to force YYYY-MM-DD format on people but my conscience gets the better of me so [strftime] would probably be used.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Of course, these would only prepend information at the top of the wiki (nothing else is practical, IMO).  So I guess we have to call for "votes" on whether updates should be restricted to the tops or "scattered" (perhaps in archives, even??).  I much prefer the "scan down until you recognize what was on top last time you read and then read the items going up" algorithm.  I think I'd probably just mostly give up on reading the wiki if I had to scan the whole think looking for new stuff every time.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When we did the first wiki we voted on whether to append to the bottom or prepend to the top.  I recall the "new stuff on top" having a clear "margin of victory".
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
BTW, (in case anyone is wondering) the way permissions on Everything work, to have nodes w/ replies that can only be seen by one group would require the creation of a section, a node type, and a new &lt;b&gt;note&lt;/b&gt; type (which we've never done) for &lt;i&gt;each&lt;/i&gt; group.  This would require reworking much of the display code so it could handle multiple "note" types.  So that large chunk of work was not done.  And I'm not in favor of that anyway.  I think if we have such a large discussion that threaded nodes are really required, then it is probably something that the community should be allowed to take part in as well.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[chromatic] 2002-06-27&lt;br /&gt;
Wishlist:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;automatic formatting of wiki updates (why not add username and timestamp automagically?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Your Wikis nodelet that lists the last updated times of Wikis (saves having to message the appropriate group)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VSarkiss] 2002-06-26&lt;br /&gt;
Oh, now there's a great idea.  How about a structure where you can reply to individual comments starting from a root comment, and we indent each level a bit, and ....  Oh, wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Not sure if this is necessary, but ;-)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For what it's worth, the "add at the top" paradigm has never really worked for me.  It reads upside-down.  I think I'd rather scan for updates as long as the sprites keep archiving the old stuff off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-06-25&lt;br /&gt;
I'd rather have updates applied in chronological order rather than try to keep some kind of threaded structure to the wiki.  Dissenting opinions welcome but I know I'm likely to not notice updates that happen "down the page" and I don't have a problem understanding updates that interleave on multiple subjects.&lt;br&gt;
FWIW [demerphq] agrees&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Chady] 2002-06-21&lt;br /&gt;
All I saw was the source code of index.pl, I don't know if anyone was able to get through and if any internal code was shown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[demerphq] 2002/06/21 12:45&lt;br /&gt;
For around an hour or so today (Aprox 11am GMT +1 to 12:30 Am GMT +1) Perlmonks was only displaying 
source code.  I dont know if this may have revealed potential security vulnerabilities or not, but I think a [god] should review what happened with the aim to ensure that it does not occur again.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  [ar0n], 2002-06-25
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Even though [tye] already knows this, just for keeping 
  records: It was me.  I applied [belg4mit]'s patches, which
  broke the code a bit, so I rewrote it, then forgot about 
  it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-06-20&lt;br /&gt;
One of the [gods] modified [talkbar] and broke it without leaving any traces.  Please, [gods], if you change a node, either produce a patch or update [pm-port wiki]!  I've fixed it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Bug Report&lt;/strong&gt; 2002/06/20 14:34&lt;br&gt;
08:21: [giant]: Does anyone know who maintains &lt;A HREF="http://www.perlmonks.org/index.pl?node_id=3184&amp;displaytype=raw"&gt;web CB client&lt;/A&gt;? it doesn't work since yesterday any more when clickling talk :(&lt;br&gt;
[demerphq]
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 [crazyinsomniac] Wed Jun 26 02:15:44 2002&lt;br /&gt;
It's a question ( a poor attempt at an inflamatory mark designed to invoke some kind of response ).  All I got was "use the wiki son".  But hey, [vroom] has added the status nodelet, so it doesn't matter now.  I'd be fine with expunging said words from the wiki.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  [ar0n], 2002-06-25
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;i&gt;is it that you're all really &lt;b&gt;JavaScript&lt;/b&gt; programmers so the perl's too advanced for you?)&lt;/i&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  Is that an insult, or a joke?
&lt;/p&gt;
[crazyinsomniac] Tue Jun 25 06:52:14 2002 GMT&lt;br /&gt;
So what's up? Youse guys say use the wiki, still no kind of response, comments, criticisms, anything? Hello? (yeah, i'm a little impatient, but I don't really see what the hold up is.  when other stuff crops up you're quick with the replies, is it that you're all really &lt;b&gt;JavaScript&lt;/b&gt; programmers so the perl's too advanced for you?)
&lt;p&gt;
[crazyinsomniac] Sun Jun 23 06:08:13 2002 GMT&lt;br /&gt;
I &lt;strike&gt;am writing&lt;/strike&gt;wrote a mini approval nodelet to do this (which takes item 8 on tye's list).  You can see it at [pad://crazyinsomniac].
&lt;p&gt;[Chady] 2002-06-21&lt;br /&gt;
my suggestion wasn't &lt;code&gt;not to reply&lt;/code&gt; but a &lt;code&gt;note not to reply&lt;/code&gt; as in a note that suggests that the node is considered, and one can choose whether to reply or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[crazyinsomniac] Thu Jun 20 06:26:45 2002 GMT &lt;br /&gt;
I didn't think I was unclear, but since clarification is needed, here goes:
Currently, only users with the consideration nodelet can see whether a node is considered or not, and only if they have the consideration nodelet turned on.
What I was asking is, should a monk without access to the consideration nodelet, less than  level6, know if a node is considered (so they don't reply ~ so they choose not to reply)?
&lt;Br /&gt;
(simple yes or no)
Like if I see two duplicates, and i'm not level five, I wanna know which one to reply to.
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-06-19&lt;br /&gt;
See my item (8) below for what I think should be shown and how.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[grinder] 2002-06-19 08:07 UTC&lt;br /&gt;
in response to [crazyinsomniac] question as to whether unconsidered nodes should be tagged,
I say yes. As to Chady's remark suggesting one not reply, I say no. That's not the point. (Unless one assumes that all NtC is good for is for reaping nodes).
All that is needed is a red bullet (or something iconical) along side the title. People are
free to reply regardless of whether the node is considered or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now I'm confused because I can no longer recall whether ci was initially talking
about consideration or approval and I have deleted his /msg. For everyone's sake, PLEASE
STOP USING /msg TO PMDEV. Use the wiki.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;a name="TYE-TO-DO"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-06-18&lt;br /&gt;
Did you read [id://174416]?  I just posted that I don't think the [Other Users] changes will be made.  I came to this decision yesterday.  I'm not hiding some master plan. (:  If you are &lt;em&gt;worried&lt;/em&gt; about making some major change that won't be used, then get some feedback before you start, &lt;em&gt;of course&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Here are some things that need changing:
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;You can approve your own nodes via each section's main page.  It appears that my patch to disable this in the [approve] opcode got lost so I'll find that &lt;b&gt;(&lt;/b&gt;found and applied now&lt;b&gt;)&lt;/b&gt; but it'd be great if someone would add 'disable="disable"' to those checkboxes.  &lt;b&gt;Update&lt;/b&gt;: You can also approved reaped nodes this way.  Only [editors] should be allowed to approve reaped nodes but the [approve] opcode doesn't enforce that.  Perhaps a 'canapprove' htmlcode is in order.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The [editors nodelet] should not allow a node to be moved if it is approved for its section.  Editors should unapprove it for its section (and/or the frontpage, tho this is probably not required) and then move it (and reapprove it, if desired).  We should test that leaving a node approved for the front page then moving it causes it to move to a different section on the front page (this takes a few minutes as the frontpage is cached).
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The [message] opcode should allow delete/archive/unarchive of messages that are to a group that you belong to (or any message if isGod($USER)).
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;We'll need a way to edit messages in [message inbox] (such as an "edit" link for each message and/or a global "edit" checkbox that displays all archived messages in text boxes so you can edit several at once).  To reduce (but no eliminate) race conditions, the actual update should check that the current text is the same as the starting text and refuse to update otherwise (probably with "update ... where message_id=? and msgtext=?" so SQL can perhaps completely remove the race condition).
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;[Message inbox] should optionally show date/time of each message.  I usually do this type of thing by first adding the option (check boxes: "[ ] Show date [ ] Show time") to [message inbox], then allowing something in $VARS to set the default, then updating [user settings] to allow setting the default.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;We should cache the chatterbox more effectively.  I'd like the [message] opcode to call another htmlcode that inserts the record (I think it already does this; &lt;b&gt;update&lt;/b&gt;: no, but moving this functionality from [message] opcode to [repeatedchatter] is nearly trivial) and have that (if not a /msg) also pre-HTMLize the record and add it to [cachedinfo] with code_id=[chatterbox], cachekey='HTML'.$message_id, and lastupdate=message.tstamp and have the code that [chatterbox] calls just read and concat these cached HTML records instead of rebuilding the HTML each page display.  Similarly, add 'XML'.$message_id records and have the [chatterbox xml ticker] just read and concat those.  A periodic process (such as [other users] nodelet) could delete old cached chatter.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Once we have well-cached HTMLized chatter, we can host a [cblast35]-type node that has a more PM-like UI.  I'd like to show only the minutes:seconds of the message timestamp (with a final "MM:SS of silence" note) and not put the message text into text areas.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you don't have the [approval nodelet], then it should automatically appear among the nodelets in it's "small" form which will have a title of "Node Status" and will show whether the node is considered, and who approved/frontpaged it.  If it would be empty, then not even it's title will display.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;More likely to come...
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VSarkiss] Tue Jun 18&lt;br /&gt;
[crazyinsomniac] /msg'ed me that my note below was unclear (I said I was confused ;-).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, [theorbtwo]'s patch goes against [Other Users], but there's another nodelet [New Other Users] that has the functionality the patch adds, and other goodies besides.  I was wondering if there's a plan to deploy one or the other.  [tye] says it's unlikely either will be.  I guess the question in the large is, "Do [pmdev|we] know what the [gods] are planning, so people don't patch obsolete or obsolescent code?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-06-18&lt;br/&gt;
No, dropping "node_id=user_id" would result in a huge "cross product" query that would spew millions of "matches", combinations of &lt;b&gt;unrelated&lt;/b&gt; records from the node and user tables.  My take on the query is that we don't really use 'title' so just select user_id from user and skip the node table entirely.  Adding an index on "lasthere" in the user table might be a good idea and might not (probably not since we update that a ton and we'd be better off just querying it less often by having things like [other users xml ticker] use a cache similar to the way the [other users] nodelet works). It would be nice if the "borging nodelet" (whatever that was called) would use such.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Please add new entries &lt;b&gt;at the top&lt;/b&gt; of the wiki.  It is confusing to have the chronology run in two different directions.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I doubt tagging "special" users in the [other users] nodelet will be implemented.  I'd much rather see group inboxes so, if you want an editor you "/msg editors" (and that just goes to a shared inbox unlike the way it separately /msg's each editor now).  Much of the work to support this has already been done.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[theorbtwo], 2002-06-14&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[id://174423] is my implementation of [crazyinsomniac]'s [id://174392|suggestion], putting &amp;#91;E] next to [editors] in the [Other Users] nodelet, and &amp;#91G] next to [gods] (as [tye] suggested in a /msg).  I'm sure I messed up this one too, please /msg me as to why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
[crazyinsomniac] ~ Mon Jun 17 10:59:20 2002 GMT &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;CODE&gt;
my $csr=$DB-&gt;getDatabaseHandle()-&gt;prepare("	
	SELECT node_id, title FROM node, user
	WHERE node_id=user_id and
	type_nodetype=". getId ($DB-&gt;getType('user')) ." and
	(UNIX_TIMESTAMP(now())-UNIX_TIMESTAMP(lasttime) &lt; $time)
	order by experience desc 
        LIMIT $limit");
&lt;/CODE&gt;
I'm not too much of an SQL guy, but i'd just get rid of
&lt;CODE&gt;WHERE node_id=user_id&lt;/CODE&gt; altogether, and just stick with
&lt;CODE&gt;WHERE type_nodetype=15&lt;/CODE&gt; (15 is [id://15]), since we do index type (right?), and there is no point in adding more criteria which are already covered
The rest looks good.
&lt;/P&gt;&lt;p&gt;[theorbtwo] - 2002-06-17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Good to know I didn't mess up anything.  As to the line you mention, I didn't do that.  I copied out the code from the text box, made my changes, pasted it in, and lo! the line you point out did appear in green.  I can only assume that somebody else removed the type_nodetype line while I was doing my editing, though I don't see it in the [pm-port wiki] (should it be there?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nice to know that in these times of crisis, Murphy's Law still holds true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I suspect that &lt;code&gt;WHERE type_nodetype=15&lt;/code&gt; is the fastest of the three options (type_nodetype test against hardcoded 15, type_nodetype againgst getId call, and node_id test), but that's a complete guess... which agrees with [crazyinsomniac], who almost certianly knows better then I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VSarkiss] Mon Jun 17 13:21:58 2002 GMT&lt;br /&gt;
It looks like there's also [New Other Users] which has this functionality, and more as well (! for power users, etc).  I'm confused.  Which one will get deployed?  Or is the plan to let you pick in [User Settings]?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-06-07&lt;br /&gt;
Reworked the patch to [XP xml ticker] to fold in planned changes to make it actually produce valid XML and not be vulnerable to XML::Generator quirks (probably resulting from mod_perl quirks).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Reworked and replicated the patch to [perlman display page] as noted in my reply to the referenced thread.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I wrote the following in [editors' wiki] and [kudra] wrote the next part there.  There are some good projects here for you [pmdev]ers to take on.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thanks for the hard work, [kudra].  You forgot "edit" links to each node directly from [Nodes to Consider].  Those all make sense.  Perhaps we need to give [editors] read-only access to [pmdev wiki] and [pmdev] read-only access to the [editors] wiki?  To save me time, I'll just cut'n'paste your comments into [pmdev] wiki in hopes of getting someone to start working on these things.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;kudra, 2002-06-06&lt;br /&gt;
I was recently making a number of suggestions to ar0n, and it got to the
point that he recommended I make a list here to get other opinions (and
probably to save himself some msgs).  This is not to say that I'm not
happy with the improvements to editor tools, such as ehomat and the 'edit'
link in nre, but I still find myself repeating a lot of the same tasks
several times daily and I think there's room for more automation, especially
as the nodes that require editor assistance continue to increase.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An editor's version of ntc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Right now, you have to click on a node in order to give it an editorial
delete vote, or to unconsider it (assuming it doesn't have enough edit
votes to show up in nre).  I would like to see editorial delete and
unconsider options that can be applied to a number of nodes at one
time, much like the current ntc options.  The delete would be useful 
for large numbers of blank nodes (there were at least 5 in ntc today), 
whereas the unconsider could be used for nodes which have too many
keep votes to be deleted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automatic messaging box for unconsidered nodes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I have recently started msging people when I unconsider their nodes
due to a large number of keep votes.  The message is generally:
&lt;em&gt;[id://1|a node you considered] has been unconsidered due to the
number of keep votes.&lt;/em&gt;  It should probably also contain a link to
the consideration guidelines.  I'd like the choice to send a message
whenever I unconsider something (as I get with reparenting and editing).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor's signature&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I paste in the same few lines every time I edit a node.  I'd like
to see a default signature (either one written by each editor, or
a generic one) in a seperate text box below the node I'm editing,
with a checkbox (by default selected) to include the signature.
Putting it in the textbox allows me to fill in the reason, and
perhaps the date, although it would be much nicer if the date were
automagically supplied.  Having the checkbox allows me to leave out
the signature, as I generally do when the author considered the node
her/himself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multiple tasks in the same form&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Editing currently involves many, many reloads.  I'd like to see
some of the tasks combined in to the same form.  For example,
when editing a node, the 'submit' button could also include
an unconsider checkbox, and a message to the node author (with
a radio button to enable/disable sending it).  In this instance
the preview button would ignore everything other than the message
text, regardless of its values.  Another example is in ehomat:
there could be an option to unconsider the child node and message
the author of the child node on the same screen as 'does this look
right?' (naturally ignored if you opt for no).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anon authors excluded from default message sending&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If the author is anon, it would be nice not to have the default 
message displayed after editing.  I usually catch myself, but sometimes
I try to message anon when I've edited a node.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
I do hope that some of these will be implemented, because it would
really reduce the amount of work for editors.  Right now I rarely
spend less than 15 minutes a day editing, and I only see the time
increasing :(
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[theorbtwo] - Sun Jun 2, 22:22 2002 EST&lt;br /&gt;
[id://171104] is my solution to [I want site documentation updates and I want them now.| the problem of onsite perldocs].  Take a look, please.  There's a hook in there for a user setting, but it'll work fine without it (though in that case, the text is a bit confusing).  Let me know what the problems with it are -- I'm sure there are plenty.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[jaybonci|jb] - June 1, 2002 Added a small patch in the form of [XP xml ticker - (patch)], that allows the ticker to take an additional paramater "for_user", a string of the username of the person to view. The patch also blanks out the amount of votes a person has left if it is not the current user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VSarkiss] - Fri May 31 22:54:59 2002 UTC&lt;br /&gt;
I added [id://170773|a small patch] to [Perl Monks User Search] so nodes in
the newly re-opened [Perl News] will show up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[theorbtwo] - Sun May 26 2002 2:24 PM EST&lt;br&gt;
[id://169348] is a simple patch to the pmdev nodelet to only show the "dump fields" link if you'd not get a "Dump permission denied".  (This is convient, but means that the permission checks should be kept in sync if changed.)  On a related note, is there sensitive data in the fields of nodes not of type user, or would &lt;code&gt;isGod($USER) || $USER==$WHAT&lt;/code&gt; work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[crazyinsomniac] ~ Fri May 24 11:28:15 2002 GMT&lt;BR&gt;
This is a request for the first god to see this, please make [id://134822] obsolete by adding a "d/l code" capability to [scratch pad viewer].  Just create a new node of type fullpage would be simplest, something like [id://28597] with a few bits from [scratch pad viewer].  Shouldn't take long to write. &lt;B&gt;update&lt;/B&gt;: i wrote something a while back, [http://crazyinsomniac.perlmonk.org/perl/misc/scratchpadviewer.patch.txt|scratchpadviewer.patch.txt], that might also be of interest).
&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[belg4mit]&lt;br&gt;Sat May 18 01:36:41 UTC 2002&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Would it be possible to back out the changes made
to the layout on [ad_and_talk]? They have caused
the table to be twice as large in Netscape
(one thing being that Netscape mishandles
newlines before &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;), 
alternately putting each td and its contents
(for the blue tr only) on it's own line like so
&lt;code&gt;
  &lt;td ...&gt;&lt;img ...&gt;&lt;input ...&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td ...&gt;&lt;input ...&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td ...&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td ...&gt;&lt;a href="/" target="_top"&gt;&lt;img ...&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
also works.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2002-05-15&lt;br/&gt;
See my note from 2002-05-08, [belg4mit]:
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;
belg4mit, I didn't apply Super Search - (patch) because I don't find the results more compact and I don't like having to use both the keyboard and the mouse in order to select multiple items.
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You have a point about selecting "all but X" being easier that way.  I'd rather have an "all but" checkbox instead, though.&lt;/p&gt;

[belg4mit] Wed May 15 00:38:49 UTC 2002&lt;br&gt;
Uno) If it helps, you can also get the image
to display by right-click "View image",
and then htting back.&lt;br&gt;
Due) Would a god take a gander at [id://164453]
and get back to me? It seems to make more sense
than a slough of checkboxes. Another feature is it makes it much
easier if say you want to search all but one section, or even
just half the sections. Who knows, if it's more usable maybe submitted
queries will become more manageable for the database?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 [Petruchio] Tue May 14 19:07:42 UTC 2002 -
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 On some versions of Netscape 4, but not others, there is a problem with
 home node images.  The images do not display when the page loads...
 though as [kudra] points out:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;i&gt;
  if I view the source and then go to the picture, I can see
  it--and then when I go back to your homenode, I can also see
  the picture.
 &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 This problem seems familiar to me, but I cannot recall a solution.
 If anyone knows or figures how to correct this behavior, please speak
 up.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-05-13
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I don't know what was causing the multiple updates problems that broke op=nuke for cat Q+A and that caused warnings about not updating wikis that were actually updated, but it has gone away.  Not long ago we restarted all of the httpd's on one of the web servers because a bunch of them were giving back zero-length pages and they didn't die nicely so perhaps these problems were an early symptom of that.  I'll keep my eye open for recurrances, but I haven't noticed any recently.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[jaybonci|jb], sorry, but canReadNode() isn't strong enough of a check.  That would allow you to view full names, private e-mails, user settings, personal nodelet contents, etc. of users, for example.  [dump node fields] is mainly for use by [gods] but can also be used by [pmdev]ers to look at the structure of nodes by viewing the fields for a node of a given type that the [pmdev]er owns.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So adding a "dump this node" link to the [pmdev nodelet] probably isn't worthwhile.  Your changes are adding features to the [pmdev nodelet] that are already in the [admin nodelet].  [Petruchio] has made it so that these nodelet are moved/removed via [user settings] but he hasn't defined a way for determining which nodelets "privileged" people are allowed to add; otherwise I'd just tell you to add [admin nodelet] if you want those features.  I'll probably just move features from the [admin nodelet] into the [pmdev nodelet].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Though most of the items currently in [pmdev nodelet] (everything but "view code") are just plain links so I'd rather have them in a separate node or at least greatly shorten the link titles for them.  Especially since individual [pmdev]ers can put them in their personal nodelet if they like 1-click access with longer names.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The site slowdown in the early morning is due to loading the backup database, not due to dumping the main database.  I've disabled that for now and will later make it less of a pig.  Let me know if you still see site slow-down in the morning as I'm not around then so my conclusions are drawn from indirect evidence.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[vroom]: Sun May 12, 2002 
added fix to categorized question display page.  The javascript confirmDelete()
function had doubled quotes around the url to delete which caused a javascript
error preventing the dialog from popping asking for the user to confirm.
&lt;HR&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[jaybonci|jb]: Sun May 12, 2002 - I've added a patch for [PM Dev Nodelet] that displays the node_id of the current node and a link to the raw type to make it easier to do some pmdev scouring for myself and others. If you could apply the patch, that would be good. Danke. &lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: Take the second patch. It encorporates all of the first patch + [dump node fields] convenience link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; - also - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patch at [nodetype display page - (patch)] which fixes some wierdness at the bottom of nodetype displays.  You don't need the sexisgood parameter, and there was a hardcoded link to nodes of type pmmodule or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; - Moving along - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Dump node fields - (patch)] makes [dump node fields] un-useless. It was calling canUpdateNode instead of canReadNode.  pmdevers can't update nodes other than themselves and nodes they have created (such as writeups), so it really wasn't very useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; - this just in - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Possibly fixing the "QandAEditors can't nuke" issue is [categorized question display page - (patch)], which fixes a javaScript syntax error. urlGen() gives you quotes around the URL string by default so adding them in in this case is causing a syntax error.  Also, you should consider stripping out or escaping quotes (possibly using $dbh-&gt;quote or s/\"/\\\"/g, whichever be yer style), because nodes with quotes in the title won't be able to be deleted, because of the javascript injection. &lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: Or vroom could fix it after me =P. That works too.  
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
[crazyinsomniac] Sun May 12 08:58:10 2002 GMT &lt;br&gt;
Every night around 1-2am PST (4-5am server time), the site slows down considerably.  This is due to the DB backup (so i believe).  And every night, monks start wondering why the site is slowing down.  I propose this to the gods, let's deal with this [http://everything2.com|E2] style, and during this time disable the site, and throw a static page saying that perlmonks are doing their daily database backup, and if they still wish to &lt;i&gt;read&lt;/i&gt; perlmonks in the meantime, to visit [http://perlmonks.thepen.com]
&lt;hr /&gt;
Backed up to [id://166549].
</field>
</data>
</node>
