<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="218593" title="pmdev wiki through 2002-11-13" created="2002-12-09 12:32:59" updated="2005-08-02 09:36:26">
<type id="68046">
wiki</type>
<author id="142755">
tye&amp;nbsp;</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
Continued from [id://228724]...
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-11-13&lt;br /&gt;
[maintenance] routines are run after things happen.  So the best you could do with that would be to delete the question right after it was added.  And it would be difficult to get such to give reasonable feedback to the user.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[crazyinsomniac] Sun Nov 10 13:40:30 2002 GMT&lt;br /&gt;
Can someone explain to me how [id://5831] works? and if it's the place to prevent Anonymonk from answering questions (esp. to ones that don't exist)? Thanks
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[theorbtwo] 2002-11-09&lt;br /&gt;
I wasn't attempting to spider, mearly to download the code of individual nodes.  It did indeed get somewhere -- I first wrote code to use exactly the method I had stated there (fairly trivial -- LWP and a regex.  Not the best way, but it worked).  Then I rewrote it using the XML view, and an XML package.  Unfornatly, the code is now on the wrong side of a dual-boot system -- I'll /msg myself and post it somewhere the next time I'm in linux.  (If anybody knows how to get to a riserfs partition under winxp, /msg me.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Aristotle] 2002-11-09&lt;br /&gt;
[theorbtwo] mentions in [id://202365] that he was going to write a PM code spider. I wonder if that thrust led to anything?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2002-11-07&lt;br /&gt;
No, PM does not get updates from Everything nor visa versa, except when such are applied by hand.  Yes, we have two web servers and one database server.  I think PM started with Everything 0.8 and has made quite a few changes since then.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[perrin] 2002-11-06&lt;br&gt;
Okay, another question then.  The code I want to hack on is the caching code, which seems to be part of the everything core.  I haven't seen mention of the hardware running PM.  Does any change in the caching scheme have to support a cluster with multiple mod_perl servers?  Also, if I submit my patch to the everything core and it gets accepted will PM eventually get it?  I assume the answer is yes, but I don't know if PM usually runs the latest everything code or if it is stuck on an older version.  (I guess that was two questions.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[tye], 2002-11-06&lt;br /&gt;
You can get all of the code right here.  See [id://202202] for the last time I heard this discussed.  I'm not fond of the idea of handing out DB snapshots as they contain everyone's password and e-mail, any undeleted "phone sex" /msgs between flirting members, etc.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you go to any of [pmmodule], [htmlcode], [superdoc], etc. you can click the link at the bottom "list all ... nodes" and see all the source code.  If you want to get all of the source code downloaded in one convenient operation, then you have full access to what is needed to figure out how to write such so Feel Free (as discussed in the thread I linked to above).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  [perrin] Wed Nov 6 2002 &lt;br&gt;
  Is there a doc that explains where to get the PM code?  I don't see anything linked from the pmdev nodelet that helps with this.  I know I need the everything code and support modules, but where do I download the PM-specific stuff?  Also, is it possible to get a database snapshot for testing?  I want to benchmark any changes that I make, and having real data makes that easier.&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;i&gt;(Moved this question from a /msg pmdev to the wiki at [tye]'s request)&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  [Petruchio] Sat Nov 2 19:24:09 UTC 2002:&lt;br /&gt;
  Relax.  They're transitional, and will depart shortly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[belg4mit] on Wed Oct 30 20:51:17 EST 2002&lt;br&gt;
I'd just like to register my belated bewilderment at the
necessity/waste of the "add to foo" links in the upper left.

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt;[footpad], ~Wed Oct 23 00:53:21 2002 (GMT)&lt;br /&gt;
Hi, folks!  You may have noticed [id://207248|this announcement] of some patches being applied to the Full Page Chat.  Just wanted to let you know that I'm trying to help [tye] go through and evaluate some of the outstanding patches.  If there's something that's been outstanding for awhile, let me know via /msg.
&lt;HR&gt;&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-10-20&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks, [VSarkiss] for the patches.  I've applied them.  Now we have images on [Awards], etc.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-10-20&lt;br /&gt;
The wikis are using application/x-www-urlencoded forms instead of multipart/form-data.  This may explain why some browsers silently truncate the text at 32KB.  We should fix that.  &lt;b&gt;Update&lt;/b&gt;: I fixed it.  It'd be neat to know if we can go to 64KB now in browsers that couldn't before (the doctext field in the DB is limited to 64KB).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[blakem], 2002-10-30&lt;br /&gt;
Sorry it took me so long to notice this... The Q&amp;A_Section pages have been refreshed on thepen and no longer contain the outdated form.  Let me know if 
I've missed any, its an easy fix on my end.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-10-20&lt;br /&gt;
No, thepen just has old versions of some of the Q+A sections that still contain the "add your question" form.  It appears that refresh is triggered by page hits so the problem should continue to disappear.  We don't prevent ppl from faking up their own forms to submit questions.  Feel free to design and patch in such a scheme, but I don't consider it worth much effort as it would only apply to Q+A.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[crazyinsomniac], Sun Oct 20 16:09:32 2002&lt;br /&gt;
So you're looking at raw logfiles and [blakem]s doing something funny?  Is he somehow changing the user_id field for the Q&amp;A posts? Or is it something completely different?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-10-19&lt;br /&gt;
AnonyMonk is adding categorized Q+A via perlmonks.thepen.com.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VSarkiss] 16-Oct-2002&lt;br /&gt;
I finally had a chance to come back to this and add patches for the previous discussion, aka "IMG in [document] nodes."  They're [id://205919] and [id://205922].  I cooked up an "allowImg" parameter to [parselinks].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-10-14&lt;br /&gt;
[Mr. Muskrat] noted that trying to &lt;a href="/?parent=108949&amp;lastnode_id=108949&amp;node_id=2437&amp;parent_node=108949"&gt;reply to the scratch pad viewer&lt;/a&gt;, for example, gives you access to the source code for the node in question.  We should patch the reply functionality to refuse to handle nodes not of the proper type (for example, there is a setting for "types of nodes that you can vote on" which is pretty close, if there isn't some other setting that is even closer).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-10-14&lt;br /&gt;
I just meant that I didn't have time to do the below research and didn't want to open a security hole because of that.
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;
You'd have to pass something to [parselinks] from [document display page] saying "allow img tag".  Which is what that patch was doing....
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
No, that patch was saying "allow all tags" not "allow img tags", which is the distinction that I was objecting to.  But it would be easy to patch [parselinks] to support an override parameter of "img=src,alt,height,width" and/or an alternate node name to use in place of [approved HTML tags] with "override" still meaning "no validation" and then edit your patch to make use of this. (:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VSarkiss] 13-Oct-2002&lt;br /&gt;
I just meant [note] as an example.  To be precise, of the 82 defined node types, about a third are derived from [document].  However, [document display page] is used by:
&lt;table border=1&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;nodetype&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;# of nodes&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;OK?&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Note&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;[meta-user]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Blame [ar0n] for [18215]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;[perlexercise]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Unused? [994], [1013]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;[superquestion]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;[superquestionarea]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;I get "tough beans" when I try to view these.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;[hint]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;26&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Only looked at a few, but all look similar.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;[testnodetype]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;[21836]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;[includefile]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;[91810], which I get "tough beans" on, but it's the tutorials source&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;(Thank goodness for [Node navigator]....)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still don't know how you would add &amp;lt;img&amp;gt; as an allowed element only "in this case".  Changing [approved html tags] affects everything, and changing [parselinks] affects a ton of stuff as well.  You'd have to pass something to [parselinks] from [document display page] saying "allow img tag".  Which is what that patch was doing....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-10-10&lt;br /&gt;
Actually, there are a ton of node types derived from [document].  I'd love to see [htmlpage display page] list the node types that use it (and have nodetype list &lt;b&gt;all&lt;/b&gt; of the htmlpage nodes that apply to it).  Note the highlighting I added to the last three words of my previous text.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VSarkiss] 2002-Oct-10&lt;br /&gt;
Um, the timezone in the state of Confusion is ten days ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it belongs to [document], I assumed [document display page] was only used for that nodetype.  I just went thru the other nodetypes and confirmed that it's only used for [document].  [note] is derived from [document] but has its own [note display page].  I did previously eyeball the other [document] nodes, and also concluded nothing bad would happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we don't want to add &amp;lt;img&amp;gt; to [approved html tags], do we?  That setting's used by [superdoc], among others, so people could start putting pictures in SOPW.  No?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-10-10&lt;br /&gt;
What time zone are you in that October 18th and 19th have already passed?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thanks for the patch.  Did you check what other node types use [document display page]?  I've already checked that we don't have any nodes of type [document] that would cause problems (though, I'd still rather be safer and just add 'img' to the list of approved tags &lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;in that case&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt;).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VSarkiss] &lt;strike&gt;18-Oct-2002&lt;/strike&gt; 8-Oct-2002&lt;br /&gt;
A couple of people in CB pointed out that &lt;code&gt;&lt;img&gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags in [document] nodes aren't rendering right, like in [Awards] and [Hour Stats].  I lost the thread following the links, but the problem appears to be somewhere in the [parselinks] code.  [tye] conjectured it's because IMG isn't an approved tag, which is correct, but I can't find the code that encodes it rather than stripping it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[VSarkiss] &lt;strike&gt;19-Oct-2002&lt;/strike&gt; 9-Oct-2002&lt;br /&gt;
(Yep, talking to myself.)  [tye] was right: Everything::HTML::htmlScreen gets called on [document] nodes, so IMG doesn't get through.  A simple patch like [id://203963] should fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
Let's get rid of our FAQ pages, or simply ressurect [id://519]( [http://perlmonks.thepen.com/519.html|faq_monk] ), at least as a "node", not neccessarilly of type "user"
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[boo_radley] - Fri Oct 04 08:41&lt;br/&gt;
how did [id://202559] get posted [id://198644|in light of these changes]? It was my understanding that the anonymous monk could no longer do cat q&amp;a.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[wil] - 01/10/2002.
&lt;br&gt;
In response to [id://201879] and many other countless people who have submitted a /msg in the [approval nodelet] -- can we please apply [crazyinsmniac]'s [id://186170] that stops this?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[crazyinsomniac] ~ Tue Oct  1 03:16:14 2002 &lt;br&gt;
I'd like to add 
&lt;CODE&gt;
  $str.="\n&lt;p align=right&gt;".linkNode($NODE, "add \"$$NODE{title}\"", {addpersonalnodelet =&gt; getId($NODE)});
  $str.="&lt;BR&gt;".linkNode($NODE,"add to scratchpad",{op=&gt;'addtoscratchpad'});
&lt;/CODE&gt;
from [id://1063] to every page, much the same way we see
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;font size=2 &gt; by &lt;a href="/index.pl?node_id=114"&gt;gods&lt;/a&gt; on Aug 24, 1999 at 12:17 (&lt;a href="/index.pl?node_id=372&amp;displaytype=print"&gt;print&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="/index.pl?node_id=372&amp;displaytype=xml"&gt;xml&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
cause I  display my Personal Nodelet only on the front page (The Monastery Gates), but I'd still like to add nodes and such to my scratchpad/personal nodelet.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;update:&lt;/b&gt; I just found the node in question ([id://841]) and [id://201922|wrote a patch].

&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[Shendal] - 2002-09-30&lt;br /&gt;
I've submitted [id://201802] as my first patch to perlmonks.  It adds support for ie and mozilla's sidebars, including links at the bottom to add them.  [Boo_Radley] had some code to get me started.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[theorbtwo] - 2002-09-27&lt;br /&gt;
[id://201400] should fix the problem pointed out in [id://201294].  Also, there's several patches of mine fixing the &lt;a href="/?node_id=3184&amp;displaytype=raw"&gt;chatterbox frameset&lt;/a&gt; to remove the useless bottom frame, make links open in a new window, fix a couple of HTML errors, and update to mostlyXHTML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[NodeReaper] - 2002-09-23&lt;br /&gt;
I don't explain things.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[blakem], Mon Sep 23 01:03:13 PDT 2002&lt;br /&gt;
Can someone explain what happened with [id://200000] aka node #[id://200000|200,000]?  How does the [worst nodes|worst node of the day] wind up on the front page?  How did it become
authored by [NodeReaper] in such a way as to thwart any type of community 
consideration/reaping?  I don't mind when special node ids are reserved for 
silliness (see [antivroom]) but this one caused a bit more commotion than I thought appropriate.  Can someone please explain?

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-09-19&lt;br /&gt;
Note the new "/msgs" link in the pmdev nodelet.  Anyone can "/msg pmdev" and all messages go to this shared inbox (even when a member of pmdev sends the message).  This is primarilly for non-members to send us information.  We can use it for things that are &lt;b&gt;very&lt;/b&gt; transient that don't need to be in the wiki. Please, err on the side of putting it in the wiki, tho (I put a /msg in there just so you'd see how the link changes).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You can archive/unarchive/delete messages in the shared inbox.  Please archive a message when you "solve" it or otherwise deal with it.  Please only delete shared messages after they are at least a couple of weeks old.  Later we'll have a way to edit a /msg to add your own comments to it (such messages will be marked so you can't make it look like someone said something they didn't).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The "/msgs" link will show you how many new messages are in the shared inbox that you haven't seen yet.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thanks to [Macphisto] for the most recent work helping me to get this working.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Now we need to get the 'wiki' link doing something similar.  And we need to add nodelets for the other groups (doc clan, power users, etc.) so they have a place for links to their inboxes and wikis.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-09-16&lt;br /&gt;
In reply to [j.a.p.h.]'s /msg to the group, "Please don't /msg the group. Use the wiki."  In reply to the content of it about indicating wiki updates in the nodelet: "In the words of the unknown implementors: 'Feel free'. That is the plan. You can help. Personally, I don't care for 'wiki update' /msgs in the mean time, I just check the wiki."
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Kanji] - 2002-08-15&lt;br /&gt;
I noticed [Perl Monks User Search] doesn't use 'pmuslen' when determining how many nodes to list (it only populates the 'length' field ATM), so I've [id://198001|submitted a patch] to match up the implied and actual uses of the setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Chady] - 2002-02-13&lt;br /&gt;
in [id://197504], [claree0] asks about not allowing frontpaging without the node being approved, well, here's a small [id://197531|patch] that hides the Frontpage checkbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] - 2002-09-12&lt;br /&gt;
Next thing we need is to have [message inbox] (well, [showprivatemessages2]) set a user variable w/ the ID of the newest message in the box when you look at the newest messages of an inbox other than your personal one.  After that, we can have an htmlcode that reports how many message are in a specific one of your shared inboxes (for use in the group-specific nodelets).  Any takers?  Something like $VARS-&gt;{"inbox$recvId"}.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Macphisto] - Wed Sept 11 3:15:00 EST 2002&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Submitted a [id://197044|patch] so that shared messages can be deleted by the recpient as per a request that [tye] made in his listing of things he'd like to see altered.  If there are any problems with the code, I'd like to hear about it.  New to actually submitting patches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[OeufMayo] - Mon Aug 26 23:10:42 CEST 2002&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're block images this way, you might as well counter the (old, but rarely used) &amp;lt;input image="foo.gif"&amp;gt; trick.&lt;br /&gt;
The regex may not be 100% fool proof though. [id://193005|patch here], you can see the trick used [briac|here]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that you can also insert images when Lev&amp;lt;5 with CSS, with embedded styles in div, and a background:url() property.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ar0n]. 2002-08-26&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Applied, thanks.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[grinder], 2002-08-26 20:03 UTC&lt;br /&gt;
[mousey] has come up with a new way of getting an image onto a homenode, with the &lt;code&gt;&lt;image&gt;&lt;/code&gt; element. I didn't even know such a thing existed. See [id://192928] for details. [id://192976] is a patch to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-08-23&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
[elusion] says &amp;#91;...&amp;#93; it seems that posting to perl news doesn't increase your writup count, I'd assume this is leftover from not being able to submit to it in the past
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
I'll be gone for 2 weeks so it'd be nice if someone else patched this.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ar0n], 2002-08-22&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Fixed it.  I believe it was [Petruchio] who rewrote [monktitlebar].
  He was appending the first two links to &lt;tt&gt;$str&lt;/tt&gt; and then appending
  a &lt;tt&gt;join&lt;/tt&gt; of $str and list of other links.  A simple oversight.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[crazyinsomniac] Thu Aug 22 11:52:53 2002 GMT &lt;br&gt;
"Log crazyinsomniacout | crazyinsomniac"
appears twice.  I know [titlebar] is one place where that string is formed.  I don't know where the other is.  Somebody take one-of-em out (preferably whoever added the duplicate).  Thanks.  I looked at the port-wiki and I couldn't track it down.
&lt;HR&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[crazyinsomniac] Wed Aug 21 03:44:16 2002 GMT &lt;br&gt;
So QandAEditors can see createtime of nodes [id://191649].
&lt;br&gt;
I have one request though, that the patch textfield be made wider.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ar0n], 2002-08-20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I'd suggest you simply display the latter version of the post, but note the 
  fact that the post has been altered. After all, the latter version of the 
  post apparently is the one the author had intended.  ( Even though in this case, it's not a very nice thing of the author to do :-/ )
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I'd like to know what the other gods think, though.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  PS.  What is the update frequency for home nodes on thepen?  I noticed your
  version of [http://perlmonks.thepen.com/ar0n.html|my] and other home nodes 
  are several months old (5, in fact).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[theorbtwo] - Mon Aug 19 05:14 EDT 2002&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/me notes that this is a policy matter, not a development one, and should thus either be brought up in a PMD node (for public discussion) or in the [gods wiki] for private discussion.  That being said, I'm somwhat ambivilent, but mostly think it's a good idea -- editing often gets used for things it shouldn't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[blakem] - Mon Aug 19 04:38:44 EDT 2002&lt;br /&gt;
As many of you know I run a static mirror of perlmonks at [http://perlmonks.thepen.com].  A possibly controversial "feature" has cropped up and I'd like your advice.  Basically, I grab new nodes within 15 minutes of their original posting, then refresh the data three hours later to account for any updates.  On the whole, this works quite well.
&lt;p&gt;
The unintended feature is that the original data is being saved in a backup directory.  My question is, should I make this data available to the public?
&lt;p&gt;
For instance, [id://191069|this node] was silently edited between the two times that I mirrored it. The change that was made somewhat disrupts the flow of the thread.  Since the update happened before I refreshed the data, the [http://perlmonks.thepen.com/191069.html|mirrored page] reflects this change.  However, you can see the [http://perlmonks.thepen.com/191069.bak.html|original node] at a special link on thepen. (note the differing code block)
&lt;p&gt;
So, should I make this available to everyone, or is the ability to modify/erase ones node more important than the ability to see what was originally written?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[crazyinsomniac] - Fri Aug  9 15:14:39 2002 GMT&lt;br /&gt;
Not much to it, patcho [id://188870]
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[demerphq] 2002/08/09 14:23 GMT+1&lt;br /&gt;
Today there was a node with an unterminated PRE section in it.  Accordingly the whole thread became messed up.  If people think its worth the effort I dont mind putting together something that will filter certain un-balanced tags.  Can people message me if they think this would be useful and worth the energy please?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Also a while back I wrote a pach to add entity name support for square brackets.  At the time I was told that this patch would get rolled into some other effort.  Im wondering what the status of that effort is, and if its not going to happen sometime soonish can the patch or something similar be applied?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[grinder] 2002-08-06 09:08 UTC&lt;br /&gt;
[id://187963] fixes the [id://3559|display problem]. (Scroll down to the end to see the freshly-minted saints). I also lightened the colors a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[theorbtwo], 2002-08-03&lt;br /&gt;
[id://187320] should take care of the possible resource-eating behavors of bad votes, without getting rid of all our fun.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-08-03&lt;br /&gt;
I almost forgot to mention this.  I copied CGI.pm into our 0.8mods directory so I could patch it.  It has an design mistake where it does escapeHTML() on the labels for radio buttons and check boxes.  These items are not part of some HTML tag so they don't need to be escaped and &lt;b&gt;should not&lt;/b&gt; be escaped.  You'll note that [Super Search] has &lt;i&gt;Italic&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;b&gt;bold&lt;/b&gt; words in some of the radio button labels.  This would have required rolling my own code that duplicated some nice features of CGI.pm in order to have them not show up as &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;.  Searching for where we call these CGI methods currently, this patch will not change anything (since the labels are always identifiers that contain no &amp;lt;, &amp;gt;, or &amp;amp;).  Using inheritance to make this change via Everything::CGI would have involved copying way too much code.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-08-03&lt;br /&gt;
The reason to patch this is because we dont want people casting a vote for vote=27859 and wasting lots of resources.  The miscounts are kinda "fun".  And [Chady]'s patch won't fix the more serious part of the bug.  If it weren't for this more serious problem (probably not horrid, tho), I'd vote for "leave it".
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[TheOrbTwo], 2002-08-02&lt;br /&gt;
[ChemBoy]++.  It is, indeed, a feature.  People can, if they so choose, vote for options that aren't listed by handcraftinig a querystring.  The number of listed votes for each listed option is correct, as is the number of total voters.  They don't add up quite correctly.  Also, this isn't the correct place to fix this, if it does need to be fixed; [id://1451] should be made to error on "illegal" votes, if it's the oppinion of the [Gods] that this is a bug, not a feature, which I don't think it will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Update:&lt;/b&gt; Fixed link&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ChemBoy], 2002-08-02&lt;br /&gt;
Hey! That's a feature!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Chady], 2002-08-02&lt;br /&gt;
I submitted a [id://187123|patch for the poll display] that fixes the wrong total voters. The number of votes being passed blindly in [id://1451] as [BigLug] points [id://186997|here] is generating more hits for the total, so I hope my patch is logical; splicing the array to delete entries that are more than the amount of choices. I hope someone reviews it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- oops! didn't put a ruler --&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-07-22&lt;br /&gt;
Sorry, all of those nodes but one were "dead" nodes (and the one live one [ar0n] ended up making other improvements to).  I'm sorry you wasted your time on those. ): See [id://72241] for the list of active XML tickers.  I renamed the dead nodes to avoid future confusion.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I fixed the duplicate problem (op=new was included twice in [listcode]) and deleted the duplicate patches.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The chatterbox HTML-izer will probably be replaced soon anyway so don't worry about that change right now.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Scroll down in [patch lister] just after your patches and you'll see qq(Show "view code" link for [fullpage] and [patch] types).  So, yes, just hit the "view code" link for a patch to see the code instead of the diff (also mentioned below in the wiki).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thanks for your work.  Sorry again for the confusion.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[demerphq], 2002/07/22 14:32 GMT+1&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Posted another patch to fix the chatterbox. Sorry about the duplicates, not real sure why that happened. One patch changes the query logic slightly so as to avoid some unnecessary overhead, the others leave the logic alone. Both change the generator to use XML::Fling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BTW Im not sure what [tye] meant by &lt;i&gt;the chatter HTML-izer set $AUTHOR&lt;/i&gt; but if someone wants to add detail and point me at the correct stuff to change Id like to look into patching the &lt;code&gt;[pad://]&lt;/code&gt; thing...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ok patched the newest nodes generator to use XML::Fling as well. Also was able to remove an unneed hash that was getting populated. Judging by recent p5p traffic Hashes occupy slightly more than twice the memory they need so getting rid of unnecessary and potentially large hashes (like this one) could be a huge time/memory saving for the site. Something to keep in mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patched the cached chatter box XML ticker as well. Used the same modifications as in the optimized chatter patch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Howcome the patches are duplicated? Is this the way to view the source as well as the diff? (On checking it would appear not to be...)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[demerphq], 2002/07/22 11:28 GMT+1&lt;br /&gt;
In [id://183434] I asked about what we should used for a mnemonic for &amp;#91; and &amp;#93;.  It seems that in at one ISO standard the entity name is defined as &amp;lsqb; &amp;rsqb; but more votes were registered for &amp;lsb; and &amp;rsb;.  On my scratch pad is a patch for Everything/html.pm to add support for &amp;lsqb; &amp;rsqb;.  What are the thoughts about applying this or a variant?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[grinder], 2002-07-20 23:21 UTC&lt;br /&gt;
Wandering through the nodelister, I came across [id://2564]. It is just a document, so I'm not sure if/how it gets refreshed, but it looks like it's going through one to many levels of entiti&amp;#91;sz]ation. I wonder if this has anything to do with the recent HTML/entity changes on the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-07-19&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks, [demerphq].  I tested it, made minor changes, and applied it (as a separate patch so [pmdev]ils can compare).  The important change was adding getHttpHeader("text/xml") so that non-IE browsers will know the output is XML.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Any [pmdev]il should feel free to make the same (fairly simple) rewrite for any nodes that [search internal code] finds that mention "XML::Generator".
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You can now "view code" for patches (for when the "diff" output is too ugly).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
We need to have the chatter HTML-izer set $AUTHOR and then we can make &lt;code&gt;[pad://]&lt;/code&gt; use $AUTHOR to expand to &lt;code&gt;[pad://tye|my scratch pad]&lt;/code&gt; (for example). (:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Anyone working on items from my list (near the top of the previous [id://178924|wiki archive]) ? :)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thanks for the recent patching activities.  I really appreciate the work.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[demerphq], 2002/07/19 17:06&lt;br /&gt;
  Ive patched the "user nodes info xml generator" to use XML::Fling.
  Hope I did it right, somebody should definately review it carefully.
  Cheers.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ar0n], 2002-07-19&lt;br /&gt;
  Everybody, please say hi to the new global in town: &lt;tt&gt;$AUTHOR&lt;/tt&gt;.
  &lt;tt&gt;$AUTHOR&lt;/tt&gt;, this is [pmdev].  This will be your new home. They'll
  use you and abuse you and eventually you'll learn to like it. [pmdev],
  &lt;tt&gt;$AUTHOR&lt;/tt&gt; is &lt;tt&gt;$NODE-&gt;{author_user}&lt;/tt&gt;'s user node, so you'll
  no longer have to fetch it manually.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-07-16&lt;br /&gt;
Created [datacache].  Am adding [patch lister|patches] to prepare to make use of it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ar0n], 2002-07-16&lt;br /&gt;
Applied.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[belg4mit] 2002-07-15&lt;br/&gt;
I submitted two patches to bring the two other users in sync,

and save code. Please consider applying them ;-)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-07-12&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
[theorbtwo], I reworked your patch to [scratch pad viewer] (see [patch lister] for the reworked patch and your original -- thanks for submitting it).  There was a period were we tried to simplify things by moving from &lt;code&gt;$q-&gt;htmlshortcut(...)&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;qq[&lt;input type=...&gt;]&lt;/code&gt;.  But that latter has several problems.  It doesn't do intelligent defaulting based on input parameters (which is sometimes a pain which is why there is &lt;code&gt;-force=&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;) which was why your patch was needed in the first place.  The bigger problem is that you have to always remember to HTML-escape anything you put inside.  Down the road we even hope to make stuff like &lt;code&gt;$q-&gt;table(...)&lt;/code&gt; smarter to handle CSS and other special processing so the new starndard is no non-trivial hard-coded HTML.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Chady], &lt;code&gt;scalar localtime();&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
On another note, I think the location of (print, xml) should be adjusted
a bit cause it can get confused with the date of the node. maybe it should be where the [edit this node] is at the wikis?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[chmrr], 11 July 2002&lt;br /&gt;
  The "print" displaytype is showing up funny because it points to
  [print displaytype stylesheet] as the CSS stylesheet -- and that location has
  a whole lotta html in it.  Shouldn't [print displaytype stylesheet] be made to
  be a [rawpage] or somesuch?  &lt;b&gt;Update:&lt;/b&gt; Fixed by [ar0n].
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[chromatic], 10 July 2002&lt;br /&gt;
I think there's a node XML displaypage in the Everything 1.0 snapshots.  It could be useful to come up with something between the two.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ar0n], 2002-07-10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Recently [vroom] wrote up a node that outputs XML given a range of nodes for 
  [shotgunefx] so he could work on a search engine for PM.  I cloned the node 
  and tinkered with it a bit, and the result is the 'xml' displaytype.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Nearly all nodes should output at least basic node information, such as node 
  id, title, createtime, author, etc.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The code that handles the displaytype is at [id://180656].  I would like to
  hear any additional ideas you might have before we announce it to the general
  public, so we (hopefully) don't have to change the XML format later on.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The xml displaytype is only supposed to give information about the node in 
  question, not any relation it may have to other nodes.  For node relations,
  we need to create new xml tickers.  [id://180684] is one example.  Again, let
  me know of any ideas/suggestions you may have.  Thanks.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-07-05&lt;/p&gt;
Applied and tested. Thanks!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[theorbtwo], 2002-07-05&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[id://179605] should fix a minor problem with the chatterbox frameset -- the randomonk picture showss as &amp;ltm;img ...&gt;.  It's escaped by tye's changes to linkNode.  The patch is fairly obvious, given the (undocumented, but clearly coded) behavor of linkNode, and the usage in [monkbar2001].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[theorbtwo], 2002-07-02&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we're on the topic of changes, can people please note changes here, on the [pm-port wiki], or as a [perl monks discussion|discussion] node, or at least generate a diff?  Espeicaly changes that are user-visible or change how other code will/should work/be written?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changes around here lately that you may not have noticed include [NodeReaper] /msging the writers of reaped nodes.  There are probably others that I don't know about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and nodes occasionaly show up as having a create time of "&lt;i&gt;Never&lt;/i&gt;" for a short period.  They seem to fix themselves, so I can't link to an example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ar0n], 2002-07-02&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Just for future reference, &lt;tt&gt;$q&lt;/tt&gt; is now exported along with 
  &lt;tt&gt;$query&lt;/tt&gt;;  &lt;tt&gt;$query&lt;/tt&gt; will still work, but we'd prefer
  it if you used &lt;tt&gt;$q&lt;/tt&gt; from now on.  If you're a lazy typer,
  you'll learn to appreciate this.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[dws], 2002-07-01&lt;br /&gt;
Did someone accidentally break &amp;lt;READMORE&amp;gt;? One &lt;strike&gt;is&lt;/strike&gt; &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; showing up visibly in [id://178785|this node].
&lt;hr /&gt;
Continued in [id://178924]...</field>
</data>
</node>
