<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="320945" title="SDC Wiki archive ending 2004-01-13" created="2004-01-13 08:10:02" updated="2005-08-02 09:54:29">
<type id="68046">
wiki</type>
<author id="24736">
boo_radley</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
Continued in [id://420478]

&lt;!-- Mr. Muskrat - 2004-01-17 - renamed to be in line with other wiki archives --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat] 2003-12-26 2259 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
I agree with [tye] on this one.  We really only need to document the PM-specific ones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2003-12-26&lt;br /&gt;
I don't think it makes a lot of sense to start building our own net acronym database when there are already so many decent ones available.  I'd rather just link to a few of the others lists and include the PM-specific ones, like we are already doing (as I noted in that thread).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Louis_Wu] 2003-12-26 1335 PST&lt;br /&gt;
I suggest that we wait a few days until [id://316525] settles down before we add that content to a faqlet.  I'm sitting next to [Theo] as he updates his Meditation for what seems like the 57th time, and I don't think the /msgs will stop flowing soon.  
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat] 2003-12-25 0847 CST&lt;br /&gt;
Merry Christmas!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[theorbtwo] sent us a message asking if we could add the info from [id://316525] to [id://89535].  I sent a reply that we would review the node and decide which should be added (message archived).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm adding the thought balloon (which isn't an acronym but so commonly seen and asked about that I think it belongs in [id://89535].  What does everyone else think?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat] 2003-12-15 2310 CST&lt;br /&gt;
Good catch [pfaut].  I added a quick note about 'ticker=yes' to [id://72241] as requested by [Aristotle].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[pfaut] 2003-12-15 18:45 EST&lt;br /&gt;
I archived a couple of the ones that mentioned the xml generators page.  It looks like they were taken care of but not removed from the inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat] 2003-12-14 2239 CST&lt;br /&gt;
We have seven messages in the inbox.  I really don't like to let them pile up like this.  Can anyone spare the time to research just one of them?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt; [boo_radley] 2003-10-29 0859 MST&lt;br /&gt;
Mr. Muskrat - I think they should still belong there, because [id://237057] acts as an explanation to the different areas. This conflicts with the title though, and thus messes with nodal &lt;i&gt;fung shui&lt;/i&gt;. Maybe we stress the point that these two sections have special meaning? "No posts accepted here." for the Library's description is about as good as no description at all. Something like "Although not a section that monks can post to, the Library is the monastery's collection of documentation from perl's various POD files to serve as an online reference to same." You know, fill it out a little. The offering plate should stay for the same reason, it's part of, uh, what -- monkbar? something? -- and people will see "Offering Plate" on top of each page. If it's really impossible to stand their incorporation, maybe replace descriptions with links to more indepth faqlets. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; [Mr. Muskrat], 2003-10-28 2304 CST&lt;br /&gt;
While reviewing [id://237057] I couldn't help but wonder if [id://148] and [id://71130] belong in there at all.  What do y'all think?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt; [boo_radley] 2003-10-28 0740 MST &lt;br /&gt;
There's 24 nodelets marked as beta, most from February this year. Let's make a quick pass over them for accuracy &amp; etc. and get them to stable by Nov. 7th or 8th. &lt;br /&gt;
back again, boo
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; [Louis_Wu] 2003-09-20 1205 PDT &lt;br /&gt;
Started to add the [http://www.perlmonks.org/headlines.rdf|RDF feed] to [id://72241] per [theorbtwo]'s /msg request and found my newsreader couldn't read the feed.  I commented out the added text in the faqlet.  I am currently investigating the state of our RDF and am wondering if we should document a broken feature/interface. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;UPDATE, 1235 PDT&lt;/b&gt; I talked to [theorbtwo] and he pointed out that while the feed is "broken" it is still useful, so I documented it as such.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[pfaut] 2003-09-15 09:37 EDT&lt;br /&gt;
That link points to [jdporter]'s user information page in edit mode ([jdporter] was the one to insert it according to the comments).  There is no 'Edit your user information' page, really.  What you do is access your own homenode in edit mode.  I don't think there is any way to represent the current user's homenode as a link so it would probably be best to replace that link with directions for getting to the user information edit page through the link on the user's own homenode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[monsieur_champs|Monsieur Champs] 2003-09-12 0940 BRT&lt;br /&gt;
Fellows, I was translating the [id://156910] and discovered a broken (?) link, where anybody can read &lt;a href="/index.pl?displaytype=edit&amp;node_id=170442"&gt;"Edit your user information"&lt;/a&gt;. Its seems to point to the current user's user information node, but I can't figure out how to calculate (or substitute) the current user's node id so this link works. Maybe the most experienced [SiteDocClan] monks could help me figure out how to fix this.&lt;br /&gt;Thank you all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat] 2003-09-05 1505 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
I have patched [id://153] as outlined.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ybiC], 2003-09-05 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
Brer [silent11] recently /msg'd [editors] with candidate URLs for adding to [id://153], and I found another one or two. &amp;nbsp; I'm not entirely satisfied with the State of the Onion being merely summarized for 2003, but had no luck finding it in it's original uncut glory. &amp;nbsp; Similarly, I'm not sure that the 1996 chunking writeup merits inclusion, although perhaps on historical merits. &amp;nbsp; *shrug*
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li /&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.perl.com/pub/a/2001/07/25/onion.html"&gt;SotO 2001&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;li /&gt;&lt;a href="http://dev.perl.org/perl6/talks/2002/onion2002/2002.txt.htm"&gt;SotO 2002&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;li /&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.perl.com/pub/a/2003/07/16/soto2003.html"&gt;SotO 2003&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;li /&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.linux-mag.com/1999-10/uncultured_01.html"&gt;Uncultured Perl (Linux Mag interview)&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;li /&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wall.org/~larry/chunking"&gt;1996 chunking article&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

P.S. I though y'all might get a chuckle from my petition to the [gods] for to join SDC:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Being of unsound mind and body, I hereby nominate myself for inclusion in yon august body heretofor identified as SiteDocClan, for non-exclusive purpose and intent of securing updates toward inclusion in and amongst The St. Larry Wall Shrine.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-09-05 1226 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
Let's give a nice, warm welcome to our newest member... [ybiC]!!!!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;The sound of applause fills the room!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Monsieur_Champs], 2003-10-05 0949BRT&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Update: &lt;/b&gt;Welcome to the [SiteDocClan], [ybiC].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Louis_Wu], 2003-09-03 1230 PDT&lt;br /&gt;
Hmm, I think that [id://258824|Moderation Primer for Anonymous Monks] was how I thought of the faqlet, not how it should be named.  It should be named for the users, not the writer.  Title change - [id://258824|Can't See Your Post?] is the new name.  Thanks.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ailie], 2003-09-03 1000 EDT&lt;br /&gt;
I think that Can't See Your Post? is a better name than Moderation Primer for Anonymous Monks in the context of the FAQ. MPfAM sounds more serious and technical, and it isn't the sort of phrasing that would pop into my head when encountering that situtation. CSYP also matches the tone of the node better - informal but informative. Nicely done. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Louis_Wu], 2003-09-02 2240 PDT&lt;br /&gt;
I pushed the [id://258824|Moderation Primer for Anonymous Monks] to stable, and pondered [keymon]'s trouble today. (He created [id://288476|created] duplicate [id://288504|nodes].)  It's pretty obvious that he thought he had a technical problem - this was his first line in the second node, "The first attempt was unsuccessful for some reason..."
&lt;p&gt;
The question I have is, how do we draw attention to the "Show Unmoderated Content" option in [user settings] for members?  How does that jive with what we tell the AnonyMonk?  (Assuming FAQful users, of course.)  Should I just change the name of [id://258824] to [id://258824|Can't See Your Post?] and move on?  Thanks.
&lt;p&gt;
And welcome back, [ailie]. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-08-28 1654 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
[ailie]'s back!  Huzzah!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], 2003-08-27  0214 EDT&lt;br/&gt;
Ack!  I seem to have started at the wrong end.  I went through every SDC-authored node and
made edits I deemed appropriate.  (Hey, at least I'm fessing up!)  My edits mostly entailed changes of the following types:&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;a name="foo"&gt;Bar Quux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt; --&gt; &lt;code&gt;&lt;a name="foo"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Bar Quux&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;[PerlMonks FAQ]&lt;/code&gt; --&gt; &lt;code&gt;[id://237040]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other instances of removing "alt text", e.g. &lt;code&gt;[pmdev|PMDev]&lt;/code&gt; --&gt; &lt;code&gt;[pmdev]&lt;/code&gt;,
  esp. so as to change to using the &lt;code&gt;[id://...]&lt;/code&gt; form.
&lt;/ol&gt;
Now I'll go back and start at [SDC Master Plan Wiki|the top].
&lt;i&gt;Mea maxima culpa!&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-08-15 1251 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks for adding the link and don't worry about the mistakes.  We're all human (well, I'm not sure about [tye] ;-).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Monsieur_Champs] 2003-08-15 14:39 GMT+3&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Update:&lt;/b&gt;Ooops. That means that I've made a stupid thing today... =-&amp;#93; I've posted a new translation as a tutorial. Sorry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Monsieur_Champs], 2003-08-15 14:38GMT+3&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Update:&lt;/b&gt; How you Americans say? "&lt;i&gt;Piece of cake&lt;/i&gt;". It's done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[pfaut], 2003-08-14 10:23 EST&lt;br /&gt;
Go for it.  It's certainly better than what I had come up with.  I'd do it but I'm at work and shouldn't even be here....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-08-14 0825 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
Does anyone have any objections to the changes suggested by [woolfy] in [id://283495]?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-08-12 1236 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
Looks good to me [monsieur_champs].  You have even linked to it in the [id://237040].  Good job!  &lt;b&gt;Update:&lt;/b&gt;Can you edit [id://283274] and add a link to [id://17404] in the same style as the previous translations?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it is simply a translation of an existing FAQ, then there is no need to post it as a tutorial.  If it's a new FAQ, we prefer you post it to your [id://108949|scratchpad] and post a note here asking for comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everytime you make changes like this, just make notes in the [id://237008] as to what you have done.  Also update the [id://240586] as needed or leave a note here asking for help in doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BTW, thanks [tye]!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Monsieur_Champs], 2003-08-12&lt;br /&gt;
I think I made a stupid thing. I've created a new FAQLet node and pushed "[id://283274]" into it, and published it. Should I publish a new translation as a new tutorial instead, where people can add comments?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2003-08-12&lt;br /&gt;
I conceed. (:  I made a quick update regarding &lt;a href="?node_id=236794#code"&gt;
CB escaping&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-08-12&lt;br /&gt;
While doing &lt;code&gt;[id://123|Title of node 123]&lt;/code&gt; does save a database dip, it also allows the person editing the doc to see the node title even if that person is editing offline.  I'm sure we could write an LWP (or WWW::Mechanize) script to do a search and replace of all nodes linked from the [id://237040] if a title is updated.  I'll start thinking about such a script.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2003-08-08&lt;br /&gt;
I don't see much point in doing &lt;code&gt;[id://123|Title of node 123]&lt;/code&gt; to save a database dip.  I do see a point in not duplicating node titles all over the place such that it becomes a huge effort to update a node title.  Just FYI.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Louis_Wu], 2003-07-30 23:55 PDT&lt;br /&gt;
I have been overly busy, I should have checked in the CB FAQ.  Take it and make it lickably linked; or some such Mac talk.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-07-30 1251 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
[Louis_Wu],
I haven't heard from you in over a month now.  Have you made any progress on the #linked TOC for [id://236794]?  I made a slight update to it yesterday so you might want to take a gander at the changes outlined in the [id://237008].  If you don't have time for this project right now, it's okay.  Just let me know.  I am more than willing to take over this endeavor as I haven't found anything really pressing to work on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-07-29 1524 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
[id://222879|Wikis of the world, unite!] is [pmdev]-only :-(  I don't know why I thought that any of the [cabal] could view it.  I have added some additional links to [id://240586] that should make it unnecessary to read [id://222879|Wikis of the world, unite!].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the place to discuss ideas about site documentation.  [id://237008] is where you "acquire a lock on a task".  Just add a note there saying what you are working on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Monsieur_Champs], 2003-07-29 17:05 GMT+3&lt;br /&gt;
Thank you for the invitation for discussion, [Mr. Muskrat]. I've quite busy last weeks, sorry. I tryied to access the "[id://222879]" article, and receive back a "Permission Denied" answer. Suppose that this is not the article... can anybody please try to figure out what's going on there?&lt;br /&gt;
Hey! There are lots of things to do here! I've already found the [id://240586], but can't figure out how to aquire a lock on a task. Can anybody please help this newbye document writer? Please /msg me if you can.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-07-29 0912 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
Replaced missing entries from memory.  Maybe it's time to rotate the wiki...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[boo_radley], 2003-07-28 18:00 MDT&lt;br /&gt;
patches to [Site How To] and [Voting/Experience System] applied &amp; tested.
Jesus, you guys have been busy. Everything looks amazing. I notice that the [id://239623|nodelets] faq links in [PerlMOnks FAQ] have title attributes noting that they're in beta status. All of the information looks good on them &amp; I can't see anything that needs to be added; unless some objection rises up, I'll get those titles removed by 2003-08-01. Man, even the cross-referencing's done and stuff, too. Awesome.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-07-28&lt;br /&gt;
I submitted a patch for [Site How To] to correct the link to the [PerlMonks FAQ].&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-07-28&lt;br /&gt;
I have submitted a patch for [id://5938] as mentioned below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-07-22 0758 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
[monsieur_champs], feel free to discuss [SiteDocClan] things here.  As for the problem with [id://17404], the final closing comment tag disappeared for some reason.  I put it back a minute ago though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-07-18 1410 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
I haven't yet.  Instead, I said that he should read all of our wikis before attempting to do anything.  I also forwarded him a copy of [boo_radley]'s email entitled "PerlMonks SiteDocClan Info".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[pfaut], 2003-07-18 16:14 EDT&lt;br /&gt;
Welcome, [monsieur_champs].  Keep up the good work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Has someone explained to [monsieur_champs|him] how to create faqlets?  Can we get the nodes he's already created converted to faqlets?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-07-18 1410 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
Take a look at [id://5938].  See the paragraph that begins "Now you're probably wondering what are levels and experience good for?"  I think that this can be removed.  I'll mention it in the [pmdev wiki] as well.  If no one objects, I'll submit a patch to remove it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat] 2003-07-18 1210 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
Let's give a nice, warm welcome to our newest member... [monsieur_champs]!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[Mr. Muskrat] starts clapping really loudly...&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[pfaut] 2003-06-18 20:36 EDT (MM says: that's a dubious date [pfaut] ;-)&lt;br /&gt; 
Re: linking to translations - I like [Mr. Muskrat]'s idea.  That was exactly what I was thinking when I saw [monsieur_champs]' /msg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-07-14 1333 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
We should invest some time in reorganizing [id://236794].  In addition to the #linked index, we should move things around so that the questions are organized by topic.  i.e. CB FAQs after CB info, /msg FAQs after the /msg info, etc...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-07-14 1144 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
Should we add links from [id://237040] to [monsieur_champs]' FAQ translations?  If so, what linking method should we use?  Perhaps something like this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;About PM&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="?node_id=243870"&gt;What is PM?&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="?node_id=272361"&gt;pt_BR&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="?node_id=243871"&gt;Who runs it?&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="?node_id=272362"&gt;pt_BR&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Updated:&lt;/b&gt; s/br_pt/pt_BR/g;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-07-10 1600 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
I updated [id://236970] in response to two old messages in the inbox (which I deleted after completing the update).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-06-27 1708 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
I have been without net access at home for some time.  I understand.  I only asked because I pointed someone to [id://236794].  I looked at it and remembered that I had mentioned it before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Louis_Wu], 2003-06-27 1400 PDT&lt;br /&gt;
[Mr. Muskrat], I've been without net access at home for over 2 weeks (I'm occasionally checking from work, which is how my homenode update happened.) and I've also been busy with a "real life".  Verizon claims that I'll have DSL back tonight, but I'm not holding my breath.  I have some of the FAQ linked, but I've been avoiding anything which reminds me of my non-nettedness, so the FAQ has been sitting, stale, in emacs.  I'll give it a whack this weekend, and hopefully update it if I have connectivity.  If no net, I'll USB-drive it to work.  ...  &amp;lt;/soap opera&amp;gt;
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; 
Which means, I'm not ready to post it, but I haven't forgotten it. :(
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-06-27 1518 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
[Louis_Wu], how is the #linked index for [id://236794] coming along?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-06-24 0809 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
One to two weeks should be fine.  I was simply thinking of those that are only on occasionally.  I should have been clearer in my last line though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2003-06-23&lt;br /&gt;
My policy is to not archive messages until they are taken care of and then delete them a week or two later (so those who care can note that the item was taken care of).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat] 2003-06-23 0750 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
As time permits, we need to go through our archived /msgs in the &lt;a href="?recipient=17342&amp;type=strangedoc&amp;node=message%20inbox"&gt;SDC inbox&lt;/a&gt;.  Old messages should be deleted if the issue has been resolved.  New messages should be kept archived for two weeks to a month (?) or until resolved, whichever is longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[pfaut] 2003-06-18 20:36 EDT&lt;br /&gt;
Well, I've hardly been here at all since getting this new job.  Took me two days to notice your last post, [Mr. Muskrat].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until we get a significant number of faqlets translated, I'd say add a link on the existing index page next to the existing links to the translation.  When there's a significant number of translated pages, create a new index page for the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think [monsieur_champs] should be given membership in [SiteDocClan].  I also think the translated faqlets should stay here.  Doesn't make a whole lot of sense to me to have PM faqlets offsite just because they're not in English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat] 2003-06-16 1306 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
No one else has anything to say about this?&lt;br /&gt;
Meanwhile, I see that [monsieur_champs] has been busy translating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat] 2003-06-11 1455 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
[monsieur_champs] spoke with me today about this very issue and I was the one who instructed him to contact you.  I think that it would much nicer if the translations here.  Since he is wanting to translate pages that fall under our domain, I would have to say let him in.  That will give him access to the wikis and the guidelines that have been set forth for us to work under.  By the way, those translations are Brazilian Portuguese and not french.&lt;br /&gt;
And thanks ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[boo_radley] 2003-06-11, 1319 MDT&lt;br/&gt;
monsieur champs would like to translate the faq into french : [pad://monsieur_champs]. Should this be a page in perlmonks or on an outside mirror? Also, should he be sdc?&lt;br/&gt;
the patch to user settings looks nice.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-06-05 1627 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
I have submitted a patch for [id://1072] that adds super-q links to [id://239623].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[pfaut] 2003-05-31 EDT&lt;br /&gt;
Good ideas, [Mr. Muskrat].  It might also be beneficial to add a link to [id://239623] from [id://1072].

&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-05-30 1228 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
[tye] patched the page where you edit your user information to add a link to [id://17639] (as well as adding a super-q to the bottom).  I patched [id://1072] to add a link to [id://17642].  [tye] applied both patches as soon as they were submitted.  He also asked that in the future, if an SDC member runs across a page that would benefit from a help link but that they are unable to edit, to annotate it here for the members who are also [pmdev]ils to patch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Louis_Wu], 2003-05-29 1711 PDT&lt;br /&gt;
Good idea.  I'm on it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-05-29 1547 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
I've been a bit busy with other projects but I'll get to SDC stuff real soon.  In the mean time, I noticed that [id://236794] needs a #linked index.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-05-23 1103 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
I have updated [id://43037] as noted in the to-do wiki.  I'm starting work on [id://5938] but I'd appreciate feedback as to what this paragraph should say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, my FAQ Trek will continue until I am sure that all the FAQ's link back to [id://237040] by id instead of name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-05-22 0903 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
Okay, I found that [id://43037] has outdated information regarding FatBrain and kickbacks.  Also, we might want to fix the formatting of [id://168266].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-05-22 0849 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
I'm at it again today. :-)  Still wading through changing 'Perl Monks' to 'PerlMonks' where appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-05-21 0919 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
I'm on a roll today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[id://5938] says:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Now you're probably wondering what are levels and experience good for? Well right now it's just about status, but soon higher level users will be able to approve, cool, and delete writeups. They'll also be allowed to bless or curse other users. Other benefits of higher levels might include getting free stuff like a t-shirt. Who knows what might be in the works. In the mean time you just might as well work for experience points and help us to improve the content of our site.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
I'm going to start drafting a new paragraph to replace this one.  It is terribly out of date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-05-21 0904 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
I think that I will start looking through the older 'Stable' FAQlets today.  I will wait to make changes to [id://84115] until I get feedback about my proposed changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat], 2003-05-20 0823 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
I have started looking through the 'Aged' status FAQlets and I will be updated them as needed.  For example, I came across [id://84115].  It doesn't mention that you can use the advanced Google search features. (&lt;code&gt; [google://muskrat site:perlmonks.thepen.com] &lt;/code&gt;)  See the &lt;a href="?node_id=108949&amp;user=Mr. Muskrat#SDC"&gt;SDC section&lt;/a&gt; of my [pad://Mr. Muskrat|pad] for the specifics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[pfaut], 2003-05-20 EDT&lt;br /&gt;
[id://243874] is posted.  I added it to [id://240586] as alpha.  Is anyone regenerating [id://237040] on any regular basis or should we be doing this ourselves when we make significant changes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2003-05-19&lt;br /&gt;
None that I know of.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[pfaut], 2003-05-19 EDT&lt;br /&gt;
I updated [pad://pfaut|my scratchpad].  Slight alterations to the first paragraph.  Does anyone know whose affiliate list PerlMonks is on for books?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2003-05-19&lt;br /&gt;
I'd rather have the sanity of &lt;code&gt;[id://12345]&lt;/code&gt; keeping the title up-to-date over the paultry saving of a single record fetch with &lt;code&gt;[id://12345|What the node title was when I made this link]&lt;/code&gt;, FWIW.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[boo_radley]2003-05-18&lt;br/&gt;
pfaut, the homework node looks good. It should mention that seeing several requests from different people for the same problem trigger a lot of homework detectors.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[pfaut] 2003-05-17 EDT&lt;br /&gt;
I have a start towards &lt;i&gt;Is PM a good place to get answers for homework?&lt;/i&gt; on [pad://pfaut|my scratchpad].  Please read it and /msg me with feedback or reply here.  In particular, I included a link to Barnes and Noble and implied that ordering books from there would help the monastery.  I was originally going to link to FatBrain but noticed that ISBN links pointed to Barnes and Noble.  So, my questions are: 1) Is PerlMonks a Barnes and Noble affiliate or should that link point somewhere else?  2) Is there anything else that needs to be included in the link for PerlMonks to get credit for books ordered through it?  3) Should the link be there at all?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Re: Link styles - I think I've been using either &lt;code&gt;[id://12345|title]&lt;/code&gt; or just &lt;code&gt;[id://12345]&lt;/code&gt; with a nearby HTML comment indicating what it points to.  My guess is the first is easiest on the database since no lookups need to be performed unless someone actually clicks on the link.  The second format would be second best and would be updated if the node's title were to change.  With the comment nearby, people attempting to work on the document later won't have to follow the link to see where it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Louis_Wu] 2003-05-16 2043 PDT&lt;br /&gt;
I was /msging with [Mr. Muskrat] recently when the subject of link style came up.  Many of the faqs seem to link like so: &lt;code&gt;[243870|What is PM?]&lt;/code&gt;, which is odd, because it assumes the node id would map to the node title.  Also popular from the BBL era (Before [BigLug] went hog-wild improving SiteDocClan methods) was &lt;code&gt;[login|log in]&lt;/code&gt;, which assumes that the name won't change.  I was under the impression that the prefered link method was: &lt;code&gt;[id://243870|What is PM?]&lt;/code&gt;, which goes directly to the node_id and also supplies the name (which I'm assuming reduced db load).  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Is this the prefered method?  If not, what is?  When we are in or near an "old" faq, do we change it to match our currently prefered methods?  (See my recent entry in [id://237008] for an example.)  
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat] 2003-05-12 1235 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
Should we add PMD to [id://89535]?  I am seeing it used more frequently.  What other acronyms could be added as well?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat] 2003-05-09 1315 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
I posted the alpha version of [id://243870] earlier. [theorbtwo] mentioned two follow-up nodes, "who owns perlmonks" and "on what hardware/software does perlmonks run".  Personally, I like the idea but I wanted to get some feedback from others.  Do we need/want to add them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat] 2003-05-08 1057 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
I've added some more quotes to my [pad://Mr. Muskrat|pad] in the hope that I can finish the alpha version of [id://243870] this week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[pfaut] 2003-04-29 EDT&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks, [tye].  I just went to check some of the other links in the information nodelet.  [Site How To] looks extremely old and contains the same bad link.  If it would be useful to keep any of the information there, I would propose copying it to a new FAQlet so that [SiteDocClan] can maintain it.  Most of the information there is also contained in other FAQlets.

&lt;p&gt;[boo_radley], 2003-04-29&lt;br /&gt;
I'll be getting a new case/ps/motherboard soon and my sdc'ing will resume. Doo dah, doo dah
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2003-04-28&lt;br /&gt;
Fixed and fixed.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[pfaut] 2003-04-28 EDT&lt;br /&gt;
[VSarkiss] sent us a /msg stating that [Perl Monks Site FAQ] contains a link to [Perl Monks FAQ] which goes to the 'search again?' screen since that page doesn't exist.  Can [SiteDocClan] get ownership of that page so we can fix it?  Better yet, can the link in the information nodelet get changed to [PerlMonks FAQ]?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat] 2003-04-25 1004 CDT&lt;br /&gt;
I have started work on [id://243870].  The text is currently residing on [pad://Mr. Muskrat].  If anyone has any further ideas about what should be included in this node, please make them known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[pfaut] 2003-04-22 EDT&lt;br /&gt;
I just added [id://252754] and linked it from the master plan.  Feel free to add/alter to your hearts content.  I'm not thrilled over the title but it seems opinions on frontpaging range from 'only the best' to 'only not the worst' and it was the best I could think of to reflect that.

&lt;p&gt;[pfaut] 2003-04-22 EDT&lt;br /&gt;
The end of [id://29730] talks a bit about what should be frontpaged but it does not seem to agree with recent discussions on the topic.  I think enough can be written about reasons for/against frontpaging that it should be a separate faqlet linked from this node (and [PerlMonks FAQ]).  Having it as a separate page might make it more visible to those who have recently acquired moderation privileges and are looking for guidance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2003-04-22&lt;br /&gt;
I like the summary at [pad://pfaut].  One point:
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;
lack of turnover on the frontpage makes the site look inactive to someone who hasn't figured out how the site works yet 
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
should add "and those who choose to use The Gates to navigate the site just out of personal preference".  Note also that the number of SoPW shown on the gates was increased a few months back so that each section has room on The Gates for about a typical day's worth of nodes (my design choice).  Some of the nodes about the FP turning over too fast might be from before that change (I recall replying to one of those regarding this change but didn't have time to find that reply at the moment).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[pfaut] 2003-04-22 EDT&lt;br /&gt;
I just dug up the following nodes that might be relevent towards developing some consensus on frontpaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
[id://227268|Considering Front Paging a Node?]&lt;br /&gt;
[id://221991|Is the front page change too quickly?]&lt;br /&gt;
[id://252340|Why should I frontpage a node?]&lt;br /&gt;
[id://229083|Front Paging (again...)]&lt;br /&gt;
[id://167147|Front Page with Negative Rep..]&lt;br /&gt;
[id://164667|What's up with frontpaging?]&lt;br /&gt;
[id://134525|Posts, The Front Page and Temptations]&lt;br /&gt;
[id://114756|Rampant Frontpaging]&lt;br /&gt;
[id://91872|Points system for frontpaging nodes]&lt;br /&gt;
[id://84500|When to frontpage a node]
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On [pad://pfaut|my scratchpad] I have a short summary of some of the thoughts expressed in the first thread.  I'll expand on this as I find time.  Anyone else should feel free to grab it and work on it.  Anyone have any ideas on how we can better collaborate on things like this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Louis_Wu] 2003-04-22 PDT&lt;br /&gt;
[tye] was gracious enough to prod us in [id://252369] to create some good docs for consideration and moderation.  Specifically addressing reasons to frontpage a node.  What else do we have on moderation and consideration?  Where are the philosophical FAQs on when and why to moderate?  How do we express the differing opinions on moderation without marginalizing any one opinion?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[pfaut] 2003-04-20 EDT&lt;br /&gt;
[id://17558] looks like someone edited it externally and pasted it in twice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat] 2003-04-18 Good Friday&lt;br /&gt;
I'm not sure if you've seen it or not but [Erudil] wrote up [id://131253] which quotes [TheDamian].  [TheDamian] mentioned the PerlMonks charter -&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;A prime example of that are the Perl Monks. Their charter is to be:&lt;br /&gt;* an attempt to make learning Perl as non-intimidating and easy to use as possible&lt;br /&gt;* a place for individuals to polish, improve, and showcase their Perl skills&lt;br /&gt;* a community which allows everyone to grow and learn from each other.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Couldn't this information be used for the 'What is PerlMonks?' FAQ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat] 2003-04-17&lt;br /&gt;
I have looked and searched and looked some more yet I still do not see a node that links to the Perl Exercises: [id://994], [id://1008], [id://1013] and [id://1017].  Is this an accident or on purpose? :-)  I think that they should be documented somewhere... the FAQ perhaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[boo_radley] 2003-04-03&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, I decided to keep the original content in case the linked faqs went over poorly. &lt;br/&gt;
I've also gotten a new job, and been painting my house, etc. etc. spring cleaning. I tried not to let it interfere too much with my perlmonking, but SWMBO grew wroth...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[BigLug] 2003-04-01 Aust&lt;br /&gt;
That's a [boo_radley] fix. I think he's pasted his 'cross referenced' version at the top of the old node without removing the old one.&lt;br&gt;
BTW: Sorry I haven't been around for the past few weeks, I'm really busy with the DateTime project at the moment. I'll be back soon!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Louis_Wu] 2003-03-31 PST&lt;br /&gt;
(attn [boo_radley] and [BigLug]) &lt;br /&gt;
I noticed that [id://17558|Writeup Formatting Tips] has the old version of the faqlet visible in the node.  Should we comment out the original node content with &lt;code&gt;&lt;!--  --&gt;&lt;/code&gt; HTML comments?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
What follows are the "edited-by" HTML comments within the node.
&lt;code&gt;
&lt;!--2003-03-20 boo_radley - 2.1 - cross ref --&gt;
&lt;!-- 2003-03-05 - SDC BigLug - 2.0 - Updated and rewrote most --&gt;
&lt;/code&gt; 
Lots of new faqlet content.
&lt;code&gt;
&lt;!-- orginal content follows --&gt;

&lt;!-- 2003-03-05 - SDC BigLug - 2.0 - Updated and rewrote most --&gt;
&lt;/code&gt; 
Lots of old faqlet content.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I think we should comment that old content out, at least until [boo_radley] or [BigLug] is comfortable with the current content and they are willing to erase it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[pfaut] 2003-03-31 EST&lt;br /&gt;
Edited [id://72241].  As per [merlyn], the value for sinceunixtime is GMT (previously the node said it was not clear what timezone it was).  Also, the node query xml generator appears to return information for any node so I removed some text that stated it wouldn't return information for certain types of nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[boo_radley] 2003-03-24&lt;br /&gt;
Maybe Louis' new nodelet (explaining approval to anonymous monks) would get a link on the submit screen (only when an anonmonk submits)?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2003-03-22&lt;br /&gt;
[user settings] and "Nodelet nodelet"??  Those suck.  You meant [Nodelet settings].  (:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat] 2003-03-22 0743 CST&lt;br /&gt;
Yesterday I submitted four patches and a bugfix (I'm not perfect :) to bring you the [SiteDocClan nodelet].  It will show up in [User Settings] or the [Nodelet nodelet] for members of [SiteDocClan] where you can enable it.  It is simply a collection of links.  The /msgs link will have a number in front of it and it will be in bold if there are new messages.  The wikis will have a (*) next to them if they have been updated since you last read them.  Thank you [boo_radley] for changing the parent container type.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Mr. Muskrat] 2003-03-21 1140 CST&lt;br /&gt;
Would anyone be interesting in a [SiteDocClan] nodelet?  If so, I'll make a note in the [pmdev wiki] and start work on it.  &lt;b&gt;Added:&lt;/b&gt;  [Louis_Wu] pointed out his mention of [SiteDocClan] nodelet in the archives so I'll start work just as soon as I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Louis_Wu] 2003-03-21 PST&lt;br /&gt;
I'll take on the old Chatterbox FAQs.  Reduce node count, cross-link, polish explanations.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[boo_radley] 2003-03-20 PST&lt;br /&gt;
    [What is Consideration?] and [What nodelets are available on PerlMonks?] have been cross referenced. Comments welcome.
&lt;br/&gt;
Can someone take a look at :&lt;br/&gt;
[id://17611]&lt;br/&gt;
[id://17534]&lt;br/&gt;
[id://17434]&lt;br/&gt;
[id://17544]&lt;br/&gt;
[id://17989]&lt;br/&gt;
and see if the information is in [id://236794]? I'd like to reduce the chatterbox' faqlet count to just 236794. Some of it doesn't need to exist at all, "Using the Chatterbox: Linking" is entirely in "What shortcuts can I use for linking to other information?", and could just be a link off of 236794. &lt;br/&gt;
Cross referencing continues apace.&lt;br/&gt;
also :
[id://84115]
[id://84121]
[id://17441]
[id://17950]
[id://17371]&lt;br/&gt;
duplicated in [id://43037]?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[boo_radley] 2003-03-18 PST&lt;br /&gt;
mea culpa, mea maxima culpa :-)&lt;br/&gt;
Thanks, Louis. Anyway, all the placeholders are up, after adjusting the faqlet creation to not dispense xp on command. The only faqlets not with nodelets are the 'little levels', ones that don't garner special abilities. Should we put these all into one faqlet, or into separate ones for future possible power additions by pmdev?&lt;br/&gt;
Also bringing [jdporter] up to speed on sdc.&lt;br/&gt;
Note to self: Style guide still lists 'super-q' for crossref links.

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[Louis_Wu] 2003-03-18 PST&lt;br /&gt;
We're creating duplicate node names for the key nodes.  The following have/had duplicate faqlets.  I am fixing them now.
&lt;code&gt;
Newest Nodes
Cool Uses for Perl
Seekers of Perl Wisdom
Library
Craft
Meditations
Perl News
Reviews
Tutorials
&lt;/code&gt;
Fixed. I added 'faqlet' to the end of each title, so the [Newest Nodes] faqlet is now the [Newest Nodes faqlet]. :) BTW, [Meditations] didn't have a dupe. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[boo_radley] 2003-03-17 EST&lt;br /&gt;
BigLug : please strike the Chatterbox, Poll and Scratchpad entries from PM Tour in your indexer. They're duplicated elsewhere (Chatterbox section, Voting Booth and "How do I change my home node?" respectively)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[boo_radley] 2003-03-17 EST&lt;br /&gt;
I've stopped creating the placeholders for now... It looks like creating a sitefaqlet garners 1 xp, and I felt a little awkward about gaining xp for no good reason :-)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[BigLug] 2003-03-18 Aust (My Birthday!)&lt;br /&gt;
I've fixed [id://237057]...very very strange. It was a case of the unclosed A-href tags. I'd previously fixed non-closed a-name tags, but missed those. Hmmm .. very weird .. hope its not a gremlin somewhere....
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[BigLug] 2003-03-18 Aust (My Birthday!)&lt;br /&gt;
[boo_radley]: Yup, status of 'alpha' will currently not be indexed .. I'll add 'placeholder' sometime soon.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[boo_radley] 2003-03-17 EST&lt;br /&gt;
Also, [id://237057] has a link titled "Read this carefully before you post to make sure you do it right.", which leads to The Offering Plate section. While this is amusing ("answer your question, I can, but first you must cross my palm with siiiilverr"), I wonder if that was the initial intent.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[boo_radley] 2003-03-17 EST&lt;br /&gt;
my main pc at home had a power supply die, and over the course of the week, I've only been able to recover a few files from the old box. The upshot is that the cross referenced guide to the faqlets is pretty much inaccessible for time being. I've resigned to starting over.&lt;br/&gt;
Additionally, I'd like to fill in the missing faqlets with placeholders (empty faqlets) so that I can easily reference node ids when cross referencing. The Master Plan could reflect these placeholders with a status of 'empty' or 'placeholder' so that they don't get forgotten. Comments?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[pfaut] 2003-03-13 EST&lt;br /&gt;
I just added [id://242931].  Please review and /msg me with feedback.  I'd like to add something about the user settings option to disable JavaScript on home nodes but I still don't know what it does if anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[BigLug] 2003-03-06 Aust&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks [tye].&lt;br /&gt;
Can people take a look at the &lt;a href="?node_id=240586#masterplan"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Master Plan&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and check the status of their documents. I've fixed my script that generates [id://237040] so it works as documented. It will now not create links to 'alpha' documents, but it will create links to anything else (including 'beta', 'stable' and 'outdated'). Beta status will be marked (in a title attribute) in the index.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2003-03-05&lt;br /&gt;
The group that was "Site Documentation Clan" has been renamed [SiteDocClan] and there is a new group, [Site Documentation Clan] with a single member, [SiteDocClan].  This means that old links that used the node_id of the SDC will continue to work.  Other links (by title) will go to the new group which explains that it is defunct.  It also means that people can use old-style stuff like &lt;code&gt;/msg [site documentation clan] ...&lt;/code&gt; for a little while longer.  To deal with such messages, if any, see &lt;a href="?node=message%20inbox&amp;recipient=site+documentation+clan"&gt;Temp SDC Inbox&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So update instructions as appropriate.  Let me or [boo_radley] know when you want this wiki renamed to match.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Note that usergroups can have descriptive text.  See [gods] and [pmdev], for example.  You guys might want to check these and consider updates, though you'll have to get one of the [gods] to apply such.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[BigLug] 2003-03-06 Aust&lt;br /&gt;
OK, no probs on the no-index-on-small-FAQlets&lt;br /&gt;
Also the &lt;a href="?node_id-240586#styleguide"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Style Guide&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="?node_id-240586#masterplan"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Master Plan&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; have moved to the [id://240586]. Thanks for the new node [Vroom]. I've done this because the to-do was going to need archiving, which would effectivly archive the Masterplan.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2003-03-05&lt;br /&gt;
I agree that an index in short faqlets is counter productive.  Yes, you can't send a private message to a user named "_ _" without using square brackets.  The use of square brackets should be encouraged over using underscore.  In fact, I'd like to see it documented as "&lt;code&gt;/msg [user name] message&lt;/code&gt;" with a note that the brackets are optional if the user has no spaces in their name.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I think I figured out how to rename Site Documentation Clan that won't break stuff.  If someone wants to veto this move, speak up soon.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Louis_Wu] 2003-03-04 PST&lt;br /&gt;
I fixed the CB FAQ omission regarding messages to intra-spaced usernames.  I then updated the [id://20842] FAQ, and renamed the node, making the old node name  the second question asked by our ficticious reader.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[BigLug], this node is so short, I think an index would be counter-productive. People might think that there are more pages to read, because anchor links on a page that short seems silly. Opinions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[pfaut] 2003-03-04 EST &lt;br /&gt;
There are two ways I know of to send private messages to a user that has spaces in their name.  The first is to replace the spaces with underscores.  This probably won't work if the name also has underscores in it.  The second is to enclose the name in brackets like &lt;b&gt;&amp;#91;Site Documentation Clan&amp;#93;&lt;/b&gt;.  I think this is all spelled out in the CB FAQ (at least the first way is).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BTW, I sent a message to [Mr. Muskrat] on behalf of the group after seeing all his messages in the inbox: "The [Site Documentation Clan] would like to thank you for your excellent feedback and complement you on your proofreading skills."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[BigLug] 2003-03-05 Aust &lt;br /&gt;
Just fixed [id://17558] as per [podmaster]'s request in the &lt;a href ="index.pl?node=message%20inbox&amp;recipient=17342"&gt;SDC Inbox&lt;/a&gt;. People in the CB seem happy with it, but take a look and see if there's any glaring errors or omissions. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[BigLug] 2003-03-05 Aust &lt;br /&gt;
I've deleted a couple of Wiki-type messages from the &lt;a href ="index.pl?node=message%20inbox&amp;recipient=17342"&gt;SDC Inbox&lt;/a&gt; and have 'archived' messages I've dealt with. Someone who's more au fait with the XML generators needs to take a look at the two message there related to the XML generator. I'm taking a look at [podmaster]'s post concerning readmore tags. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[BigLug] 2003-03-05 Aust &lt;br /&gt;
Looks great. Just a few style things: need a title at the top in H1 tags and needs an index. I'd also love to get a description of each client in there, maybe we should /msg each client's author and get them to submit one?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Note to all:&lt;/b&gt; When a page says "If you know of others, /msg any Site Documentation Clan member" it should say "/msg Site Documentation Clan", but how do they message the clan as we have a multiple-word-nickname? Can we change our name to SiteDocClan? Please? I'm sure theres a way to message the current name but I normally wouldn't be bothered figuring out how to do it, just to report a doc error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[pfaut] 2003-03-04 EST &lt;br /&gt;
I agree with [tye].  Also, the java chatterbox client is available from sourceforge.  There ought to be some mention of this. I find it much easier to run as a standalone app than as an applet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2003-03-04&lt;br /&gt;
Looks great, [Louis_Wu].  I'd move "Windows Only" to the end.  This is not because I dislike Windows, but because I prefer portable solutions.  If we end up with some Unix-only or Linux-only clients, then we can have a flame fest on which set to list first. ;)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Louis_Wu] 2003-03-03 PST&lt;br /&gt;
I've reformatted [id://20842] What did I miss? What do you think?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[BigLug] 2003-03-04 Aust&lt;br /&gt;
Just used [pfaut]'s list of FAQlets to update the MasterPlan (and by default the [id://237040] index.) There shouldn't be any FAQlets left out in the cold now. Its amazing how little of our MasterPlan we have left to write. Sure there's a lot of updating that needs doing, but I'm amazed how little has to be done! &amp;lt;grin&amp;gt; If you look at the MasterPlan (or at the [id://237040]) and think I've put something in the wrong category, feel free to change it. I've added a new section 'All in Moderation' which is about (drumroll...) Moderation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[BigLug] 2003-03-04 Aust&lt;br /&gt;
Changed the one's I'd made to 237040. Updated the Style Guide also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[pfaut] 2003-03-03 EST &lt;br /&gt;
We made all the 'Back to PerlMonks FAQ' links to the old FAQ page by ID. We need to go change them all from 17316 to 237040 now or link by name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good ideas by [BigLug]. Yes, the information nodelet ought to be standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[boo_radley] 2003-03-04 &lt;br /&gt;
The faqlet overview is now the [PerlMonks FAQ]. You may find the old version at [The Old Perl Monks FAQ]. I have posted a notice to the monstery at large.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[BigLug], 2003-03-04 Aust&lt;br /&gt;
Just turned on the 'Information' Nodelet and was quite surprised. This is a nodelet that should be part of the default nodelet set. However before I petition for that, I'd like to petition for a few other things:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I suggest the following links go in it:
   &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;[id://972] -- Made editable by SiteDocClan and updated. Basically its a 'here's what its all about' page.
      &lt;li&gt;[id://174051] -- Who wrote this? (Or who posted it as an FAQlet?)
      &lt;li&gt;[id://237040] -- Renamed 'PerlMonks FAQ' as per below
      &lt;li&gt;[http://www.perldoc.org/|Perl Reference Library] (Offsite) -- Lets stop linking to the local (outdated) version!
      &lt;li&gt;[id://382|Perl FAQ]
   &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'd like to rename [id://237040] to 'PerlMonks FAQ' -- its more 'FAQ'like than the current [id://17316]
&lt;li&gt;At the same time I'd rename [id://17316] to 'PerlMonks FAQ Index'
&lt;li&gt;To ensure that links aren't broken, we'd need to set up a new node called 'Perl Monks FAQ' that would either:
   &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Alias the above mentioned 'PerlMonks FAQ', or
   &lt;li&gt;Say something like "The PerlMonks FAQ can now be found at 'PerlMonks FAQ'. We've removed the space."
   &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lets also see 'PerlMonks FAQ' and 'Outside Links' in the main site navigation
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[boo_radley], 2003-03-02 EST&lt;br /&gt; once again, here's the &lt;a href ="index.pl?node=message%20inbox&amp;recipient=17342"&gt;SDC Inbox&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;[id://240052|archived the wiki].
&lt;/p&gt;
</field>
</data>
</node>
