<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="331288" title="editors' wiki through 2004-01-30" created="2004-02-23 22:25:28" updated="2005-08-02 09:42:45">
<type id="68046">
wiki</type>
<author id="142755">
tye&amp;nbsp;</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
...continued from [id://74283]
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt; 
[BazB] 2004-01-30&lt;br /&gt; 
I've unconsidered (again) the root of [Wassercrats] infamous node.&lt;br /&gt; 
There was also a futher reply from [Wassercrats] which had been considered - I unconsidered that too.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 

Whilst I (and most of the many others by the sounds of things) wish the thread in question would just go away, following discussion between [tye] and myself in the CB sometime ago (after the 2nd or 3rd consideration of the node) it was seems that the approach is to just ignore the thread, unconsidering if need be. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;hr /&gt; 


&lt;p&gt; 
[dvergin] 2004-01-26&lt;br /&gt; 
In response to [BazB]'s questions below: &lt;br /&gt; 
[Editor Requests] is a remnant of the early days at Perl Monks. It is not nearly as important as it once was. For example: folks can edit their own root nodes and much of the load originally handled through [Editor Requests] is now taken care of promptly and effectively by the consideration process. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
Wanting a niche where I could contribute to the good of the order, I stumbled across [Editor Requests] some time back at a point when there were several outstanding requests. It seemed a nice place to be of help, so in the clever guise of the ER Hobbit, I quietly began handling the items posted there. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
It has been a long time since the ER load was very heavy. And it is even lighter recently since people can edit their own root nodes. So there isn't much reason for more than one person to watch the queue (if that person checks regularly -- I have a script that checks for me every 20 minutes whenever I am on line). Still, if you see an unanswered request there and want to handle it, go ahead. Don't worry that it will plunge my life into meaningless oblivion. ;-) 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
ER items do not automatically appear in [Nodes Requiring Editing]. Sometimes I log on to discover an ER item that has already been separately submitted for consideration and handled. Other times, I handle an ER request by submitting a node for consideration myself. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
FWIW: A few thoughts regarding having ER items automatically appear in [Nodes Requiring Editing]. 
&lt;ol&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;Doing so would effectively give *all* participants the right to submit items to NRE -- as you know, this power is currently reserved for monks of a certain level (level 5?) or above. Note that while ER is intended to be for requests regarding one's own nodes, this is not programatically enforced. 
&lt;li&gt;Related point: not every request in ER is appropriate fodder for NRE. Both in my experience and in the 200 or so answered ER items that were there when I began service there, it regularly happens that the appropriate response is advice to the petitioner, action a bit different from the actual request, or an explanation to the petitioner that their request is impractical or against policy. 
&lt;li&gt;My impression is that in practice, the ER process often involves more hand-holding than Consideration -- specifically, if a NRE request is denied, there is generally no explanation to the petitioner -- if an ER request is denied, I try to provide a friendly and helpful explanation to the petitioner. 
&lt;li&gt;It is not uncommon for an ER item to be much longer than NRE notes are. The layout and flow of the NRE page might suffer. 
&lt;/ol&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
Regards,&lt;br /&gt; 
TERH 
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;hr&gt; 

&lt;p&gt; 
[BazB] 2004-01-26&lt;br&gt; 
Excuse me if this another question that's already been answered, but what is the situation with [Editor Requests]?&lt;br&gt; 
Does [dvergin|The ER Hobbit] deal with all ERs, do ERs appear in [nodes requiring editing], or is another page that needs regular checking?&lt;br&gt; 
If ERs don't appear in [nodes requiring editing], could the [pmdev]ils change that? 
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;hr&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[castaway] 2004-01-25&lt;br /&gt; 
[ysth] was concerned that the contents of [What is True and False in Perl?] are somewhat misleading (implies that stringification actually occurs when checking for truth). This was linked to on the Tutorials page under the 'Getting started with Perl' section. Since there is another 'What is truth' link down in the next section under variables, I've just removed the link. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
[BazB] 2004-01-23.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; 

What's happening with [id://322280]?&lt;br&gt; 
It's under consideration pending the [chanio|author] reposting it elsewhere, apparently.&lt;br&gt; 
[chanio] has linked to it from [id://322499] which confuses things - not to mention that there are loads of delete votes too...&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; 

&lt;code&gt;Move [ ] edit [ ] delete [ ] look confused [X]&lt;/code&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;hr&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[castaway] 2004-01-15&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;i&gt;[castaway] thwacks [theorbtwo] for joining so many groups ;)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 
I'd prefer it to be changed to not be able to attempt to /msg Anony Monk, for the correctness of the thing. If some visual clue is needed to show when an edit has actually taken place, how about the result just shows the actual node, and not the edit box again? With a bold 'node updated' underneath, and then the box for /msg, if appropriate? 
&lt;p&gt; 
(Just cos we've gotten used to visual clues, doesn't mean we can't get used to other ones ,) 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2004-01-15&lt;br /&gt; 
Thanks, [theorbtwo] for the patch to not show the "/msg AnonymousMonk I change your node &amp;#91;id://...&amp;#93;" in theh case of AnonymousMonk.  I'd rather keep the form field for the consistancy of visual cues (it is my primary cue that I've committed the changes and not just previewed).  Perhaps just change the message text in the case of AnonyMonk?  "/msg AnonymousMonk You can't receive messages"?  Oppinions? 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[theorbtwo] 2004-01-15&lt;br /&gt; 
Allo, all.  I've just been made an [editor], so please, thwack me if I get too far out of line.  I'm purtiularly looking for editor-related dev work that needs doing, and I've got a mass-move script that needs testing, so if you see any places where it's approprate (in purticular, where the wrong dupe got reaped, or where both dupes have threads under them), please, let me know, so I can do some more testing, and release it.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Relatedly, the one known bug I think might really be a bug in [editor's hall of mirrors and trickery|ehomt].  If there's a N &gt; C &gt; G (where G is the grandchild of N by way of C), and C is moved to a new root node, the "in thread" link of G does not get changed correctly.  Has anybody else seen this?  Is it worth fixing?&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Like I said before, I'm looking for things that the [editors] would find useful, so point them out to me.  Editor's signatures and not showing a /msg field for anonymonks is on my list right now. 
&lt;hr /&gt; 


&lt;p&gt;[BazB] 2004-01-11.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt; 
Could someone tell me how one moves a post from one section to another, after it has been approved? I've tried unapproving a post, expecting the "Move to..." dropdown to appear, but no luck. 
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Update:&lt;/b&gt; sorry everyone, ignore me: I think it must be a caching error on my part. Doh. 
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;hr&gt; 

&lt;P&gt;[footpad], 28 Dec 2003 . o O ( /me agrees with [tye] ).&lt;/P&gt;   
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2003-12-25&lt;br /&gt; 
It belongs on the author's home node.  What belongs elsewhere is covered in [id://316791]. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[dvergin], 2003-12-25&lt;br /&gt; 
Regarding [id://316525]: I agree in part. Tutorials doesn't seem quite right. [id://316525|OTOH] only a few of the items are PM specific (AM, CB, PM, SoPW). So it doesn't seem like it should go with site-specific stuff. It's actually just a brief hacker's acronym guide with a few PMish items thrown in. Yes. Worth saving. But where to put it? Hmmm... 
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;hr /&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[jeffa], 2003-12-25&lt;br /&gt; 
[id://316525] has been "nominated" for Tutorials. While i agree that this is a node worth 
"keeping", shouldn't it belong somewhere in SiteDocs instead? I ask this because it is a 
PM specific node - almost a FAQ item even. Thoughts? 
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;hr /&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[ybiC], 2003-12-14&lt;br /&gt; 
Thanks for your thoughts, [castaway]. 8^) 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
Having since learned &lt;i&gt;(been reminded?)&lt;/i&gt; that Editorial Delete was originally introduced to streamline removal of duplicates, I don't strongly disagree with "&lt;i&gt;delete uncalled for&lt;/i&gt;". 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Determining trollism is, of course, a highly subjective matter. &amp;nbsp; My own criteria include &lt;tt&gt;lack of substantiave content&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;inflammatory&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;anonymous&lt;/tt&gt; and  &lt;tt&gt;1337-ness&lt;/tt&gt; and doubtless a few others that slip me atm. &amp;nbsp; So to me, those two posts seemed strongly borderline troll-ish, the first less-so, the second moreso. &amp;nbsp; But I certainly respect you and others holding different qualifiers. &amp;nbsp; discussion(open)++ 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
As for editors being here to only carry out the wishes of the masses, I respectfully disagree, albeit within substantial limits. &amp;nbsp; I seem to be in good company, as other respected monks/editors have noted here in the EW. &amp;nbsp;  Not that diverse approaches and opinions are any less healthy in this realm than in others, eh? 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
I really like something mentioned in the CB shortly after this fracus arose - idea of converting Editor Deletion to Editor Reaping. &amp;nbsp; Anyways, apologies if I'm just (windjamm|blowgutt)ing here, sers and brers. &amp;nbsp; %^p 
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2003-12-12&lt;br /&gt; 
Personally, I think the physical delete was uncalled for, a normal delete would have done.. And if enough people cared, and voted keep, which they did, then they should have been kept. Remember, we're here to carry out the wishes of the majority (as defined by the system), and not to do what *we* personally want. I sometimes dont edit nodes that are in [nodes requiring editing], because I dont agree with the consensus, but I also do not remove the consideration, as surely someone else will.. &lt;br /&gt; 
(The first of those nodes wasnt trollish, in my opinion (if memory serves correctly)) 
&lt;hr /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[ybiC], 2003-12-12&lt;br /&gt; 
Both "&lt;i&gt;[id://313835]&lt;/i&gt;" and "&lt;i&gt;[id://313881]&lt;/i&gt;" look significantly trollish to me. &amp;nbsp; So would anymonk else not feel bad if they were both Editorially deleted? &amp;nbsp; I don't feel strongly about this, but posting anonymously adds to their trollosity. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
If they are indeed seen as trollish by the community-at-large, then saying so explicitely in the consideration might facilitate quicker action. &amp;nbsp; "&lt;i&gt;Devoid of content&lt;/i&gt;" and "&lt;i&gt;profanity&lt;/i&gt;" don't come across as clearly as "&lt;i&gt;Troll? Vote delete to delete&lt;/i&gt;" or somesuch. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
My thoughts, worth exactly what you paid for them. 
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;kudra, 2003-12-12&lt;br /&gt; 
Nodes are not automatically reaped if they have 2 or more keep votes. 
This is in recognition of the itchy trigger finger you described. 
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[thelenm], 2003-12-11&lt;br /&gt; 
Hi [Chady], and welcome!  You know, I think "delete" votes are often noise. :-)  Lots of monks seem to have itchy delete fingers in general.  But regardless of that, in this case, it looks like the overwhelming consensus (now 2/4/20) is to delete the node.  I thought that nodes were automatically reaped when they received a certain number of delete votes and had a negative reputation.  Someone who knows: is that not true? 

&lt;p&gt;[Chady], 2003-12-11&lt;br /&gt; 
Hello guys, I'm new here, so here goes some questions:&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;How much should I use my own judgement in applying consideration requests? for example, there's [id://313881] which is considered for deletion for containing profanity. For now, votes stand like so, edit:3 keep:2 del:14. One could either edit out the offensive word, or delete, but there are edit and keep votes, which sometimes can be noise. So how do you judge against that, and where's the line? how many votes does it require to assume a certain action? &lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;!-- I think it needs an hr here? dunno, never got the hang of this. --&gt; 
&lt;hr /&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2003-11-29&lt;br /&gt; 
I've unconsidered a few nodes at what I thought was that stage, only to come back later, find them reconsidered, and deleted (or whatever) .. While I'm playing around with editing considerations (should be finished), I wonder if there's any call for a field which shows that something has already been considered once, and the outcome. (Though that'll probably need new db fields, since currently 'unconsider' removes the rows pertaining to the consideration (text and votes) completely. Hmm, probably too much. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[Corion], 2003-11-20&lt;br /&gt; 
I unconsider such "tied" nodes. If there is no "clear enough" voting in either direction and "enough" votes (say, 20) have ammassed, I feel that no consensus can be found without more discussion than what is possible in the consideration box. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[ybiC], 2003-11-20&lt;br /&gt; 
What do janitors think about considered nodes like "&lt;tt&gt;[id://308650]&lt;/tt&gt;"? &amp;nbsp; It was considered as "&lt;tt&gt;OT?&lt;/tt&gt;", and stands at &lt;tt&gt;edit:3 keep:10 del:7&lt;/tt&gt; roughly 20 hours after post. &amp;nbsp; My inclination is to unconsider it, but am curious/interested in others' thoughts. 
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[thelenm], 2003-10-21&lt;br /&gt; 
I tend to leave everything as is except when a node has been considered or when there's an obvious change that needs to be made (like adding code tags).  I do that partly because I'm still fairly new and feeling out the territory, but mostly because I don't like changing anything about other people's posts unless there is an explicit need to do so.  (Personally, I also like all the "Re"s and wouldn't like it if someone changed them in a post of mine, so I can see [PodMaster]'s viewpoint, but I don't think I'd ever flame someone for it. :-) 
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[BazB], 2003-10-21&lt;br /&gt; 
I'll stick with October for now :-)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 

I've had further msg's with [PodMaster] and he considers the number of "Re"s in a node's title to be an integral part of the nodes contents and should not be altered except following consideration.&lt;br /&gt; 
A slightly odd view point IMO. Just a warning to other [editors]. 
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt; 
Which brings me onto the subject of altering unconsidered nodes.&lt;br/&gt; 
I checked with other [editors] before I started editing my first node and the concensus of opinion is that minor cleanups are OK.&lt;br /&gt; 
I'd like to be "proactive" (buzzword! :-) and fix things before they're considered (formatting mostly).&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt; 
I think I'll steer clear of titles for now :-) 
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt; 
BTW, I did read the various threads on automagical Re: compression. 
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2003-10-21&lt;br /&gt; 
Some [editors] seem to be in December already, do tell me the trick.. (Actually I'd prefer November.. :) 
&lt;p/&gt; 
&lt;p /&gt;[dvergin], &lt;strike&gt;2003-12-05&lt;/strike&gt; 2003-10-20 &lt;small&gt;(dratted copy-and-paste!)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 
BazB mused: &amp;nbsp; "&lt;i&gt;...or fix them anonymously?&lt;/i&gt;" 
&lt;p /&gt; 
While it is not the preferred practice, it is certainly possible to edit a node and leave no visible trail. But do remember that any editor can click the "history" link in the Editors Nodelet to get a log of edits (and their perpetrators) to the node in question. 

&lt;p/&gt;[broquaint], &lt;strike&gt;2003-12-05&lt;/strike&gt; 2003-10-20 
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt; 
Did I, in fact, break some unwritten law that I didn't know about? 
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; 

There's nothing strictly wrong with shortening an ever-growing title in an endless debate, but unless it's been considered then they're fine to be left alone to grow in the wild. Although it's fine to consider/edit-if-necessary new nodes that have excessively long titles. 

&lt;p/&gt; 

&lt;p&gt; Grumbling [BazB], 2003-10-20&lt;br /&gt; 
I've just taken a pretty out-of-proportion flaming from [PodMaster] over changing the titles for [id://300374] and [id://300373]. 
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt; 
Is this something I should expect more of? &lt;br&gt; 
It was a trival change, which I commented, which tidied things up with negligible effort. 
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Should just ignore fixing minor problems such as that, or fix them anonymously? 
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt; 
Did I, in fact, break some unwritten law that I didn't know about?&lt;br /&gt; 
Enlightenment welcomed. 
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;hr&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2003-10-16&lt;br /&gt; 
That sounds like a job for an extra button on the editors nodelet to me.. Since we're chosen/vetted I would hope we would be trusted enough to do such a thing, maybe something that needs at least 3 editor votes like the DB-delete function. *hmm* 
&lt;p/&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
[broquaint], 2003-10-16&lt;br/&gt; 

That does indeed require the powers of the [gods] as it necessitates changing a field in the database which designates the author of the node. 
&lt;p/&gt; 

&lt;p&gt; 
[BazB], 2003-10-15, 22:51 GMT+1.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; 

Quick question that might be useful in future: I'm new to this whole [editor] gaff, so I might be missing something, however:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; 

Is it within an [editor]'s power to re-assign authorship of nodes (as with [id://299508] recently), or does that require one of the [Gods] to rummage around in the DB?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; 

Answers here and/or on a /msg, please :-) 

&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;hr&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2003-10-15&lt;br /&gt; 
Ok, maybe I'm just going slightly insane.. :) 
&lt;p&gt; 
That *was* my first ever attempt at using a Wiki tho, yippee! :) 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[Corion], 2003-10-15&lt;br /&gt; 
This is weird - for me, the removal of the CUFP-approval worked directly and afterwards the approval for Meditations worked fine... Strange ... 
&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2003-10-15&lt;br /&gt; 
I attempted to move [id://298682] from CUFP to Meditations, by unapproving, moving, then reapproving, ([theorbtwo] suggested this was how to do it).. However it now appears to be moved, but ignores my attempts to re-approve it. Im wondering if this is another of those cases where something is approved but not showing as such, or its really not approved? Something is broken there anyhow.. 
&lt;p&gt; 
.. And the editors nodelet is still showing 'remove approval from CUFP', although the node claims to be in Meditations, what fun. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[Corion], 2003-09-25&lt;br /&gt; 
[id://294046] is orphaned and I don't know a good place where to reparent it - it corrected a QandAAnswer that was dangerously wrong and I killed that answer. [davido] dosen't mind if his reply gets deleted, so I propose it gets a hard delete (not reaped due to the XP penalty which I would find uncalled for in this case). 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2003-09-01&lt;br /&gt; 
There is no "move to module reviews". 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[dvergin], 2003-08-31&lt;br /&gt; 
jeffa, Editors can edit the [Tutorials] page. But you have to go to the [id://91810] page and *then* click on 'edit' in the Editors Nodelet. If you attempt to edit the standard [id://954] page, you will be refused access. 
&lt;hr /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[jeffa], 2003-08-30&lt;br /&gt; 
I unconsidered [id://287793] - [LAI] requested it be moved to Tutorials and 
(with my keep vote) it was tied at 5 edit 5 keep. It's short, it's sweet, i 
say move it to Module Reviews instead. Question: is [footpad] still in charge of 
updating the Tutorials page? It's time for another update, methinks, and if 
no-one else is dying to do it, i'll get in there and make the changes ... do i have to be a member of SiteDocClan? 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2003-08-10&lt;br /&gt; 
No!  Root nodes are not replies to the section that they are in so that is *not* the way to move between sections.  If you go back in the wiki a ways you'll see instruction that you have to remove all approvals before moving a node between sections. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[dws], 2003-08-10&lt;br /&gt; 
I'm feeling dense today, and would appreciate someone pointing me to whatever instructions there are for moving a top-level post from Meditations to SoPW. 
It would seem that I need a node id for SoPW to the the hall of mirrors. 
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2003-07-17&lt;br /&gt; 
Thanks, [dvergin].  The problem was that I didn't belong to [editors] due to testing the patches. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
I'm a little shocked to see that two editors voted to nuke [id://273742].  What, we can't be humorous anymore?  I'm not sure I get the joke, but I certainly don't see what harm the node was causing. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[dvergin], 2003-07-17&lt;br /&gt; 
FWIW: Clicking 'edit' on the [Tutorials Source] page works for this ungodly editor. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2003-07-17&lt;br /&gt; 
Note that we can now move items *out* of [Perl News] and we can move nodes into and out of [Tutorials] (and only [editors] can do these 3 things).  &lt;b&gt;However&lt;/b&gt;, you don't move something into Tutorials unless it is linked from [Tutorials source].  It looks like only [gods] have access to that at the moment (strange, it didn't used to be that way, no?). 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
So we can move stuff already in [Tutorials] so that they show up as being tutorials (not meditations).  However, [super search] won't find them as meditations any more (it is either or here).  I'd rather great meditations get reposted as tutorials if people think they are that good (with updates suggested in replies).  But that doesn't always need to happen and we currently have a lot of mediations on the tutorials page. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
So you should probably shouldn't move anything into [Tutorials] until we've discussed this some more.  I've gotta run... 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 

&lt;p/&gt;[broquaint], 2003-07-17&lt;br/&gt; 
WRT &lt;i&gt;"Re: (duplicate) ..."&lt;/i&gt; that was just clueless monks replying to a node I'd marked with '(duplicate)' which I guess wasn't explicit enough, so have now uppercased the marking (see. [id://275135]) and moved all the offending nodes to the correct parent. 
&lt;p/&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2003-07-17&lt;br /&gt; 
Reaped nodes are fine (no need to unreap them, I've decided). I was hoping to reduce the number of new replies required, but reducing it by 1 doesn't help much. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
BTW, please don't use a retitle-thread tool to add "(duplicate)" to a title.  I saw a "Re: (duplicate) ..." node and thought "The fool!", but then it occurred to me that an editor overusing a thread retitler could be to blame. (: 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 

&lt;p&gt; 
[jeffa] 2003-07-17 &lt;br /&gt; 
Thanks [tye]. I digged up a few myself. These have no replies to them: [id://138287], [id://137720], [id://140694], [id://141035], and [id://139250]. 
The last one is a root node SoPW by AnonyMonk. I don't know which is better, to 
find reaped nodes with no replies and add some, or just find reaped nodes with 
replies already attached. Either way, i am not partial to any of these nodes, so do what thou (we) wilt. ;) 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;hr /&gt; 


&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2003-07-16&lt;br /&gt; 
I usually edit based on my judgement more than based on votes.  I don't edit content (except at the author's request).  I only edit formatting and titles.  And I don't edit formatting that isn't at least somewhat "a hazard to navigation".  So I won't "fix" a node that uses POD or is all in one big CODE tag if it pretty much looks "ok" (unless it is the author that requested the change), because down that road lies madness and way too much work. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
I don't usually much care what the vote is on such things.  I pay attention to votes on requests to move to a new section or perhaps if an editor did the consideration rather than just making the edit because they felt it was a border-line case (of if I think it is a border-line case). 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
I nominate nodes [id://25793] and [id://53966] for testing.  If no better candidates crop up, then I *might* (haven't decided) unreap them and make the latter owned by AnonyMonk (so no /msg's are sent if we reply). 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
I also considered [id://51025] because (nearly?) every node in it is owned by an editor and there are several interesting title munging in there.  But if there is risk of losing title information, we shouldn't test with it. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[thelenm], 2003-07-16&lt;br /&gt; 
I think having a "fire building" thread or two would be very useful, for me at least.  Time to go on a hunt for really old, bonehead threads?  Of course, if we add replies to an old thread, they'll show up in [Newest Nodes] and maybe attract non-bonehead replies.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Oh, by the way, another question: is there any particular ratio or number of "edit" versus "keep" votes that you look for before editing a node in [Nodes Requiring Editing]?  I guess it's pretty much left up to our own judgment? 
&lt;hr /&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2003-07-16&lt;br /&gt; 
If there aren't any replies by non-editors than it is pretty much locked.  I suppose random people could add replies to some really old thread, but then it just takes 3 of us to take care of that.  There is no "lock" feature so unless you plan to write one over the weekend... (: 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 

&lt;p&gt; 
[jeffa] 2003-07-16 &lt;br /&gt; 
Oops, that what i get for trying to be clever and writing a script to can the 
date and HTML that formats this blurb. I'll see if i can find such a root node. 
Should (can) the root node and it's threads be easily locked for editor's 
only? 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;hr /&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2003-07-16&lt;br /&gt; 
Huh? "[jeffa] 2003-16-07" is not a date format used anywhere in the world, is it? 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
For the testing of moving nodes, [ar0n] and [tye|I] used the "threads" of [ar0n] and [tye] ([super search] for just replies to just users if you like).  But those won't work well for testing retitling. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
I think I might prefer to use some existing old thread(s) if appropriate one(s) can be found.  Such as some [editors]' really old bone-head root node that may not have even ever got a reply (that we can add replies to if needed). (: 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 

&lt;p&gt; 
[jeffa] 2003-16-07 &lt;br /&gt; 
[Corion]++ for [id://274951]. What does everyone think about having a 
"fire building"? That is, a thread that contains dummy nodes that new editors 
can practice on. Maybe even two threads for the purpose of moving nodes. 
Just a thought. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;hr /&gt; 

&lt;p&gt; 
[thelenm], 2003-07-16&lt;br /&gt; 
Reading all the way through the Wiki and taking notes sounds like a great way to learn.  Thanks for all your help, everyone!  I'm sure I'll have more questions as I go.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt; 
[jeffa] 2003-16-07 &lt;br /&gt; 
Welcome to the crew [thelenm] ... i learned a few [editor] tricks by 
&lt;strike&gt;bugging [tye] with lots of /msg's&lt;/strike&gt; 
cleaning up nodes listed at [id://28877]. Edit the "easy ones" first: ones 
that need code tags, readmore tags, add that missing &amp;lt;/ul&gt; tag, etc. Changing 
titles requires a bit more work, as you really need to change all title in 
thread. Moving nodes obviously can be a little tricky. Last night i went all the 
way back to the [id://91826|oldest archived editor wiki] and i am currently 
working my way to this point, making notes as a i go. I recommend you do the 
same. :) Oh ... and i guess i should stop hitting the Delete button ... i have 
been using it liberally thinking it was magic chicken blood or something. :/ 
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], 2003-07-15&lt;br /&gt; 
I'm not sure where it is documented, but the Delete button on the Editors Nodelet is a hard database delete and it needs ?three? editors before a node is erased.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If a node has been edited, I either unconsider it or mark it as done in [Nodes requiring editing|nre].&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reaping has some documentation, I think in the Voting FAQ (too lazy now, sorry)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most work as a [editors|janitor] consists of cleaning up ugly/missing formatting and quickly marking the "right" dupe (that is, a dupe without replies) as such, so that noone feels compelled to reply to them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Do we have a Editors FAQ where this stuff is collected?&lt;/i&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[thelenm], 2003-07-15&lt;br /&gt; 
As a brand-new member of [editors], I've been lurking without touching for a little while, but I'd like to help out however I can.  Should I ask my dumb questions here on the Wiki? :-)&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;My first question is about the node [jeffa] and [tye] are discussing... when viewing it, I see an "unconsider" option.  Since the node has been reparented, is unconsidering it the right thing to do now?&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Another question I have is about how nodes get reaped... are they automatically reaped after receiving a certain number of "delete" votes and/or a negative reputation?  Or does an editor need to choose "Delete" on the Editors Nodelet?&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, what would you say is the easiest way for me to help out, given that I want to be useful but don't want to break anything I'm not familiar with?  Thanks for humoring me, all.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;hr /&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2003-07-14&lt;br /&gt; 
[Re-root notes] does this very automatically (but you can't see this node).  I thought ehomat took care of it (most of the time?) but also knew there were bugs with it.  There were only two mis-rooted notes so I do think ehomat often gets this right. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
There is a patch that changes ehomat so that it moves all replies from one node to another (and this also fixes some bugs in the current ehomat), which would make fixing duplicates with lots of replies on each side much easier.  It is on my list of patches to test/apply.  One problem is that I don't want to prevent reparenting of nodes that have no current parent and I don't really want two ehomat-like tools.  So I'll probably end up patching some more as well. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
[jeffa] 2003-07-14&lt;br/&gt; 
I moved [id://274012] to [id://274004] and the former had a reply, 
[id://274014]. This reply's 'in thread' still points to the original (reaped) 
root node ([id://274010]) and not [id://274004]. Last time i did this, [tye] 
fixed it ... but i am curious to know if there is a better way ... (not that 
[tye] does a bad job, of course ;)) 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 


&lt;P&gt;[footpad], 16 Jun 2003&lt;br /&gt; 
Greetings!  I've just updated the tutorials and added the ones from the list below.  (Sorry for the delay; life has been, um, "real.") 

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2003-06-10&lt;br /&gt; 
I don't see any value in preventing people from providing translations.  As for the title change, you can certainly /msg the author and request them to make it if you don't feel comfortable doing it, but I don't think we should be very shy about changing titles, especially for tutorials.  The linking style proposed looks fine to me.  I would have just put the links in one line labeled by standard two-letter codes for languages, but that is probably too terse. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
We handle quality pretty much like we always do; if there is a problem and anyone cares, then someone will speak up.  If a lot of translations start getting done, then someone should volunteer to create an index for a specific language.  I'd just do it as a regular tutorial and link to it from the main tutorials page. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[dvergin|ER Hobbit], 2003-06-09 -- late night&lt;br /&gt; 
[kudra] asks in the CB if there has been some discussion of translations and continues, "Given that all the content except for a few tutorials is in English, I'm not really seeing the benefit of translated welcome pages". &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;I am not aware of any prior discussion of this topic. The sole prompting for the following post was the two requests by [monsieur_champs] in [Editor Requests] that his translations be linked to from the English originals.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[dvergin|ER Hobbit], 2003-06-09&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;b&gt;Update:&lt;/b&gt; [monsieur_champs] has submitted another translation called [id://264471] and asked in [Editor Requests] that it also be linked in the same manner. Read on... 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
I am inclined to implement the [Editor Requests|Editor Request] in [id://264421] but thought I'd check in with the clan first since it potentially involves a matter of policy and style that could easily propagate to other documentation-type nodes. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
What about issues of quality? Do we have a second reader of (in this case) Portuguese? Or do we just post and respond later if there are reports of inaccuracy? Or perhaps if no fluent reader responds to the translated post with approval, I could post a request for appraisal as a response to the translated node. Or we could publish an appeal for people willing to screen translations.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
Back to the specific request (update: request&lt;u&gt;s&lt;/u&gt;)If I have your support to proceed with this, the best place for such translation links, I suppose, would be at the top of the original node where they would be spotted readily by an ESL reader. The trick would be to do it so that as other translations become available it would make a neat, non-distracting list at the top of the original. Right-justified maybe as [monsieur_champs] has done at the top of his translation -- so eventualy (as other translations become available) it might display as: 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p align="center"&gt;- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;h3 class="other"&gt;Welcome to the&lt;br /&gt;Monastery! Make&lt;br /&gt;yourself at home.&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span class="attribution"&gt; by &lt;u&gt;newrisedesigns&lt;/u&gt; on  Jun 20,&lt;br /&gt;2002 at 04:58&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="addlinks"&gt;(&amp;nbsp;&lt;u&gt;print&lt;/u&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;u&gt;w/&amp;nbsp;replies&lt;/u&gt;,&lt;br /&gt; &lt;u&gt;xml&lt;/u&gt;&amp;nbsp;)&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;p align="right"&gt;&lt;small&gt; 
[264333|Tradu&amp;ccedil;&amp;atilde;o Em Portugu&amp;ecirc;s]&lt;br /&gt; 
[999999|&amp;Uuml;bersetzt in Deutschen]&lt;br /&gt; 
[999999|Tradotto in Italiano] 
&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Monastery. We are glad you have come to join us. The monastery is spacious, etc. etc...&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p align="center"&gt;- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
What say you all and sundry? What about this specific request? What about a general policy? 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;hr /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[Corion], 2003-05-20&lt;br /&gt; 
Fixed the rest of the thread (even though I had to specify all node ids separately, but it's still better than doing it manually :-) ). I also modified the code below to exclude the &lt;tt&gt;(was: ...)&lt;/tt&gt; stuff. 
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2003-05-19&lt;br /&gt; 
I fixed the root node based on the consideration.  [Corion], please fix the rest of the thread. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[Corion], 2003-05-18&lt;br /&gt; 
Yes, that was the thread I let the program loose on, I forgot to mention this. Straight retitling is the better solution, as these titles _are_ a bit long (this I see with the fresh mind of the morning instead of the clouded late-night mind that wrote the below script :-) ). 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2003-05-17&lt;br /&gt; 
I see we have a thread using titles like "Typing square brackets in the monastery(was: Typing square brackets in the monistary)".  I don't see any value in documenting for prosperity the orginal typo, especially in such a verbose way.  I'd rather leave the original typo in place if it is so important rather than have such long titles.  I don't see much value in documenting original titles, in general.  And I dislike including the original (presumably bad) title in the new title.  If there is something important about the old title, then my preference would be something like: 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Edit by [tye], retitled from "Typing square brackets in the monistary"&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
instead. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[Corion], 2003-05-17&lt;br /&gt; 
I wrote a bulk node retitler, appended below. It retitles the given node (as node_id) and all nodes below it that contain the title of the node in question.&lt;br /&gt; 
There is some stuff missing, for example it does neither create the comment 
nor does it /msg the users of the touched nodes. The replacement must currently 
still be done within the script in the vars &lt;tt&gt;$old&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;$new&lt;/tt&gt;. But before I begin with the goldplating I want comments on the general approach and whether this script should better be discussed "in the open" - it has a certain potential for mayhem by lowering the barrier of entry to people automating Perlmonks (but then, so has my constant pimping of WWW::Mechanize::Shell). 
&lt;i&gt;That code now lives at [id://274951]&lt;/i&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2003-05-05&lt;br /&gt; 
I'm tired of NTC being full.  Here is the data from it.  I cleaned it out. 
&lt;table border="1"&gt; 
&lt;tr&gt; 
 &lt;td align="center" bgcolor="#CC99CC"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;node_id&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td align="center" bgcolor="#CC99CC"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;keep&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td align="center" bgcolor="#CC99CC"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;edit&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td align="center" bgcolor="#CC99CC"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;del&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td align="center" bgcolor="#CC99CC"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;description&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt; 
&lt;/tr&gt; 
&lt;tr&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title="Object Oriented configuration values" href="/index.pl?node_id=234012"&gt;234012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;23&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;46&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;&amp;#91;Louis_Wu&amp;#93; Move to Tutorials section.&lt;/td&gt; 
&lt;/tr&gt; 
&lt;tr&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title="Extended Patterns of Regular Expressions" href="/index.pl?node_id=236866"&gt;236866&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;64&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;&amp;#91;footpad&amp;#93; Promote to Tutorials? (Edit==Yes, No==Keep)&lt;/td&gt; 
&lt;/tr&gt; 
&lt;tr&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title="S And M -- modifiers, that is..." href="/index.pl?node_id=238272"&gt;238272&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;49&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;&amp;#91;BrowserUk&amp;#93; Promote to tutorial&lt;/td&gt; 
&lt;/tr&gt; 
&lt;tr&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title="Zen and the Art of Match Variables" href="/index.pl?node_id=245725"&gt;245725&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;82&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;&amp;#91;diotalevi&amp;#93; Promote to Tutorials? Yes = Edit, No = Keep&lt;/td&gt; 
&lt;/tr&gt; 
&lt;tr&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title="fork-bomb!" href="/index.pl?node_id=254078"&gt;254078&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;18&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;18&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;&amp;#91;kelan&amp;#93; Perhaps move to Tutorials&lt;/td&gt; 
&lt;/tr&gt; 
&lt;tr&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title="A Practical Guide to Compiling C based Modules under ActiveState using Microsoft C++" href="/index.pl?node_id=249803"&gt;249803&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;62&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;&amp;#91;diotalevi&amp;#93; Promote to 'Tutorials'? Edit == yes, Keep == No.&lt;/td&gt; 
&lt;/tr&gt; 
&lt;tr&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title="An informal introduction to O(N) notation" href="/index.pl?node_id=227909"&gt;227909&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;89&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;&amp;#91;jarich&amp;#93; Promote to tutorial? &amp;nbsp;Edit-&amp;gt; yes.&lt;/td&gt; 
&lt;/tr&gt; 
&lt;tr&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title="POD in 5 minutes" href="/index.pl?node_id=252477"&gt;252477&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;59&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;&amp;#91;Coruscate&amp;#93; promote to tutorials: edit =&amp;gt; promote, keep =&amp;gt; no promote, delete =&amp;gt; does nothing :)&lt;/td&gt; 
&lt;/tr&gt; 
&lt;tr&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title="Schedule Win32 Perl Scripts with AT" href="/index.pl?node_id=217597"&gt;217597&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;21&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;79&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;&amp;#91;rob_au&amp;#93; promote to tutorials (edit - yes, keep - no)&lt;/td&gt; 
&lt;/tr&gt; 
&lt;tr&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title="Shrink Your CGI Searches with CGI::Search" href="/index.pl?node_id=244635"&gt;244635&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;55&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;&amp;#91;rob_au&amp;#93; edit -- Promote to tutorials? (Edit -- yes, Keep -- no)&lt;/td&gt; 
&lt;/tr&gt; 
&lt;tr&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title="Pack/Unpack Tutorial (aka How the System Stores Data)" href="/index.pl?node_id=224666"&gt;224666&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;95&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt; 
 &lt;td&gt;&amp;#91;footpad&amp;#93; Promote to Tutorials? (Edit==Yes, Keep==No)&lt;/td&gt; 
&lt;/tr&gt; 
&lt;/table&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2003-05-01&lt;br /&gt; 
I took care of [id://254456].  The consideration of &lt;code&gt;[traveler] Retitle: "Convert string to octet" to avoid single word title&lt;/code&gt; was fine.  Single-word titles (it was originally just "Conversions") should be strongly avoided as they trip up single-word simple searches (and aren't very helpful besides).  I say just unconsider the other one. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[ybiC], 2003-04-30&lt;br /&gt; 
Two nodes have been considered for re-titling, and it looks to me like both considerations might best be dropped. &amp;nbsp; But before doing so, the little voice of reason(?) in my head suggested that I solicit y'all's thoughts. &amp;nbsp; I don't make heads or tails of "[id://254456]", and "[id://253863]" doesn't look to actually be about CHAP - rather about some home-grown that works similarly to CHAP. &amp;nbsp; I suppose I'll proceed unless I hear otherwise in the next few days.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;P&gt;[footpad], 18 April 2003, ~12:40pm (GMT+7)&lt;br /&gt; 
Sorry for letting the [Tutorials|tutorial] submissions pile up.  I'll try to take care of them later this evening.&lt;/P&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[ybiC], 2003-04-18&lt;br /&gt; 
There seems to be an acumulation in nre of nodes considered for promotion from meditations to tutorials. &amp;nbsp; My own inclination is to promote those with a clear and substantial majority of edit over keep votes (40/4, 70/4, 82/6), provided they fit a reasonable definition of 'tutorial'. &amp;nbsp; This has been discussed before in this wiki, but I'd like to hear others' thought before actually doing any moving/promoting. &amp;nbsp; Anyone? &amp;nbsp; Beuller?&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[kudra], 2003-01-18&lt;br /&gt; 
We've been able to read other wikis for a year I see (having a little trouble 
with the date, tye? ;).  Any chance of getting a cabal link in the Editor's 
Nodelet? 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-01-17&lt;br /&gt; 
Now all [cabal] members can read each other's [wiki wiki|wikis]. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-01-16&lt;br /&gt; 
The duplicate was ID 227414 and it was nuked, probably by 3 [editors] voting for that to happen. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[broquaint]: Thu Jan 16 19:03:39 GMT 2003&lt;br/&gt; 
Just a small note - [id://227413] is not a duplicate at all, so could someone please unconsider it when possible (currently the votes are 2 deletes vs. 1 keep). I'm not entirely sure what [scain] was on, but it certainly didn't improve his clarity :-/ 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;hr/&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[boo_radley], 14JAN2003&lt;br /&gt; 
go, footpad, go! &lt;br/&gt; 
I've decided to work on the site's documentation a bit. [Ailie] has produced an excellent outline to this end on [http://www.perlmonks.org/index.pl?node_id=108949&amp;user=ailie|her scratchpad], and I intend to use it as a basis for my work. Would appreciate any comments or additions you have. Further, if you would like to pick a piece of this up, more power to you. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;hr /&gt; 
&lt;P&gt;[footpad], ~Tue Jan 14 20:44:22 2003 (GMT)&lt;br /&gt; 

I just finished cleaning out [id://28877|ntc], which was up to 43 nodes under consideration.  In doing so, I added 12 tutorials and changed the hidden comments we use to track who added what.  Since I seem to be doing the lion's share of the work in that node, I replaced "footpad" with "--f" in a very simple attempt to keep a handle on download size.  I documented this with a comment and promised to explain it here.  So now you know. &lt;/P&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[ar0n], 2003-01-08&lt;br /&gt; 
The 'history' link in the editors nodelet takes you to an overview of the node's edit history.  Right now, the link is shown all the time instead of just for editable nodes because doing so would require an extra DB hit on each page load.  It may change in the near future, though. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;hr /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[ar0n], 2003-01-04 (happy new year, etc)&lt;br /&gt; 
Every time the wiki is updated a &lt;tt&gt;(*)&lt;/tt&gt; (which is wrapped in a span with the &lt;tt&gt;wikiupdate&lt;/tt&gt; class as an attribute, for easy CSS customization) should appear next to the [editors' wiki|ew] link in the [Editors Nodelet].  I can change the &lt;tt&gt;(*)&lt;/tt&gt; to something more appropriate, if you so wish.  Just suggest it here on the wiki and come to some consensus. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;hr /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[dvergin], 2002-12-26&lt;br /&gt; 
I agree with the general drift of the conversation. [mt2k] seems to be a nice enough fellow, but the combination of the boredom-relieving ("harmless") exploit and the general character of the "vote me in" post raises significant question about [mt2k]'s readiness for a position of trust. I feel that [tye] has bent over backwards to give [mt2k] the opportunity to prove himself and... &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; I mean... &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; to mess around while on probation?? 'Nuf said. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[kudra], 2002-12-21&lt;br /&gt; 
As I haven't been able to be here since November, I have no doubt missed 
other conversations on this thread.  My short opinion is that it would 
be possible to ignore his actions from 1 or 2 years ago, if his recent 
actions were above reproach.  However, from tye's account of the pmdev 
exploit, that doesn't seem to have been the case.   
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
His recent post makes yet another case for not including him in the editors, 
in my opinion.  It resembles the 'am I paying vroom to 
consider his dictatorship' thread (which was not by mt2k).  Although I 
think it worthy to bring up for discussion the policies and actions of 
certain priviledged groups, when this is done with the ulterior motive 
of trying to force one's way into the groups by popular acclaim (vote 

for me to be in the group), it cheapens the criticism and demonstrates the 
very reason the author should not join the group. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
As for putting him among the doc editors, I believe what he did while in 
pmdev should rule him out for any position of trust.  One can argue that 
if he's bored, he's going to try to exploit things...but it seems boredom 
is inevitable after some time.  He got into pmdev, and then he exploited 
his position.  Eventually he'd get bored with doc editing, and frusterated 
that he isn't among the site editors.  If rejected, he'll probably make 
trouble.  But it seems that if accepted, he'll also make trouble, so it's 
safer for someone like that to have as little access as possible without 
the complete exclusion that might lead to more harmful exploits. 
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-12-18&lt;br /&gt; 
The abuse was to trigger the "clear out poll vote records" so he could revote on the poll.  He wrote a script to repeatedly vote on the poll until all options had the same number of votes.  I think he ran this script more than once before reporting the problem.  I'm sure some would agree with the "but that didn't do any &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; harm" whine.  I didn't appreciate it.  And I consider it very inappropriate for one in [pmdev] on probation (especially since he found the hole using [pmdev]-only access).  The amount of work that went into writing that elaborate of an the exploit should certainly have been put to better use, IMO. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
So feel free to reconsider if you feel this wasn't serious enough of a violation. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
I'm still mulling if/how to remove him from [pmdev].  He did make two useful patches about the same time, which is probably a big reason why I'm still mulling.  But based on his recent revelations about his feelings about being in [pmdev], I think I will eventually remove him. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
[boo_radley] 18DEC2002&lt;br /&gt; 
I was unaware that he'd exploited pmdev. That turns the question from "Why isn't he in [editors]?" to "Why is he in [pmdev]?" or possibly "Why is the bouncer still letting him in?", athough that's probably too draconian for some.&lt;br/&gt; 
weighing in late, 
boo 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-12-15&lt;br /&gt; 
As far as the word being incorrect, yes, the context doesn't matter much.  The common definition for "elite" certainly doesn't fit [editors].  No offense to current members, but I don't think they were chosen primarilly for consumate skill or intellect but instead primarilly for evident good judgement.  And it fits even less my intended meaning. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
At this point I'm not planning on taking any "corrective action" (an apology), though, as I think that pot may be better served by being left unstirred. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
[Petruchio] Sun Dec 15 16:39:01 UTC 2002: 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
I really don't think context matters all that much in this case. 
On the other hand, I don't think the issue matters all that much, 
either.  FWIW, I didn't know you had said it (thought I'd pretty 
much guessed), and I don't regard the matter as worthy of anything 
like a personal attack, even if I were inclined to make one.  I 
stand by my observation that 'elite' is an unfortunate choice of 
words to describe editors... and I say this with the expertise of 
one who chooses unfortunate words every day.  :-) It's a small 
matter. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
As far as the section, I'd assumed that the intention was to 
make the editors party to the conversation, and solicit opinions. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-12-14&lt;br /&gt; 
Yes, it was out of context. Quoting people out of context in a bit of grandstanding doesn't strike me as the type of behavior of someone with the temperament to be an editor.  And he even posted the item to the wrong section.  My word, if you can't even get the right section when you post your request to take on the job of putting other peoples' nodes into the right section...  It shows that he doesn't take much care in his actions.  He doesn't want to be an editor for good reasons.  He's bored! 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
I meant "select".  So sue me.  In terms of power and potential for mischief, the [editors] are only second to the [gods] and just leave everyone else in the dust.  I'm very, very picky about adding [editors].  I don't think it would make a good impression to the probably many people who haven't been "making problems" but have seen [mt2k] doing so to then see him promoted to such a powerful position. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
And I didn't "shut him down".  I even asked in #perlmonks if any [gods] thought he'd make a good editor.  No answer.  I said &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; was not inclined to add him.  I got the impression he was going to ask someone else.  Feel free to add him.  I'll just keep my "I told you so" for later. (: 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
I added him to [pmdev] and told him he was on probation.  What did he do?  He used his new power to find a hole and exploit it to sate his boredom and then later reported the problem.  He didn't just test it once to verify that it was really a bug.  He wrote a little exploit that used the hole over and over again.  He failed probation in my book.  I'm inclined to remove him from [pmdev], especially since he says it doesn't interest him. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
Since he knew he was on probation, this shows that he continues to have problems with self control.  So I don't think putting him on probation again will produce any better results.  I think it would be a mistake to make a bored person with self-control problems an editor. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
I doubt janitorial work will sate his boredom.  Based on what has entertained him in the past he'll code up some interesting hack that creates loads of mischief and then whine that he didn't do any &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; damage. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
If he's interested in site doc work, that'd be great.  Just keep those backups prepped. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
I also like [mt2k], BTW.  I like a lot monks.  Very few impress me as people that I'd want to be [editors].  I've had a few requests and I've taken them very seriously.  I did some research.  I ended up rejecting them.  (With [mt2k] I didn't have to do any research.) 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
[Petruchio] Fri Dec 13 14:08:53 UTC 2002: 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
I agree that describing the editors as an "elite group" isn't 
very tasteful.  It is true, of course, strictly speaking, but 
it seems an unfortunate choice for a word to describe a group 
devoted to the service of the Monastery.  It's important that 
we do a better job of remembering the distinction between 
"servant" and "ruler" than our politicians do. :-) 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
I have reservations about [mt2k].  I like him, I believe he 
is well-intentioned, and I think he has made interesting 
contributions to the monastery over the years.  On the other 
hand, he is somewhat inconsistent, and he has shown more 
enthusiasm than judgement on a number of occasions.  Not all 
of these are long-past. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
For instance, one evening very recently he created two accounts, 
with names identical to other users', only with control characters 
appended.  In itself, not a bad experiment; however he chose to 
do so without asking or telling anyone first.  I'm certain he did 
not mean to break Newest Nodes for many users by doing so, but 
good fortune rather than good planning had me onhand to delete 
the accounts.   
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
Similarly, I have to wonder why he chose not only to create 
the [ 1/2] account, but to post with it.  Actions like these tend, 
for me, to fortify the impression that he made in years past... 
and I think an editor needs to be circumspect and consistent. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
A writer of documentation, however, should be intrepid.  I 
think that if he's interested in that sort of work, [mt2k] 
could probably contribute a lot in this area; he knows the 
place well, he's enthusiastic, and he's bright.  And in any 
case, I think we need the help there more. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
Also, if we feel we need more editorial help, I think we have 
better candidates for the position.  [ybiC] springs to mind, 
for instance, as a trustworthy man of excellent judgement. 
While I don't necessarily oppose editorship for [mt2k], I 
can't say I'd vouch for him, either. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[jcwren], 2002-12-12&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[mt2k] recently has expressed a desire to be an editor, and was "shutdown" with the comment ".. not inclined to add you ... it's an elite group ...". &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;First, I find this attitude disturbing.  It may be somewhat out of context, but it reeks of elitism in it's self.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[mt2k] has been around a good while.  While he has readily admitted that he's screwed up in the past, there are some people on this list that can say the exact same thing, yet they are [editors].&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;What I propose is to give him a two or three week provisional editor status.  And the end of this, if we find he's been more trouble than he's worth, he can be removed.  If it's working out, we keep him.  I feel that not giving him a chance is to going to remove someone who clearly (at least for now) has some excess energy that can be put to good use.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[boo_radley] mentioned this idea: "Sitedoc for 2 weeks, have him work some of tye's doc todos".  Sounds like a good plan to me.  We'll tell him to stay out of conventional nodes, or put him in the [Site Documentation Clan] to see where he goes with it.  I feel that the former will demonstrate an ability to follow instructions that would be a good "test".&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;hr /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-11-13&lt;br /&gt; 
I fixed your link, [broquaint]. I was tempted to also drop the "|this" as I see no use for hiding the subject from people like that.  The node had a functioning READMORE tag when I found it.  It also had some nonfunctioning CODE and /CODE tags that I've now removed.  I unconsidered it. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[broquaint]: Wed Nov 13 13:17:06 GMT 2002&lt;br/&gt; 
I think [id://211630|this] is going to have to be unconsidered since Craft will only except code. Or is there a way of forcing a &lt;tt&gt;&amp;lt;readmore&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt; without non-godly powers? 
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[footpad], ~Mon Sep 30 21:55:08 2002 (GMT)&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;B&gt;Update&lt;/B&gt;: The [id://202215|reply] claiming to be from the OP contains the same email address as those reaped (and later elided) Snippets from last week.  This is what prompted my reply to that thread.  It's meant as a friendly warning.  If (as the OP claims) they're innocent, then maybe it'll help stop the destructive code.&lt;/P&gt; 

&lt;P&gt;And, yes, I know that [diotalevi] did a fairly extensive review of the code, however, I'm not sure about the bits that modify the registry keys and the GUID entries.  (I simply haven't had time to dive through my own Registries to see if there are additional risks.)  That's what makes me nervous, as this poster has already demonstrated at least a small knowledge of the Windows API and its side effects (in the masked password stealer).&lt;/P&gt; 

&lt;P&gt;In any event, I'm not trying to be overly paranoid, however, I am trying to be cautious.  Just thought y'all might appreciate the background.&lt;/P&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[footpad], ~Mon Sep 30 21:55:08 2002 (GMT)&lt;br /&gt; 
I've been trying to grok [id://200878], which has been under Consideration for more than a few days now.  It *appears* to be an Internet Explorer remover, however, I have some misgivings about the extended characters that are being written to the registry.  Has anyone actually deparsed this node?  Is it safe?  (Given that we've been seeing a few snippets that aren't recently, it seems fair to ask.)  Also, given that its Rep is (currently) -8 and has collected a fairly high number of delete votes, one also wonders why it hasn't been reaped yet.  Basically, I'm wondering what we should do with this one, if anything.&lt;/P&gt; 

&lt;hr /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-09-25&lt;br /&gt; 
A while ago I noticed this and considered unreaping it, but decided against it as I felt that more downvotes would just make the author more likely to be more trollish for longer.  If I thought expressing this idea to the author would make him feel more like he "belonged"/fit it, I'd do so. But with potential trolls, sometimes reaching out just sets them off.  So I lean toward "don't disturb it". 

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
Though, I also worry that it serves as a bad example to high-level monks, too many of which seem to quickly and easily latch on to such examples, thinking they are good examples.  (Thank [footpad|new god] that we have somewhere to point them when this happens.)  But not enough to goad me into action. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[dws] 25 Sep 2002&lt;br/&gt; 
I /msg'd the author with an explanation of "stubmit", considered the node, and was surprised at how quickly it racked up downvotes. Then I noticed that the author was, well, making a name for himself in the CB. I'd be fine with unconsidering the node and leaving approval to the whim of others. 

&lt;p&gt;[footpad], ~Wed Sep 25 15:09:59 2002 (GMT)&lt;br /&gt; 
Anyone else think that [id://200538] should be unreaped?  It's not a great node, I'll admit, and a question we've seen far too often, but it's got replies and I don't think it's flagrantly trollish.  Thoughts?&lt;/P&gt; 
&lt;hr /&gt; 

&lt;P&gt;[footpad], ~Mon Sep 23 09:48:55 2002 (UTC) - Good enough for me.&lt;/P&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-09-21&lt;br /&gt; 
The review states that it was placed on this site because it is a good book on OO programming, despite "java" in the title.  So I'm not convinced that it is "clearly not-topical". YMMV (: 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;P&gt;[footpad], ~Sat Sep 21 17:34:53 2002 (UTC)&lt;BR /&gt; 
You might have seen the [id://199710] book review.  Clearly not-topical, however, we've leaned toward some flexibility in the past.  We've also nuked non-perl book reviews in the past (Anyone recall that really bad C++ primer one?)&lt;/P&gt; 
&lt;P&gt;Should this be Considered?  Should we consider adding another review section for such things?  I confess I'm sure we want to set a precedent.  OTOH, I'm not sure we want to be overly hard-nosed about it.  Thoughts?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;HR /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-09-19&lt;br /&gt; 
Note changes to the "emi" (editors' message inbox) link in the editors' nodelet.  Anyone can "/msg editors" and all messages go to this shared inbox (even when a member of editors sends the message).  This is primarilly for non-members to send us information.  We can use it for things that are &lt;b&gt;very&lt;/b&gt; transient that don't need to be in the wiki. Please, err on the side of putting it in the wiki, tho. 

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
You can archive/unarchive/delete messages in the shared inbox.  Please archive a message when you "solve" it or otherwise deal with it.  Please only delete shared messages after they are at least a couple of weeks old.  Later we'll have a way to edit a /msg to add your own comments to it (such messages will be marked so you can't make it look like someone said something they didn't). 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
The "emi" link will show you how many new messages are in the shared inbox that you haven't seen yet. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
Thanks to [Macphisto] for the most recent work helping me to get this working. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[dws] 2002-09-18&lt;br/&gt; 
For the second time in recent memory, [nodes requiring editing] was empty this evening. A round of quiet applause is due for all of the behind-the-scenes broom wielders. 

&lt;hr/&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kudra&lt;/strong&gt; 2002-09-15&lt;br/&gt; 
A node needs to have 2 edit votes or an appropriate number of keep votes 
(4, I think) before you can unconsider it.  I'm seeing an unconsider option 
for this node, so perhaps it just hadn't gotten enough votes when you 
were asked to handle it?  It sounds like it, since nodes without enough 
edit votes don't show up in nre either.  I just unconsidered it; it had 
5 keep votes.  If someone reports an error in considering I generally 
ask them to vote edit on it and do so myself, because then I can remove 
it right away.   
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[Ovid] ~ 2002-09-15&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Okay, I confess, I tend not to use my Editor Super Powers other than approving nodes and editing poorly formatted nodes.  So today, when [Aristotle] /msg'd me about his accidental consideration of [id://198048|this node], I found that I could not unconsider it.  Do I have to remove the approval first?  I tried using [nodes requiring editing] to mark it as done, but the node didn't show up.  I suspect that I should start editing more as I'd be more likely to know what I missed, but I'm rather confused as to why I cannot unconsider this.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;hr /&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-09-13&lt;br /&gt; 
Since I think we should usually err on the side of not changing, and I think that people seem unlikely to casually vote "keep", I like to have twice the number of "edit" votes to "keep" votes and a bigger ratio (at least 3- or 4-times as many "delete" votes to "keep" votes).  But I also heavily use my own judgement. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kudra&lt;/strong&gt;, 2002-09-11&lt;br /&gt; 
What's the ratio we should be using for unconsidering nodes?  There seem 
to be quite a few right now that have a fair amount of keep votes, and 
slightly more edit votes (for instance, 9 keep and 12 edit).  I tend to 
unconsider them unless the edit votes far outweigh the keep ones, but I 
was wondering what other people think before I cleaned these out. 
&lt;hr /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-09-10&lt;br /&gt; 
Well, it appears [nighthawk_] thinks "replace the code with an explanation of why you removed it" means "replace the node with a SoPW in the wrong section". *sigh* I give up and return to work. At least the virus code is gone. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-09-10&lt;br /&gt; 
I've unreaped the node so, for now, the author can "benefit" from their actions.  I stand by my assertion that even stupid virus-like code in the wild is a bad idea and does often contribute in a small but crucial way to the production of destructive viruses and so feel the code should go.  But, in numbers, I suspect the majority of our community disagrees, considering such small steps "harmless" and hiding them to be a form of denial rather than a prudent step in slowing the spread. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
I've /msg'd [nighthawk_] asking for some self sensorship.  Read the [id://91940] thread (if you haven't already) before taking action.  I'm not sure how to get a community consensus to justify action by [editors] on this. *sigh* 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;P&gt;[footpad], ~Mon Sep  9 16:05:51 2002 (GMT)&lt;br /&gt; 

[id://196087] looks to be another snippet that's been reaped, but still shows up fine.  Since it has replies, I'm thinking the code should be obscured (or removed outright).  Comments?&lt;/P&gt; 

&lt;P&gt;Out of curiosity, is anyone working on anything related to the reaping of Snippets?&lt;hr noshade size="1" width="50%" /&gt;&lt;/P&gt; 

&lt;P&gt;Mon Sep 2, 2002 -- The [dvergin|ER Hobbit] wanders through and takes [id://193352] with him. [id://193169] still has one editorial delete vote to go before facing oblivion.&lt;/P&gt; 

&lt;P&gt;[footpad], Sun Sep  1 04:23:34 2002 (UTC)&lt;br /&gt; 
I've obscured [id://193352], which still needs one more editorial delete to fully go away.  (You can still view source to get the original content.)  I think the reason [id://193169] still remains is because it needs to be voted down before [NodeReaper|Skinny] gets interested.  I know [kudra|some of us] have expressed reservations about having to vote down true duplicates, but until someone comes with a better implementation, it's what we've got to work with.  If you'd rather not vote it down, it has one editorial delete already and could use two more.  At least that doesn't affect XP.&lt;/P&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kudra&lt;/strong&gt;, Thu 29 Aug 2002&lt;br /&gt; 
A couple of days ago, I found [id://193169] considered as a duplicate with 
two replies.  I would have picked the other (which also had two replies, but 
was more recent), but since 193169 had already been considered, I tried to 
give it a nudge by considering the replies for relocation and changing the 
title.  At that time it already had keep votes, perhaps because of the 
replies.  I probably should have reconsidered it but for some reason didn't. 
It's already gotten my delete vote.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; 
Ps. Is it really neccessary that we msg whenever we update the wiki? 
I consider it just another thing to check daily, along with newest nodes, 
ntc and nre. 
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[Ovid], ~Wed Aug 28 15:08:59 2002 (Pacific) 
&lt;p&gt;I'd vote to nuke the [id://193352].  It's pretty trivial to duplicate, but I see no need to encourage the &amp;pound;337.&lt;/p&gt; 

[footpad], ~Wed Aug 28 20:36:47 2002 (GMT)&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;P&gt;A couple of nodes need further attention:&lt;/P&gt; 
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;[id://193352] has been reaped, however, because it's a Snippet, it's still displaying normally.  Should the code be obscured or the node itself be nuked?&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt; 
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;[id://193169] is a [id://193172|true duplicate] with a Rep of zero. However, if you check the [nodes to consider|NTC listing], you'll it says the node has two replies.  These were moved to the other node yesterday.  I'm not sure why the dup hasn't been reaped yet (it may only be the zero rep), but this one also needs a little help to go away.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt; 
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;hr /&gt; 

&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;Continued in [id://200924]...&lt;/I&gt;&lt;HR /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</field>
</data>
</node>
