<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="510149" title="Pedagogues Wiki" created="2005-11-19 15:43:04" updated="2005-11-19 10:43:04">
<type id="68046">
wiki</type>
<author id="357600">
de-merphq</author>
<data>
<keywords>
<keyword rating="">
pedagogues</keyword>
<keyword rating="">
wiki</keyword>
<keyword rating="">
tutorials</keyword>
<keyword rating="">
how-to</keyword>
<keyword rating="">
tutlist</keyword>
<keyword rating="">
tutstring</keyword>
</keywords>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;!--
Add new entries below the top part, which is static!
--&gt;
&lt;table border=1 cellspacing=0 width="100%"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;
Some important functions and resources for [id://499790]:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [href://?recipient=499790;node_id=48824|Pedagogues Message Inbox] &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [id://615833] &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [id://954] section &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;li&gt; [id://510154] - new Tutorials section &lt;/li&gt; --&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [id://519201] - tutorials show up in this list as they're created, but should be moved to an appropriate section once they are no longer new. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [id://591017] &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [id://487572] - old FAQlet; could use some updating &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [id://244017] - new FAQlet; has no content yet &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [href://?op=new;type=tutlist;node=available_tutlist;displaytype=edit|Create a new tutlist node] (Be very sure you know what you're doing before you click this!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [href://?op=new;type=tutstring;node=available_tutstring;displaytype=edit|Create a new tutstring node] (Be very sure you know what you're doing before you click this!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;i&gt;For [pmdev]s only:&lt;/i&gt; List all: [href://?node_id=106927;whichtype=510147|tutlists], [href://?node_id=106927;whichtype=519031|tutstrings] &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [id://587754] (this is linked as "Help for this page" in the upper right, when editing a [tutlist].)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [id://743094|Master Tutlist] Compendium of all tutorials, tutlists, and tutstrings.
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Interesting/relevant old node by [footpad]: [id://178419]

&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;

&lt;!--
C&amp;P the following template into the wiki and add your text. New stuff goes at the TOP. 
The 'wikihead' template will be auto-filled in on submit/preview.

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;wikihead&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

=======================================================================
--&gt;


&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2009-10-05 09:08:12" name="2009-10-05 09:08:12"&gt;[localtime://2009-10-05 09:08:12]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Conscientious Monk [jakobi] has sent me some private messages recently regarding [Tutorials].
In particular, he seems to feel that some clarifying/introductory content could be added to [id://519394];
see [pad://jakobi]. I think I've seen him trying to discuss this publicly in the cb as well. I have to confess, I have a hard time
making heads or tails out of what he's trying to propose, but I get the sense it is fairly radical relative to the existing 
infrastructure and policy framework. Does anybody else have a better idea of what he wants, and so can shepherd him toward
an improvement which fits within the PerlMonks [wp://M.O.]?  TIA...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I told him that [id://519394] is just a list of links to other nodes, and so does not contain actual tutorial material itself.
He went looking for an explanation of [tutlist] and found none.
(And indeed, anything which might be edifying is "tough beans" for him.)&lt;br&gt;
So I'm wondering if maybe we need a sitefaqlet explaining the infrastructure of [Tutorials] in laymonks' terms.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2009-07-13 17:59:16" name="2009-07-13 17:59:16"&gt;[localtime://2009-07-13 17:59:16]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Not only is there the question of author's intent/permission, but also there is something of a policy (iiuc)
against converting a node's type beyond a certain period of time after it was posted.
A statute of limitations, so to speak.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I'd be quite content with leaving that node as a [Meditations|meditation]. I will unlink it from [Tutorials], too.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I do think we need a good tutorial on context, covering the material in [On Scalar Context].
I will probably put something on [Tutorials Quest] to that effect.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[yitzchak], &lt;a href="#2009-07-12 01:27:45" name="2009-07-12 01:27:45"&gt;[localtime://2009-07-12 01:27:45]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
There was a request to convert [On Scalar Context] to a tutorial;  I'd rather see
a new node written that established some broad categorizations (as pointed out in
some of the comments) and gave rationales (ditto).  As is, this is more of a
reference work than a tutorial.  (Or are there other examples of that?)
&lt;p&gt;
Also, do we convert things to tutorials without the author's permission?  I don't
recall.
&lt;p&gt;
Meta-comment: hrs don't belong in dls; this style of wiki irritates me every time
I post.  Maybe we could have css to give the dd's a bottom border or something instead?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2009-04-08 07:30:25" name="2009-04-08 07:30:25"&gt;[localtime://2009-04-08 07:30:25]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I have updated one of the "Ovid's CGI Course" tutstrings, [id://519641], to point to my resurrected version off site, and updated the [Tutorials] to include it.  I have reverted the other one to simply [id://590378].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2009-03-01 15:57:40" name="2009-03-01 15:57:40"&gt;[localtime://2009-03-01 15:57:40]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I am pleased to announce a new feature available to the [Pedagogues]: the [id://743094], an automatically maintained comprehensive list
of all tutorials, tutlists, and tutstrings.  (By "automatic", I mean you click a button to launch an updater when you want to, vs.
manually maintaining the contents of the lists by hand.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2009-02-17 12:41:23" name="2009-02-17 12:41:23"&gt;[localtime://2009-02-17 12:41:23]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
bookmark: [id://614525] &amp;mdash; has some good and fairly current discussion of the issues surrounding the editing/editability of tutorials and the handling of orphaned tutorials.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2009-02-14 07:15:48" name="2009-02-14 07:15:48"&gt;[localtime://2009-02-14 07:15:48]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I've put Ovid's CGI Course up at [http://jdporter.perlmonk.org/cgi_course/].
I've already done some editing, mostly "micro" stuff, and it could use some more.
But if someone has any ideas how it can be improved on a "macro" scale &amp;mdash; content, organization... &amp;mdash;
please let me know.  Do you think it's ready for prime time?  That is, should we go ahead and update the various old broken links,
e.g. the tutstring?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Btw... it looks like [Ovid] had a PerlMonks audience very much in mind as he was developing the Course.
He posted his progress in the following series of nodes:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  [id://35535] &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  [id://36186] &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  [id://41039] (Lesson 3) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  [id://41237] &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  [id://89546] &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [id://136655] &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [id://155100] &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [id://420760] (Lesson 6) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2009-01-28 13:06:53" name="2009-01-28 13:06:53"&gt;[localtime://2009-01-28 13:06:53]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Btw... [tye] has made it pretty clear that he does not condone changing the section (i.e. the nodetype) of a node
after it has resided in a certain section for a long time. He says that if a node is to be moved, it should be
done within a very short window after initial posting, due to things like an error in section selection on the part
of the poster.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Given that, Option #1, below, is essentially not an option, for this task.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2009-01-27 16:40:33" name="2009-01-27 16:40:33"&gt;[localtime://2009-01-27 16:40:33]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So, I'm going through [Tutorials], trying to eliminate the non-tutorial nodes linked there (ignoring tutlists and tutstrings, of course).&lt;br&gt;
For background, see my post - [id://739048], which is based on [href://?node_id=322009#2007-06-28 12:11:28|this Cabalists' Wiki entry].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In general, when a non-tutorial node is found in [Tutorials], the decision is among the following courses of action:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Have the [gods]/[janitors] convert it to the tutorial nodetype; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Unlink it from [Tutorials] (and, if appropriate, linking it somewhere else so it isn't lost); &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Leave it be, and live with the horror of having non-tutorial nodes in [Tutorials]. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Furthermore, if Option 2 is chosen, there is the additional possible action of replacing the removed meditation with an equivalent tutorial.
We'd probably want this if the node is of sufficient quality and tutorial character. This entails a decision point: 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Have the author of the meditation post the replacement tutorial; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Have one of us post it. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This will generally come down to whether the author is still active on PerlMonks or not; but it could also happen that the author is active but refuses, for one reason or another, to re-post the med as a tut.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As a mostly orthogonal decision to the above, we'd want to consider whether any node in [Tutorials] (of any node type &amp;mdash; tutorial, meditation, or whatever) should be taken from its original author and ownership given to [Pedagogues|us].  I think, in general, this is only warranted when the original author is "gone for good" &lt;b&gt;and&lt;/b&gt; we have some reason to need to modify the node.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Now, having said all that.... I would like your opinion on the following: There is a certain tutlist, [id://519396], which contains all of the "Perl Idioms Explained" posts.  These posts are &lt;b&gt;all&lt;/b&gt; meditations except one, a tutorial.  I, personally, would be happy to unlink them from [Tutorials] and forget about them. However, having the one tutorial complicates this course of action.  I could (and am planning to) ask the [gods] to convert that one tutorial into a meditation, to make it consistent with the others; but I anticipate that this could be a tough sell.  My feeling is that we should not be obliged to retain an index to any arbitrary series of useful meditations (see [id://622396]).  On the other hand, if concensus turns out to be to keep that list as it stands, then I will, naturally, argue that the meditations in it should be converted to tutorials.  What are your thoughts?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2009-01-12 21:20:05" name="2009-01-12 21:20:05"&gt;[localtime://2009-01-12 21:20:05]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
OK, I've gotten "Ovid's CGI Course" back up, at
[http://jdporter.perlmonk.org/ovids/].
Please review and let me know what changes you think ought to be made.
I plan on editing it with a fairly heavy hand, so don't be shy.  Thanks!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;/dl&gt;

Continued at [id://739420]



































































































</field>
</data>
</node>
