<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="581860" title="editors' wiki through 2006-10-25" created="2001-07-14 06:15:20" updated="2005-08-15 10:15:34">
<type id="68046">
wiki</type>
<author id="979">
vroom</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;!--

&lt;p&gt;&lt;wikihead&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

--&gt;
Next wiki: [id://74283]

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], [localtime://2006-10-25 03:10:31]&lt;br/&gt;
I saw that change and meant to comment on it but forgot :-( But no, I think adding cross-links is not a task of the janitors. Such stuff should be &lt;c&gt;/msg&lt;/c&gt;ed to the authors but otherwise left alone.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], [localtime://2006-10-24 17:00:05]&lt;br/&gt;
Anyone else think that adding 'see also' links to [id://579895] is &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; a job for janitors (especially considering the node author's willingness to make useful updates) ?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[planetscape], [localtime://2006-09-08 18:40:41]&lt;br/&gt;
If you put this: &lt;c&gt;[http://82.69.8.31/cgi-bin/pmnode.pl?node=`id`|Original content of `id`]&lt;/c&gt; in your [id://492700], you can view the "original" for any node (with caveats, such as, since [g0n]'s been running his script... see below).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], [localtime://2006-07-22 01:45:05]&lt;br /&gt;
[bobf] has expressed an interest in participating in [janitors].  I've /msg-ed the [gods] to offer my endorsement.  I'm happy to act as mentor to him as he learns the ins, outs, dos, donts and hows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[davido], [localtime://2006-05-04 23:08:53] &lt;br /&gt;
For the record, [id://547565] stands as an example of reparenting a string of Anon troll posts (about a dozen posted within a few minutes of each other) reparented under a single thread to clear up the clutter.  As an added bonus, if any of the nodes manage to get reaped, the ones that get reparented vanish from sight altogether.  Bug or feature? ...doesn't seem to matter.  I recommend reserving this sort of thing for obvious strings of AM troll posts that occur within a few moments of each other, but when that does occur, proceed.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[g0n], [localtime://2006-04-30 09:50:00]&lt;br/&gt;
Thanks [tye], I've amended the script accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2006-04-29 22:50:49]&lt;br/&gt;
When spidering a web site, always wait between requests at least as long as the request took.  So time how long it takes you to get each node, and then sleep for (1+x)*T + y where x &gt;= 0 and y &gt;= 0 and T is how many seconds the previous request took.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[g0n], [localtime://2006-04-29 17:30:00]&lt;br/&gt;
The ongoing occasional problem with node authors removing their node content, or replacing it with 'thanks guys' or something to that effect, has cropped up a couple of times this week. Sometimes when this happens, the original node content can be retrieved from [http://www.prlmnks.org] or (if the node has been edited by a janitor) the node history. Other times the content is not easily available and (I think) we're reliant on [gods] or [pmdev|devels] to restore the content. As a 'spit and loo roll' temporary solution to this, I've written a little script to get the content of each node as it is posted. The script runs every 15 minutes from cron, reads the node using the xml displaytype, and writes the output to a file in [http://g0n.net/perlmonks] (there are some dns oddities with the g0n domain - if you can't reach that url try [http://82.69.8.21/perlmonks]. It's limited to retrieving a max of 25 nodes at a time so that it doesn't place too much load on the server. It retrieves the node only once, at the time of posting (or up to 15 minutes later) and doesn't pick up any modifications, but that does at least mean that deleting the original node content won't affect the copy. If there are no objections I'll leave it running for the time being to see if it's useful.
&lt;p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2006-02-23 11:46:58]&lt;br/&gt;
Don't let [g0n] dupe you. I'd never say threads should be marked "(DUPE)" since the long-standing abbreviation for 'duplicate' is 'dup', because it has the distinct advantage of not already being a common word with an unrelated meaning.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I like the word "dupe", so I'd mark threads with "DUP".
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2006-02-23 09:04:23]&lt;br/&gt;
I totally agree with [g0n]. I believe this should be a standard practice, documented in the [id://324056].
I think it should say that it is to be done only when the janitor is absolutely sure the node is a dupe.
The point is to alert people that they should not be replying to or upvoting the node.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[g0n]: [localtime://2006-01-17 15:17:00]&lt;p&gt;
In a conversation about a duplicate that continued to get upvotes long after it had been considered this afternoon, [tye] commented that he had long advocated retitling dupes with a (DUPE) marker or similar as soon as they are considered, to avoid monks not noticing the consideration. I must admit I've seen this once or twice, but I don't &lt;i&gt;think&lt;/i&gt; most of us are doing it, and I haven't seen anything documented about this practise. Should this be in [id://324056], or have I failed to read/register something I should have?&lt;p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[GrandFather], [localtime://2005-12-16 19:15:00]&lt;br/&gt;
I echo [davido]'s sentiment. In the case that stimulated [jdporter]'s note I thought that the edit should have been left to the OP, especially as the OP is a frequent attender. In general least done is best consistent with minimum mess.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], [localtime://2005-12-16 00:35:21]&lt;br /&gt;
Perhaps we're reading that paragraph differently.  When I read it, the &lt;em&gt;as much as possible&lt;/em&gt; referrs to "echo what the original poster probably intended."  It doesn't refer to "We tidy up..."  In other words, it is trying to say that as we tidy up, we try to preserve the OP's layout intent as much as possible.  It shouldn't be read as "We tidy up as much as possible."  And by preserving the OP's layout intent, I mean that we should look at the source that the OP typed.  Many times there are strong clues there: line breaks in what was typed, but that don't appear in what gets rendered because they lack the necessary HTML formatting to match the layout that was typed in.  ...if that makes sense.  I'm not sure I know how to phrase it more clearly.  But I do seem to remember being the one who most recently touched that part of the documentation, and I can only attempt to clarify its intent here.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, it's my belief that the goal should be to touch as little as possible, and if practical, give the OP an opportunity to affect the change first.  But if we're clearly dealing with a newbie who has dumped twenty lines of text all run together with no formatting at all, that's a good time to look at the post's source, and attempt to elevate it out of line noise type obscurity by placing the formatting that will cause the rendering to appear pretty close to how it was actually typed (which is usually pretty legible).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's my feeling that if a post just needs a 'thing or two', it should probably be left alone.  If it's an utter unreadable disaster, it's not beyond our jurisdiction to make it readable without altering its content or the OP's intent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2005-12-15 13:11:16]&lt;br/&gt;
We recently had a bit of "discussion" in the cb about the extent of [janitors|our]
mission wrt cleaning up html in a node.  In this case, someone had used some html
which is (and has always been) supported in browsers, but is not HTML 4.01 compliant
and is rendered somewhat oddly (though usably) in certain picky browsers.
The author was alerted by the user who detected the "problem". However, a janitor
subsequently "fixed" the html.  Appeal was made to [id://324056], which says, "We tidy up with ... formatting to &lt;i&gt;as much as possible&lt;/i&gt; echo &amp;#91;what] the original poster probably intended." (Emphasis mine.)  I argue that this does not actually reflect current janitorial policy, which I understand to be as follows: We add &lt;i&gt;minimal&lt;/i&gt; markup to ensure that the node renders &lt;i&gt;usably&lt;/i&gt;. (Exception for markup-less nodes as noted under &lt;b&gt;How do we do it?&lt;/b&gt;). I don't think we are in the business of making sure nodes are HTML 4.01 pure. I don't see how we &lt;i&gt;can&lt;/i&gt; be.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I invite discussion of the question; and when it's done, I'll update
the [id://324056] if necessary.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2005-12-10 18:51:15]&lt;br/&gt;
If anyone edits [id://514234] per [Corion]'s consideration, they should note that there are several replies in the thread that warrant the same action.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[demerphq], [localtime://2005-11-27 03:28:36]&lt;br/&gt;
Maybe when people gain new powers they should receive a /msg with links to the docs?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2005-11-26 22:17:29]&lt;br/&gt;
We have an ever expanding number of considerers (aside from the releveling adjustment); whenever you see a consideration that goes against site policy, feel free to /msg the considerer a link to said policy.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], [localtime://2005-11-24 11:44:37]&lt;br /&gt;
All the comments you should need on the topic of reaping nodes are provided free of charge in [id://92975].  As you'll see there, that was an inappropriate use of consideration for deleting.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[g0n], [localtime://2005-11-24 14:40:00]&lt;p&gt;
re [id://511349]. This is gradually accruing both reap &amp; keep votes, but my feeling is that 'Reason: : delete, poster is not reporting problem accurately, and is too lazy to come up with a meaningful title ' is not really a valid consideration for deletion &amp; should be unconsidered anyway. Anyone care to comment?
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2005-10-14 03:53:27]&lt;br/&gt;
Thanks, [jdporter].  Looks nice.  I am a little bothered by the inconsistency of whether the tutorial author is listed.  Perhaps it should be only for off-site links written by monks?  Update: I see now it lists author for all but the really ancient anonymous ones, which is fine so never mind.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2005-10-13 23:29:53]&lt;br/&gt;
So, I went into [Tutorials] and cleaned up a bunch of stuff, mainly having to do with
off-site links. &lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt; I eliminated "off-site tutorials" as a separate section. (Actually,  it had been combined with "related topics"; that section is now known as "other topics".) All the off-site links that were there have been moved to the relevant topical sections. (There were only three.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;i&gt;All&lt;/i&gt; off-site links now say &lt;i&gt;off-site&lt;/i&gt; by them.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt; I'm really unsure how we should handle off-site tutorials. On the one hand, it's nice to have them in our index, for those who might be searching/scanning titles. OTOH, content text searches won't hit them. The status quo is fine, I guess, but I do worry (perhaps unnecessarily) about a proliferation of links to off-site material.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], [localtime://2005-10-12 18:04:52]&lt;br/&gt;
There a few new [Janitor Tools]; not all have been integrated into the  Editors Nodelet yet.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2005-09-21 22:39:40]&lt;br/&gt;
That seems fine to me, but please /msg the owner of the tutorial.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2005-09-21 19:05:31]&lt;br/&gt;
Question about janitorial prerogative in the [Tutorials] section:
What if a tutorial has borked links?  In particular, someone tried to link
to some standard perly docs... and maybe they worked at the time. But
the times and tides have... well, you know.  Can/should a janitor go and
fix them so they point to a working standard location now? TIA...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[castaway], [localtime://2005-09-10 07:17:54]&lt;br/&gt;
I thought that would help them not wrap, but OK then.. "inbox" works for me too. I quite like "unsnippet" for the last one. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2005-09-09 19:14:08]&lt;br/&gt;
There is no space between "/" and "msg" so a non-breaking space is not what you want (it'd make the link "/&amp;nbsp;msg").  It is unfortunate that browsers have decided to break where there isn't whitespace (even though there is white space very close by) and even worse that they sometimes refuse to break on whitespace for inscrutable reasons (such as there being a comma before the space or a slash after it).  We could try putting a "no break" span around "/msg", but I'd rather just drop the "/" or make the link "inbox".
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
"sopwify" is not a good label as the node it links to doesn't even always make things into SoPW nodes.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Dropping "Fix:" and using "retitle" and "reparent" works for me (eventually; I didn't like it at first but "reparent" in particular is much clearer).  But what to call the last one without the "Fix" part?  "desnippetize" is rather long (and a bit corny).  "snip2X" or "snip2_"?  "unsnip" or "desnip"?  I think I'd vote for "[snip2_]" at this point.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[castaway], [localtime://2005-09-09 14:07:40]&lt;br/&gt;
Can I put in a belated request for slightly longer/more understandable links/title-texts in the editors nodelet, please? I'd prefer "retitle" "reparent" and "sopwify" (or somesuch, on that last one, I assume thats what its for?), instead of the (to me odd-looking) "Fix: .. " ? Is there also a reason these show up at all on nodetypes they're not relevant on? Also the "/msgs" link needs a non-breaking space between the "/" and the "msgs".
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], [localtime://2005-09-07 05:38:41]&lt;br/&gt;
Could whoever moved [id://489179] please add the usual janitor's note stating where the node was moved from and why (and remember to re-approve it). Thanks.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[jdporter] 2005-08-26 2045 UTC&lt;br/&gt;
O.k., I've 86ed the consideration, and moved the node to SoPW.
Maybe now a request for a better title will stand a better chance.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], [localtime://2005-08-26 15:01:16]&lt;br/&gt;
I think [id://485905] is more a SoPW than it is a PM Discussion, so should be moved and retitled as such. But in general, the suggested title is only a suggestion and you don't have to re-consider the node to apply a more appropriate title. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter] 2005-08-26 1700 UTC&lt;br/&gt;
Unconsideration is definitely in order.  And your suggested new consideration sounds reasonable.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
[g0n] 2005-08-26&lt;p&gt;
I note that [id://485905] has been hanging around with a consideration for a title change for a few days. I've been reluctant to act on the consideration, because the suggested title seems to assume the node is a SoPW, rather than a question about the best way of posting a question. Does anyone else think it should be unconsidered (and perhaps reconsidered with a title like "How best to post large chunks of code")?&lt;p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[demerphq], [localtime://2005-08-22 05:06:35]&lt;br /&gt;
Presumably every janitor is a newbiew janitor at some point. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Chady], [localtime://2005-08-22 03:43:44]&lt;br/&gt;
I wonder how many newbies are janitors.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[demerphq], [localtime://2005-08-22 03:35:34]&lt;br /&gt;
I wouldnt mind if there was a way to select longer links in [User Settings]. The super short links are good for the people who know the nodelet well, but arent much good for newbies and others not particularly familiar with the options. &lt;b&gt;Update:&lt;/b&gt; never mind, i didnt realize the tool-tip text was what you meant by text=. And it looks like it sorts things out nicely.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], [localtime://2005-08-21 16:54:41]&lt;br /&gt;
Some more thoughts on the Editors Nodelet: 
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;s/child/parent/ as we're changing the parent of this node&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;with link to cabal wiki gone, 'Wiki' is unambiguous&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;use /msgs for link to inbox so there is consistency with other cabal nodelets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;remove link to user group (does anyone use that link?; other cabal nodelets 
    don't have one)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;don't go overboard with acronyms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;table width="26%" border="1"&gt;
  &lt;tbody class="nodelet"&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt; 
      &lt;td&gt; [display] [edit] | Fix: &lt;a href="#" title="Thread retitler"&gt;title&lt;/a&gt; 
        &lt;a href="#" title="Reply mover"&gt;parent&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="#" title="Convert Snippet to Code"&gt;snip&lt;/a&gt; 
        | &lt;a href="#" title="Janitors' Wiki"&gt;Wiki&lt;/a&gt;(*) &lt;a href="#" title="Janitors' message inbox"&gt;/msgs&lt;/a&gt;(&lt;b&gt;2&lt;/b&gt;) 
        | &lt;a href="#" title="Editor requests"&gt;ER&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="#" title="Nodes requiring editting"&gt;NRE&lt;/a&gt; 
        &lt;a href="#" title="Nodes to consider"&gt;NTC&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="#" title="Recent janitorial edits"&gt;RJE&lt;/a&gt; 
        | &lt;a href="#" title="Janitorial guidelines"&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2005-08-19 10:08:45]&lt;br /&gt;
consistency is good. That is why we always show the link text but sometimes just don't make it a link (when it is cheap enough and easy enough to tell when it isn't useful). "fix: [title] [child] [snip],".
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Also, s/guidelines/jgl/, s/hysteries/rje/, s/ets// (and update that node), and let's not have 'cw' links in so many different nodelets, eh?  Add title= for those rare times when you go to use something that you haven't used for a while.  Fix the division between "this node" links and global links:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;table width="50%" border="0"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td width="50%"&gt;
&lt;table width="100%" border="1"&gt;&lt;tbody class="nodelet"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;
[display] [edit] Fix: &lt;a href="#" title="Thread retitler"&gt;title&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="#" title="Reply mover"&gt;child&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="#" title="Convert Snippet to Code"&gt;snip&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="#" title="Janitors' Wiki"&gt;JW&lt;/a&gt;(*) &lt;a href="#" title="Janitors' message inbox"&gt;JMI&lt;/a&gt;(&lt;b&gt;2&lt;/b&gt;) &lt;a href="#" title="Editor requests"&gt;ER&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="#" title="Nodes requiring editting"&gt;NRE&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="#" title="Nodes to consider"&gt;NTC&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="#" title="Recent janitorial edits"&gt;RJE&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="#" title="Janitors (user group)"&gt;JUG&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="#" title="Janitorial guidelines"&gt;JGl&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td width="50%"&gt;
&lt;table width="100%" border="1"&gt;&lt;tbody class="nodelet"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;
[display] [edit] Fix: &lt;a href="#" title="Thread retitler"&gt;title&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="#" title="Reply mover"&gt;child&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="#" title="Convert Snippet to Code"&gt;snip&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="#" title="Janitors' Wiki"&gt;jw&lt;/a&gt;(*) &lt;a href="#" title="Janitors' message inbox"&gt;jmi&lt;/a&gt;(&lt;b&gt;2&lt;/b&gt;) &lt;a href="#" title="Editor requests"&gt;er&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="#" title="Nodes requiring editting"&gt;nre&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="#" title="Nodes to consider"&gt;ntc&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="#" title="Recent janitorial edits"&gt;rje&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="#" title="Janitors (user group)"&gt;jug&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="#" title="Janitorial guidelines"&gt;jgl&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Note that I've tried to list the links in a logical progression: (this node (fix)) (communication from most-internal to most-external) (other info sources from most-dynamic to most-static).  I left out the link to approved HTML tags in part because there is more than one set and so linking to just one doesn't make much sense while linking to all of them seems a bit much and those links are completely static anyway so people can add them to their Free or Personal nodelet along with links to write-up formatting tips or other quasi-janitorial nodes.  Note that I even added title= "tips".
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter] 2005-08-19 1313 UTC&lt;br/&gt;
Ehhh... not 'move'. Too ambiguous. How about 'codify'?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], [localtime://2005-08-19 07:04:02]&lt;br /&gt;
My preference is to only show these links when it makes sense e.g. only show the link to the snippet converter if the current node is a snippet (and call the link 'move'). 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2005-08-19 06:13:06]&lt;br /&gt;
Um.  Do you have suggestions for 3-5 letter links?  I was thinking of "reparent retitle snipmove".
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2005-08-19 03:03:16]&lt;br /&gt;
You might want to put a bit of non-breaking text into your Free Nodelet so that your nodelets have a little wider minimum width so they aren't as tall.  Even 5 more janitor links wouldn't be a whole line for me (and I use a small browser window).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I'd also personally trim some 'fat' from the cabal and pmdev nodelets.  I like the janitors' nodelet style (I shoot for 3..5 letters per link).  I'm tempted to extend the free nodelet templating to support wiki / inbox polling so I can just replace all those other nodelets with my personal design. Maybe someone else will be tempted?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2005-08-19 00:46:15]&lt;br /&gt;
The disadvantage to having them all linked in the nodelet is space; for me, the XP Nodelet, Editors Nodelet, Tick tock, and Cabalists' Nodelet just fit on the first page; those are the things I most want to get to without scrolling.
&lt;p&gt;
But you've made a good case against lumping them together, so unless anyone strongly objects, we can do it your way.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2005-08-18 17:47:17]&lt;br /&gt;
Then you have to worry about avoiding CGI parameter name collisions.  And perhaps other interesting interactions from having them all being loaded and run (in some order) where you are only actually wanting one of them to do something.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Having links to them all together in the nodelet (which is more convenient because of the ability to preload them based on the node you clicked from) means that there is little advantage to having them all together on one page.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So I see risks and little advantage.  But if anyone wants to work on them the hard way because they see some advantage that I don't, they can feel free.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2005-08-18 17:18:52]&lt;br /&gt;
Having them all together doesn't preclude preloading the node to be modified.  I was thinking each tool would be a separate htmlcode called by ehomat.  Or there could be separate superdocs lumped together with frames and /bare.  (Former preferable, latter slightly easier and giving individual tool access as well.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2005-08-17 20:46:55]&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, they should all have individual links in the nodelet so that following the link can preload the node to be modified.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I'm not fond of the idea of throwing them all together in one node because it surely makes the code for each harder to maintain.  A whimsical node name is not enough justification for that. (:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], [localtime://2005-08-17 20:27:14]&lt;br /&gt;I'll vote in favor of ehomat containing forms for each of those tools all on one page.  Why?  Semantics: It &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a hall of mirror&lt;u&gt;s&lt;/u&gt; and trickery.  So far we have only one mirror, and one trick there. ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2005-08-17 20:20:06]&lt;br /&gt;
We now have several janitor tool pages: [The editors' hall of mirrors and trickery], [Thread Retitler], and [Convert snippet to code].  Should they all have individual links in the Editors Nodelet?  Should ehomat be changed to be a list of links the available tools, and the current reparenting stuff move to a new page?  Or should ehomat show the forms for all the tools?  Opinions?
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], 2005-08-08 20:12:36 GMT-1&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I prefer &lt;i&gt;"Re^4: $&amp;#91; is under respected. (Welcome to the monastery)"&lt;/i&gt; which would de-emphasize the "Welcome to the monastery" part while preserving the author's intent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2005-08-08 14:30:09]&lt;br /&gt;
[jdporter] had considered [481127] for retitling from "Welcome to the Monastery" to "Re^4: $&amp;#91; is under respected.".  It seemed to me the title chosen was a significant part of the response to the parent node, and so I changed it to "Welcome to the monastery (Re^4: $&amp;#91; is under respected.)".  [jdporter] objects: "When people search on "Welcome to the monastery", this node should not come up!" and asks that the (now unconsidered) consideration be implemented as originally specified.  I don't feel comfortable removing content that way, but wanted to pass along his request in case anyone else felt it was appropriate to act on in any way.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2005-07-17 00:56:18]&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, that was a very poor title suggestion; the questioner's posed problem seems to involve what happens &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; working around proxy problems, and it removes the keyword "module" from the title to replace it with "DBI" when the problem seems fairly clearly not module specific.  But I see it's been changed; oh well.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[g0n], 2005-07-15&lt;p&gt;

[id://474386] has been considered for a title change, but I'm not sure about [Arunbear]s suggested alternative. It's been sat in nre for a few days. I've msg'd the node author asking for a more descriptive title, msg text as follows:
&lt;p&gt;
/msg artsnova re [id://474386] Could you look at your node. It's been considered for a title change. Could you give us a more descriptive title to use and someone will retitle the thread? Pls respond by /msg to [Janitors] - thanks.

&lt;p&gt;
BTW, I agree with [davido] on [id://282181].
&lt;hr&gt;



&lt;p&gt;[davido], [localtime://2005-07-10 03:07:22]&lt;br /&gt;
But it is not &lt;em&gt;off topic&lt;/em&gt; as a [Meditations|Meditation].  We fix problems, and occasionally facilitate author requests.  This one isn't a problem, and the author hasn't requested any action.  If nothing's wrong with it being a meditation, and the author hasn't expressed a desire to have it moved, leave it alone.  ...just another 2-cents. ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2005-07-10 02:35:11]&lt;br /&gt;
My feeling is that it does make a good tutorial, but I prefer to get author approval before moving to tutorials.  I /msg'd [Cine] about it on 20050623, but s/he hasn't been around since then.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], 2005-07-09&lt;br /&gt;
There are a number of meditations on the [Tutorials] page e.g. [id://227909], [id://270016], [id://288022] and [id://317520]; and I'm not convinced that a node that was 'born' a Meditation should never be promoted to a Tutorial.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in this case I think that [id://282181] is not sufficiently insightful nor does it have a strong enough Perl focus to be  a Tutorial. So I agree with [davido]'s suggested course of action (though for different reasons).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], [localtime://2005-07-09 00:36:14]&lt;br /&gt;
Let's come to a consensus on [id://282181] (&lt;c&gt;[id://282181]&lt;/c&gt;).  This node has been considered for moving to [Tutorials].  The node was written 8-8-2003, which is nearly two years ago, but was considered a few days ago.  The vote currently is (keep/edit/delete) =&gt; 11/50/0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal feeling is this:  It was posted as a [Meditations|Meditation], and two years ago nobody felt strongly enough about it to move it to [Tutorials] back then.  Furthermore, it &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; posted as a meditation, by a PerlMonk who has been around since 2001.  If he had intended to post it as a Tutorial, he would have (or should have). Also, the author has not voiced any opinion one way or another on moving this node.  I would expect that if he wanted it moved, he would have let someone know.  Given all those arguments, I don't see any reason to move it now, two years later, out of Meditations where it was approved, without the author's recommendation.  I'm in favor of unconsidering it, documenting the vote, and spending the rest of the evening playing Soduko. ;)  But given the fact the vote so strongly supports moving it, I wanted confirmation of my position before I unconsider it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Corion], [localtime://2005-07-06 10:21:56]&lt;br /&gt;
My rule of thumb is not do touch stuff (janitorially) where I'm involved personally. That is, I dont unconsider nodes written by myself and I also don't frontpage threads where I replied. I do clean up nodes to which I reply though, or consider these nodes.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2005-07-05&lt;br /&gt;
Inappropriate, yes.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], 2005-07-05&lt;br /&gt;
If a node authored by a janitor gets considered for reaping but does not eventually get reaped e.g. [id://471519], would it be unethical for that janitor to unconsider his/her own node?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[davido], 2005-06-07&lt;br /&gt;
Today I noticed a bug in the [id://417955|Janitor's Thread Retitler] wherein the automated /msg sent to a thread's base-node author would fail to reach its intended destination if the author's username contained whitespace.  This is related to the common slipup in the CB, where if you type "&lt;code&gt;/msg Abe Vigoda Too many prunes, sir!&lt;/code&gt;" the message would be sent to "Abe", not "Abe Vigoda".  The bugfix in the code is the same as the CB fix: wrap the username in &lt;code&gt;[ ... ]&lt;/code&gt; brackets.  The bug has been fixed in the [id://417955|Janitor's Thread Retitler].  If you use this code, please grab the latest version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was at it, I also added a sanity check so that /msg's won't be sent to [Anonymous Monk].  (Prior to the bugfix, they were probably all going to someone named [Anonymous] anyway.  Whoever that is never complained. ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Corion], 2005-05-25&lt;br /&gt;
For future reference, when I approved [id://460278] (quite shortly after it was posted), it immediately appeared without content - neither title nor body were there, although the author was still there. I'm not sure if the author tried to wipe the node (I got no reply on that), or if it is a site-internal error, maybe a race condition. So I'm documenting the incident here. I restored the node content (title+body) from the browser history.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2005-05-25&lt;br /&gt;
I'm certainly for a consideration history, which will show what considerations have been made on a node, who made them, what the voting came to, and what action was actually taken. I was planning to add that to my moderation changes, when they actually get added in ,)
&lt;p&gt;
I agree with your node, the problem here is education of the users, a) those who consider, and b) those who vote. The first I was also planning to help out, by changing the methods of consideration. Instead of just a textfield to type in, we'd have a list of things to choose from, for example, when choosing "duplicate" you wouldnt be able to submit the consideration until you'd entered a valid node_id that its supposed to be a duplicate of, and so on. See my posts on considerations. It's also waiting for the above to prove itself - so many ideas, so little time.. I'm still pondering on the education of the voters though, we can't force them to read the content or think first.
&lt;p&gt;
I assume you mean a wiki for janitors/cabal, to discuss people that make bad considerations? I cant really see a use for it, /msging them usually helps, I find. And if we have a consideration history, we'll be able to look overall at who's considered what, why etc. Maybe someone should start in on this already, it shouldnt be all that hard to add.
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ysth], 2005-05-24&lt;br /&gt;
I'd appreciate feedback or discussion of [id://460210].  Especially if you disagree.  Tangentially, if we had a wiki for recording feedback given to considerers for bad consideration, would you use it?  I ask because my browser remembers that I've asked the considerer in the above case to make sure to link to the claimed duplicate node before, and I'm wondering if we should start collecting data on repeat offenders.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2005-05-20&lt;br /&gt;
Okay, I'll speak up.  It doesn't qualify as a tutorial to me.  Personally, I'd move it to [Meditations].  That is, I don't think it is of sufficient generality and detailed tutoring to be what people are looking for when they search through [Tutorials].  I think it is a fine explanation and is educational.  I think it could become a tutorial if extended quite a bit.  But that is just one opinion.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[dvergin], 2005-05-18&lt;br /&gt;
In the node [id://458419] in [id://6345], [5mi11er] requests that his recent tutorial, [id://457993], be listed on the [Tutorials] page. My tuit supply is in deficit at the moment and I'm a bit foggy about the process for screening Tutorials for addition to the Tutorials page. 
&lt;p /&gt;
Is there someone who could handle this?
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], 2005-05-10&lt;br /&gt;
[id://17558] is probably a better place to point to by default (and pmaht is one of the first links on it).  Care to suggest a default message in full?  Right now it's: 
&lt;code&gt;"/msg $authtitle I've edited [id://$id]; see [node://$id;edithistory|node history]"
&lt;/code&gt;
(with everything from the ; on removed if the edit was marked private).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[merlyn], 2005-05-09&lt;br /&gt;
It'd be nice if the /msg sent to users when I edit their node also included the [pmaht] link,
since I'm almost always editing some crap they put in because they don't know about that.
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2005-02-08&lt;br /&gt;
IDs of [PERLscienceman]s emptied nodes, since I'm unconsidering them from NTC. [271337], [271391], [301386], [301464]. (Should we really care to restore them at some point. I would, only they don't seem to exist on thepen.)
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], 2005-01-24&lt;br /&gt;
It's bothered me for awhile, and [castaway] finally gave me the nudge that got me moving on it.  I've updated the [id://417955|Janitor's Thread Retitler] so that the attribution appended to the end of the base node being retitled now includes the original title.  The text appended will now default to: "&lt;code&gt;Retitled by [yourusername] from 'old title'.&lt;/code&gt;"  I hope this helps.  For now the plan is for the latest version to always reside at [id://417955|417955].  Questions/comments, please contact [davido|me].
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[davido], 2005-01-09&lt;br /&gt;
The offtopicroot section was created as a proof of concept, and while I agree with the concept, it is my understanding that it is not intended for actual use at thie time.  That being the case, it should probably be empty, though I can't imagine those nodes will be missed. ;)  But yes, it's not an official '&lt;em&gt;for use&lt;/em&gt;' section yet since there has never been a consensus among the [gods] as to whether it's a proper way of handling off topic stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], 2005-01-09&lt;br /&gt;
Is [castaway]'s patch [id://410885] (which would allow offtopicroot nodes to be listed  in writeups and hence be found by their authors) likely to be applied? Otherwise would anybody mind if the current 3 offtopic inmates ([id://398314], [id://399363] and [id://410972]) were released back into the Monastery?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2005-01-02&lt;br /&gt;
Unconsidered it. You're right. Despite how some people may like us to improve spelling, grammar, punctuation and information given, we don't do that. IMO linkifying things falls into that category. Especially as in that consideration, linkifying bare html addresses I do do occasionally.
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[davido], 2005-01-01&lt;br /&gt;
Happy New Year folks...&lt;br /&gt;
[id://191366] has been considered for editing to linkify some of its text.  I oppose doing this for the following reasons:  (1) The node is 2.5 years old; if it hasn't been considered for this before, why now?  (2) I don't think we should be getting in the habbit of linkifying posts; once started down that road where do we stop? Plus, if the original author wanted links, he would (or should) have put them there him/herself.  The node isn't harmed by not having them, it's just not as effective as it could be.  But there are a lot of nodes that are less effective than they could be... we don't upgrade the quality of the content of peoples' posted nodes.  If there is no significant argument to the contrary, I favor unconsidering this node and opting for inaction in this case.  But based on the current consideration vote, I don't feel comfortable acting on my own without conferring with the rest of this clan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[davido], 2004-12-29&lt;br /&gt;
You're probably tired of updates, but [id://417955] is a complete rewrite based on [id://417429|PerlMonks::Mechanized].  The PM::Mech module made it easier to add features, while simplifying the code.  The command-line options were streamlined, &lt;code&gt;s/from/to/&lt;/code&gt; was implemented, transactions added, etc.  See the node for details.  This is probably the last major update I'll be doing on it unless something breaks.  In the future, minor revisions will be carried out on the root node, at which time I'll just make a quick notice here in the wiki.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], 2004-12-23&lt;br /&gt;
With two voices of opposition, and nobody among the [Janitors] disagreeing with [Arunbear]'s point, I've removed the &lt;u&gt;OT: &lt;/u&gt; prefix from the thread's titles.  I think that just like any of the [Janitors], I try to exercise good judgement, and to err on the side of inaction rather than hasty action.  This was a node that did seem off topic to me, though when presented with the argument [Arunbear] makes, I have to agree that my first and second impression may have been wrong.  To be fair, I should state that the vote for retitling was (keep/edit/delete) &lt;b&gt;0 / 20 / 2&lt;/b&gt; at the time that I went ahead and added the &lt;u&gt;OT: &lt;/u&gt; prefix.  But in the spirit of erring on the side of inaction, I've put it back to original state.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2004-12-23&lt;br /&gt;
Agreed, Arunbear.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], 2004-12-23&lt;br /&gt;
The question in [416768] is vague (probably due to English not being the OP's native language), but I would interpret it as "I am looking for a web-based text editor implemented as a Perl CGI script, which has editing features similar to Vim". One of the OP's [416810|replies] even mentions that Perl code is being sought. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that what the OP is looking for probably doesn't exist does not make the post off-topic. I think the mob was wrong in their consideration of this node, and am surprised that it was retitled.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[davido], 2004-12-14&lt;br /&gt;
Done.  Good call.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Corion], 2004-12-14&lt;br /&gt;
As a General Hint, I recommend using environment variables instead of hardcoded strings for storing passwords, if only for the reason that you can post code without worrying about posting your password. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[davido], 2004-12-14&lt;br /&gt;
I've done a lot of work on revamping and improving the Janitors Thread Retitler in response to Janitor suggestions.  I've implemented most of the suggestions that have been submitted.  The new version is located here: [id://414646].  Please do let me know if you have any additional thoughts / comments / needs / suggestions.  Enjoy!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], 2004-12-11&lt;br /&gt;
IMO [id://413961] should not have been reaped. It is neither off-topic nor offensive. I hope that the [gods] will unreap it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2004-12-10&lt;br /&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://412764], as we can't move nodes from Snippets to SoPW. Shame, that..
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2004-12-01 (Happy December!)&lt;br /&gt;
Hmm, ok, moved node back to perlquestion, retitled, and unapproved it. 
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[davido], 2004-11-30&lt;br /&gt;
I've posted a newfangled tool here: [id://411280].  It requires WWW::Mechanize version 0.74 or newer.  I've tested it on complex threads that run as deep as 20 levels, and it works great.  It is fairly verbose as to what it's doing at all times.  Because it uses the XML tickers instead of screen scraping to walk the thread, it should be more robust than the previous de-facto tool.  Enjoy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2004-11-30&lt;br /&gt;
offtopicroot was a proof of concept. I haven't seen any concensus on actually making use of it, so I don't think using it is advisible (except as part of proving or improving the concept or trying to stimulate a move toward concensus on more of the issues surrounding off-topic nodes).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I don't see this as an issue not meant to stimulate discussion so I think it should be moved to the Inner Scriptorium, especially since "the public" may wonder what happened with that node.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2004-11-30&lt;br /&gt;
I did both of those. The unconsideration was because we (as editors) currently cant edit offtopicroot nodes, I should have edited first, then moved, but didnt. So now I have it in my TODO to fix, should anyone apply my patches to allow editing off offtopicroot nodes. (Or fix otherwise, should [gods|someone] decide this isnt desirable). There are no official or hard and fast rules for 'what is offtopic', everyone has their own opinion on it, unfortunately. Its more of a 'you know it when you see it', thing.
&lt;p&gt;
For the curious, my scale goes something like (for SoPW): &lt;br /&gt;
OnTopic = Contains perl code, asks how to do something in perl, how to install/setup perl&lt;br /&gt;
BorderLine OnTopic = Algorithms (using perl code preferably), SQL using perl/DBI, file permissions in perl etc. pp. CGI problems when using perl, HTML/jscript (extreme borderline)&lt;br /&gt;
OffTopic = Linux installations, Apache installations/config (borderline when its directly about mod_perl/cgi), how to do stuff in other languages (borderline = communicating between them and perl), computer unrelated (tho we hardly get those)
&lt;p&gt;
As for the other sections, in PMD anything about the site is ontopic, everything else isnt; in Meditations theres room for philosphising about programming in general .. Theres probably some stuff Im forgetting. The biggest difficulty is when a question is posted, and its not immediately obvious that its about perl, try to assume it is, unless .. well hard to tell how otherwise. If its not obvious, then post a reply asking for clarification, before considering for OffTopic.
&lt;p&gt;
When Ive moved my Moderation changes over (soon, I promise!), I was planning to have a go at improving considerations, eg: consideration history for nodes, msg to author on consideration, msg to considerer on edit/reap/unconsider (with reason), more concrete consideration reasons.

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear] 2004-11-30&lt;br /&gt;
Yesterday, [410798] was blessed (or cursed?) as an offtopicroot. It was also considered for a retitle - 'add OT to title' (I voted 'delete'), but was finally unconsidered without the title change being made. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is this now the official way to deal with off topic posts? If so, an announcement needs to made to that effect. Also, the Consideration and Editor's guidelines would need updating.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2004-11-23&lt;br /&gt;
How is this not a topic meant to lead to discussion?  Please move this to the Inner Scriptorium.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], 2004-11/23&lt;br /&gt;
I could see raising the number of keep/edit votes necessary to block reaping to three, or at the very most, four.  I believe also that there should be a minimum consideration time, so that if enough 'delete' people jump onto a node quickly to get it reaped, the system still gives a few minutes for voices of reason to weigh in.  Maybe it could be something like this:  If there are zero keep votes, the consideration lasts ten minutes.  If there are one, two, or three keep votes, consideration lasts an hour.  And if a fourth keep vote comes, reaping is effectively blocked.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editor deletes wouldn't be subject to the wait period.  This will allow a few Janitors to jump on something truly offensive if necessary.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ysth], 2004-11-23 &lt;br /&gt;
The larger number of senior monks means more lemming-votes too.  I'd rather keep it at 2 even at the cost of more trouble for janitors/gods.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2004-11-23 &lt;br /&gt;
Folks, Any objections to raising the number of keep/edit votes needed to prevent a reap? (We can raise the number of reap votes needed too if need be) - reason, there are many more &gt;lvl5 than there used to be, so more likelyhood of bungled votes, IMO. In fact, having these as some (small) precentage of the number of users &gt;lvl5 would fix it for good.. 
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[dvergin] 2004-11-21 Thanks to all who became involved in this matter.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2004-11-21&lt;br /&gt;
Patched. Should now complain unless the parent node is one of: &lt;br /&gt;
monkdiscuss perlmeditation perlquestion perltutorial CUFP poem obfuscated perlnews note&lt;br /&gt;
Also fixed another funky bug while I was at it... 
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[theonetwo] 2004-11-21&lt;br /&gt;
Sigh.  Reblessed the node into SoPW, removed the cruft from the note table.  There's a big difference between a node being a reply to the page that displays [perlquestion] nodes, and being a node of type [perlquestion].  EHoMT makes a node into a reply to the selected node.  It does /not/ do what you want.  Big hint: Root nodes, by defintion, have no parent.  Hint 2: putting a "0" in the parent field won't do what you want either.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ysth] 2004-11-20&lt;br /&gt;
I meant creating a perlquestion named "Adopting Modules" and moving the bad note to be under it.  Sorry for not being more clear.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[dvergin] 2004-11-20&lt;br /&gt;
Quothe [ysth]: "&lt;i&gt;For now perhaps a dummy SoPW should be created (with that same title)...&lt;/i&gt;"
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you did that, where would the link called "Seekers of Perl Wisdom" (at the top of this and nearly every PM page) take people? It points to the page by title, not by nodeid. Besides, at present, [409184] is poorly accessable but safe. How would your "for now" measure improve on that.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Thanks for the heads-up on moving non-root nodes with children.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ysth] 2004-11-20&lt;br /&gt;
Sorry, wasn't trying to comment on [409184], just pointing out another place where ehomat will let you shoot yourself in the foot, and how you can correct that case.&lt;p&gt;
For now perhaps a dummy SoPW should be created (with that same title) and 409184 moved to under it?
If no one objects in the next few hours, I may do this.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[dvergin] 2004-11-20&lt;br /&gt;
[409184] is a root node. The issue is not a matter of children following or not following it when moved. The issue is that my attempt to move it from Meditations to SoPW using ehomat has messed up its status. It reports now as a 'note' rather than a 'perlmeditation' or a 'perlquestion' and it thinks it is a &lt;i&gt;reply&lt;/i&gt; to SoPW rather than a proper root node posting. Repairing this is, AFAIK, beyond my current capability.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ysth] 2004-11-20&lt;br /&gt;
Last I checked, ehomat also doesn't correctly handle moving non-root nodes with children; the children don't get their root set properly.  You have to go and move them in place to fix it (i.e. reparent them one by one to what's already their parent, elders first.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[dvergin] 2004-11-20&lt;br /&gt;
Sadly, [409184] presently believes it is nodetype: note rather than perlmeditation or perlquestion. So it cannot be unapproved through the normal mechanism. Leaving me to plead again for divine intervention.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
And yes, [tye], your gentle-but-pointed encouragement of this woefully dormant pmdev member is noted and taken to heart.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2004-11-20&lt;br /&gt;
Good idea.  I look forward to seeing your patch.

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Root nodes are not replies to the section that they are in.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
To move between sections, you unapprove the root node (and then revisit the node so the approval nodelet properly updates).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[dvergin] 2004-11-20&lt;br /&gt;
I've broken some data relationships. Monk [jk2addict] politely requested in [Editor Requests] that [409184] be moved from Meditations to SoPW. The reasoning seemed okay, so I tried using [The editors' hall of mirrors and trickery|ehomat] to do it, using 479 as the new parent id. Bad idea. I &lt;i&gt;did&lt;/i&gt; look for a Move Between Areas tool. Seems to me there used to be one, but I may just be thinking of the Q&amp;A mover tool which includes the SOPWify option. Is there such a tool?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now [409184] thinks it is a &lt;i&gt;reply&lt;/i&gt; to SoPW. Not the right state of affairs at all. And the node in question now seems to be listed in neither of the areas in question. &lt;b&gt;I humbly beg one of the Gods (or whomever) to undo what I have done.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Not to defend my own recklessness (ISLAGIATT), but perhaps [The editors' hall of mirrors and trickery|ehomat] should not allow misguided people to break things. Or at least the page could include a suitably ominous warning.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[demerphq] 2004-11-06&lt;br /&gt;
Rotated Wiki.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Steve_p] 2004-11-02&lt;br /&gt;
If you see a considered noded sitting for a while with a high total vote count, you should probably assume that the other janitors might have issues with the edit.  If the considered node is highly in favor of a particular action, adding a note to a node that it was unconsidered for a particular reason will help to prevent it from getting considered all over again.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2004-11-02&lt;br /&gt;
If you don't feel that a requested edit is appropriate, no matter what the voting on it, you shouldn't make the edit.  If all of the janitors feel this way and the edit is never made, then I trust a unanimous non-action of the janitors much more than the vote tally from the mob.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But please give the node plenty of time before unconsidering it if the vote tally is calling for action.  If you have issues with a consideration, then there are more appropriate actions than a lone-gunman removal of a consideration.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[theorbtwo] 2004-11-02 (Americans, go vote!)&lt;br /&gt;
If you think these are out of line, the best thing to do is to write a PMD on retitle considerations.  Considerations should only be dropped on the floor if they're clearly wrong or highly dangerous.  (Retitling "Help Needed" to "I'm a complete idiot" would be an example of the former; retitling it to "Newest Nodes" would be an example of both.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[Chady] 2004-11-02&lt;br /&gt;
Also an issue with considerations to retitle; there have been a lot of strange considerations lately, and, looking at votes, I think I'm the only one to disagree. I can completely understand the need to retitle "Help Needed" into "Problems installing Perl on Microwave system". But (for example) what is the point from retitling [id://404427|Hosting companies not supporting Perl] to "How do I get my Win32 hosting company to support Perl?"  What better purpose does it server? I'm inclined to unconsider, but there are 18 edit votes (as of this writing)&amp;lt;/rant&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[demerphq], 2004-11-02&lt;br /&gt;
The issue as i see it is that we would prefer that htmlcode and infrastructure nodes are unambiguous and they are virtually always single word names. Changing the search mechanism cant help this issue as no matter how look at it once the names are duplicated they (obviously) can't be uniquely resolved. Not only that but allowing the ambiguities to occur can mean that old code "breaks" for no reason (ie links that were once direct no longer are.) I dont think forbidding single word titles is wrong, on the contrary IMO people should be strongly encouraged not to use them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2004-11-02&lt;br /&gt;
I'm more bothered by changing them at all. If the only reason is because 'the search box otherwise doesnt actually search', then why dont we either a) rename it to 'Go To', or b) make it actually search? (Or even c) make another up there that searches)
&lt;hr /&gt;
Continued in [id://405784]...
</field>
</data>
</node>
