<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="593415" title="editors' wiki through 2007-01-06" created="2007-01-07 13:03:15" updated="2007-01-07 08:03:15">
<type id="68046">
wiki</type>
<author id="474174">
yitzchak</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;p&gt;[Corion], [localtime://2007-01-06 10:12:23]&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [perlpodtut] and [perlcheat] due to their votes. The haznav presented by them isn't that high as both actually link to the nodes the user likely would have wanted otherwise ([doc://perlpodtut] and [doc://perlcheat], neither of which exist locally).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The counts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[perlpodtut]: 
Considered: [jdporter]: Retitle (haznav): "RFC: Should perlpodtut (POD in 5 Minutes) be added to the Perl doc?" Keep: 15, Edit: 39, Reap: 0
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[perlcheat]: Considered: [jdporter]: Retitle (haznav): "RFC: Should perlcheat (the perl cheat sheet) be added to the Perl doc?" Keep: 14, Edit: 39, Reap: 0
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[demerphq], [localtime://2006-12-31 07:12:31]&lt;br/&gt;
Yes my consideration it was a bit hasty. But the form of the posting smelled wrong to me. Anyway, sorry for the trouble
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], [localtime://2006-12-30 23:56:19]&lt;br /&gt;
That's something the [gods] alone can do, and must be requested of [gods|them].  It's another example of hasty consideration, and a slew of hasty lemming-style voting.  Let's try to be on guard.  All it needed was two sensible keep votes to block reaping.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], [localtime://2006-12-30 17:18:10]&lt;br/&gt;
Please unreap [id://592339]. As [id://592365|pointed out] by [BerntB], it is a joke not spam. What Perl hacker would not be amused at the notorious [Eval] being raised to sainthood?!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], [localtime://2006-12-24 21:01:15]&lt;br /&gt;
Good call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], [localtime://2006-12-24 19:41:02]&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://589736] (consideration was &lt;i&gt;[planetscape]: Please re-parent under [id://589544], to which this is properly a reply&lt;/i&gt;; Keep: 13, Edit: 51, Reap: 3; considered on 2006-12-14) and moved it to PMD. It is addressed to the monastery rather than the author of [589544], and reparenting it would likely puzzle someone reading the resulting thread.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="removal2"&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2006-12-24 06:30:47]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Per &lt;a href="#removal1"&gt;earlier mention&lt;/a&gt;, the ranks of the [janitors] have been thinned from 43 to 11.  Everyone left, please do try to read the wiki; either the Editors Nodelet or the Cabalists' Nodelet will let you know when it's been modified.  For the time being, the wiki is still readable to all the former members; if any of them notices they've been dropped, you can direct them here to see what they missed.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], [localtime://2006-12-24 01:37:00]&lt;br /&gt;
I unconsidered [id://590386].  The consideration was: &lt;em&gt;[tinita]: Duplicate of Installing using CPAN without internet. reparent maybe?&lt;/em&gt; The vote was 5/19/7.  But the node was not a true duplicate, and the number of good replies makes it stand as its own thread, not in need of reparenting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[GrandFather], [localtime://2006-12-23 17:23:45]&lt;br/&gt;
I'm available to continue as janitor if my services are desired.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[gryphon], [localtime://2006-12-19 16:09:42]&lt;br/&gt;
I'd like to continue to be a janitor, despite having little time right now to do much besides read.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], [localtime://2006-12-19 03:57:44] &lt;br /&gt;
I think we need to cautiously hold off on taking any retitling action on [id://316079] and [id://237910].  [Juerd] has expressed a strong desire to keep the nodes as they are. I'm reluctant to put words in his mouth against his wishes. There is a hazard to navigation issue on the one hand. On the other hand, the nodes are both at least three years old already.  On the one hand, we've pretty much banned one-word titles, and these titles can conflict with actual POD.  On the other hand, the site isn't actively maintaining a local POD anyway. The titles may be a problem, but until we've had time to reach a consensus that [Juerd] is happy with too, it won't hurt to let those three year old nodes remain unchanged a little longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone has opinions on the matter, let's hear it.  My own feeling is that if the nodes are going to be changed three years after the fact, it's the author who should probably be the one to do it.  But that regrettably doesn't solve the one-word-title issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[davido], [localtime://2006-12-18 01:21:16] &lt;br /&gt;
I moved [id://590389] from PMD to SoPW and added format tags to match OP's intent.  [jimman666] has been /msg'ed with an explanation of the move, and a pointer to [id://17558].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[planetscape], [localtime://2006-12-17 21:50:40]&lt;br/&gt;
But [demerphq|you] look so &lt;i&gt;good&lt;/i&gt; in your halo... ;-)&lt;br/&gt;
Count me in too, please.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[demerphq], [localtime://2006-12-17 13:37:52]&lt;br/&gt;
Not sure if this is really necessary in my case, but id like to preserve my right to access the janitorial controls using this account. Id rather not have to put on my halo to do so if I need to.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Chady], [localtime://2006-12-15 15:41:00]&lt;br /&gt;
I'd like to continue to be a janitor.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[g0n], [localtime://2006-12-15 12:56:00]&lt;br /&gt;
I'd like to continue [janitors|janitoring] as well.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], [localtime://2006-12-15 03:32:03]&lt;br /&gt;
I'm also game for more punishment.  Count on me, and count me in as a [Janitors|janitor].  ...and again my apologies for the occasional fumble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Corion], [localtime://2006-12-15 03:00:37]&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;aol&gt;me too&lt;/aol&gt; ... maybe we oughta allow &lt;c&gt;&lt;aol&gt;&lt;/c&gt; tags ...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], [localtime://2006-12-14 19:49:10]&lt;br/&gt;
I too would like to continue doing janitorial work.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2006-12-14 19:39:22]&lt;br/&gt;
I'd like to continue to be a janitor.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="removal1"&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2006-12-14 19:35:50]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In an effort to have more consistent application of site policy, we are trying to reduce [janitors] to just those who intend to be active and are willing to be responsive to feedback.  Anyone wishing to continue as a janitor, please say so here in the next 7 days.  Thanks.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2006-12-14 16:21:37]&lt;br/&gt;
The original consideration I saw was to move to PMD.  So either yet another silent unconsideration was done or you misremember (or perhaps I do, though I recall that quite clearly).  Move to PMD isn't out-of-hand an invalid choice.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
To quote myself "&lt;em&gt;clearly&lt;/em&gt; bad consideration ... (clearly bad to me and clearly bad to most others)".  Otherwise it should get a chance and, if it gets unconsidered quickly (because the voting on it was fast and "against"), then a footer is likely appropriate.  Though I'd much rather have a moderation history table for such notes.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Being in a rush to "fix" things is usually the best way to make a mistake.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], [localtime://2006-12-14 13:46:16]&lt;br /&gt;
I'll take responsibility for the unconsideration.  I believed that the original consideration was incorrect in recommending that the node be moved to [Meditations], and that the proper recommendation would be to assign it to the thread to which it was responding.  Clearly it's not a SoPW, nor a stand-alone Meditation.  It's a response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I discussed it with [planetscape] because I wanted a second opinion, since I felt I was too close to the discussion to take action myself.  However, I do want to say that my motives were not influenced by my proximity to the thread.  I actually believe that reparenting it, while the right thing to do, will make it easier for people to downvote my own node in the thread, so if anything I have a disincentive, and yet I still feel it's the right thing to do.  But I do want to apologize for the controversy, and will at least leave a note in the wiki in the future to document unconsiderations and the reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We see a lot of way-off-the-mark considerations, where a much better action is prevented from being voted on by the lingering errant consideration.  Maybe this wasn't one of those cases, though I felt it was.  But let's discuss for a moment what the proper course of action is in such cases where a good consideration is being prevented by a bad one lingering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2006-12-14 04:33:11]&lt;br/&gt;
It is a balance. Marring nodes with "unconsidered" footers isn't great but sometimes is probably the best route (for now).  Leaving people (like me) wondering what happened to the previous consideration isn't great.  Leaving a consideration up for a longer time means that I (and others) are likely to get a chance to see where the voting is going and not be left wondering as much -- so that is my preferred route in most cases.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Personally, I don't mind quickly unconsidering in many cases of a &lt;em&gt;clearly&lt;/em&gt; bad consideration where the janitor sends a /msg to the considerer (clearly bad to me and clearly bad to most others).  Title change considerations are the ones I most often see that I find clearly bad, and early unconsideration makes it more likely that someone else will provide a better new title suggestion if the node needs a new title but the consideration sucked.  But recently I've seen a lot more considerations for trivial title changes (trying to improve a title instead of fix a broken title) and those I prefer to stay up a while so people have a chance to see the voting (and so I can see how the voting is going to guage trends) and see that the change isn't being made and see how many trivial requests are being thrown around, etc.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I wouldn't quickly unconsider a request to reap even if it seemed pretty clearly bad.  The only drawback to waiting is that the node's author will get a few extra downvotes.  There are more important benefits by giving everyone time.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;
And I will also confess to voting to reap [id://587931], but I did &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; unconsider it; that would have been, IMHO, a textbook case for leaving an unconsider footer to prevent it being immediately re-considered for the same reason.
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But a footer doesn't prevent a node from being reconsidered for the same reason.  Leaving the consideration up actually does.  And if you are going to leave a footer, at least let the consideration exist long enough to justify a footer.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I'd just disallow unconsidering in less than 3 days if it weren't for "edit" considerations that get taken care of or mistake considerations.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If janitors discuss some action, then don't keep the rest of us in the dark.  If it warranted discussion, then it warrants not being kept a secret.  You don't have to have the conversation in the wiki, but at least leave a note that the discussion was had and the conclusions.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In this case, I'd not have rushed to remove the consideration even after some discussion.  At least a discussion in public would have been better, so those visiting the site around the time of the consideration would have some chance to see that.  And a lot of people would have had a chance to comment before someone's consideration was thrown away.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[planetscape], [localtime://2006-12-14 03:36:50]&lt;br/&gt;
As may probably be inferred from the fact that I (re)considered [id://589736] for reparenting, I was the one who initially (silently) unconsidered it, after discussion with [davido], who also felt it was more appropriate to reparent to the node to which it evidently replied than to move to [Perl Monks Discussion]. I saw nothing wrong with applying what, after consultation with a fellow [davido|janitor], seemed a more appropriate consideration, but felt moving without considering would have been far too hasty. (Actually, I did that {silently unconsidering} twice, as the first time I mistakenly typed something to the effect of 'please reparent to itself'. D'oh!)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And I will also confess to voting to reap [id://587931], but I did &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; unconsider it; that would have been, IMHO, a textbook case for leaving an unconsider footer to prevent it being immediately re-considered for the same reason.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], [localtime://2006-12-14 03:46:58]&lt;br/&gt;
At least this time I'm perfectly confident that I didn't unconsider that node.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; I'm about to unconsider [id://588386] and [id://588859], but as both were actually bad considerations, I don't see much sense in adding the "unconsidered by" footer to the nodes, as the node authors didn't have anything to do with the consideration. Should such happen, or does that fall under the "silent" umbrella too?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2006-12-14 03:12:40]&lt;br/&gt;
I disagree.  It isn't a reply to the author of that node but it is a reply to that node.  But I haven't voted on that consideration because I'm not completely comfortable with such a move (nor am I completely opposed to such).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This is yet another case of me coming back to nodes after a few hours and finding them silently unconsidered.  I've seen quite a lot of those recently.  I don't mind reluctance to add "unconsidered" footers to a node, but the absense of such certainly means that the act of unconsidering needs to be done at a much more relaxed pace.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And I'm still waiting for someone to fess up to prematurely unconsidering [id://587931] (and more recent examples, for that matter).  If nobody cares to discuss their actions, I'll likely do the extra work to figure out who it was and just kick them out of [janitors] for lack of transparency.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2006-12-14 02:36:36]&lt;br/&gt;
Re: [id://589736] (currently under consideration for reparenting under [id://589544]) I'd rather see it left as a root node but moved to PMD,
since it explicitly seems to be &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; addressed to the poster of [id://589544].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], [localtime://2006-12-08 01:36:56]&lt;br /&gt;
(Is this enough whitespace?)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I unconsidered [id://162123] (yes, that's 162123, from December 2002).  Three reasons for not taking action: First, the Craft section is officially closed and not accepting new posts.  There are a few good reasons for that, but one of them is that its structure makes code tags (or any other tags for that matter) irrelevant.  That means there's no way to "fix" the long lines in this post without altering content, and we're not going down that road.  The consideration called for changing pre tags to code tags.  Neither were used in the butchering of the layout of that node, so our action cannot do what the consideration asks, nor can we do anything to fix the appearance without altering the content.  Second, the node is so old it shouldn't be up for consideration anymore.  ...and I guess I've forgotten my third reason but it's done. ;) I just wanted to document the unusual unconsideration in case anyone asks why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt; 


&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2006-12-07 17:01:52]&lt;br/&gt;
(Why do you all hate vertical whitespace above your comment? Do we really need a screaming header in &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; wiki too?)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
NTC and NRE list nodes in order of when they were considered.  So lingering considerations are automatically conveniently moved down, out of the way.  And they won't remain forever.  Considering old nodes is nearly against site policy already.  And a few "don't touch any time soon" items often being present makes for good practice for [janitors] to not be busybodies.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], [localtime://2006-12-07 15:56:27]&lt;br/&gt;
I have a vague recollection about being annoyed by the consideration of [id://587931], but I have no memory of unconsidering it. But as nobody has owned up, maybe I really did unconsider it - a fruitless effort indeed, and I should've voted "keep" instead to move the consideration into the nonreapable limbo...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[GrandFather], [localtime://2006-12-08 8:27:00]&lt;br/&gt;
If we are going to adopt a policy of leaving considerations open then we need a way of dropping them off the [id://28877] and [id://59481] radar or the noise to signal ratio will become so high that those facilities will be useless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps a new "Inconsiderate" state would be appropriate. A considered node could be set to signal that it has been considered and was now in an unconsidered but locked state to prevent further consideration. If a note is needed for why, can it go in the edit history forthe node?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], [localtime://2006-12-07 13:39:44]&lt;br /&gt;
I have nothing to report.  It wasn't me.  But I'm happy to discuss.  You're discussing allowing a consideration to linger, in order to prevent re-consideration.  I think that's a good idea, though there might be a little "reputation vote" tainting by having an open consideration, but I guess them's the breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we're on the subject of leaving considerations open to prevent re-consideration, what about using considerations as instructional flags?  What I mean, for example, is instead of considering an OT node for reaping (which we shouldn't be doing), why don't we consider it for &lt;em&gt;remaining&lt;/em&gt; un-approved.  That would be a clue to all those lemmings out there that perhaps this one shouldn't be approved for the section into which it was posted. (All the caveats about the need to approve [Anonymous Monk] posts so he won't double-post are a different, probably settled discussion.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as for reaping off-topic, there may be a difference of opinion on what is the right thing to do, but there is no ambiguity in the site docs that constitute site policy.  We don't reap off-topic.  From [id://92975]:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Please only do this for blatant trolls (egregiously offensive) and true duplicates (where a post consisting of "I gave the same answer as some other monk but was slower" is not a duplicate). For useless, stupid, off-topic, and annoying nodes: if it is a root node, then don't approve it for any section; if it is a reply, just ignore it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And a little further down that same section:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please don't rush to consider a duplicate for reaping.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find it frustrating enough when the general population considers something for reaping when they shouldn't.  But I find it inexcusable when a [janitors|janitor] does it.  We ought to know what's in our site's documentation.  If we disagree with that, lets discuss and refine the policy.  But until it's changed, let's execute it as written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2006-12-07 12:20:43]&lt;br/&gt;
So nobody is going to report?  Being unable to own up to a possible mistake or being unwilling to discuss it is not compatible IMO with privileged access.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2006-12-05 23:04:11]&lt;br/&gt;
Whoever unconsidered [id://587931], please report to the wiki.  That was way too hasty.  You should have predicted that it would just get considered again.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And demerits to [GrandFather] for "calling for votes".  People vote on considerations without paying enough attention and/or enough thought already (as reinforced by several recent considerations).  One leap to the wrong conclusion should not be turned into a node reapage because the mistaken person encouraged others to vote their way in haste.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[g0n] [localtime://2006-11-28 13:06:00]&lt;br&gt;
Thanks for the clarification [tye]. I was being a little vague in lumping the two issues together [ysth]. 'Frequent' doesn't apply to edits/considerations for NSFW language - I'm vaguely aware of a small number (certainly single figures, probably less than 5) over the last 12 months, one of which was edited by me. It came to mind because in light of recent discussion I would no longer make that edit.&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
On the basis of what's gone before, would the appropriate behaviour be 'leave it alone,  *possibly* reconsidering for removal of inappropriate formatting tags if present'?
&lt;p&gt; 
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2006-11-28 12:50:52]&lt;br/&gt;
Hear, hear.  [tye] seems to have covered everything I would have wanted to say...except for the critically important issue of &lt;c&gt;[NSFW]&lt;/c&gt; vs. &lt;c&gt;(NSFW)&lt;/c&gt;.
[g0n] said:
&lt;blockquote&gt;
There are two other content edits that are frequently made though - Non worksafe/family safe language
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
I wasn't aware this was occurring at all, much less frequently.  Can you give an example?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2006-11-26 10:48:58]&lt;br/&gt;
I've repeatedly stated exactly why I think that trying to enforce a third party's copyright against the presumed infringement from a fourth party is a quite bad idea.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It is my experience that removing usernames and passwords is a mistake.  Every case that I've seen has actually been for naught because each time it was discovered (which never surprised me) that the author had actually not created a security problem.  But even if the author had, trying to unring the bell and pretend that the security problem had not been created isn't doing anyone a service.  The only fix for such a situation is for the original password to be changed.  So the best action is to notify the author and leave the node alone.  It isn't like there aren't tons of cached copies around anyway, including ones [g0n] provides.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And we shouldn't be in the business of jumping to conclusions about whether or not a security problem was created.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I'm more in favor of removing personal information, at least temporarily, if it is suspected that it was posted with malice, though not without reservations.  Posting your own password is a mistake you should face and deal with yourself.  Someone else posting your personal information isn't such.  A security problem really shouldn't be dealt with by minimizing it, leaking the password to only a presumed small part of the internet doesn't remove the need to change the password.  Personal information often can't be changed and getting less spam is better than getting more spam so reducing the impact of such a leak may be warranted.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Un-work-safe language (etc.) is best dealt with by encouraging the author to change it or letting the community reap it.  Beyond that, adding a "(NSFW)" tag to a title would be my preferred approach for quite a few reasons.  It'd be nice to add such a tag in way that replies drop it automatically, since the "Re:"-handling code does drop certain things, but I'm not sure that'll work in many cases and won't pursue it further at this point.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[g0n], [localtime://2006-11-26 14:29:]&lt;br /&gt;
While the subject of what is appropriate for janitors to edit is being discussed, there are a couple of points that we could perhaps do with a definite /documented policy on. The [id://324056|Guide] states that node content should only be changed to remove passwords/email addresses. There are two other content edits that are frequently made though - Non worksafe/family safe language, and links to pirated content.&lt;p&gt;
For my part, I'd say that the former depends on the post. I dare say few if any workplaces will have so restrictive a web access policy that curse words embedded in a page will trigger anything, and all the words that are likely to be flagged up as not family safe will be familiar to anyone old enough to have any interest at all in programming. On the other hand, many of us work in open plan offices, and an otherwise on topic post containing swear words in 30 point red text is likely to draw unwelcome attention. I've seen one or two of these, and had to click somewhere else sharpish.&lt;p&gt;
As to links to pirated content, such nodes seem to be routinely edited to remove the link, and in my view rightly so, but whether we should do this is not stated anywhere.&lt;p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;



&lt;p&gt;[davido], [localtime://2006-11-22 01:35:59]&lt;br /&gt;
I wanted to mention that [Old Gray Bear] considered [id://585446] for janitorial work to fix the all-caps title, and a couple of capitalized words in the body of the post.  The title, while a little unsightly, is not a danger to navigation, and not a threat to browser rendering.  I feel that we should leave it alone, and wanted to mention that here.  And if the title shouldn't be messed with, much less the body.  There's no way I would feel comfortable changing the fact that the original author (rightly or wrongly) chose to use caps for two of the words in his post.  Of course I'm one opinion among many [janitors], so if others wish to express their opinions, let's do it and resolve it here before any action is taken on that node.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[GrandFather], [localtime://2006-11-11 11:12:00]&lt;br/&gt;
As I recall [id://573374] was considered for reaping or editing to remove a link to a (presumed) illegal electronic copy of PBP. The node was reapd then a little while later someone ([jdporter] perhaps) pointed out that the link was still available. I "commented" it out. I notice that the link now leads to a message stating that the material has been removed following complaints.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], [localtime://2006-11-10 16:12:28]&lt;br/&gt;
I'm no fan of editing reaped nodes - I think reaping is enough. But on the other hand, wikipedia-style edit wars have no place here.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2006-11-10 15:45:18]&lt;br/&gt;
What's up with [id://573374] ([href://?node_id=573374;displaytype=edithistory|history]) ?  This looks like something that should be brought into the open rather than just dueling edits.  Summary of history:  [GrandFather] editted a reaped node to hide the link to details in HTML comments and [Arunbear] undid that edit a month later.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], [localtime://2006-11-09 18:24:27]&lt;br /&gt;
A note to [janitors] all: Please do be active in voting on considerations, even if you're often less active in performing edits.  You've been dubbed [Janitors|Janitor] because the [gods] believed in your wisdom.  Sometimes the best wisdom can be imparted by actively voting.  This is especially true of 'keep' votes.  So many simply think, "Hmm, sounds good to me..." and vote "edit" even if a prudent [Janitors|janitor] would assert that the best course of action is to leave it alone.  Your 'keep' votes might be the only ones out there.  But your opinion matters significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see on the [id://28877|ntc] list nodes considered for changing PRE to CODE tags, retitling, marking off-topic, and various other issues.  Some of those issues are more serious, and easier to fix, such as changing out errant PRE tags in favor of CODE tags.  Others may be less compelling.  When voting (and subsequently either acting or not acting), ask yourself if what you're doing matters enough for you to tamper with a node.  Often it does matter enough.  Sometimes it doesn't.  In the US, they say a person is innocent until proven guilty beyond reasonable doubt.  Perhaps we should look at the threshold for our intervention with a similarly conservative perspective.  Leet's not rush to convict a node if it might not be necessary to do so.  Remember the excellent counsel given in [id://459456].  I would take it a step further and suggest that we, in addition to being [janitors], have a responsibility to be teachers of the ways of the Monastery.  The /msg system is our tool to that end, along with our examples, and our working with [SiteDocClan] to maintain accurate and helpful documentation for newcomers.  We should be sending helpful /msg's to posters, and to those making considerations alike.  Such minor corrections in individuals' courses will help to maintain the aggregate course of the big ship.  (Sorry for the metaphor; Monasteries don't have physical courses, much less websites, so I had to come up with another object.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to summarize my long-winded thoughts: Vote on considerations.  Don't be afraid to vote 'keep'.  When you feel that a consideration misses the mark somehow, /msg the person who considered the node.  When you feel that a post should have been formatted or posted differently, /msg the author regardless of whether or not any janitorial work gets done.  Keep it kind and helpful.  Teach.  Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[planetscape], [localtime://2006-11-08 05:20:23]&lt;br/&gt;
My apologies: I have been ill with the flu, which is why I didn't comment earlier, but I realize I made a bad call, and I'll do my best not to repeat it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2006-11-07 15:33:50]&lt;br/&gt;
The last "public" statement she made (to the cabal) boiled down to "I still don't see how I could have done anything better".  If admitting any more than that prompts you to conjure up setting herself afire, then I think you've lost objectivity on the subject.  Based on my private communications with her, she tried to make such and failed so I expect her to try again at some point.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Yes, [demerphq], having special privileges may require that one swallow their pride and compose a "mea culpa", especially if they hope to keep those special privileges.  That is part of the price.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It is also often frowned upon to claim to not have time/energy to compose the "mea culpa" while still finding time/energy to make use of the special privilege.  It looks like [planetscape] may not have "janitored" since Nov 3rd so perhaps she has realized this, if a bit late. (:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[demerphq], [localtime://2006-11-07 14:06:38]&lt;br/&gt;
I think its clear that [planetscape] should immolate herself with a can of gasoline in the monastery courtyard. Anything less is an indication of her lack of repentance and proof that she really should be hung drawn and quartered as a traitor to the realm.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Seriously tho, what exactly does she have to say to be redeemed? Does she have to perform a public self criticism? I personally dont think she does.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], [localtime://2006-11-05 18:03:54]&lt;br/&gt;
[tye], I don't think you have any reason to be apologetic. 
[planetscape] has been a janitor for quite some time but unlike most other janitors still did not appreciate 
that a large number of edit votes does not make an inappropriate consideration any less inappropriate.
It is somewhat disturbing that she did not learn from [id://546480|previous] bad judgment, (and has yet to admit to bad judgment in the current case). 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2006-11-04 04:20:57]&lt;br/&gt;
Thank you, [davido], for those very practical points.  I agree with all of them.  Thanks for your support and thanks to a few other monks who have already now expressed in private their support for my view.  It is like a weight lifted.  One monk pointed out that they had already agreed with me in private, but that part of the discussion hadn't been clear to me (it felt like just "it's not our job"). Please continue to chime in in public or private so that whatever the consensus is becomes clear, perhaps especially if you disagree.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
What is also clear is that many worry that I've been too harsh on [planetscape].  For that, I apologize.  My intent is not to be harsh on her person, but I did and do feel strongly about the action.  Although it is easy to see it as having crossed the line only a little bit (yes, even I can see it that way), I find it too important of a line and the action still too clearly across it (however short of a distance) to leave the matter not clearly resolved (it appears that several have discussed the matter in private with [planetscape] and so are privy to responses from her that I am not and so see the matter as more clearly resolved than is evident to me).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I feel that a mistake was made.  We all make mistakes.  Having made a mistake is not something to lose much sleep over.  I spoke strongly, in part because I was speaking about something I see as important / fundamental.  My intent was not to strongly criticize [planetscape] as a person (ney, not to criticize her person at all).  I hope I didn't do that outright, but understand that it is hard to read strong words associated with criticism and not be hurt by them.  So I apologize again for what hurt I may have caused.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], [localtime://2006-11-04 02:16:00] &lt;br /&gt;
Ok, I saw the wiki, saw what happened, saw [tye]'s response, and felt the issue had been handled.  When I spoke with [planetscape], it seemed she understood, and I was satisfied that she had a better handle on what's appropriate now.  My own reluctance to jump into the wiki on this has nothing to do with a lack of support for [tye]'s position, but rather, that I just felt he expressed himself clearly enough to put the issue to rest.  But I understand how [tye|you] feel like you've been the only champion of the cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let me state my position on edits (which has evolved somewhat over the past year or two, and I'll try to point out those areas where I've evolved):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consideration votes are recommendations only.  A prudent steward would listen to the recommendations, and weigh them with his/her elevated experience and understanding on how things are supposed to be done around here.  50 edit votes doesn't mean it's right if the consideration is asking us to do something that we simply don't do.  It's ok to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; act on an affirmative consideration vote.  We have been given this stewardship &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; the [gods] felt we had an elevated understanding / experience.  Let's not be afraid to do what's right rather than what's popular.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just like it's ok to decline to take action on a consideration, it's also ok to take action even when there hasn't been a consideration.  It usually doesn't hurt to wait, but sometimes it's preferable to just get it over with when you know it's needed.  An example of this might be when a node has been considered for code tags, and while you're working on the code tags you realize there are also a bunch of pre tags forcing long lines.  ...clean that up while you're there too, rather than waiting for a second consideration.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are lots of [janitors]: When in doubt, leave it alone for someone else to act on, or to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; act on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resist the urge to participate just because you want to use your powers.  Ask yourself, would it hurt anything if I left this node alone?  Am I just jumping in because I can, or am I really doing this because I should?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never ever under any circumstances alter text.  I take this to also mean never linkify (though it may be ok to fix a link that's broken, if the author cannot be contacted or doesn't respond to contact attempts).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restrict edits to: code tags, formatting to match the OP's intended layout, removal of formatting that damages page rendering (such as really wide pre blocks), retitling when absolutely necessary to protect navagability, addition of readmore tags when it's blatantly obvious that they're needed.  When I say "formatting to match the OP's intended layout", this is easy to determine when looking at the editor's display of a node, because in that display you can see exactly how the OP typed his post.  Chances are good those posts where everything is all run together actually have neat and tidy formatting in the way the node was entered.  It just lacked the markup to cause that formatting to render.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reparenting is ok rarely, but probably best to wait until there's been a consideration, and some [janitorial] discussion first.  That's probably the tool we should be using the least, but there are times when it's the right thing to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tread as lightly as possible.  If a minor formatting edit gets the job done, don't dive into a major edit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Here's where I've evolved: I don't feel it's usually necessary to leave a janitorial attribution.  In other words, unless you think people actually need to know you've touched a node, don't leave your tag-line at the bottom.  I used to add such lines religiously.  But doing so &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; altering the text of a node, even though it's not the same as putting words in someone's mouth.  And we're just not here to plop our names into every node we can.  We're here to quietly fix problems and fade into the background again.  An exception to this sentiment is with retitling.  There, it's good to put the attribution at the bottom of the node along with the original title. This is mostly as an aid to the author.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contrary to what I just said, it's probably ok to leave attributions on nodes we've edited which were authored by Anonymous Monk.  Why?  Because there's no way to /msg him explaining how to improve.  So the attribution will concisely let him know (if he's watching) that his post was edited... so that &lt;em&gt;hopefully&lt;/em&gt; he'll take the initiative of trying to learn what to do next time so it won't be necessary.  Another situation where it's probably wise to leave an attribution at the bottom is when a node is reparented, so that people can see where it came from, and how it came to reside where it is after the reparenting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And lastly, &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; /msg the author letting him know what you did, and why.  If at all possible, seek to get the author to fix things himself before you (we) take action.  Sending a /msg to someone asking them nicely to fix something will often have the proper effect.  If you've tried that already, and it hasn't panned out, do the edit, and then /msg them again letting them know what you did, why, and where to read to learn to do it correctly next time.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, I guess that about sums it up, except that I'm sure I missed a bunch of topics.  The important points are: We should be minimalists, we should never alter text, and we should be the voices of reason even when the mob insists that we sway to their demands.  If disastrous nodes can be made to appear legible, and otherwise our presence is barely noticed, except by the author who got a kind and educational /msg from us, we've done our jobs right, imho.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, another thought... When you see lousy, improper, poorly worded, un-actionable, vague, or otherwise deficient considerations, /msg the considerer to let him know why it's bad.  Everyone likes to help out, but in their eagerness to help, they often present us with considerations that aren't helpful at all.  It'll keep happening unless we one-by-one help these moderators to understand where they can improve.  I've made it a practice to vote 'keep' on any consideration that isn't right on target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2006-11-03 23:42:49]&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;
I do care about this issue. I've always felt that altering peoples words, in good faith or bad is a real problem on the internet. Ive personally had comments modified or deleted without my control on other sites, and I was very very disturbed by it.
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thank you for that.  Frankly, I'm both a bit worried and disappointed that it took this long and yours is still, to my eyes, the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; expression in support of my premise.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Via private or group message I've seen several arguments that saw no problem with the edit that was done.  (For the record, I got no private messages supporting Monks' rights to their own words.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
To paraphrase a couple of them, "I changed what you wrote (and left it posted under your name) but that's no problem at all because me and a few friends agreed that you wouldn't mind."
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;
but no real harms done, not malice intent involved
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Yes, I agree on those points.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;
in hindsight it was inappropriate, &lt;/i&gt;&amp;#91;...&amp;#93;&lt;i&gt; lesson learned hopefully all around
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Was it?  I have yet to see any acknowledgement by [planetscape] that in hindsight it was inappropriate or that any lesson was learned.  If, after the objections, such had appeared, my response certainly would have been different.  Here it is many days later and I'm still left with the opposite impression from "If &amp;#91;you&amp;#93; still disagree with the decision, please do let me know how I could have done better in this case".  That sounds like "I don't see anything wrong with what I did".
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So I'm left with one voice of support, a few rather cool "No, that isn't our job"s, and several "Yes, that's perfectly appropriate."
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you go modifying my words because a few guys decided I wouldn't mind, then there's a good chance I'll be quite upset.  I think I have valid reason to be.  [footpad] corrected my spelling once and /msg'd me after.  I was mostly struck speechless.  I was sure he had good intentions and the change was like a single letter, so part of me felt that I couldn't berate him.  But part of me wanted to scream at him:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
What's the matter with you?! Do I thwart normal security to break into your house because I notice that you are putting your spoons on the wrong side of the plate when you set the table and just leave you a polite note, "I fixed your spoons. You're welcome."  How would you react to this?  Perhaps more importantly, how do you think other reasonably average people might react?
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Luckily he did it again and so I was able to tell him to cut it out.  If he'd sought prior permission (and, I feel I have to say this and that irks me: prior permission can only come from &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;), then it wouldn't have been a big deal at all.  Does everybody &lt;em&gt;get&lt;/em&gt; that?  Do you see why &lt;em&gt;some people&lt;/em&gt;, fairly reasonable people, could be quite upset by a janitor changing their words or adding to their words?  Do you see how some could be quite disturbed by such changes being made to someone else's words?  And note that this is about more than [planetscape]'s edit; it is about the response (to both the edit and my ranting) and the lack of it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Just a fairly quick point:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;
and how absurd it would seem (totally ignoring the edit votes
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The mob was shouting "Shoot him! Shoot him!" so it would have been &lt;em&gt;absurd&lt;/em&gt; for me not to do it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The mob vote doesn't give the janitor additional powers and duties.  A poll is a horrid way to determine policy.  It is my experience that a 100% vote in favor of a consideration can easily be followed by an outcry against it where nobody joins the &lt;em&gt;conversation&lt;/em&gt; speaking in favor of the action that was taken.  The "mob" can take part in a &lt;em&gt;discussion&lt;/em&gt; to change the policies and responsibilities assigned to janitors.  People don't have to think much to vote "edit".  In this particular case, I agree with the people who voted "edit" because they felt the suggested change would be an improvement.  I doubt many of those who voted considered "Is this type of edit something that would be appropriate for janitors to take on." That is why the &lt;em&gt;janitor&lt;/em&gt; must consider that before acting (such as asking first, if the action is something they've never seen done before or that feels rather inappropriate to them).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
(repeating) I should have voted "keep".  A few others that have written in this wiki should have as well.  That probably would have "solved" this.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So I'm still wondering if anyone else agrees that there is a world of difference between 1) adding a separate footer, visual distinct, with your name in it, providing administrative information because, for technical reasons, there isn't another place to put it and 2) adding a normal-looking paragraph of &lt;em&gt;content&lt;/em&gt; to someone's node that looks exactly like it'd been written by the author of the node.  How about anyone that agrees that a janitor who considers that distinction "absurd" perhaps is better suited to other work?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;
On the other hand I dont think we have to roast [planetscape] for this.
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I'm not trying to roast anyone.  Even taking my most pointed question, I don't consider it a short-coming to not be "janitor material".  Even if my life depended on it, I doubt I'd be able to become even a mediocre salesman.  I rarely lose sleep over that.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I'd like to manage to get [planetscape] to either 1) do what you said (admit a mistake, learn a lesson) or 2) declare otherwise. And the janitorial body to decide and clearly declare either A) oh, sure, change whatever you want so long as a few people don't think anyone will mind or B) janitors don't change nor add to "real" content, no matter how many "edit" votes (or perhaps something between).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Yes, in the case of (2)+(B), I think it would be only appropriate for [planetscape] to concentrate on [pedagogue]ry and relinquish [janitor]ial membership.  But I see no shame in such an outcome.  I find that [sitedocclan] and [pedagogue] membership rightly attracts those with a desire to improve things, even perfect things, and such work is of more value than janitorial work anyway.  But such leanings also appear to me to be in conflict with what makes a good janitor: someone who does nearly the minimum in order to clean up only something that is a real mess.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;
lets not make a bigger issue out of this than there needs to be.
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; (anyway) &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to know whether janitors are supposed to highly respect others' words.  I'm not getting that impression.  But the opposite impression is not clear either.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[de-merphq], [localtime://2006-11-02 04:47:19]&lt;br/&gt;
Rotated the log as of 2006-10-25. And now I have no idea why I wanted to edit this page in the first place. Dang. :-(
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Oh, wait, yeah, I do. I wanted to say in respons to [tye]s question that yes I do care about this issue. I've always felt that altering peoples words, in good faith or bad is a real problem on the internet. Ive personally had comments modified or deleted without my control on other sites, and I was very very disturbed by it.  PM's policy on things like this has always felt to me to be a good one. Allow edits, but only with community supervision, and with an extremely conservative approach.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
On the other hand I dont think we have to roast [planetscape] for this. I view it like a court system. The prosecutor summoned a grand jury on flimsy grounds, the judge used some questionable reasoning in deciding if the jury's vote should count, the jury voted, somebody appealed, the press went mad, then the issue was kicked to the higher courts, where finally the supreme court laid down the law. Everybody happy, and nobody really did anything wrong, and the original judge is a little wiser about those damn prosecutors, and the prosecutor hopefully got a good chiding from their boss for wasiting time. End of story. :-)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
IOW, the change was made, it was documented, in hindsight it was inappropriate, but no real harms done, not malice intent involved, lesson learned hopefully all around and lets not make a bigger issue out of this than there needs to be. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[g0n], [localtime://2006-10-27 08:51:51]&lt;br/&gt;
I'm inclined to agree that adding links to the previous nodes is the job of the node author, not a [janitor]. If memory serves me right, the biggest problem with that node was the title, which didn't make it at all clear that it was a follow on from previous nodes about the 'book in progress', and wasn't in any way descriptive. Probably the most appropriate action to have taken would have been to unconsider, and reconsider for a more appropriate title to resolve the immediate problem, and also to /msg the author requesting links to the other nodes.
&lt;p&gt;
Might I suggest that in questionable cases like this a note in this wiki asking whether other [janitors] feel a change is appropriate? After all, there's no reason a consideration has to be acted on immediately. While the post was likely to be picking up downvotes for utter vagueness until something was done, that's largely the OPs problem, not ours. I can see an argument for quickly warning the OP that this needs action, but we're not here to protect people from their own ropey posts.&lt;p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Corion], [localtime://2006-10-27 02:44:49]&lt;br/&gt;
I prefer &lt;c&gt;/msg&lt;/c&gt;ing over editing too because of its educative aspect. If I clean up the nodes
for people every time, they will never improve their formatting and linking, which means even
more work for me. I try to edit only one post of a logged-in user, after that I expect them to learn how formatting is done (via [Writeup Formatting Tips]). 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[Anonymous Monk] lacks the educative facility of &lt;c&gt;/msg&lt;/c&gt;, so there I'm more lenient toward linkifying and formatting.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2006-10-26 22:14:23]&lt;br/&gt;
I saw the comments in the wiki, clicked the link and saw the consideration (not an editted node).  Most likely, it was just a stale page in my browser cache.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But that doesn't matter much to me.  That was just in response to [GrandFather]'s claim that didn't match my impression of the timeline.  The timeline isn't important to me.  I've said how I feel about such edits.  The timing doesn't matter and the vote count doesn't matter.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
What matters is whether it's okay for janitors to change the &lt;em&gt;contents&lt;/em&gt; of people's nodes.  I find that to be a bright line and although "content" is a bit slippery here, I don't find that rule slippery at all.  Janitors have more leeway when it comes to titles, and yet should still err on the conservative side.  They have leeway when it comes to fixing formatting that is so broken as to cause a hazard to navigation.  That isn't "improving formatting".  I guess I don't even mind "improving navigation" provided it is done &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; by changing formatting (like turning a URL into a link) and preferrably only for Anonymous Monk (I'd rather that last part be a harder rule but get tired of fighting and if nobody else cares then the whole thing can eventually deteriorate to anarchy and I'll just stop trying).  They have some leeway in adding clearly distinguished footers but that should also be done conservatively and I hope one day that this leeway will be removed.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The act of adding content that can't be clearly distinguished from what the author wrote is a huge difference to me and if a janitor doesn't "get" that difference, then I have to question either their judgement or their appropriateness to be a janitor.  It may seem subtle to some, but I think a real-world editor would find using:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
Mr. Doe said, "I was not present when it happened."
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
in place of
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
Mr. Doe said, "I was not present when &amp;#91;it&amp;#93; happened."
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
to be a moral issue.  Subtle difference from a typographic perspective.  World's of difference to me.  And clearly so.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Does anybody else care?  Should I just slag off and stop being a prick about it?  Who cares if we edit other people's words?  What's the difference?  We edit nodes.  We don't abuse the power.  Nobody minds.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And [GrandFather], bad considerations are often the ones that hang around for a long time.  They often get lots of "yes, do it" votes.  This causes a conflict for janitors (well, me anyway) who wait hoping that some consideration voters will pay attention and think "that isn't appropriate for someone to do to someone else's words" so the janitor can remove the consideration without having to disregard the vote.  It is easy to remove a bad consideration when it has a bunch of "keep" votes.  It is harder (well, it should be, at least &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; think it should be) to remove a bad consideration when it has nothing but "edit" votes.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;That is why&lt;/em&gt; it is important for janitors to have an internal compass about what is appropriate and what isn't.  I don't think that it is clear that the solution is to remove the consideration sooner.  If there is a clearly documented rule that makes the consideration invalid, then that helps a janitor to remove the consideration despite the vote.  &amp;#91;I remove "Change title" (no alternate title suggested) considerations immediately upon seeing them so that others have a chance to actually suggest a better title; and I /msg the considerer.&amp;#93;  But janitors work best when they work slow, IMO.  The vast majority of janitorial mistakes are a result of quick action.  I didn't feel comfortable quickly removing that consideration.  And if I don't feel confortable about an action, then I'm extra unlikely to invoke special powers in order to take that action.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; have voted "keep" on it (I'm a bit surprised that I didn't, actually).  Other janitors who felt the action was inappropriate should also have voted "keep" on it.  Just the 3 keep votes that the wiki evidence says &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; have been cast would have likely given me the validation I needed to remove the consideration.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If an inappropriate action is taken by a janitor, I sure hope someone will speak up after it happens.  "Bemoaning" is an important check.  Let's not discourage "bemoaning" the potential misuse of a powerful privilege.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[planetscape], [localtime://2006-10-26 20:13:44]&lt;br/&gt;
With all due respect, [tye], [id://434853] clearly shows that I made my edit on the 23rd. No one objected until more than a day later:

&lt;c&gt;editors' wiki 	33751 	Arunbear 	wiki 	doctext 	Oct 24, 2006 at 16:01 CDT
...

Book update: "Exploring Programming Language Architecture in Perl" 	33705 	planetscape 	perlmeditation 	doctext 	Oct 23, 2006 at 05:33 CDT&lt;/c&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2006-10-26 18:50:41]&lt;br/&gt;
I don't know how many consideration votes you've paid attention to when they were followed by controversy.  14 people, most of them mostly mindlessly clicking "edit" as a "look I'm doing my part to help the site" isn't anything I'd call a "mandate" much less a strong one.  I expect janitors to follow their conscience over consideration vote totals when their conscience is leaning toward not changing something.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I don't consider janitors not changing real content to be a guideline.  That is why I referred to it as a "bright line".  If "we" want to mount the slipery slope of "well, the author probably didn't mind &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; change", then I'll resign my [janitors] hat now and ask that janitors please, please, never ever touch any of my nodes.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;
It's all very fine bemoaning the action taken after the fact. It would be better if pre-emptive action were taken before it became an issue.
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Perhaps you noticed these notes prior to the action?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
I saw that change and meant to comment on it but forgot :-( But no, I think adding cross-links is not a task of the janitors. Such stuff should be &lt;c&gt;/msg&lt;/c&gt;ed to the authors but otherwise left alone.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
Anyone else think that adding 'see also' links to [id://579895] is &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; a job for janitors
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I don't forfeit my right to state my mind when I think a janitor has clearly crossed what I consider to be an important line, especially not just because I didn't bother to append "me too" to the wiki before it was done.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[GrandFather], [localtime://2006-10-27 09:29:00]&lt;br/&gt;
The real issue with that node is that the consideration was inappropriate. It ought not have been considered in the first place and ought have been unconsidered (probably without a footnote) and the considerer /msg'd much sooner. By the time it was edited the strong mandate for the change made it inappropriate to do anything else. This place runs in guide lines rather than rules, and the guide lines are influenced by current opinion. An intelligent edit in keeping with the OP's material that didn't materially alter the content of the node (but simply eased navigation) and done with a strong mandate was sensible in this case.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It's all very fine bemoaning the action taken after the fact. It would be better if pre-emptive action were taken before it became an issue.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2006-10-26 14:52:57]&lt;br/&gt;
Putting words into someone else's "mouth" is something altogether different from adjusting broken formatting or adding a &lt;em&gt;clearly-marked and separate&lt;/em&gt; footer due to &lt;em&gt;technical limitations&lt;/em&gt; of the site.  I feel that should be a "bright line" and a good janitor should feel "icky" upon considering adding "real" content to a node.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you can't resist the urge to add content, then do it as a reply or else you probably shouldn't be a janitor (in which case you'll be forced to do it as a reply or ask the author to do it).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I'm even reluctant to add janitorial footers and would much rather there just be a "node history" log.  If only those patches could get applied...  I certainly don't add extensive footers and when I see such or more than one, I find them distasteful but hope the information is found useful and so don't object.  I'll be glad when there is no excuse for janitors to add any content to nodes.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], [localtime://2006-10-26 14:13:31]&lt;br/&gt;
Personally, I only use the "unconsidered by" stuff to indicate that
considering the same node for the same reason again is useless.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In your case, I'd have stayed away or discussed the matter, or simply left the non-links as text, if the old reason had to be given verbatim.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[planetscape], [localtime://2006-10-26 13:53:15]&lt;br/&gt;
Re: [planetscape|janitorial] changes to [id://579895] &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understand that [janitors] do &lt;b&gt;not&lt;/b&gt; "[324056|correct spelling, grammar, move things around, delete pieces etc.]", but the fact of the matter is, we &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;add&lt;/b&gt; content &lt;i&gt;all the time&lt;/i&gt;: [id://477713].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought about unconsidering that node, but realized what such a (still necessary) [id://477713|Janitorial Signature] would look like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;small&gt;
  Considered by [ww]: add links to [id://578390] and [id://543564] &lt;br /&gt;
  Unconsidered by [planetscape]: [janitors] do not add content ( keep:0 edit:14 reap:0 )
&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and how absurd it would seem (totally ignoring the edit votes, protesting that we don't add content in content we've added), and I thought about how [janitors|our] purview is also to "[324056|keep your impact low]". I thought that the change plus signature I ended up making:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;See also: [id://578390] and [id://543564]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Edited by [planetscape] - added "see also" links &lt;readmore title="view votes"&gt;( keep:0 edit:14 reap:0 )&lt;/readmore&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;fit that mission quite well. I went with the majority opinion ( keep:0 edit:14 reap:0 ); I added my [id://477713|Janitorial Signature]; the change I &lt;i&gt;did&lt;/i&gt; make had the same net effect, was (IMHO) more aesthetically pleasing, of lower impact, and far less absurdity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If my fellow [janitors] still disagree with the decision, please do let me know how I could have done better in this case.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;
Continued in [id://581860]...


</field>
</data>
</node>
