<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="739420" title="Pedagogues Wiki through 2009-01-10" created="2009-01-28 00:28:46" updated="2009-01-28 00:28:46">
<type id="68046">
wiki</type>
<author id="474174">
yitzchak</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;dl&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[planetscape], &lt;a href="#2009-01-10 03:05:39" name="2009-01-10 03:05:39"&gt;[localtime://2009-01-10 03:05:39]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many thanks, [jdporter], for all the work you've done behind the scenes and otherwise - really do appreciate it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Don't worry about the [id://519641|two] [id://590378|tutstrings]; I only discovered it quite by accident when I [link://?node_id=106927;whichtype=519031|listed them all].)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And many thanks to [bobf] for contributing, even though I'm going to disagree with him in a minute. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK, turns out [id://597958] will be easier than I expected; I found an alternate [http://www.cgidir.com/tutorials/Beginner/tutorials/RegularExpressionsPerl.html|location] for it and, by the time I post [id://510149|this], I will probably already have changed [id://597958] from &lt;code&gt;http://virtual.park.uga.edu/humcomp/perl/regex2a.html&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;http://www.cgidir.com/tutorials/Beginner/tutorials/RegularExpressionsPerl.html&lt;/code&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That just leaves (for me) [id://519419]. I have &lt;code&gt;/msg&lt;/code&gt;ed [tachyon-II] asking him if he has any preferences re: its resurrection. Still waiting to hear, but I get the impression he's away from PM a lot. At some point, I'll try e-mail if I don't hear via [id://48824].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess that leaves issues of hosting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal preference, where there are no complicating factors such as graphics, would be to post the material here, as a [id://956], ownership set to [Pedagogues], all original copyright notices, etc, retained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second choice would be posted here, either as [id://598673] or with [id://731367|relaxed restrictions], again with [Pedagogues|peds ownership] and full copyright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My third choice - though I'd certainly understand if other Monks prefer this option for things they've devoted extra effort to re-creating, editing, etc. - would be hosting elsewhere such as [http://perlmonk.org/|perlmonk.org] or [http://en.wikibooks.org/|Wikibooks].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Since, AFAIK, [http://perlmonk.org/|perlmonk.org] consists of a [id://111309|donated server] and purely [id://535931|volunteered time/effort] to maintain it, I hesitate to ask for any more than [jcwren] already graciously provides. Unless of course we can find some way to compensate [jcwren|him] for the additional time and money.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IMHO, this hierarchy represents the best tradeoff in terms of preserving worthwhile material while not unduly overburdening others/sites with hosting and maintenance issues. I am certainly open to further discussion of merits, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- Generated using PerlMonks editor version 1 --&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2009-01-09 21:13:20" name="2009-01-09 21:13:20"&gt;[localtime://2009-01-09 21:13:20]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
OK, I finally heard back from [Ovid] about the CGI Course (via LiveJournal - can you believe it):
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Hi John,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Thanks for your interest in the course. Feel free to repost it. I'd like to be credited as the original author, but beyond that, do anything with it that you feel is in the best interest of the Perl community, including any rewriting that you feel is necessary. I've not bothered to repost it myself due to other projects that have better held my interest, so I'm glad someone else is willing to help out here.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Cheers,&lt;br&gt;
Ovid
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
So, I'll proceed with that. I'll probably end up putting it up in my account on perlmonk.org, at least for starts.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2009-01-09 11:02:41" name="2009-01-09 11:02:41"&gt;[localtime://2009-01-09 11:02:41]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Also of interest: I have verified with the [gods] that it is possible to have the ownership of a Tutorial changed to [Pedagogues], at which point it will be communal property; we will all be able to edit it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2009-01-09 08:39:04" name="2009-01-09 08:39:04"&gt;[localtime://2009-01-09 08:39:04]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As to the question of where/how we should host [Pedagogues|our own] tutorials off site...&lt;br&gt;
My personal feeling is that shared ownership/editability (such as via a wiki-based site) is
not very necessary; individual monks (including members of [Pedagogues]) can and do post their
own tutorials here; off site shouldn't necessarily be different.  E.g. I may just go put up my
copy of Ovid's CGI Course on perlmonk.org.  As long as I and it are still around, it's no big
deal. That said, if y'all want to identify a collaboration host, or set up a new one, for this
purpose, I say go for it. :-)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2009-01-09 08:33:51" name="2009-01-09 08:33:51"&gt;[localtime://2009-01-09 08:33:51]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thanks, [planetscape].&lt;br&gt;
I'm working on Ovid's CGI Course, and currently awaiting response from [Ovid|him] regarding it.
Eventually this will time out, and we'll make our own decision. I think what I may
do, in that event, is to apply some major edits, among other things to remove his
personal coloration from the material - of which there is a lot, such as rant about
the importance of "decency" on the part of web developers.  And since it turns out
that his version of the tutorial is based on material by a previous author, I think
this would be in line. :-)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I did not realize there were two tutstrings for that tutorial. :-/&lt;br&gt;
Currently neither one is linked in [Tutorials] (and shouldn't be, because they're b0rked).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[planetscape], &lt;a href="#2009-01-08 22:52:00" name="2009-01-08 22:52:00"&gt;[localtime://2009-01-08 22:52:00]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew there were a few things I'd forgotten to mention; here are a couple of them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;[id://597948] is broken, irretrievable from the [http://web.archive.org|Wayback Machine], and I planned on removing it from [id://519395], but I suspect [jdporter] beat me to it (when does [jdporter|he] sleep?)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;[id://597958] is broken but retrievable and fixable; I am merely awaiting consensus as to what I should do with the material&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When [pedagogues|one] finds a broken [tutstring] link, and after deciding that it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; worth resurrecting, and in the event that it does not seem to be currently hosted anywhere, yet is [http://web.archive.org|retrievable], I think it is reasonable to attempt to determine if the author(s) is a past or current Monk, or otherwise contactable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Has [Ovid] been contacted with regard to [id://519641]|[id://590378]?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linking [tachyon]|[tachyon-II] to each other and to a probable RL identity and e-mail address seemed fairly straightforward; determining whether [id://597958|Carl Franklin and Gary Wisniewski] are past or current Monks may be less so. I don't know yet, but I'll be looking into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once contact information is found, I do think we should atttempt (within reason) to contact the author(s) and inquire as to their preferences regarding the [Tutorials|Tutorial]: whether they would re-post it, allow / help us to re-create / host it, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming reasonable efforts to contact the author(s) have failed, I think it is within the terms of [wikipedia://Fair Use] to post a reconstruction of the [Tutorials|Tutorial] based on content from the  [http://web.archive.org|Wayback Machine] (where available) or where it is possible to reconstruct something that seems in line with original author intent (i.e., missing graphics), always assuming that authorship/copyright info is retained. However, the standard disclaimer applies: [jargon://IANAL].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(BTW, I also &lt;c&gt;/msg&lt;/c&gt;ed [spx2] and informed/reminded him that [http://hop.perl.plover.com/|HOP] is freely available.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[planetscape], &lt;a href="#2009-01-08 04:37:31" name="2009-01-08 04:37:31"&gt;[localtime://2009-01-08 04:37:31]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite some time back (&lt;a href="#20061228"&gt;Dec 28, 2006 at 06:01 CST&lt;/a&gt;), I wrote about my attempt to resurrect [tachyon]'s  "[http://web.archive.org/web/20051028110253/http://tachyon.perlmonk.org/tutorials/behind_the_gui_lives_the_shell.htm|Behind the GUI lives the Shell]" tutorial. I have all of the HTML via the [http://web.archive.org|Wayback Machine], and am missing only one of the images. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, a wee bit of digging seems to strongly suggest that [tachyon] &lt;code&gt;eq&lt;/code&gt; [tachyon-II]. So my next step will probably be to attempt to contact [tachyon]|[tachyon-II] and ask (a) if he'd like to re-create it here, (b) if he minds me re-creating it here, and/or (c) if he can supply the missing graphic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More recently, I've changed [id://669689] from &lt;code&gt;http://www.hydroman.org/gtk/&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;http://forgeftp.novell.com//gtk2-perl-study/homepage/&lt;/code&gt; and [id://520071] from &lt;code&gt;http://personal.riverusers.com/~swilhelm/gtkperl-tutorial/&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;http://www.ae.gatech.edu/people/jcraig/classes/ae6382/perl/gtkperl-tutorial/html/index.html&lt;/code&gt; . Also, I added [id://732932].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(More to come as RL allows.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[bobf], &lt;a href="#2009-01-04 20:24:33" name="2009-01-04 20:24:33"&gt;[localtime://2009-01-04 20:24:33]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I vote for hosting on perlmonk.org under a new user ("PerlMonks"?), provided we get permission to use that site for this purpose.  It would add a little extra importance to ensuring the site is available and backed up, but it is probably the site most closely related to perlmonks.org and makes sense (to me) to utilize it for hosting.  Edit permissions and access would have to be resolved, of course.  For that reason a wiki might be good.  What about asking perlmonk.org to host an instance of semantic mediawiki?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[Arunbear], &lt;a href="#2008-12-31 10:11:21" name="2008-12-31 10:11:21"&gt;[localtime://2008-12-31 10:11:21]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Another possibility is to put the content on [wb://|Wikibooks] which can also handle the images (see e.g. [wb://Human Physiology/Cell physiology]). Then it could be maintained by anyone so interested.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2008-12-30 23:08:59" name="2008-12-30 23:08:59"&gt;[localtime://2008-12-30 23:08:59]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I am in the process of trying to resuscitate [id://519641], as it seems to be a perennial link-to favorite (though, honestly, having read it, I fail to understand the fascination).&lt;br&gt;
Its entire contents (almost) can be horked from [http://www.archive.org/|the wayback machine].&lt;br&gt;
It includes numerous graphics, as well as form input elements (which are not allowed in [Tutorials]).&lt;br&gt;
Its total size (html content only) is over 140kb, which means it won't fit in a Tutorial node.&lt;br&gt;
In its original form, it is broken across about a dozen different pages.&lt;br&gt;
This is clearly not a trivial tutorial to re-post here.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I have consulted with [tye] and [Corion] on the prospects of posting it as a [largedoc] &amp;mdash; a nodetype which is
not only large enough to hold 140kb+, but is exempt from the normal [id://29281|html restrictions]. The problem would then be one of ownership/editability.  There would also remain the question of where to host the images. Hosting them on PerlMonks would be preferable, for significant reasons, but would also introduce problems of ownership/management. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As an alternative, I've submitted a [id://731367|patch] which would relax the [id://29281|html restrictions] for [Tutorials]. I think this makes a lot of sense anyway, but additional work would need to be done to secure against rogue &lt;c&gt;&lt;form&gt;&lt;/c&gt;s, for example. If this is the approach by which Ovid's CGI tutorial finally gets posted here, it will mean that I'll have to post it as at least three [Tutorials] &amp;mdash; something I consider very distasteful, but I'd deal. There would also remain the question of hosting the images. Maybe I'd just put them on perlmonk.org.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Q.&lt;/b&gt; Why is it so important to host Ovid's CGI tutorial on PerlMonks?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;A.&lt;/b&gt; It's not critical, obviously, but one consideration is the fact that the tutorial contains &lt;i&gt;lots&lt;/i&gt; of links to PerlMonks nodes.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2008-12-30 13:35:05" name="2008-12-30 13:35:05"&gt;[localtime://2008-12-30 13:35:05]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It seems that as time goes by, more and more off-site tutorials are evaporating, leaving us with broken links.
I think we need to agree on some kind of policy on how to handle this.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In the remediation of each broken link event, the first thing to do is decide if the tutorial is worth any effort to resurrect. In many cases, it will be appropriate simply to delete the broken link and move on. &lt;c&gt;return unless worth_the_trouble();&lt;/c&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Assuming the tutorial is worth resurrecting, the first thing to try is to see if it has moved, in which case we can simply link to its new location. Failing that, we can try contacting the author to see if there might be some other way we can continue to link to it off site &amp;mdash; e.g., if the author is willing and able to re-post it on his server of choice. Failing &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt;, our manifest onus increases considerably.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In the most trivial of cases, the off-site tutorial exists in [http://www.archive.org/|the wayback machine],
includes no graphics or other external files, and fits in 64kb.  In such a case, the tutorial can be horked from Mr. Wayback and posted here as a tutorial.  If it doesn't exist in the WM, and the author can't provide the content, then the tutorial is officially kaput, so we delete the link and get on with life.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Containing graphics (as many tutorials do) and having total content size of over 64kb complicate things for us.  If the textual content can be retrieved but the graphics cannot, then we have to decide whether to (a) recreate the graphics, (b) convert the tutorial to succeed without graphics, or (c) kill off the tutorial &amp;mdash; a kind of triage.
If option (b) is executed, then the tutorial may be posted here (again - only if it fits in the 64kb node size limit).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If a tutorial contains graphics, or is "very large", then often it will be easiest simply to post it on another site ([http://www.perlmonk.org/|perlmonk.org] is probably a good choice) and update the off-site link. Posting such a complicated tutorial on PerlMonks is not entirely out of the question, however, but doing so requires authorization and assistance from the [gods].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I think it would also be a good idea for each [Pedagogues|'gog], whenever you've made short work of a broken link, or are having long work of a broken link, to write about it here. Include such things as the location of the b0rked link (typically a [tutstring]), the scale of the problem, and your expected resolution.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2008-12-30 13:05:04" name="2008-12-30 13:05:04"&gt;[localtime://2008-12-30 13:05:04]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I responded to [spx2]'s request for books, saying "we" do not have any.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2008-12-17 07:01:30" name="2008-12-17 07:01:30"&gt;[localtime://2008-12-17 07:01:30]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Yeah, I found him in the cb immediately after he sent those messages.
However, I suspect that he still needs some handholding.
Not sure what to recommend, exactly; just be on the lookout for more opportunities to guide, I guess.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Not to mention the fact that someone who is so new to the Monastery probably doesn't have a good idea
of what makes a good Tutorial here.  IMHO we should steer him toward posting his thing as a Meditation,
without a view toward ultimately making it a Tutorial.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[bobf], &lt;a href="#2008-12-16 23:34:49" name="2008-12-16 23:34:49"&gt;[localtime://2008-12-16 23:34:49]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[rq] sent two msgs to [pedagogues|our] inbox today, both of which have been moved to the "archive" folder.  I assume someone replied to him but I didn't see any msg to him from our sent box.  Has this request been handled?  Thanks.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[bobf], &lt;a href="#2008-07-30 22:06:31" name="2008-07-30 22:06:31"&gt;[localtime://2008-07-30 22:06:31]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thanks for clearing that up, [jdporter].  I didn't notice the msg was moved to 'archive' and the link on our site was fine so I assumed [rovf] was referring to a link in the off-site page. *sigh*
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2008-07-30 09:29:15" name="2008-07-30 09:29:15"&gt;[localtime://2008-07-30 09:29:15]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A bit of a misunderstanding here. [rovf] was informing us that &lt;i&gt;our&lt;/i&gt; link to PGI was broken, and he provided to us
the current link. I already updated the affected tutstring. So this "ticket" was "closed" before you got to it.
The messages from [rovf] had already been moved to the 'archive' folder.&lt;br&gt;
If you concur, [planetscape], perhaps you should re-/msg [rovf] with "never mind". ;-)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[planetscape], &lt;a href="#2008-07-30 02:39:15" name="2008-07-30 02:39:15"&gt;[localtime://2008-07-30 02:39:15]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
From the [http://www.perl.org/tpc/1998/Perl_Language_and_Modules/Perl%20Illustrated/|page itself], I note:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
© 1998 Gisle Aas
&lt;aas@sn.no&gt;
$Date: 1998/07/03 10:37:29 $
&lt;/code&gt;
I have /msged [rovf] to try that e-mail address, or search for [google://"Gisle Aas"].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[bobf], &lt;a href="#2008-07-30 00:18:16" name="2008-07-30 00:18:16"&gt;[localtime://2008-07-30 00:18:16]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[rovf] sent a msg to [Pedagogues|our] inbox informing us of a broken link in PerlGuts Illustrated, which is hosted at [http://www.perl.org].  I was unable to find an address to forward to [rovf] - anyone know if it is being maintained?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2008-07-10 09:18:56" name="2008-07-10 09:18:56"&gt;[localtime://2008-07-10 09:18:56]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Reminder to [Pedagogues]: When you handle a new Tutorial submission by adding it to
an appropriate section of the [Tutorials], please don't forget to remove it from
the [id://519201] section as well!  tia...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2008-04-16 09:35:57" name="2008-04-16 09:35:57"&gt;[localtime://2008-04-16 09:35:57]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It already exists as a FAQlet, and is linked in the FAQ. I don't see the point in having it in two places.
In any case, I'd prefer to keep the number of non-Tutorial nodes linked in [Tutorials] to the absolute
minimum necessary... and I don't think this one sufficiently merits exposure there.
(PS - FYI - If it was agreed that this document would be better in Tutorials rather than the FAQ,
it would be trivial to convert its nodetype. Just in case anyone was wondering.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[planetscape], &lt;a href="#2008-04-15 10:57:07" name="2008-04-15 10:57:07"&gt;[localtime://2008-04-15 10:57:07]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Apr 13, 2008, [ww] /[id://48824|msg]ed me to ask: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;Would [Markup in the Monastery] be suitable for adoption as a tut? Is merely languishing in custody of [sitedocclan]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I vote "Yes" as I'd like to see it as widely promoted as possible, although I see [ww] has made laudable strides in that [id://174180|direction] already.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2008-02-17 16:55:33" name="2008-02-17 16:55:33"&gt;[localtime://2008-02-17 16:55:33]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I unlinked [id://668450] from [id://519201], as it clearly
is &lt;b&gt;not&lt;/b&gt; [Tutorials] material. I also [/msg|chastise]d the poster,
who (I would think) should have known better.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2008-02-04 22:12:24" name="2008-02-04 22:12:24"&gt;[localtime://2008-02-04 22:12:24]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Regarding the &lt;c&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/c&gt;, I omitted it intentionally, as a way of
indicating the "threadedness" of the adjacent entrues.  
Far from an ideal solution, obviously...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[bobf], &lt;a href="#2008-02-04 21:49:00" name="2008-02-04 21:49:00"&gt;[localtime://2008-02-04 21:49:00]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
D'oh!  Thanks for the catch.  Too many previews and not enough updates, I guess.  Fixed.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;small&gt;(BTW, did [jdporter|you] intend to remove the hr after your comment or was it a C&amp;P error?  I was going to add it back in but thought it might have been intentional.)&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2008-02-04 08:42:22" name="2008-02-04 08:42:22"&gt;[localtime://2008-02-04 08:42:22]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thanks, [bobf]. However, I think you must have forgotten to save your changes, as
[id://615833] shows no recent edits. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[bobf], &lt;a href="#2008-02-03 23:33:27" name="2008-02-03 23:33:27"&gt;[localtime://2008-02-03 23:33:27]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I added [Limbic~Region]'s request for a new tutorial about dynamic programming to [id://615833], and moved his message from the pedagogues' inbox to the archive.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[bobf], &lt;a href="#2007-06-26 22:54:29" name="2007-06-26 22:54:29"&gt;[localtime://2007-06-26 22:54:29]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It looks good to me.  I made one small addition to emphasize that new Tutorials should be posted first as a Meditation, lest the Tutorials section get flooded with first-draft posts.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2007-06-26 10:19:02" name="2007-06-26 10:19:02"&gt;[localtime://2007-06-26 10:19:02]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
OK, it's been a month, with no feedback, so I'm assuming
we're all OK with taking [id://615833] live.
Before I write the PMD and the [Tidings] entry, any last comments/concerns? 
I've populated the wiki with the one outstanding Tut request that I know of,
the one from [ww] on 2006-01-24.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2007-05-25 11:13:58" name="2007-05-25 11:13:58"&gt;[localtime://2007-05-25 11:13:58]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Also, it's probably not too soon to start adding actual tutorial quests to the list.
Once we're happy with the blurb at the top, and any questions about the title have
been resolved, we'll announce the thing in [Tidings] and add a link to it at the top of [Tutorials].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2007-05-24 19:29:07" name="2007-05-24 19:29:07"&gt;[localtime://2007-05-24 19:29:07]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thanks, [bobf]. I went ahead and wrote up a skeleton content for [id://615833].
Please hack away!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[bobf], &lt;a href="#2007-05-16 23:41:01" name="2007-05-16 23:41:01"&gt;[localtime://2007-05-16 23:41:01]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[jdporter]: Thanks for following up on this, and thanks to [yitzchak] for creating the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I'm fine with "Tutorials Quest" (or a similar "Quest"-based name), but I think we need a paragraph of text at the top that explains what the page is for and how it should be used (as per our discussion Jan 25-30, below).  &lt;small&gt;&lt;small&gt;If I had more time ATM I'd draft something, but if someone else beats me to it I'll be happy to look it over and add comment.  Sorry... *sheepish grin* &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2007-05-16 15:26:43" name="2007-05-16 15:26:43"&gt;[localtime://2007-05-16 15:26:43]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thanks, [yitzchak]!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Now, before we proceed &amp;mdash; does anybody have any strong
feelings about what this wiki should be named?&lt;br/&gt;
Remember, it's going to be a public billboard where we solicit
tutorials from the entire monastery population.&lt;br/&gt;
My personal feeling is that it should be named "Tutorials Quest",
to keep it harmonious with what goes on in the [Quests] section.
(The fact that it is not an actual '[pmdev://quest]'
node is not a problem, imho.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[yitzchak], &lt;a href="#2007-05-16 12:45:58" name="2007-05-16 12:45:58"&gt;[localtime://2007-05-16 12:45:58]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[id://615833|Tutorials Needed].  Enjoy.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2007-05-15 18:16:25" name="2007-05-15 18:16:25"&gt;[localtime://2007-05-15 18:16:25]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Some time around the 10th inst. I sent a /msg to the [gods] requesting
that a "Tutorials Needed" wiki be created for us.  (See entries below
between 1-25 and 1-30 for context.)
No response from [gods] yet...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[planetscape], &lt;a href="#2007-05-13 06:25:33" name="2007-05-13 06:25:33"&gt;[localtime://2007-05-13 06:25:33]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moved [id://614808] from [id://592240] to [id://546527] per [syphilis|author] [href://?recipient=499790;node_id=48824|request].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;[syphilis] says &lt;/i&gt;I think my tutorial "Compiling C/C++ based Modules under ActiveState using MinGW" would be better placed in "Installing Modules" instead of "Creating and Distributing Modules". (But it's not a big deal for me :-)&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href="#2007-03-27 16:17:23" name="2007-03-27 16:17:23"&gt;[localtime://2007-03-27 16:17:23]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
After extended discussion with [brusimm],
I have added his [Meditations|meditation] &lt;i&gt;[id://595955]&lt;/i&gt;
to the [id://519265] section of the [Tutorials|Tut].
Again, he may eventually post an actual Tutorial to take its place,
but there doesn't seem to be a driving need for it now.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2007-03-09 12:07:31]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I have added [muba]'s [Meditations|meditation] &lt;i&gt;[id://383015]&lt;/i&gt;
to the [id://519265] section of the [Tutorials|Tut].
It's pretty good. If he doesn't make a Tutorial out of it, then
we've got it; if he ever does, then we can update the link.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Update:&lt;/i&gt; [muba] told me that he thinks the med is good enough,
he doesn't plan on writing an actual tut node.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2007-03-07 10:34:48]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I have placed [id://603609] in the Tut, in [id://519264], just below [id://408254].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[planetscape], [localtime://2007-02-09 19:31:58]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
On January 4, 2007, [wfsp] sent us this message:
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;not sure what the procedure is but could [592954|this] be considered for the tutorials page?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
I asked [BrowserUk] whether he'd be willing to consider some minor modifications to turn [592954|his node] from a reply into a [Tutorials|Tutorial], and he replied eagerly yes. [id://599204] is the result, and just now I placed it in [id://520304].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2007-01-11 00:33:30]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[bobf] (and everyone else), please try to get in the habit of leaving some space (blank lines) between your entry and the wiki prologue above it. TIA.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I assume [brusimm] was referring to the very first regex tutorial, [id://962].
Yeah, we're not likely to really unlink it.  That was merely rhetorical. :-)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[bobf], [localtime://2007-01-10 23:53:41]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[jdporter]: Thank you for replying to [brusimm] on our behalf.  I saw [ysth]'s note yesterday but at the time I couldn't determine which tutorial(s) [brusimm|he] was referring to ("the original entry"??) - I guess it really doesn't matter.  I am interested to see what (if anything) [brusimm] writes, especially if it was geared towards newbies, but I may be hesitant to remove something from [Tutorials] even if [brusimm|he] does rewrite it.  A tutorial geared towards intermediate or advanced users is just as important as one geared towards newbies, IMO (assuming the content is good and the difference between them is the intended audience).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2007-01-10 18:06:36]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[ysth], please try to get in the habit of leaving some space (blank lines) between your entry and the wiki prologue above it. TIA.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I'll send a /msg to [brusimm] as follows:
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Just go ahead and write a new regex tutorial. Don't worry about the crappy old one. It can't be fixed, but if we get good ones to supercede it, we may just unlink it from [Tutorials]. Follow the procedure outlined at the top of [id://954].
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2007-01-09 22:37:24]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The following /msgs were sent to [gods].  Perhaps someone here could respond.
&lt;p&gt;
        brusimm says "Should I rewrite the entry to be more explicit" for the newbies such as myself. I'm on chapter 8 of the lama book, dealing with this matter. Not sure when or how much time I could devote, if possible. Thanks for your time.  &lt;i&gt;end msg&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	
	brusimm says my question is, is anyone looking at the idea of rewriting the original entry to be more inclusive of base information? Being new, I do not know how to approach this thought.. the thought being &lt;i&gt;cont’d&lt;/i&gt;


&lt;p&gt;	
	brusimm says I was recently looking up regular expressions [href://?node_id=954#Pattern-Matching-and-Regular-Expressions|here] and noticed how it did not seem geared towards newbies &lt;i&gt;cont’d&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2007-01-07 04:38:56]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[planetscape] We can store images as nodes here.  Looks like perlmonk.org is down at the moment, so I can't look at your .zip file :(
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2006-12-28 09:43:32]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I moved [davido]'s new [id://591988] from [id://520304] to [id://520393], because
that is where the old [id://970] and [id://287544] were, which [id://591988] was intended to replace. ([davido] fulfilled the potential of [id://287544] at my urging. Thank you, [davido]!). Subsequently, I have removed [id://970] and [id://287544] from that category.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And this brings us to a point of discussion: What should we do when a tutorial doesn't clearly fit into a single category? I'm very reluctant to link things in multiple places (although I did so with [id://128283]), because that would probably double the size of the FAQ. The categories are a rough approximation, useful perhaps for browsing for new knowledge; users looking for something specific should probably use searching to find it. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
On a related note, I think we should consider eliminating the [id://519266|Getting Deeper Into Perl] tutlist and move its contents up to the main level of [Tutorials]. Currently there seems to be a false dichotomy between what goes in there and what goes at the top level.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[planetscape], &lt;a name="20061228"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[localtime://2006-12-28 07:01:41]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Actually, with just a wee bit of digging, I've managed to recover all but one or two of the images from the [http://www.archive.org/index.php|Wayback Machine]'s archive of [tachyon]'s [http://web.archive.org/web/*/http://tachyon.perlmonk.org/tutorials/behind_the_gui_lives_the_shell.htm|tutorial], and I am thinking it should be possible to reconstruct the missing ones (&lt;c&gt;folders.gif&lt;/c&gt; and &lt;c&gt;explorer_small.gif&lt;/c&gt; according to my preliminary count) via context from the text of the tutorial and a little Paint Shop Pro magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only impediment I see to doing as [jdporter] suggests
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;hork the content
from the w.m. and post it here as an on-site tutorial&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
is that nodes may not contain images. So, if the idea meets with approval, I hereby offer to reconstruct missing images and post the reconstructed page to my [http://planetscape.perlmonk.org/|perlmonk.org account].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone is interested, [http://planetscape.perlmonk.org/behind_the_gui_lives_the_shell.zip|here] is a .zip file of what I was able to retrieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would also like to offer a belated &lt;i&gt;Thanks!&lt;/i&gt; to [ysth] for his work on [perlexercise]s and [perlsolution]s, and to [jdporter] for cruft-removal operations. :-) 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2006-12-27 21:07:34]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I agree that documenting all removals is probably a good idea. 
I can't foresee what possible good it could do, but it couldn't hurt.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; dislike the idea of linking to things in the wayback machine.
It just feels wrong. And the wayback machine's copies of
the tutorial in question are missing their images. 
I think it's a stretch to be linking to off-site tutorials in the first place; 
we shouldn't feel obliged to link to off-site material which is broken and
unmaintained like this.
I think, if we feel this tutorial is so valuable, we should hork the content
from the w.m. and post it here as an on-site tutorial.
(It would be ideal, obviously, if [tachyon] would do it, but that looks like
a slim chance...)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[Arunbear], [localtime://2006-12-27 17:41:56]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Re [id://519419], the content is still available via the [http://web.archive.org/web/*/http://tachyon.perlmonk.org/tutorials/behind_the_gui_lives_the_shell.htm|Internet Archive], so no need to remove it. We should document &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; nodes that are removed from display, as such removal cannot be traced via the edit history.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2006-12-27 10:46:27]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I have removed tutlists [id://520390] and [id://520391] from tutlist
[id://520389], since the tutorials they contain are quite old and
substandard, and besides, they  (there's about 8 of them) are linked
in tutorial [id://918], which acts as a kind of index, and I'm leaving
that one visible in tutlist [id://520389]. (In a related move, I renamed 
[id://520389] from "Control Statements and Looping", which was a conflict.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In the same way, I removed tutorial [id://969] from tutlist [id://519265].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I've un-listed tutstring [id://519419], as its link is now broken.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I also did a bunch of other re-arranging, including making some new tutlists.
I unlinked a handful of meditations and other cruft (including a snippet) which weren't tutorial quality.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2006-12-26 23:25:38]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thanks, [yitzchak]! That is most excellent!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Update:&lt;/h4&gt;
[yitzchak], I draw your attention to the four nodes of type [superquestionarea].
I know that these nodes are completely unusable (they're off limits to all but [gods]), but unfortunately they (or some of them) have really useful names, and there are already some collisions.  Would you mind renaming them, or even deleting them? That
would be quite helpful. And I thank you in advance. :-)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[yitzchak], [localtime://2006-12-26 16:22:55]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Ownership of an early monastery attempt at pedagoguery has been transferred to the pedagogues ([id://994], [id://1008], [id://1013], [id://1017]) so that [jdporter] or others can fix typos, etc.
Editing these doesn't produce edithistory.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2006-12-16 10:04:52]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When editing [tutlist]s (such as [id://510154]), you will now see in the upper right corner the link 
&lt;small&gt;&lt;b&gt;[id://587754|Help for this page]&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/small&gt;, which takes you to some helpful information about how to use the tutlist edit page.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2006-10-16 10:21:42]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Yes; but (depending on the situation) it is OK to link to the individual categories, just as they're linked in [id://954]: for example, &lt;c&gt;[id://519264]&lt;/c&gt; &amp;rArr; [id://519264].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[planetscape], [localtime://2006-10-16 08:06:02]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
For future reference, here's how to create internal links to Tutorial Sections:
      &lt;table width="100%" align="center" valign="top" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" border="0"&gt;
         &lt;tr align="center"&gt;
            &lt;td width="45%" align="left" valign="top"&gt;
               &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;
                  [link://?node=Tutorials#New-Tutorials|New Tutorials]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;code&gt;[link://?node=Tutorials#New-Tutorials|New Tutorials]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;
                  [link://?node=Tutorials#Learning-to-Use-PerlMonks|Learning to Use PerlMonks]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;code&gt;[link://?node=Tutorials#Learning-to-Use-PerlMonks|Learning to Use PerlMonks]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;
                  [link://?node=Tutorials#Getting-Started-with-Perl|Getting Started with Perl]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;code&gt;[link://?node=Tutorials#Getting-Started-with-Perl|Getting Started with Perl]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;
                  [link://?node=Tutorials#Functions-Subroutines-and-Variables|Functions Subroutines and Variables]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;code&gt;[link://?node=Tutorials#Functions-Subroutines-and-Variables|Functions Subroutines and Variables]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;
                  [link://?node=Tutorials#Regular-Expressions|Regular Expressions]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;code&gt;[link://?node=Tutorials#Regular-Expressions|Regular Expressions]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;
                  [link://?node=Tutorials#Files-and-Directories|Files and Directories]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;code&gt;[link://?node=Tutorials#Files-and-Directories|Files and Directories]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;
                  [link://?node=Tutorials#Databases|Databases]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;code&gt;[link://?node=Tutorials#Databases|Databases]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;
                  [link://?node=Tutorials#Object-Oriented-Perl|Object Oriented Perl]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;code&gt;[link://?node=Tutorials#Object-Oriented-Perl|Object Oriented Perl]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;
                  [link://?node=Tutorials#Network-Programming|Network Programming]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;code&gt;[link://?node=Tutorials#Network-Programming|Network Programming]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;
                  [link://?node=Tutorials#CGI-and-related-Programming|CGI and related Programming]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;code&gt;[link://?node=Tutorials#CGI-and-related-Programming|CGI and related Programming]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;
                  [link://?node=Tutorials#Writing-Installing-and-Using-Modules|Writing Installing and Using Modules]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;code&gt;[link://?node=Tutorials#Writing-Installing-and-Using-Modules|Writing Installing and Using Modules]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;
                  [link://?node=Tutorials#Tutorials-on-Specific-CPAN-Modules|Tutorials on Specific CPAN Modules]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;code&gt;[link://?node=Tutorials#Tutorials-on-Specific-CPAN-Modules|Tutorials on Specific CPAN Modules]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;
                  [link://?node=Tutorials#Tips-Performance-and-Troubleshooting|Tips Performance and Troubleshooting]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;code&gt;[link://?node=Tutorials#Tips-Performance-and-Troubleshooting|Tips Performance and Troubleshooting]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;
                  [link://?node=Tutorials#Miscellaneous-Perl-Tutorials|Miscellaneous Perl Tutorials]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;code&gt;[link://?node=Tutorials#Miscellaneous-Perl-Tutorials|Miscellaneous Perl Tutorials]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;
                  [link://?node=Tutorials#Perl-Idioms-Explained|Perl Idioms Explained]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;code&gt;[link://?node=Tutorials#Perl-Idioms-Explained|Perl Idioms Explained]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;
                  [link://?node=Tutorials#Non-English-Tutorials|Non English Tutorials]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;code&gt;[link://?node=Tutorials#Non-English-Tutorials|Non English Tutorials]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;
                  [link://?node=Tutorials#Win32-Topics|Win32 Topics]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;code&gt;[link://?node=Tutorials#Win32-Topics|Win32 Topics]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;
                  [link://?node=Tutorials#Other-Topics|Other Topics]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;code&gt;[link://?node=Tutorials#Other-Topics|Other Topics]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
                  &lt;/li&gt;
               &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="20%"&gt;
               &amp;nbsp;
            &lt;/td&gt;
         &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;/table&gt;
(I can never remember how this works, and copy &amp; paste is so much easier and less error-prone anyway. :-))
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;&lt;dt&gt;[planetscape], [localtime://2006-06-04 10:31:15]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Ok, pertaining to the text immediately below... I have decided, in the absence of objections/alternatives, to go ahead and try to hook up [ww] and [Scott7477] to "collaborate" on a [Tutorials|Tutorial]... I copied the relevant portion of this wiki (for context) and a number of resources to [id://511504] to get them started. (I've been looking at this issue myself for a while now, but simply have not had the time to do anything &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; gather resources...) I then /msged [ww|the] [Scott7477|two] vict... er... &lt;i&gt;volunteers&lt;/i&gt; to let them know to contact one another and where the [id://511504|goodies] are. I've also copied the resources here to save people having to follow links just to find out what I'm up to. ;-)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;b&gt;HTML TIDY&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[http://www.w3.org/People/Raggett/tidy/|Clean up your Web pages with HTML TIDY]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[http://tidy.sourceforge.net/|HTML Tidy Library Project]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[http://users.rcn.com/creitzel/tidy.html#tidyperl|Charlie's Tidy Add-ons], including a [http://users.rcn.com/creitzel/tidy/tidyperl.tar|Perl Wrapper]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[id://224272|HTML tidy, using XML::LibXML]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Demoronizer&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[http://vsbabu.org/mt/archives/2002/11/03/demoronizer.html|Demoronizer - A perl script to sanitize Microsoft's HTML]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[http://www.fourmilab.ch/webtools/demoroniser/|Demoronizer - Correct Moronic Microsoft HTML]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[http://wh2fo.sourceforge.net/|Word HTML 2 Formatting Objects]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;WH2FO is a Java application that processes an HTML output, created with Word 2000, and transforms it into an XML content file and an XSL stylesheet file. From these files, a standard XSLT processor may be used to obtain a file containing only XSL-FO markup. You can also apply a stylesheet that converts the XML back into HTML discarding all the extra markup added by Word. Using an XSL-FO renderer, such as FOP, you can also render your document into PDF.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;b&gt;PMEdit&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[GrandFather]'s [id://543242|PerlMonks Editor] - on CPAN: [http://cpan.perl.org/authors/id/G/GR/GRANDPA/PMEdit/PMEdit-001.000104-1.pl|PMEdit-001.000104-1.pl]&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;b&gt;Miscellaneous&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[cpan://HTML::Parser] has several example programs, such as [http://search.cpan.org/src/GAAS/HTML-Parser-3.54/eg/hstrip|hstrip.pl] which might be helpful&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[http://www.openoffice.org/|OpenOffice.org] - free office suite and MSOffice alternative&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Use OpenOffice to save in HTML format. OpenOffice creates much cleaner HTML, and the resulting file may still be run through [http://tidy.sourceforge.net/|HTML Tidy] or a script such as [http://search.cpan.org/src/GAAS/HTML-Parser-3.54/eg/hstrip|hstrip.pl].&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[http://www.bilkent.edu.tr/pub/WWW/Tools/Word_proc_filters.html|Word Processor Filters]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[http://multipart-mixed.com/software/gxml.html|gxml2html]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There may well be more resources out there, but this list should get you started. I suggest examining each alternative's usage, sample (short) input and output, and a breakdown of the pros and cons...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[planetscape], [localtime://2006-04-24 05:45:25]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In the [link://?type=strangedoc;recipient=499790;node=message%20inbox|pedagogues' inbox ], [Scott7477] writes: "What subject would you most like to see a tutorial for posted to PM? Thx Scott"
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone have any preferences? I'd simply suggest he pick a subject he is competent in and comfortable with writing... Either that, or perhaps we should commission him to take on [ww]'s earlier request: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;[ww] says "though slightly OT, suggest a compilation re translation of M$Word to civilized files might be useful; cf: holli's node et seq in [id://524507] and those I mention below."&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thoughts?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;dt&gt;[de-merphq], [localtime://2006-03-22 17:27:59]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The [tutorials sitedoclet] is now empty, and will be rendered above the new submission form and under the overall list. The text in [tutorial sections] now renders when viewed from [tutorials]. So you get your cake and you can eat it too. :-)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Regarding CQ&amp;A stuff, dont confuse them with the newer infrastracture. CQ&amp;A is built around two seperate concepts: So [QandAsection] is a [nodegroup], and [categorized question] and [categorized answer] are [note]s. [tutlists] and [faqlists] are derivatives of [doclists] which are [nodegroups]. No [note] logic involved. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2006-03-21 13:00:17]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As I recently [id://537885|suggested] in the Scriptorium, I think it
would be cool to somehow associate the like-named categories in each
of the sections that have categories (namely Tutorials, QandA, and Code).
Now, of the three, Tutorials has the most modern structure/design, with
fully tree-structured, nested tutlist nodes. Each tutlist has a text
area as well. So, I'm thinking, why not let the Tutorials node for each
category be the "main" for the category, with references (links) to the
corresponding category areas in the other sections.  To see what I mean,
take a look at the [id://519391|CGI Programming] tutlist in Tutorials.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2006-03-19 19:51:50]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Well, there's just one thing.... ([demerphq]++, btw, for all you've done. You're a madman. :-)
It seems that the Tutorials page (954) is still sucking in the ol' [id://465458] for the text
at the top of the page, rather than showing the text that you can edit when you load
954 in edit mode. When you're on 954 and you click &lt;b&gt;Edit&lt;/b&gt;, you actually go to a page
for editing [id://510154] (510154); clicking on &lt;b&gt;Display view&lt;/b&gt; from there takes you back
to viewing 510154, &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; 954.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Wouldn't a solution to this be to simply make 954 an alias/redirect for [id://510154]?
Because 510154 is currently working exactly the way we want.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[demerphq], [localtime://2006-03-17 14:05:18]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Its applied. The old tutorials stuff are out of play now. Enjoy.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[demerphq], [localtime://2006-02-13 13:43:53]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Ok, ive put together a patch to make [tutorial sections] the source for [tutorials]. Unless anyone objects ill apply it soon.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[demerphq], [localtime://2006-01-30 06:07:01]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
For what its worth i think the purpose of pedagogues is to aggregate, edit and commission.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
What I mean is that its your (self appointed) job to put together summary lists of materials available here, edit tutorials that have been proposed, commission authors to convert their (or others) posts to real tutorials, and maybe if you feel like it post tutorials of your own.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But I can understand the issue of expectation management. I dont think that requests for a tutorial should necessarily be responded by a pedagogue producing a tutorial. Better I think would be to seek out a monk that had already posted on the subject to produce a tutorial from the material they already have.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I think a key point is that you all need to put some thought into what constitutes a tutorial. IMO we have always had a very loose concept of a tutorial which has lead to IMO some pretty bad tutorials being added to the list. Id like to see [pedagogues] put together a standard tutorial template (probably pod) and guidlines that can be provided to monks seeking to post a tutorial. Id like any request for a something to be promoted to a tutorial responded to by a pointer to the guidelines and a note stating that the best way to see the promotion occur is to make sure the post complies with the template and guidelines.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I think that once we work out the policy issues and stuff like that, we aught to decom the old tutorials page and put up the new tutlist based one. And then announce it in PMD with a general request for folks to help move the material we have into a standard format and structure. We have alot of good material, but its scattered around multiple nodes and tutorials, pedagogues time (IMO) would be well worth just collecting and collating that knowledge into usable tutorial documents.
&lt;p&gt;
I say this all as opinion not as a god. Its up to you guys what you do and how pedagogues run, but the above is more or less how i think it would be of most value.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;[bobf], [localtime://2006-01-28 22:48:41]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
First, thanks to [planetscape] for the great writeup and summary of our discussion.  (Sorry for the late post.  I, too, blame RL.)  I have very little to add, but I want to emphasize a few of the points she already made.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
One of my concerns about [Pedagogues] taking requests for tutorials is that it blurs the line between "tutorials section maintenance" and "writes reviews upon request", as the latter could turn into an expectation over time.  In addition, I don't want people to have to feel like they have to be a member of [Pedagogues] before they can write a tutorial.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I like the idea of using a directed approach for requesting tutorials.  An actively maintained "hot list" of desired tutorial topics would help focus monks' attention on defined problem areas.  As prospective tutorials are posted and the section fills out, the topic could be removed from the list and a new one added.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I'm undecided about using a wiki for the list, as it may have a tendency to get buried by additional posts over time (unless, of course, it was a to-do wiki that existed only for the list and not other discussion).  A separate node may help keep it more visible.  [jdporter]'s idea of a "Tutorials Quest" also crossed my mind, but if we allowed monks to post replies to the list things could get... interesting.  I would prefer to keep requests limited to /msgs to [Pedagogues].
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Finally, I think one of [Pedagogues|our] missions should be to keep reminding monks to use [id://3989] and to peruse the [Tutorials] and [id://1843] sections before posting.  Assembling an awesome [Tutorials] section won't do much good if people don't use it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;dt&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2006-01-26 20:59:20]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Wikis are easily created; if you want one, just /msg gods.
(BTW, formatting a wiki as a dl may be a bad choice; dl tags are only supposed to contain dt and dd, not hr.  But if it works...)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2006-01-26 12:31:04]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Sounds reasonable to me. Thanks for writing it up, [planetscape].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I'm not sure there's enough workload to necessitate a separate to-do wiki, yet.&lt;br/&gt;
OTOH, something publicly visible, like a "Tutorials Quest", might be interesting...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;


&lt;dt&gt;[planetscape], [localtime://2006-01-26 11:22:09]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ww] initially privmsged me about this, and [bobf] and I discussed it via IM. I apologize for the delay in addressing the issue here; I can only plead RL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, [bobf] and I came to the consensus (based on my 30-second review of the transcript; [bobf|he] may well have more to contribute) that while it is not strictly within the purview of [pedagogues] to author [Tutorials] on request, it may well be within our charter to, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Identify needs - either someone /msgs us with a request, or we notice that someMonks have been asking lots of [cpan://WWW::Mechanize] questions recently
   &lt;li&gt;Locate volunteers or Monks with an area of expertise, and make a gentle request to contribute (this may well be the Monk who /msged with the request)
   &lt;li&gt;Marshall resources - some of us by virtue of a longer residency here at PM or because we are members of other groups such as [pmdev] (I'm thinking of the [id://490460] node here) simply have a better grasp of where existing things are and/or how to find them
   &lt;li&gt;Start the process - perhaps by presenting our prospective new author with a list of resources and maybe even a "skeleton" or Tutorial template with a few things in place, external links, internal nodes, a short summary...
   &lt;li&gt;Obviously our prime focus is and must be maintaining and organizing the [Tutorials] page rather than authoring them ourselves (unless one of [pedagogues|us] takes that upon themselves)
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To this end, we thought that perhaps the [pedagogues] could have their own "To Do Wiki" to track requests, needs, volunteers, progress, etc. The communal editing would be beneficial, and having a dedicated wiki would help keep things from falling off the radar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, [bobf] and I do think that a more directed approach could only benefit PM as a whole, helping tap this marvelous resource of really knowledgeable, talented people that we have here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Thanks to [bobf] for all the excellent ideas and discussion; errors and omissions are mine alone&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2006-01-25 11:32:59]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
At 20:34 GMT+5 on Jan 24, 2006, [ww] wrote in a /msg to [Pedagogues|us]:
&lt;blockquote&gt;
though slightly OT, suggest a compilation re translation of M$Word to civilized 
files might be useful; cf: [holli]'s node et seq in [Re^2: "Demoronizer"] in 
[Best of the Best Users in Perlmonks site] and those I mention below.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Near as I can tell, [ww] is referring to 

[id://524238|holli's node] and [id://524507|ww's followup].&lt;br/&gt;
But... any idea what [ww|he] is really &lt;i&gt;talking about?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
If I had to guess, I'd say that he thinks [Pedagogues|we] should write a tutorial
(perhaps consisting of little more than a list of pointers to existing relevant nodes)
on how to demoronize MS-generated html. &lt;br/&gt;
Perhaps even for the "Welcome to the Monastery" section,
so that new posters can be made aware of the issue.&lt;br/&gt;
But is writing new tutorials in our charter?&lt;br/&gt;
I'm inclined to say not; I think the best response to [ww] is to suggest that he
write the tutorial himself, per the [id://465458|normal procedure].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;dt&gt;[demerphq], [localtime://2006-01-14 11:00:56]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[Injunjoel] has offered to assist in [Pedagogues]. If nobody objects over the next few days by /msg I will add him to the group.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[planetscape], [localtime://2006-01-02 08:42:05]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Finished populating the "Getting Started with Perl" section. Very nice infrastructure [Arunbear] and [demerphq] have created for us here. Thanks, guys!!!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[demerphq], [localtime://2006-01-01 18:46:53]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Ok, thats a possibility. Its not too difficult to allow a fair amount of flexibility in these matters, so we can play around with it a bit. In that spirit I've updated [render_doclist_group] to support a new mode, 'sections' (controlled via a node setting) which should make things like [id://510154] look a bit better. It could do with some more tinkering, for instance it should ignore sections that are empty.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BTW, if you find you can't update a faqlist/tutlist/doclist's settings get a god to check it has a record in the [setting] table for the node in question. It was added to the type at later point and its possible there are nodes out there missing the record.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[Arunbear], [localtime://2006-01-01 16:18:17]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I agree that strings used for offsite links should get &lt;i&gt;(offsite)&lt;/i&gt; added by the rendering code (so the string text itself can be a bit longer). On the other hand tutstrings seem to be the only case in which an offsite marker is needed, so perhaps just override the display code for tutstring (though i've no objection to an offsitestring type) ?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[de-merphq], [localtime://2006-01-01 14:45:01]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Ive made a few minor changes to [render_doclist_group] as part of the process of deprecating [render_faqlist_group]. One minor positive change is that ive added a way to get to a string node from the list for those with rights (ie, those who can see the nodes type).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Part of this process lead me to wonder about whether we should have a few different types of strings, with different rendering rules. More specifically, i was wondering if this would be the right way to handle offsite links, IE, have an 'offsitestring' type that would automatically get &lt;c&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;(offsite)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/c&gt; added to it. Something like that.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[Arunbear], [localtime://2005-12-27 16:41:29]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I've made a start at loading the tutorials into the new framework: [id://510154].
Feel free to populate these (yet to be filled in) sections: 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strike&gt;Getting Started with Perl&lt;/strike&gt; done by &lt;small&gt;[planetscape]&lt;/small&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strike&gt;Functions, Subroutines, and Variables&lt;/strike&gt; done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strike&gt;Tutorials on Specific CPAN Modules&lt;/strike&gt; done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Newly posted tutorials should automatically appear in [id://519201].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[yitzchak], [localtime://2005-12-27 02:10:37]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The Create link above was broken because it has to supply a default title ("New TutList"), but tutlists were set to
not allow multiple nodes with the same title, so as soon as one was created, no others could be (though the Create link would helpfully bring up an edit page for the previously created one).  I've changed it to allow multiple titles, so be cautious not to accidentally create dups.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;[planetscape], [localtime://2005-12-16 17:10:32]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I have manually added links to [Tutorials] for the following writeups, per the requests of their respective authors:
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;[id://494836|The Uniqueness of hashes] by [injunjoel]
&lt;br /&gt;[id://495975] by [bobf]
&lt;br /&gt;[id://516137] by [JamesNC]
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[de-merphq], [localtime://2005-11-24 16:05:50]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
My plan is to provide a framework much like what we have for SDC now. I've already created a [tutlist] type, which is a subclass of [faqlist]. Unfortunately I still have to fully implement its overrides, something which i was hoping that [Arunbear] might assist me with since he put together some of the existing framework for managing it. Anyway, basically the idea is to provide a way to have lists of lists. Handling offsite links is IMO to be done via the [strings] datatype, with [pedagogues] (and SDC) capable of creating/editing them. (A [strings] object is just a text field 255 chars wide that will be PM linkparsed if it is in a [faqlist] or derivative.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2005-11-22 08:47:46]&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Since we now have a place to talk about it &amp;mdash; I'd like to raise the question of
how the Tutes will be managed. I know there's been some talk of automating it, but 
I think there still needs to be some human involvement, some judgement.  I could see
something like the "normal" sections, where merit is determined democratically; or
something like the QnA section, which has an elite team of editors. Since 
[pedagogues|we] exist, I'm assuming the preference is for the latter?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
But until the new automated process is in full swing, I think we'll need to bring some
order to the Tutes manually. I propose a table listing all the &lt;c&gt;perltutorial&lt;/c&gt; nodes,
each with an indication of what category it could go in (one of the options being "none").
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[planetscape], [localtime://2005-11-21 10:19:26]&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;To send a message to the [id://499790] (if, for example, you need something added to [Tutorials]), [link://?sendto=pedagogues;node_id=48824|/msg pedagogues].&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To read messages (if you are a [id://499790|pedagogue]), [link://?type=strangedoc;recipient=499790;node=message%20inbox|pedagogues' inbox ]. :-)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;[de-merphq], [localtime://2005-11-19 15:58:19]&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first entry!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

</field>
</data>
</node>
