<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="96695" title="editors' wiki through 2001-07-14" created="2001-06-27 03:20:45" updated="2005-08-02 09:31:53">
<type id="68046">
wiki</type>
<author id="979">
vroom</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
Continues in [id://168299]
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[footpad], 13 Jul 01 - 07:30 pm (PDT)&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Several items/ideas/repeats:&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;While I think it's a good idea for us to figure out some general rules/conventions and to figure out some better ways of managing the 
problem(s).  However, I wonder if there isn't a simpler solution, one that doesn't require huge amounts of tinkering.  What if we make NTC a Level 7 Power, if only until we can get our FAQ's straight.  Once the Codes of Conduct are online, we can think about dropping it back to a Level 6 power.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;This might help flush out the rumored Friar Troll.  If the conduct continues, then we've exonerated a large number of members.  If it doesn't, then we simply track the level changes until it starts up.  Hopefully, the troll will "get it" by Level 7 and reform.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;I don't think we should penalize people for bad consideration requests and I think we should keep [NodeReaper].  We need to make certain, though, that folks know to vote the node down and to avoid replying to it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Again, I'd like to float the possibility of allowing Keep Votes to contribute to nodes appear in NRE.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;[Vroom] once mentioned that editorially-nuked nodes go into a holding tank.  Perhaps if we could see (and possibly resurrect) those, as well as [NodeReaper]'s, we could help limit the problem of over-reaping.  Perhaps a similar process as the Nuke code would help.  *Or* Perhaps we should as a Don't Nuke option, with the Node having to get three more Nuke's than Don't Nuke votes to go away.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;Uh, the wiki is too large for Netscape again.  We need another archive.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;I'm not trying to create a lot of work.  I'm simply trying to look for simple fixes that might make enough of a difference to prevent much of the problems.
&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
 [Petruchio] Fri Jul 13 09:46:02 EDT 2001
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 That people would not consider nodes for fear 
 of losing xp is the principal &lt;i&gt;feature&lt;/i&gt; 
 of my suggestion.  But that a node's contents 
 may change after it has been considered is a 
 serious problem for my idea. [kudra]++
&lt;/p&gt;
[kudra] Fri Jul 13 11:37:50 CEST 2001&lt;br&gt;
I'm not sure I like the idea of deducting xp
for nodes which are not deleted.  First, there
is the possibility of abuse--for example, someone
could bait by posting junk and then change it
once it was considered.  Next, I think it has
the potential to inhibit the proper functioning
of consideration as people choose not to consider
due to a fear of losing xp.  We already have a
situation where the perceived negative aspect of
downvoting leads people to consider rather
than downvote (or so it often seems, when you
see nodes with multiple delete votes and a positive
reputation).  There's also the question of whether
we should decide what grounds for deletion are,
or whether perlmonks as a whole should decide that.
&lt;p&gt;
The other suggestions, like sorting out edit
from delete, I'm in favour of.  Could we make
use of [id://6345|'editor requests'] to handle the edit
consideration by giving it the same kind of
interface as nodes to consider?  Right now
I'm not sure what purpose it is serving.
&lt;p&gt;
 [Petruchio] Thu Jul 12 01:49:29 EDT 2001
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 Without doubt, if we assume all node reaping 
 powers, we &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; taking power away from 
 the monks at large. This is not to say it's a 
 bad idea, but I think it best we speak of it 
 frankly. It may be the best choice for our 
 community, but we are again centralizing the 
 power structure. We are also increasing the 
 workload for the [editors].
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I think several things are worth considering 
 before we choose to do this.
&lt;p&gt;
 First off, it's hard to have reasonable 
 expectations about the consideration process, 
 when no guidelines exist.  We're having the 
 same troubles with the [Nodes to Consider|NTC]
 that we're having with the conduct of individual 
 [editors]; people have been set a task, without 
 instructions or goal, and they're getting it 
 wrong. It would be interesting to see how use 
 changed if such things were made explicit.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I think as well that we should ponder the 
 mechanism we've got in light of our objectives. 
 For instance, there are two distinct cases 
 handled by the consideration process:  requests 
 for deletion, and requests for editorial 
 intervention of one sort or another.  The 
 consideration mechanism itself makes no 
 distinction between these cases.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 Also, we can distinguish two cases which 
 have much different implications: sometimes 
 a person considers his own node, and sometimes 
 a person considers someone else's node.  It takes 
 much less judgement to reckon whether a node 
 should be reaped or moved when the request comes 
 from the author.  The consideration mechanism 
 does supply the name of the considerer, which 
 makes things easer for the voter; there is still 
 no actual difference in the way these cases are 
 handled, though.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 The quickest, easiest remedy I can think of 
 would be to publish criteria for considering 
 a node, and add an appropriate link to the 
 consideration nodelet.  Then publish criteria 
 for voting on considered nodes, display either 
 the criteria or a link to the criteria on the 
 [Nodes to Consider|NTC] page. The process for 
 determining these criteria is another matter.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I think a technological solution would actually 
 serve better. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 &lt;code&gt;&lt;!--#include file="i_know_vroom_is_busy.ssi"--&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I can see little reason to keep nodes considered 
 for deletion and those considered for editing in 
 the same list; likewise, I think that it is on 
 the whole a drawback that people may vote 'delete' 
 for nodes considered for editing, and vice-versa.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 Lower standards for action would seem reasonable 
 when a node is considered by its author.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 And I also think that more accountability for 
 those who choose to participate would be a good 
 thing.  Having the considerer's name made public 
 is a good thing; I would consider making him 
 directly liable, too.  As the ancient Athenians 
 fined someone who brought suit against another 
 and lost, I think that someone who considers a 
 node for deletion should lose XP if many people 
 vote to 'keep'.  The voting system, with it's 
 $NORM value, might serve as a model for this.
 If this deters people from participating... 
 good.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 Letting the 'public' mostly run the consideration
 process is, if only from a pragmatic, Lazy 
 standpoint, a Good Thing... assuming it actually
 worked.  I would prefer to see the process 
 centralized to seeing it continue as it has been; 
 but perhaps we can strike a balance which works
 instead.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2001-07-11&lt;br&gt;
Regarding [id://95476] which was considered with "(agoth) nonsense, plus who on earth put this on the front page???".  This is the type of thing I /msg the considerer about asking what they wanted &lt;em&gt;done&lt;/em&gt;.  This usually evokes some response about the node being "questionable" and wanting everyone to figure out what to do about it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I think that this actually results in nodes being reaped when the person considering it wasn't really convinced that it should be deleted:  The considerer thinks "well, people will vote on it so I don't really have to think about whether it should really be deleted or not" and voters think "well, it has been considered so I'll just 'do my part' and help it get 'cleaned up'" and also don't bother to think about it too much (other than, "yeah, it is kinda ugly, isn't it?").
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Retiring the NodeReaper will make this a much less serious problem.  I think we should announce this such that people realize that we aren't taking away their power, we are just replacing an automatic (and flawed) "decision" on their request with a decision by a qualified human so that obvious stuff will probably get reaped faster and easier while the tough decisions will be weighed more slowly and carefully.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Oh, and &lt;b&gt;I&lt;/b&gt; put that node on the front page because it had been around for a while with no answer.  The error message seemed rather specific so I was hoping someone would know rather precisely what that message meant and some broader exposure for it would help.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Anyway, I'll /msg this to agoth and eventually unconsider it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Feel free to express your disagreement (or agreement) with me on any of this, of course. (:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[Masem] 2001-07-11&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;The changes to [id://17645] look good; two things that I would add would be a link to [Nodes to Consider], so that the new friars understand where these nodes go, as well as suggesting to watch the NtC area for some time if they are unsure of how to decide if a node is Conciderable or not (ala the old days of usenet lurking).
&lt;/P&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2001-07-10&lt;br&gt;
No need to apologize at all, [neshura].  Docking you one week's salary should cover it (that is, volunteers are expected to get interrupted, delayed, and distracted -- at least I think so).  It looks like excellent work (the reformatting and wordsmithing).  You should update the bit about moving between threads now that I realize that [id://60309|the tool] has a few problems with even the easy cases (I updated my node regarding this).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[neshura] 2001-07-10
&lt;P&gt;hrrrm, well, uhhh....I undertook a big rewrite and expansion of the FAQ a couple of weeks ago, and I meant to tell you guys that I started, or that I hadn't finished, except I didn't because of x, y, and z...
&lt;BR&gt;anyway...I started on that level 6 friar rewrite thing and I'm glad someone got around to doing some more on it because I meant to link in a FAQ question on how consideration actually works. Which, [id://92975|if you read it], you'll recognize as being [tye]'s excellent discussion of the matter. It should have replaced the existing link. There are three bullet points in [id://17645] and as you can see, not all are mentioned. Maybe my bad, I don't remember now.
&lt;BR&gt;So SORRY, I probably should have either finished up the FAQ overhaul (hey, the Moderation and Consideration section got filled out, sorta, there's bits that are too short or say "unfinished"), or said "here's a changelog, anyone want to take this on?"
&lt;BR&gt;But I am tired and cranky, and also forgetful. Blah.
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2001-07-09 (only later, a little further to the left)&lt;br&gt;
Sorry about my last editors announcement; I think I'd already complained about that /: (I was temporarilly confused due to The Purge of [Nodes to Consider]).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As a start, could [chromatic|we] incorporate my expanded notes on what type of moving between sections is possible?  No need for a public nor private discussion on that, eh?  Or should I cut-n-paste, edit, and point [chromatic] to the results for a cut-n-paste?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2001-07-09&lt;br&gt;
Okay, I'm getting out my yard stick!  Now all of you snot-nodes [editors] go read [neshura|the new docs].  I said NOW!  *thwack*  All of it!  Okay, now you can all stop acting surprised when you can't revote on a reconsidered node.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I'd also like more of [id://89015] incorporated into [id://17645].  For example, I don't concur that personal attacks nor offensive postings should just be plonked as it now implies.  I'd be happy to do that but I have not the power and I need some feedback on parts that others don't concur on.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Surlily yours,&lt;br&gt;
Tye
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;P.S.&lt;/b&gt;:  Thanks [chromatic] and [kudra] for updating [id://17645]; it is a great idea that was done well.  Thanks [neshura], [Petruchio], and others for the new docs, also a great idea done well.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[chromatic] on 9 July 2001
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Looks like there's a little boundary condition in the [nodes to consider|ntc] voting.  Case in point, [id://95058], where I considered it early to replace those nasty font tags with code tags.  (pet peeve)  Someone apparently fixed it and removed it from consideration.  (the system works)  Unfortunately, someone else has considered it for deleting because, as it turns out, "It was not a Perl question and thus must be purged from our collective memories."  (another pet peeve).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Having voted to 'edit' it earlier, I am unable to vote to 'keep' now.  This node should not be reaped because the problem is solved.  Perhaps the voting flags should be reset per user when a node is resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 [Petruchio] Mon Jul  9 03:03:44 EDT 2001
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 The dweomer for editing [Tutorials] remains, but the incantation 
 is not obvious.  Go to [Tutorials Source] and edit that.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt;[footpad], 8 Jul 01, 02:40 pm (PDT)&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Looks like something's changed regarding the editorial abilities for [Tutorials].  I just tried to add one and got this message: "Not an editor editable type."  Are we not allowed to promote tutorials any more? &lt;I&gt;--f&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2001-06-07&lt;br&gt;
(Did I say this already?)  [editors] can't unapprove root nodes of [Meditations] (that is, w/o first moving them to another section).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 [Petruchio] Fri Jul  6 12:31:52 EDT 2001
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 This seems an appropriate way of doing things to me, [footpad]. I say 'yea'.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Footpad, 6 Jul 2001 - 07:40 (PDT)&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[CharlesClarkson] has /msg'd me privately regarding posting his [id://90647|Multidimensional Arrays] to [Tutorials].  Given that he recently [id://94010|posted] about it and that it hasn't been subsequently "promoted," it seems most of us are ambivalent on doing so. (He claims to have fixed the problems [chipmunk] noted when it was originally posted.)&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Does anyone have problems with (or alternatives to) me considering the node with "Promote to Tutorials? (Vote Edit for Yes and Keep for No)"?  This strikes me as a reasonably fair way to see what the general community feels about it. &lt;i&gt;--f&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Masem] 2001-07-04&lt;br&gt;
In the same light as [tye]'s comment, I assume the same applies to [Reviews]
&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2001-07-03&lt;br&gt;
Is [Code Catacombs] like [Tutorials] used to be, only updated by-hand by [vroom]?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  [Petruchio] Sat Jun 30 13:57:29 EDT 2001
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  [Masem] asked: "would it seem to be an abuse or an appropriate 
  use of editor power to add READMORE tags to nodes that don't 
  already have it if only to reduce front page clutter?"
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I think it safe to answer "no, it would not be an abuse".  
  Quoth [vroom]: "Their editing will largely be doing things to 
  make the site look prettier. Most of which will be getting rid 
  of PRE tags, and adding CODE and READMORE tags as necessary."  
  -- [New site editors], Feb 20, 2001
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 [Petruchio] Sat Jun 30 02:53:04 EDT 2001
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 Caution is indeed good. Perhaps if we do not attempt to make an 
 &lt;i&gt;exhaustive&lt;/i&gt; or a &lt;i&gt;final&lt;/i&gt; set of policies, we would 
 be safer and better able to act quickly without worry. Even a 
 single non-trivial principle would be an improvement. We 
 doubtless do not fully know what the policies should be; there 
 is an empirical element to such things. However there is a 
 difference between moving quickly to start and moving quickly
 to finish.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 [Developers]++
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 On another note, what editorial things is there reason *not* 
 to speak of in public?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2001-06-29, later tomorrow ET&lt;br&gt;
Anyway, back to [editors]' policy...  I was just about to say that the only problem with the current system is that it isn't going to scale (when others said roughly the same thing).  I think we are in pretty good shape for a little while.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I think we need to move toward more policies and more automatted checks and balances.  But I think we need to move slowly.  We've only been doing this for a little bit so I'm not sure we know all that much about what the policies should be.  So lets leave some room in the policies and lets start small and careful with the automation.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
First order of business in automation is the [developers] group... (have I said this before?) (: Really, I promise to never, ever say anything bad about [vroom]'s code.  I'm hot for this for the sake of the site...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2001-06-29, tomorrow ET&lt;br&gt;
See [id://89015] for another start of a FAQ about [editors].
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[neshura] 6/29/2001 6:50 PDT&lt;BR&gt;
[vroom] you r0x0r. [Petruchio], I took your suggestion and wrote up a list of editor powers that I know of. I'm not certain on how everything works, actually. I put a copy at the bottom of [vroom's wiki of love] for drafting purposes; needs some work, politely request anyone who knows better edit the list. The original is on my home node in case a [ailie|wise guy] decides to shred it and use the pieces in a quilt.

&lt;p&gt;[vroom] 2001-06-29 17:56 ET&lt;br&gt;
Fixed the anonymous edit problem
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2001-06-29 10:43 ET&lt;br&gt;
Well, I recently figured this out and [neshura]'s comments on power reminded me that I should tell [vroom] about this (just in case he isn't already aware).  And I just now noticed that [id://92565|the cat is out of the bag]...  Any AnonyMonk can edit the postings of any AnonyMonk, and it isn't that hard to figure out how.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 [Petruchio] Fri Jun 29 01:37:17 EDT 2001
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 Before saying anything else, I'd like to thank [neshura] for the most 
 stimulating exchange I've had in awhile.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I share her view that the present situation is not tenable. It is 
 certainly not scalable. I do not customarily work as root on my 
 &lt;i&gt;own&lt;/i&gt; box, and I use strict while working indepentantly on my 
 &lt;i&gt;own&lt;/i&gt; code; the idea of a system with 22 sorta-root users running 
 around without even solid policies in place is indeed spooky.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 There are two difficulties with technological solutions. First, they 
 take time and effort to implement. Second, decisions -- and possibly 
 difficult ones -- must be made as to what constraints should be put 
 in place. If a Developers group is formed, the former problem will 
 be much less serious; the latter perhaps more serious.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 In the nearer term, I think we need to improve our current cultural 
 solution. There is some very general understanding of proper conduct; 
 it is evidently not sufficient. I believe we need real policies.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I propose that we collectively create the &lt;i&gt;Lex Emendatori&lt;/i&gt;... 
 the Code of the Editors. Let's propose some tenets, debate them, 
 and form a Code out of those which seem good. This would give an 
 editor at least some objective standards to guide his actions, 
 and everyone else a rational measure by which to judge him.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 The forum for this is a little more difficult. I would suggest that 
 the [editors] use a wiki to create a rough draft, and then post the 
 draft for public [Perl Monks Discussion|Discussion]. Then create a 
 final draft, taking into account the opinions aired, and adopt it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I see two reasonable objections to this approach (assuming, for the 
 moment, that people don't object to the whole idea).  First, that 
 such a method is not egalitarian enough. I tend to think that the
 business  of composing would go more easily with a smaller group in 
 a flexible medium, and that the key thing would be to take the public 
 debate strongly into account.  Second, that this is simply too much 
 todo over what will probably be a very short document. This may be. 
 But if it works well, the approach might serve well for other 
 problems... such as what sorts of technological changes we'd like 
 see made to the site.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 As a practical matter as well, I would like for us to collect and 
 distill our knowledge of editorial powers and limitations, along 
 with some explanations as to what different things mean. Forming 
 such a document, however, would seem an appropriate editors-only 
 matter.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 *whew*  Sorry for the long-winded blather. I'm not only argumentative, 
 I talk too much... but then you knew that before you invited me here. 
 :-)  It may be that much of this should be taking place in 
 [Perl Monks Discussion|Discussion], but I wanted to say it here first, 
 to test the waters.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Footpad - 28 Jun 01, 19:30 (PDT)&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;I think [turnstep] has the right idea here.  I don't mind controversial nodes with technical merit and/or relevance.  There may be interesting things to learn from studying viral-like code or the details of DeCSS.  I do believe that it's wise to consider hiding "root-kit" sort of things, however, I don't mind discussing how those things are built.  I prefer to discuss how they're defeated, blocked, and quickly slain with a very large axe.  (Well, okay, maybe not the latter, but...)&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;And patently offensive material should be purged, quickly.  Let's keep this a family friendly site.  I like the fact that I'm not afraid to show my wife what goes on here.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Also, please remember that we're all on the same team.  Sure, we're going to make some mistakes while we figure out what we're comfortable with, but we are all working toward the betterment of the Monastery.  Please, no name-calling nor ass-u-m(e)ing.  I believe we all have the best of intentions, so let's treat each other civilly.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;[Neshura] brings up some good points, as do [tye] and [Petruchio].  This janitor job isn't going to be easy, but if we work together...we'll get our act together and help keep things copacetic.  We're here to serve the needs of the Monstery, not argue politics.  We can, of course, but we should do that publically.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;One note: Until we're able to get some more resolution tools, you may wish to consider voting Edit on nodes you might otherwise Keep.  Since nodes with two or more Edit votes can be flagged as Resolved, this may be a good way to keep the list short.  Just a thought.  &lt;I&gt;--f&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;[turnstep] 200106282103EST&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;If you come across a bear in the wilderness, curl up into a ball, 
keeping all your limbs tucked in and lay very, very still. Continue 
to do this for a long time, then continue to do it longer. The bear will 
lose interest if you are not moving, but may still be in the area, 
so it is imperative that you remain still long after you think 
it has left.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Um...so anyway...I vote to always keep "politically controversial" 
nodes (i.e. those that may be cause large organizations to stand 
up and take notice), but edit nodes that are simply offensive 
(be it erotic ASCII art, ugly font tags, personal attacks, 
porn, spam, etc.) If we roll over right away for controversial nodes, 
then thugs like the MPAA have already won through sheer intimidation. 
If they don't like something, let them send a letter to the site, and 
then we can evaluate the legitimacy of their request. I feel that many 
internet sites should (and must) be heavily moderated to maintain a 
decent signal/noise ratio and keep troublemakers out, but fear of 
repercussion should never be a factor, only how the content will be 
received by the community that is reading it.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;HR&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;i&gt;[neshura] sometime after lunch on Wednesday&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Truth be told, [Petruchio] is most likely right. Fighting isn't even the right word, I'm just trying to keep some focus on the fact that cracks (maybe not the massive ravines I've attempted to convince you of) are opening up in this system as it becomes more complex, with more layers of public and private and this, that, and the other thing.
&lt;P&gt;There is one simple fix for all of this: put a note by the submission form(s) that says "Your post may be edited for formatting and content". That gives us the leeway to protect [vroom]'s back, defend standards of good taste, and honors the principle of disclosure. Can this be done? (I know, I know, [vroom]'s busy). Is this something we can put out for discussion among the community?

&lt;p&gt;
 [Petruchio] Thu Jun 28 17:55:34 EDT 2001
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 My good [neshura],
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 Bravo! Encore! :-)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 What can one say to that? I agree with your generalizations, I applaud
 your objectives, I enjoy the flowers in your prose. A truth well-told
 is no worse for being obvious; fight on!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I can only hope that if you pen a reply to what I've said, it will 
 be as eloquent.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I do not know if you've hurt anyone's feelings, but I do think you
 spoke unfairly. My reasons do not need repeating; nor do I think
 the particular case needs belabored further. In general -- to comment
 on your generalities -- I even think that you 'fight fair', though
 I'm not convinced that anyone's fighting you. But individuals should
 be treated as such, and their actions judged for their own merits, not
 in terms of your efforts to reengineer democracy. In the absence of
 a code of conduct (much less of technological checks and balances) we
 must yet live and get along.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 [Petruchio] Thu Jun 28 17:51:45 EDT 2001
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I do not mean to put you on that side of that argument, [tye]. I am not 
 on that side of that argument. Insofar as my opinion counts, I'd say 
 (and did say) damn the torpedos.  I only pointed out that 
 [Node 541|action] as precedent for what you did, not why you did it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2001-06-28, tea time (though not locally)&lt;br&gt;
Oh!  And I'd love to see the [editors] logs made available soon!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Actually, I consider myself very much against content changing.  But I'm not nearly so against content hiding.  Temporary content hiding is even less of a dilema for me.  The virus fiasco had nothing to do with lawyers nor legalities and I was against removing the DeCCS code &lt;em&gt;at least&lt;/em&gt; until a letter from a lawyer arrived.  So it is becoming clear to me that I didn't express myself well in that thread (or at least in that node and many didn't read the rest of the thread -- not that I'd blame anyone for that) since I see people putting me on a side of an argument opposite of the side I feel myself to be on.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A couple of times I went to some work to modify the presentation of material that I'm pretty sure would have been removed otherwise (the dark poem and the ASCII nude).  Not that I particularly wanted either of those on the site, but I preferred that the site not censor them.  If I thought they would have survived "unmasked", I wouldn't have done it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I see very few cases of doing "too much" by [editors] (but I'll be glad to see the power to reap nodes take away from the masses due to demonstrated over enthusiasm) and most of those cases are followed (and/or preceeded) by the perpetrator questioning themself (one exception being the voting of "delete" on some nodes with replies, etc. which I am still interested in seeing one or two confessions for just so I can understand the thinking behind it).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Aside: I was criticized for "considering" the virus node "for information purposes" but the critic refused to explain.  Anyone want to /tell my why that creeped them out if it did?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And, no, I don't have a point.  I'm not sure what the argument is anymore.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;i&gt;[neshura] sometime before lunch on wednesday&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;P&gt;By all means, take umbrage, [Petruchio|honored warrior-editor]. No battle is ever won by rolling over and playing dead, unless you are out in the wilderness and you encounter a bear, maybe. I'll argue my hardest ("DO X BECAUSE") because this isn't tea time with the Queen Mother, this is putting together checks and balances in a community that, among other things, is trying to reengineer democracy in a new medium. Certainly one could scoff that it is only a web site and there are more important things in the world to do, which there are, and one is free to go do them, in most locales. 

&lt;P&gt;It is only by virtue of the fact that I am part of the [editors] that I can pretend (as pretense it necessarily is) to hold any editor accountable for actions taken with the aid of an astonishing level of power -- certainly no non-editor can even pretend. You as editors can't be unaware that you could change the wording of every [Anonymous Monk] post if that were your whim. You could systematically change the posts of everyone who ever disagreed with you; as long as you are careful to change only the older posts, you might never get caught. You could change [vroom]'s posts. You require no warrant from a judge, no unified editor opinion, no permission from the poster. 

&lt;P&gt;That means I have to trust [vroom]'s trust in each of you. Maybe you can understand that I don't readily cleave to the concept, given that I barely trust myself with the Omnipotent Red Pen of Justice and Good Taste. The job of the [editors] is whatever the [editors] want it to be; the charter was something the original editors worked out about "fix formatting but no content except sometimes delete it", I'm not really sure exactly. The charter, which is only in our heads, is painfully unresistant to demagoguery. At this very moment I'm waging a campaign of words to convince all of you to delete less, edit less, and support the implementation of technological checks and balances. I'll fight hard for it. I think I fight fairly most of the time -- sometimes I screw up and if I have personally hurt anyone's feelings, I want to hear about it.

&lt;P&gt;I'm not going to go into what I think the checks and balances should be (/msg me for that), because I still have to convince you that there is a gross imbalance of power. We're the police, we're also the judges, and our rule can't be overturned except by one [vroom|overworked dude] who can't possibly keep up with all our editorial maneuvers. Maybe we should wait until there is some unconscionable abuse of power, but maybe by that time we'll be so apathetic that we'll just shrug. Or maybe we won't consider it abuse, because we've been on a slippery slope and have lost track of the big picture. Do you think the community should trust us so blindly? 

&lt;p&gt;
 [Petruchio] Wed Jun 27 22:44:11 EDT 2001
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 There is [Node 541|precedent] for [tye]'s action.  And [vroom],  
 in his [63097|comment] on that matter said, amongst other things, 
 "I appreciate [merlyn] and others for watching my back so to speak"
 and "I thank all of you for your opinions on the matter as well 
 as those of you who had this place's best interests in heart when 
 acting on or alerting me to this content."
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 Note &lt;i&gt;acting on&lt;/i&gt;. Also... was the DeCSS code actually restored?
 I could be wrong, but I don't think so. In my opinion, [tye]'s action 
 was not only grounded in precedent, but was moderate, especially as 
 he asked first and was quick to undo his changes when he found 
 significant disagreement.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 But [neshura], I must say I take umbrage at your tone. Your brief 
 concession about intentions notwithstanding, it sure sounds a whole 
 lot like you're &lt;i&gt;giving orders&lt;/i&gt;. You too are a non-[vroom] 
 person, which makes it a little hard to fathom imperious statements 
 like "It's not your call", and "So don't".
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 This despite that I tend to agree with your ideas. I think that (far) 
 fewer nodes should be reaped or edited, and that such things should be 
 done more cautiously. But the fact is we don't have an editors' handbook, 
 and we are obliged to act upon precedent and our own judgement. Without 
 a policy on this sort of thing,  I think your tone is unreasonably 
 harsh. Speak your peace, by all means; but sometimes your tone borders 
 on uncivility, and I am not sure what good comes of it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;I&gt;[neshura] June 27, 2001, 2:45 Pacific&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
My surly and unforgiving home node notwithstanding, I'm fairly certain all the [editors] have nothing but the most selfless of intentions regarding the editing of content. If and when a lawyer calls up [vroom] and informs him to take down Node xyz OR ELSE, [vroom] and [nate] can decide whether to take a stand for academic freedom or throw in the towel. Hey, they might even decide to take a stand and post some rules before that happens!
&lt;P&gt;But they haven't. So don't. &lt;/P&gt; 
&lt;P&gt;P.S. I know that everyone's gotten pretty accustomed to talking in secret like this, but whenever possible, [Perl Monks Discussion|take it to the people]. The rest of the community deserves to know that subjects like this are in discussion by our not-so-little-anymore [editors|Cabal]. 
&lt;P&gt;Masem - 2001-27-06 11:30 CDT&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
As to keep accountability going for [Tutorials], I added my [How To RTFM] yesterday to the list (Under Misc.).
&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Footpad - 27 Jun 01, 07:40 (PDT)&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Looks like [Petruchio] and I are thinking along the same lines.  I agree that some accountability and HTML clean up would be desireable in [Tutorials].  I like the idea of adding a commented changelog, as seems to be the standard for editing.  An "updated on" flag would help people know when it's been changed, as well.  (I'd planned to put together a proposal for organizing the [Tutorials] and throwing it onto a hidden page on [jcwren]'s site for y'all to preview.)  
&lt;P&gt;Perhaps we should Consider tutorial candidates as "Edit - Post to Tutorials"?&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Some of the current HTML inconsistency is my fault; I started closing &amp;lt;LI&amp;gt; tags last night and wasn't able to finish before having to go to bed.  (I also added [jeffa]'s [id://65642].)&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Also, I've just considered a bunch of null nodes (discovered while seeking unposted [Tutorials]).  While doing so, I discovered that perlexercise node types cannot be considered.  (To verify, check [wml|these] and go to the second hit.)  Should we be able to consider perlexercise nodes?  &lt;i&gt;--f&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
 [Petruchio] - Wed Jun 27 10:23:30 EDT 2001
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I have taken the liberty of adding two links to the [tutorials] 
 page: [Parsing your script's command line], by [grinder], which 
 apparently had been listed there formerly, and [References quick 
 reference], a node of [tye]'s which he'd mentioned as appropriate 
 for [tutorials] and which seemed worthy.  I am inclined to add 
 [Using HTML::Template], but I want permission from [Ovid] first.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I have noted my actions with comments, which seemed the best way 
 to leave a record.  If anyone does not approve of my decisions, please 
 tell me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I mention this because editing the [tutorials] page is a new thing, 
 and a convention has not been established, so it is harder to be sure 
 one is doing it correctly.  We cannot discuss every change an editor 
 makes, but in more established matters it has been easy to follow the 
 lead of other [editors].
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 Along these lines, I noted that the HTML used in [tutorials] does not 
 follow a regular convention, and that some organizational changes might 
 be desireable.  I think that a node that various people are likely to 
 be amending would benefit from a very regular style; however I was loath 
 to make changes along those lines without consulting the group. I could 
 edit the code to this end, if it please the gods, though I would be 
 happy to leave the matter to others as well.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 I am struck again by the responsibility of being an editor; an 
 important node on the system now seems as volatile as a wiki.  In 
 the absence of an external accounting system for our actions, I think 
 making explicit record of our changes really is very important.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;HR /&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Footpad - 27 Jun 01, 06:30 (PDT)&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[Neshura]'s announcement regarding heavy-handed deletes got me to thinking.  Is there any way we can extend [nodes requiring editing|nre] to a) include a count of Keep votes (KV's) and/or b) to resolve nodes that have more than some appropriate number of KV's?  I notice that some nodes under consideration had one edit vote, but many KV's.  Is this a bad idea?  &lt;I&gt;--f&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR /&gt;
The archived ew is at [id://91826]
&lt;HR&gt;
So, I guess this is a good time for us to learn about restoring wiki nodes from backup, eh? --[tye]</field>
</data>
</node>
