<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="123123" title="MySQL and Perl for the Web" created="2001-11-04 00:14:56" updated="2005-08-10 15:41:41">
<type id="31670">
bookreview</type>
<author id="115491">
kwoff</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;H3&gt;Quick review&lt;/H3&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
&lt;A HREF="http://www.kitebird.com/mysql-perl/"&gt;&lt;B&gt;MySQL and Perl for the Web&lt;/B&gt;&lt;/A&gt;
is the second &lt;A HREF="http://mysql.com"&gt;MySQL&lt;/A&gt;-related book by
Paul DuBois, who is
&lt;A HREF="http://mysql.com/doc/C/o/Contributors.html"&gt;a contributor&lt;/A&gt; to
&lt;A HREF="http://mysql.com/doc/"&gt;the MySQL documentation&lt;/A&gt;.
I thought his &lt;A HREF="http://www.kitebird.com/mysql-book/"&gt;first MySQL book&lt;/A&gt;
a couple years ago was outstanding; naturally then, being a web developer
myself, I was excited when I found this book on the shelves. If you're
new to making web-based database interfaces, or even if -- like me --
you're looking for ideas on how to automate database-driven HTML forms,
then this book is a good investment.
&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
&lt;I&gt;Audience:&lt;/I&gt; novice- to intermediate-level web developers, though there
are some cool tricks even for advanced developers
&lt;/P&gt;


&lt;H3&gt;Detailed review&lt;/H3&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
Okay, I admit, after the initial pavlovian drooling, my next
thoughts were along the lines of
"&lt;I&gt;isn't this just a book on how to create Perl CGI scripts,
and am I not tired of making CGI scripts,
so why am I looking at this book&lt;/I&gt;?"
Well, for one thing, there's only one
&lt;A HREF="http://perl.apache.org/"&gt;mod_perl&lt;/A&gt; book,
&lt;A HREF="http://www.modperl.com/"&gt;the Eagle book&lt;/A&gt;,
and I've read that, and it's getting old anyway,
so if I wanted to get away from these tedious CGI scripts,
yet still spend the money burning in my pocket while I was at the bookstore,
then my alternative was to get a book on Java servlets
(actually I did, but that's another story :).
On closer inspection, however, this actually is a book on mod_perl --
or, at least on
&lt;A HREF="http://www.perldoc.com/cpan/Apache/Registry.html"&gt;Apache::Registry&lt;/A&gt;
scripts, which are CGI scripts stuffed into a mod_perl subroutine.
&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
The first few chapters of the book are for newbies. Of course.
Chapter 1 is a high-level background chapter,
basically saying "this class covers MySQL and Perl,
is everyone in the right classroom?
&lt;A HREF="http://www.idiotsavant.com/bueller/"&gt;Bueller&lt;/A&gt;?".
Chapter 2 gets the newbie up and running with MySQL and Apache.
This chapter includes test CGI scripts that access MySQL to verify that the
installation is working, and it gives tips along the way on what
&lt;A HREF="http://dmawww.epfl.ch/roso.mosaic/dm/murphy.html"&gt;might go wrong&lt;/A&gt;.
Chapter 2 also introduces WebDB.pm (see "Companion website" below),
which is a
&lt;A HREF="http://www.perldoc.com/cpan/DBI.html"&gt;DBI.pm&lt;/A&gt; wrapper
library developed as the book progresses, and is one of the most
useful things to come from the book if you ask me.
&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
Chapter 3 spanks you for using CGI scripts instead of Apache::Registry.
&lt;A HREF="http://www.lysator.liu.se/~marcus/ren_stimpy/FAQ.html"&gt;Steempy&lt;/A&gt;,
you eediot!
&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
Chapter 4 introduces techniques for using
&lt;A HREF="http://www.perldoc.com/cpan/CGI.html"&gt;CGI.pm&lt;/A&gt;
to process HTML forms. Chapter 5 then illustrates those techniques
with several example applications: product registration, email,
a contest, a poll, storing/retrieving images, and greeting cards.
Those are pretty typical applications that you're likely to run into
as a web backend developer.
&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
As I mentioned above, I'm getting tired of writing variations of the
same form-handling CGI scripts, so I found chapter 6 to be glorious
(*&lt;I&gt;sound of organs and harps, choir singing hallelujah&lt;/I&gt;*).
In this chapter, you take it to the next level and use
&lt;I&gt;meta-data&lt;/I&gt; -- that is, information &lt;B&gt;about&lt;/B&gt; the database
as opposed to information &lt;B&gt;in&lt;/B&gt; the database -- to automatically
generate simple tables and to do some verification of form input. Okay,
let's be real, this isn't a panacea. However, although it's not going
to work in all cases, it's certainly a start, and it'll give you ideas
to implement yourself. In fact, I used WebDB.pm with
&lt;A HREF="http://www.masonhq.com/"&gt;HTML::Mason&lt;/A&gt;
to make create automatic tools for lusers to administrate simple
database tables (no references to other databases) using web
interfaces (basically that's my job description).
&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
Moving right along, chapter 7 is 60 pages of how to do web searches.
Odd finding that in a book called "MySQL and Perl for the Web".
&amp;lt;/sarcasm&amp;gt;
&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
Chapter 8, on session management, was actually one of the reasons
I bought the book, as I was trying to figure out how to use
&lt;A HREF="http://www.perldoc.com/cpan/Apache/Session.html"&gt;Apache::Session&lt;/A&gt;
with HTML::Mason at that time. After reading this book, I got it working!
(Come on, I would've got it anyway.) There's even a WebDB::Session.pm
wrapper to make life even simpler.
&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
Chapter 9 is on security issues. It even explains how to build and
configure Apache for SSL support. If you've ever tried that on your
own, you'll appreciate this explanation. And finally, right after the
chapter on security, comes chapter 10 on e-commerce.
&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
In conclusion, I really found this book useful
and would recommend it to aspiring and experienced web developers alike.
&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;H3&gt;More info&lt;/H3&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
&lt;I&gt;Companion website:&lt;/I&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;A HREF="http://www.kitebird.com/mysql-perl/"&gt;http://www.kitebird.com/mysql-perl/&lt;/A&gt;.
&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
&lt;I&gt;Chapter names:&lt;/I&gt;
&lt;OL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Introduction to MySQL and Perl&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Getting Connected -- Putting Your Database on the Web&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Improving Performance with mod_perl&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Generating and Processing Forms&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Writing Form-Based Applications&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Automating the Form-Handling Process&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Performing Searches&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Session Management&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Security and Privacy Issues&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;E-Commerce Applications&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;
&lt;/P&gt;

</field>
<field name="itemdescription">
A book on using MySQL and Perl for the Web</field>
<field name="usercomment">
</field>
<field name="identifier">
</field>
</data>
</node>
