<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="144486" title="Practical PostgreSQL" created="2002-02-10 13:26:37" updated="2005-08-10 16:08:03">
<type id="31670">
bookreview</type>
<author id="95917">
jlongino</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;p&gt;This review was originally submitted to Amazon.com and so 
far 5 of 5 reviewers have found it useful. I regret that my 
first ever review of a book is so negative.  I strongly 
recommend that you at least peruse a copy before buying it, 
a mistake that I don't plan to repeat. &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Update 1:&lt;/b&gt; see 
the node by [VSarkiss] below and preview the online version 
before purchasing. Thanks [VSarkiss]!
&lt;p&gt;
I ordered this book thinking that it would provide the 
information necessary to setup PostgreSQL and interface 
to it via Perl. It was somewhat useful on the first count 
but Perl doesn't even have a listing in the index.
&lt;p&gt;
Speaking of the index, it is surely the poorest one I've 
encountered in any O'Reilly or other computer reference 
book I've ever seen or considered buying. It fills only 3 
pages front and back. This is a 600+ page book mind you. 
Because of the poor index you will probably spend more 
time flipping through pages or using the table of contents 
which is rather scant as well.
&lt;p&gt;
It is too bad that I bought this book by mail order because 
if I had been able to inspect it in a bookstore, I would've 
never bought it. The documentation that comes with 
PostgreSQL is more than adequate to get it installed and 
working. If you are looking to use Perl as your front-end 
language, your time and money would probably be better 
spent on [isbn://1565926994|Programming the Perl DBI] by O'Reilly.
&lt;p&gt;--Jim
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Update 2:&lt;/b&gt; Added a link to &lt;u&gt;Programming the Perl 
DBI&lt;/u&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</field>
<field name="itemdescription">
A PostgreSQL Reference</field>
<field name="usercomment">
Useful info, but not very practical &amp;nbsp;&lt;tt&gt;&lt;b&gt;**&lt;/b&gt;***&lt;/tt&gt;</field>
<field name="identifier">
1565928466</field>
</data>
</node>
