<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="144517" title="Mastering Perl/Tk" created="2002-02-10 17:18:24" updated="2005-08-15 07:30:00">
<type id="31670">
bookreview</type>
<author id="95917">
jlongino</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;p&gt;At the same time I ordered Practical PostgreSQL, I ordered 
this book at a local Barnes &amp; Noble bookstore. Fortunately, 
this one didn't disappoint me. This book lived up to all 
the hype I'd heard, and had begun to anticipate, two months 
before it was available.
&lt;p&gt;
The index and table of contents are excellent (a must for 
any &lt;i&gt;good&lt;/i&gt; reference book). The index seems very 
thorough and takes up about 30 pages.  The table of 
contents, and thus the book, is laid out in a manner that 
makes it easy to find topics/subtopics of interest.
&lt;p&gt;
There is a 60-page appendix table "Options and Default 
Values for Each Widget" which I've already placed a stickem 
on for quick reference. The appendix would have been even 
more invaluable if each widget (and possibly some lesser 
used/known attributes) had a page number reference so one 
doesn't have to find an entry there, and then have to look 
it up a second time in the index to find more details.
&lt;p&gt;
There is also another appendix that contains complete 
program listings for fun/useful programs like progress 
bars, MP3 player, RPN calculator, etc. They are useful as 
extensive examples of Perl/Tk code, if nothing else. The 
only downside is that there are no electronic copies (CD or 
web links) to these programs and some are rather lengthy.
&lt;p&gt;
Although I consider myself a rank beginner with Perl/Tk, I 
believe that it will also serve as an invaluable reference 
to advanced users of Perl/Tk and have heard from at least 
one or two monks via CB that it is far superior to Nancy 
Walsh's first book [isbn://1565927168|Learning Perl/Tk].
&lt;p&gt;--Jim
&lt;p&gt;</field>
<field name="itemdescription">
Graphical interfaces with Perl</field>
<field name="usercomment">
Highly recommended. &amp;nbsp;&lt;tt&gt;&lt;b&gt;*****&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;</field>
<field name="identifier">
1565927168</field>
</data>
</node>
