<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="169417" title="Programming Perl" created="2002-05-26 13:34:05" updated="2005-08-14 02:39:54">
<type id="31670">
bookreview</type>
<author id="159356">
mr2</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
i'm from Lithuania (europe) &amp;amp; i study english language ... &amp;amp; i had to 
introduce some kind of book ... so i chose &amp;quot;Programming Perl (3ed)&amp;quot; 
... so there is what i figured ...
&lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="7"&gt;Programming Perl&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="center"&gt;Larry Wall, Tom Christiansen &amp;amp; Jon Orwant&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  This book is the third edition book and was published in year 2000. The first 
  edition was published in 1991 and the second in 1996. It was published for a 
  few times because the perl programming language was changing, becoming more 
  powerful, and the later editions of the book were becoming less informative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was edited by several people like Larry Wall (the inventor of perl), Tom 
  Christiansen (one of the first perl programmers), Jon Orwant (the editor of 
  &amp;quot;The Perl Journal&amp;quot; which has brought together the perl programmers 
  community as a common forum for new developments in perl) and many more people 
  who were sending the authors emails, with found bugs, suggestions, examples 
  of perl scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole book is dedicated to perl (practical extraction and report language) 
  programming language that has grown explosively in popularity since its initial 
  debut in 1987. &amp;quot;Programming Perl&amp;quot; is not just a book about perl. It 
  is also a unique introduction to the language and its culture. There are a lot 
  of other books on perl, but only this one is the definitive guidebook that includes 
  all the nooks and crannies of the language. Any perl book can list endless features, 
  but only this one can tell why those features were created and how to use them 
  idiomatically. It's even affectionately known by all perl programmers as &amp;quot;The 
  Camel.&amp;quot; (because of the picture of the camel on the front of it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is divided into 5 big parts: &amp;#091;1] Overview. &amp;#091;2] The Gory Details &amp;#091;3] 
  Perl as technology. &amp;#091;4] Perl as culture. &amp;#091;5] Reference material. that are divided 
  into 33 topics, whitch consist of a lot of small topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first part is an introduction to the book and to perl. It's introduced 
  as a programming language that is used on almost all (if not all) operating 
  systems ever created, UNIX, Windows, Mac OS, even such operating systems like 
  Atari, Guardian, SCO, etc ... It is also described how perl works, because it's 
  not a programming language like many others. When you write a perl program, 
  it's not called &amp;quot;a program&amp;quot;, it's called &amp;quot;a script&amp;quot; because 
  its source is not compiled as almost all programming languages, and it needs 
  a interpreter (perl) which reads this script and acts the way it's written in 
  it. It is also talked a lot about its flexibility, its using in system administration, 
  web programming. This part of book is written in easy language with a little 
  dose of humor, everybody can easily read and it's not boring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second part discusses important basics of perl programming: variables, 
  values, hashes, input, output, that are used in programming small/large perl 
  scripts. This part is more serious, because if you misunderstand something what 
  is written there, it will be hard to understand next chapters. But if you read 
  carefully and try examples that are shown, it's not really hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third topic helps in overcoming programming problems. It's described how 
  to prepare the system, debug the scripts. It's not long, problems are shortly 
  described and simple to understand, besides, solutions are written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next chapter &amp;quot;Perl as Culture&amp;quot; talks about perl development, learning 
  on the world wide web, about programming style, perl script security which is 
  very important in our days, because of a lot of attempts on hacking. The main 
  theme is the explanation on how to become a part of wide perl programmers community, 
  how to make your own research and how to share the results. It's dedicated to 
  advanced programmers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the last one is the most serious one. It differs from others because its 
  not discussed about the basics of programming, it's like the handbook of skilled 
  programmers, who are called JAPH (witch is an acronym of Just Another Perl Hacker) 
  among perl programmers. There is a list of perl modules (libraries) that help 
  advanced programmers to write longer scripts in less time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is very interesting for people who are interested in programming, 
  system administration, web development, internet security, because it discusses 
  everything, connecting everything to perl programming language. And if you read 
  the whole, or any part of a book carefully, you will find out many interesting 
  facts, you'll learn to program in perl or just find out how perl programmers 
  community lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &amp;copy;opyLeft by mr2 &amp;#091;2002.05.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="-2"&gt;Fixed square brackets and misc formatting - [dvergin] 2002-05-26&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</field>
<field name="itemdescription">
Programming Perl</field>
<field name="usercomment">
</field>
<field name="identifier">
</field>
</data>
</node>
