<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="179099" title="Running Weblogs with Slash" created="2002-07-03 04:58:23" updated="2005-08-10 16:34:23">
<type id="31670">
bookreview</type>
<author id="2680">
davorg</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;p&gt;By [chromatic], Brian Aker and Dave Krieger&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slash is the software that runs sites like Slashdot and
    use.perl. It's all written in Perl using the Template Toolkit
    with MySQL at the back end. Despite it being based on a number
    of my favourite technologies, I'd never really the time to get
    to know how it worked. Reviewing this book finally gave me the
    excuse to spend a few hours looking at it. I decided the best
    way to ``test'' the book would to be to try and set up and
    configure a Slash web site whilst reading the book.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The book starts by giving an overview of Slashdot - the site
    that the Slash code grew out of. This is followed by an
    overview of how a Slash site looks to the user and a brief look
    at the architecture of Slash. All very interesting, but it
    didn't get me any closer to setting up my Slash site.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;That started in chapter 2, which is a guide to installing
    Slash. During this chapter I became aware that the book (or, at
    least, this part of it) wasn't really aimed at me. By this I
    mean that the chapter assumed that the reader knows less than I
    do about installing Perl modules, setting up MySQL databases
    and configuring Apache. I was fast coming to the conclusion the
    the book's target audience was people who wanted to run a
    weblog using Slash, but didn't really know very much about
    Apache, MySQL or Perl. This made reading this chapter very
    quick and in an hour or so I had a basic Slash site up and
    running.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The next five chapters look at the nuts and bolts of running
    a Slash site. They describes the processes of setting up
    authors, editing and updating stories, reviewing and approving
    submissions, dealing with comments and managing topics and
    sections. Again, I read all of this pretty quickly as the
    chapters were going over in some detail processes that I was
    finding pretty easy to work out from the layout of the Slash
    administration pages. One section stood out. In the middle of
    chapter 6 there is a discussion on how Perls's regular
    expressions can be used to filter comments. I found myself
    wondering how easily my assumed target audience would deal with
    this material.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Chapter 8 changes direction completely. This chapter
    discusses ways to manage the community that builds up around a
    successful Slash site. It was almost completely non-technical
    but, building on their ideas of what has made Slashdot so
    successful the authors present some interesting ideas on the
    nature of web communities. To me, this chapter alone justifies
    reading the book.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;In chapter 9 we're back with customising your site, with
    sections on setting up Slashboxes (little areas of content that
    go down the side of a Slash site), exhanging headlines with
    other sites using XML and managing user polls. Again there's
    not much comlpex technical content in this chapter.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;In the last two chapters we suddenly get &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt;

    technical, looking at advanced site customisation and
    administration issues. In particular, when the advanced
    customisation chapter looks at plugins, it gives an example of
    how to write a plugin and this may well all be a bit confusing
    for the target audience I discussed earlier. This is aimed at
    someone who knows what they are doing when it comes to Perl and
    MySQL.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The five appendices act as a reference to the Slash
    codebase. They contain much in depth information about the
    database tables and the API exposed by the various Slash
    modules. Appendix C contains a useful introduction to the
    Template Toolkit, which Slash uses to create all of the actual
    HTML pages. There's a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of information in this pages
    and they take up about a third of the book.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I suspect I've come across a little more negative that I
    intended in this review. I do think it's a very useful book and
    should be read by anyone running (or thinking of running) a
    site using Slash. My only problem is that is seems to be two
    half books joined together. The second half seems to be aimed
    at a far more technically literate audience than the first
    half.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;But the bottom line is that I got my Slash site up and
    running and I know a lot more than I did about how to configure
    and administer it - so the book does what I wanted it to.&lt;/p&gt;
</field>
<field name="itemdescription">
Beginners Guide To A Great Web Application Framework</field>
<field name="usercomment">
Does What It Says On The Can</field>
<field name="identifier">
0-596-001002</field>
</data>
</node>
