<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="21416" title="Learning Perl" created="2000-07-07 06:38:05" updated="2005-08-10 16:31:27">
<type id="31670">
bookreview</type>
<author id="8329">
Aighearach</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;i&gt;the Llama book&lt;/i&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
by &lt;B&gt;[merlyn|Randal L Schwartz]&lt;/B&gt; and &lt;B&gt;Tom Christiansen&lt;/B&gt;
&lt;BR&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;EM&gt;©  O'Reilly &amp; Associates, Inc.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
&lt;P&gt;My first experience with Perl was via the Llama book. I was taking some C++ classes at the time, but I wasn't really happy with some of the "features" of C, like having to keep track of my array sizes. Am I a programmer, or a bean counter? So, I decided to seek out something Different, to supplement my learning.
&lt;P&gt;Upon opening the Llama book, I found a rather bizarre forward by Larry Wall. I got a good laugh out of it, but it also made me a little nervous. Isn't programming at least a &lt;i&gt;little&lt;/i&gt; bit serious? But, it is only the forward, after all.
&lt;P&gt;Entering chapter one, "Introduction," my worries were quickly dispelled. My background was mainly in BASIC on the Apple and ASIC on DOS, and I quickly found a new thing to be concerned about. What was being described was easier, was &lt;B&gt;more&lt;/B&gt; natural than basic! This can't be efficient, can it? Little did I know...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt;From there I was taken on a pleasant stroll through scalars and arrays, control structures, hashes, basic I/O, regular expressions, functions, filehandles, and onward all the way to CGI. I found this journey to be very easy, and well planned.
&lt;P&gt;For somebody new to perl, I would give this book my &lt;B&gt;highest recommendation&lt;/B&gt;. In just a few weeks, I was able to write more clear, concise programs than I have ever been able to write in C. I found it to provide a solid foundation, so that I was completely prepared to dive into &lt;TT&gt;perldoc&lt;/TT&gt; to answer the rest of my basic and intermediate questions.</field>
<field name="itemdescription">
</field>
<field name="usercomment">
</field>
<field name="identifier">
1565922840</field>
</data>
</node>
