<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="215622" title="Perl CD Bookshelf Version 3.0" created="2002-11-25 09:29:00" updated="2005-08-10 15:38:06">
<type id="31670">
bookreview</type>
<author id="44177">
marvell</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;p&gt;Being a great fan of paper, I entered into this review with fear
and trepidation. What is a CD bookshelf? Who is it for? Is it cost
effective? Is it any good? Will it be any good for me? These were the
questions I wanted answers to, and this is how it went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A CD bookshelf is a collection of books, on a CD. More than that,
you get a master index, covering all of the books, and a search
facility, which you'd not find with normal paper manuals, of
course. The CD, in this instance, has seven books (even though the
search help page states six):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perl in a Nutshell, 2nd ed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning Perl, 3rd ed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programming Perl, 3rd ed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perl Cookbook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perl &amp;amp; XML&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perl &amp;amp; LWP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mastering Perl/Tk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pack also comes with a paper version of Perl in a Nutshell,
which was most gratifying for me, but I'm not sure what the point was,
in context. Described as a &amp;quot;Bonus Book&amp;quot;, the implication is
that it's free, which it clearly isn't. The production cost of the
book would have been large in comparison to the CD, and it adds a lot
more weight to the package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous versions of of the Perl CD Bookshelf have always come with
Perl in a Nutshell, Programming Perl and the Perl
Cookbook and have always come with a paper Nutshell. Previous other
books have included, Learning Perl, Advanced Perl Programming, Learning Perl on Win32
Systems and Perl for System Administration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that Learning Perl and Advanced Perl Programming were
included together rather implied that it wasn't really aimed at
learners. Indeed, how many learners invest this much money in a new
language up front? So, who &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; it for? Well, judging by the
titles, it's for people who program Perl and needs a good
reference. I was slightly concerned about the validity of the Systems
Administration title, but it's clear that the XML and LWP titles are
for Perl programmers, in many contexts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The choices are clearly difficult. There is not a whole range of CD
bookshelves, one for web people, one for data mungers and one for
computer scientists. O'Reilly has tried to find a balance of titles
and levels to attract as many people as possible, but is that the
right thing to do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pack sells for &amp;pound;76 and with each book retailing at
&amp;pound;20 to &amp;pound;30, you make a significant saving on purchasing
the books individually. So, would you buy them all anyway? Well, no,
but you only need to want four of them, and it's paid for itself. Of
course, this does not include the other bonuses of having a search
facility and other bonuses of electronic storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, down using it. I slapped in the CD and got on with it. Browsing
was easy. Just as easy as surfing the web. The pages were laid out
well and it was obvious what to do. The internal references worked as
you'd expect. The master index was very useful indeed, giving you the
ability to choose your book based on your type of enquiry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The search facility was implemented with ease in mind. Most search
systems I've written myself have used CGI or similar technology;
relying on a web server. This is clearly not an option for something
everyone should be able to just get on with, so the Java solution is
a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The search system is not pretty and it's no more than a boolean
full text search. It's slick, and returns results. I hope that in the
future, we can see a more complex search involving relevance and maybe
some intelligence. Clearly this would require further work from
O'Reilly, and that rather depends on the user base and popularity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have liked to seen phrase matching, ie. the ability to
match two or more words which are concurrent. With some of the pages
being very large indeed, the results can often lack context by virtue
of the fact that there are many contexts in one place. An example was
the flip-flop (..), also known as the 'range operator'. I had to
search for '(flip flop) or (range operator)' since there are no
synonym matches. This resulted in a multitude of irrelevant links,
since the words 'range' and 'operator' are frequent on many pages,
even though they are not in the same context. I would have liked the
ability to search for '&amp;quot;flip flop&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;range
operator&amp;quot;' and not have that problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another useful feature would have been to indicate the position of
the searched term in the text itself. With large pages, an extra,
browser level, search is often required to find the actual
reference. It is not beyond the ability of a good web programmer to
perform this action, nor would it to provide some context of
information when the search results were returned, which would have
been another useful feature. With so much space left on the CD, I'm
sure there is room for extra indeces and to split up the book. This
would note require extra analysis of the books themselves, but would
enhance the text searching ability greatly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tested the system on numerous browsers on different platforms. The HTML works fine, but the search Java system does not
work on newer browsers with newer JREs, like Mozilla or Opera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me the relevance of the titles was good. The value for money
was good and the extra ability to have, say, multiple pages of the
same book open and to do global searches, added value. I still like
reading books for learning, but for reference, this is much
better.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;In summary, the CD bookshelf represents a good reference source for
most Perl programmers. It is pretty much always cost effective and is
more likely to be so if you've not bought one before or you are a Perl
programmer covering many fields. It works on many system and is very
easy to use. The search engine is useful, but could be much more
so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I liked it a lot.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve Marvell is the Proprietor of an IT Solutions Provider based
in the South West of England and runs the Devon and Cornwall Perl
Mongers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This review may be used, in full, including this message, by
anyone, but may not be edited without the author's permission.&lt;/p&gt;
</field>
<field name="itemdescription">
7 Bestselling Books on CD-ROM</field>
<field name="usercomment">
A paper lover's view.</field>
<field name="identifier">
0-596-00389-7</field>
</data>
</node>
