<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="21584" title="Perl 5 Pocket Reference" created="2000-07-07 21:18:00" updated="2005-08-10 15:42:47">
<type id="31670">
bookreview</type>
<author id="5177">
CMonster</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.oreilly.com/catalog/perlpr3/"&gt;Perl 5 Pocket Reference, 3rd Edition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
by &lt;a href="http://www.oreilly.com/catalog/perlpr3/author.html"&gt;Johan Vromans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.oreilly.com/"&gt;O'Reilly and Associates, 2000&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Capsule Review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excellent book. 5 stars out of 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who should be interested in this book?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anyone who flips through the index of &lt;i&gt;Programming Perl&lt;/i&gt; at least once a day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perl programmers who find themselves in Perl quandaries when away from their bookshelves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Absent-minded Perl hackers who can't remember the regex bestiary or similar details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Full Review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got the &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.oreilly.com/catalog/perlpr3/"&gt;Perl 5 Pocket Reference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; as a gift from the Perl Conference 3.0, and it's been within arm's reach at all times since. It's an invaluable reference for those who find themselves searching through perldocs or &lt;i&gt;Programming Perl&lt;/i&gt; for tidbits on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Johan Vromans cuts stacks and stacks of Perl documentation down to the most essential at-your-fingertips facts. The book is organized like a series of appendices, covering subjects like command-line options, pragmatic modules, special variables, and regular expressions. That last one is the most dog-eared and thumbed through section of my copy; it boils the sometimes-cryptic regular expression bestiary down to the essentials and is worth list price all by itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You won't learn Perl from this book. It doesn't take the place of bibles like &lt;i&gt;Programming Perl&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;i&gt;Learning Perl&lt;/i&gt;, but you'll certainly want to keep it handy if you're an absent-minded programmer like me. I use it when I can't remember the argument order for &lt;tt&gt;push&lt;/tt&gt; or the formatting codes for &lt;tt&gt;sprintf&lt;/tt&gt;, or even if I want to thumb through a list of the standard modules to jog my memory when working on a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 3rd edition has been published recently in order to cover Perl 5.6, so make sure you get the latest edition. I know I will...&lt;/p&gt;</field>
<field name="itemdescription">
</field>
<field name="usercomment">
</field>
<field name="identifier">
</field>
</data>
</node>
