<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="21811" title="Advanced Perl Programming" created="2000-07-10 16:13:35" updated="2005-08-15 03:07:06">
<type id="31670">
bookreview</type>
<author id="20500">
gryng</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;em&gt;Advanced Perl Programming&lt;/em&gt; by Sriram Srinivasan&lt;br&gt;
ISBN 1-56592-220-4&lt;br&gt;
Copyright 1997, O'Reilly &amp;amp; Associates, Inc.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Capsule Review&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Excellent book.  5 stars out of 5.
&lt;p&gt;
Who should be interested in this book?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People who have a handle on Perl and are looking to become a super-JAPH&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anyone writing production quality Perl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JAPH's interested in: Modules/Packages, OO Programming, Networking, Tk, and Embedding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Full Review&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This book starts off strong, given you the essentials on using complex datastructures in perl -- the ins and outs of using references every concievable way.  This section in itself is invaluable, as it provides plenty of examples for the initiate to learn from (because we all know references in Perl can be very ugly if done incorrectly).
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Advanced Perl Programming&lt;/em&gt; continues the book by delivering you great examples and equally good explainations.  For example there is an entire chapter devoted to the uses and intricacies of eval.  This includes using eval for shear power, eval for speed increases, and eval security issues.
&lt;p&gt;
The book covers each of the chapters completely, a list can be found here: &lt;a href="http://www.oreilly.com/catalog/advperl/toc.html"&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/a&gt;.  Overall I would highly recommend this to any would be super-JAPH.  My only persuasion against buying this book is that is is not for beginners.  Don't forget about it, but don't buy it as your first Perl book.
&lt;p&gt;
Another great one from &lt;a href="http://www.oreilly.com/"&gt;Oreilly&lt;/a&gt;!
&lt;p&gt;
Cheers,
&lt;br&gt;
Gryn
&lt;p&gt;
p.s. Sorry for the blatant html copying [splinky].</field>
<field name="itemdescription">
</field>
<field name="usercomment">
</field>
<field name="identifier">
1565922204</field>
</data>
</node>
