<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="22047" title="Effective PERL Programming" created="2000-07-10 16:45:52" updated="2005-08-10 16:42:15">
<type id="31670">
bookreview</type>
<author id="11637">
jbardhan</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
Title: Effective Perl Programming: Writing Better Programs with Perl&lt;BR&gt;
Authors: Joseph N. Hall &amp; Randal L. Schwartz&lt;BR&gt;
Publisher: Addison Wesley, 1997&lt;BR&gt;
ISBN: 0-20141-975-0&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Capsule Review&lt;/B&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;BR&gt;
Rating: 4/5&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;BR&gt;
Who would be interested in this book?&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Beginning or intermediate programmers looking to pick up some helpful tips
&lt;LI&gt;Anyone who wants to improve their PERL style
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Full Review&lt;/B&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;BR&gt;
Disclaimer:  I'm only an intermediate grade PH, not super advanced or hardcore...so
             please keep that in mind. =)
&lt;BR&gt;&lt;P&gt;
I found this book very helpful when it came to little tricks of style and efficiency.  It
reminds me a lot of Meyers' books "Effective C++" and "More Effective C++" in the size of
the tips included.  It's difficult to write a long review for a pretty short book, which
is structured into small, bite-sized pieces, so I'll keep this short
&lt;P&gt;
The book is segmented into groups of tips, from regular expressions to references, from
proper idiomatic PERL to packages, modules, and OO PERL.  The snippets of code have often
given me good insights into ways I can better solve the problems I face at work.  The
regexp section resulted in a dramatic improvement in an application I had to modify...people
were quite impressed.  For those of us who haven't the time to read lots and lots of docs
to learn all the ins and outs of regexps and data structures, this book gives good insight
into what you may know already, but not have entirely thought through to how it may be 
applied to good coding.
&lt;P&gt;
This book is not an essential piece of a PERL library, but for those of us who are still
learning new things every time we sit down and start typing, it offers a wealth of advice,
which can save a lot of time, trouble, and wasted code.  I would highly recommend that 
beginning PERL programmers at least find a friend's copy and read it through once or twice.
It is very well-written--clear and concise, technical but not overly so.</field>
<field name="itemdescription">
</field>
<field name="usercomment">
</field>
<field name="identifier">
0201419750</field>
</data>
</node>
