<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="447942" title="Perls of Wisdom" created="2005-04-14 15:48:15" updated="2005-08-14 14:26:36">
<type id="31670">
bookreview</type>
<author id="44177">
marvell</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;p&gt;For anyone who has read The Perl Journal or any of the collected
publications, you might, as I did, be mistaken to assume this is a
similar text. It's not. Yes, it is the case that each of the articles
have come from a column or magazine, but they lack the quality of TPJ
and the organisation or other volumes.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The books starts with a quick preface, and no forward. This gives you
no real idea about what's to come, who the book is for and how to use
it, though most of us know how to use books these days.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The user level of this book is advertised as Intermediate-Advanced,
but it's not. This becomes apparent very quickly in the first chapter,
entitled Advanced Perl Tutorials. Some of it is old, back as far as
1995. It's pretty basic stuff and after the Context article, we get
onto what becomes quite an unfortunate theme of the book.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Each article is verbatim from the magazine and it prepended by a few
words from Randal. These often go a long the lines of "this came out
before some module I wrote" or "I would have done it differently".
This is a shame and I wonder why it was that the articles were not
used as a basis for the book and updated to use newer modules and
improved in ways admitted.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
There's quite a lot of Finding Files type examples which wear a bit
thin, but the Object stuff is great, although not enough and I'd be
inclined to bye his other book, should that be what you want to read
about. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Chapters on Text Processing are dull, unless you've not done much of
it, HTML and XML should have been using newer modules.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then starts my least favourite part of the book. Many, if not most, of
the following articles, especially at the end of the book consists of
an explanation of a huge listing of code. It's dull, most of the code
is dull and there are some neat tricks which could have been
summarised. I must have missed some, since I could not be bothered
reading through all the dull bits. Needle in a haystack territory.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The Webmaster's Toolkit illustrates very well that these articles
should stay in the context of a magazine. Individually, and with other
things to read, you would have a go, if they were relevant, but as it
happens, they're probably not. In this way, they form a collection of
huge listings about things that might be useful to some people some
times. They probably belong in a webmaster's toolkit book, with lots
and lots more, prepended by some specific web oriented techniques. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
At the end of it all, the index is pants. I tried to find something
interesting to show someone and ended up searching the web for it
instead, since all of these articles are there somewhere.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In summary, it's not Intermediate-Advanced, it's not full of things to
learn, it's quite a dull read and you'd be better off reading the
articles in magazines and spending your money on other books. This is a
real shame because Randal Schwartz is otherwise, an excellent author.
&lt;/p&gt;
</field>
<field name="itemdescription">
</field>
<field name="usercomment">
A disappointing collection of outdated articles.</field>
<field name="identifier">
1-59059-323-5</field>
</data>
</node>
