<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="454174" title="Perl 6 Essentials" created="2005-05-04 19:38:47" updated="2005-08-11 02:57:46">
<type id="31670">
bookreview</type>
<author id="452258">
PerlBear</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
Although I would tend to agree with my fellow monks in that Perl 6 is still quite a distance off and we can only speculate on it's true final form; this book's title immediately caught my attention when passing by the computer section of Perl at my local bookstore.
&lt;BR&gt;
Here is the book's layout:&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Chapter 1 - Project Overview: "The Birth of Perl 6...."
&lt;LI&gt;Chapter 2 - Project Development: "Developement of the Language and Virtual Compiler..."
&lt;LI&gt;Chapter 3 - Design Philosophy: "Linguistic, Cognitive &amp;amp; Architectural Considerations..."
&lt;LI&gt;Chapter 4 - Syntax: "Variables, Operators, Control Structures, etc. ..."
&lt;LI&gt;Chapter 5 - Parrot Internals: "A look at the core of Parrot the virtual runtime machine...."
&lt;LI&gt;Chapter 6 - Parrot Assembly Language: "An Introduction to Parrot...'
&lt;LI&gt;Chapter 7 - Intermediate Code Compiler: "An Intro. to Parrot's Intermediate Code Compiler"
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;BR&gt;
I found that this book, in my opinion, to be true to its form; very well structured and organized. It's key strength is the use of concrete examples.  The author(s) present a particular topic then show it is finitely utilized in relevant yet simple code example.  They were even able to explain the Parrot assembly language into terms that I was able to begin to understand. Impressive. &lt;BR&gt;
Again, I realize that Perl 6 is certainly only in its early formative stages, without a doubt subject to lots of change; however, I must say that I enjoyed this book.  It gave me finite insight into the possibilites of Perl6!.
I am indeed looking forward to the &lt;A HREF="http://www.oreilly.com/catalog/059600737X/index.html"&gt;Second Edition&lt;/A&gt; of this book.&lt;BR&gt;
Enjoy the Read!</field>
<field name="itemdescription">
Authors: Allison Randall, Dan Sugalski &amp; Leopold T&amp;#246;tsch</field>
<field name="usercomment">
</field>
<field name="identifier">
</field>
</data>
</node>
