<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="507670" title="Mining the Web" created="2005-11-11 04:09:02" updated="2005-11-10 23:09:02">
<type id="31670">
bookreview</type>
<author id="305754">
sock</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
The relatively mundane title would lead one to believe that this book would only cover some of the introductory pieces of information in regard to web crawling and mining. I would like to make it very clear that the humble title leaves only hints and traces of this wonderful and clearly illustrated book.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

I would consider this less and book and more of a tome or volume of information that is absolutely necessary for anyone who wishes to seriously become involved with mining data from the web. It takes an in depth look at the principals of crawling, content repositories, indexes, searching, learning, similarity, clustering, supervised and unsupervised learning. It also goes so far as to touch applications and practical use of the covered materials. Just when you think you've covered everything, this book then continues with selections on resource discovery and future use and techniques.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

I consider this book invaluable. Not only because of its plain and simple description of theorem, but because of its concise and to the point structure and example.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

I strongly recommend that anyone who is involved with data mining of any sort buy and study this book. I'm sure that you will find it as thought provoking and helpful as I have.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

Author: Soumen Chakrabarti&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

TABLE OF CONTENTS&lt;br/&gt;
1. Introduction&lt;br/&gt;
Part 1 - Infrastructure&lt;br/&gt;
2. Crawling the Web&lt;br/&gt;
3. Web Search and Information Retrieval&lt;br/&gt;
Part 2 - Learning&lt;br/&gt;
4. Similarity and Clustering&lt;br/&gt;
5. Supervised Learning&lt;br/&gt;
6. Semisupervised Learning&lt;br/&gt;
Part 3 - Applications&lt;br/&gt;
7. Social Network Analysis&lt;br/&gt;
8. Resource Discovery&lt;br/&gt;
9. The Future of Web Mining</field>
<field name="itemdescription">
Analysis of Hypertext and Semi Structured Data</field>
<field name="usercomment">
</field>
<field name="identifier">
1558607544</field>
</data>
</node>
