<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="731783" title="Sams Teach Yourself Perl in 24 Hours" created="2008-12-20 11:30:57" updated="2008-12-20 11:30:57">
<type id="31670">
bookreview</type>
<author id="726232">
matze77</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
&lt;p&gt; Writing about: Third Edition , Language: English.&lt;br&gt;

I was a little reluctant cause i dont like this unrealistic approach in book titles like "being a guru in 2 hours".&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

Surely you will probably need more than 24 hours to work through the book (without sleeping calculated) at least if you dont think you are a genius (but then you will probably learned all solely from manpages).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

I noticed that around 2-3 hours are needed for a chapter depending on the complexity.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

I like the book cause it has many coding examples which introduce new things btw that might be useful in that context e.g.: in reviewing the if statement rand is introduced. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

The structure is good it is not too technical it reads fluently.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

At the end of each chapter is a workshop section which contains some questions and tasks to control the learned.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

Compared to the Update: &lt;strike&gt;Camel&lt;/strike&gt; Llama Book it was more useful at the first steps for me cause it has more a "practical, howto" character. The Llama book explains it all well but i miss some useful code snipets there that go beyond the surface.&lt;br&gt;

Personal Background: I am a beginner and got almost no programming experience (i did a little simple bash programming but never heard of scalars arrays e.g. before)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

I must admit that i only read&lt;strike&gt; 6 &lt;/strike&gt; 8 chapters so far, but this already really helped me alot (i maybe adjust this with more learned)...
critic:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;A drawback is that often i wanted to know more get more detailed code examples (This is the same with the Learning Perl Book from Oreilly) it is clearly a beginner book.&lt;/b&gt;but there is e.g. in the file lesson you learn how to open a file and how to close it and how to print a line of the file but not how to change content of a file and write it. I am someone who should must nsee some practical examples how to use a language like perl cause there are so many possibilities i dont sometimes know how to put it all together...&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

&lt;b&gt;I &lt;strike&gt;strongly&lt;/strike&gt; recommend this book for beginners and dont think the money wasted. But for real more detailed projects you will need other books, more knowledge than this book could provide ...&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
What i like about the book:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;The Tipp: Take a Project you learn fastet if you got a goal which you work for ... (as your own webserver with cgi e.g.)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The code segments are well explained, like line 12 does this and maybe not that what you expected cause of ...
What i dont like:&lt;br&gt;
I wished more details as already mentioned, many times i caught myself thinking ah interesting, i want to read more, then i turn the pages and ups, the chapter is over. This book could have been really good without these flaws ...&lt;br&gt; My Opinion: If you get this book 2nd hand | cheap and your new to Perl it is worth the try ...&lt;br&gt;
btw: I like the &lt;strike&gt;camel&lt;/strike&gt; Llama book too, ofc.
&lt;/p&gt;</field>
<field name="itemdescription">
Perl Book containing 24 lessons</field>
<field name="usercomment">
A Good book for Beginners</field>
<field name="identifier">
978-0672327933</field>
</data>
</node>
