<node>
  <doctext>&lt;p&gt;[ysth], 2004-10-31&lt;br /&gt;
I'm a little bothered by the idea of changing one-word-titled replies to &quot;Re^N: The Original Subject&quot;; perhaps we could just append &quot; (was: Re^N-1: The Original Subject)&quot; instead?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], 2004-10-20&lt;br /&gt;
I'm curious why [id://401006] got unapproved from [Tutorials], and moved to [Seekers of Perl Wisdom].  As a tutorial it might have been a little incomplete, but it's not a question at all.  If it needed to be moved, it might have been appropriate to move it to [Meditations], but not SoPW, ImHO. ;)  As for the need to move it out of [Tutorials], even that was unnecessary.  If someone disagrees with the usefulness of a tutoral, it just needn't be linked to the main Tutorials page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[theorbtwo], 2004-10-04&lt;br /&gt;
[The Editors' Hall of Mirrors and Trickery] will now let you re-parent nodes of types monkdiscuss perlmeditation perlquestion perltutorial CUFP poem obfuscated and perlnews.  (I'm too lazy to tell you what they are, sorry.)  (If you know of any other types that don't have dbtables other then node, document, and which you think editors should be able to reparent, let me know.  [snippet] and [sourcecode] have extra dbtables, and thus converting them to notes is more difficult, and probably best done manually (and then reassigning ownership by a [gods|god].)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Steve_p] - 2004-10-01&lt;br /&gt;
Has there been a change made that breaks the population of node titles on a reply?  There have been at least five nodes considered so far today where the title is populated with &quot;Re:&quot; only.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2004-09-23&lt;br /&gt;
I think all non-anonymous users should see all edit history.  The &quot;non-anonymous&quot; is only there to prevent robots from following the link to that information and to prevent casual users from seeing &quot;sensitive&quot; information that a janitor felt the need to remove -- which I usually consider a waste of time. :)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], 2004-09-23&lt;br /&gt;
I would favor authors being able to see the edit history, especially if [castaway] will implement it :)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2004-09-23&lt;br /&gt;
Has been a quiet month, it seems. This is an appeal to all editors. If you edit a node, &lt;b&gt;please&lt;/b&gt; leave a note at the bottom saying who did the edit and why/what. (This mini rant brought on by a complaint from [calin] that [id://392917] was edited silently). While I'm at it, this particular edit was in error. Non-wrapping of nodes/long lines in code tags is not a reason to edit, just because some browsers fail to intrepret PMs adding of soft hyphens, or some users do not have their code wrapping turned on.
&lt;p&gt;
And since it just occured to me, part of this problem could be solved by allowing authors to view edit histories of their own nodes, possibly via the node status nodelet. Any views, objections on this?
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2004-08-22&lt;br /&gt;
To chime in again, since apparently opinion is wanted: My saying 'consider it', was a knee-jerk reaction to 'can the gods delete' (or whatever the exact question was). While I don't see the delete/recreate as a terrible idea, follow-up and/or allowing 'possession' of AM posts are probably much better ways to do it. Apparently the line on the Preview page that says 'You are not logged in' needs to be 12&quot; high and in bright red, or something, since it doesnt appear to be helping.. (Shall I patch it with a bigger font or something?)
&lt;p&gt;
My point below was more: If it's already considered, and the duplicate written, then I think trying to undo all that is more trouble than its worth. And not that this method should be the best/only WTDI.
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[davido], 2004-08-22&lt;br /&gt;
I'll weigh in on [tye]'s comments.  First, I'll stand by my original comment that it's bad form to post a duplicate as a means of correcting a 'not logged in' issue.  If someone posts something anonymously on accident, live and learn; it's not serious enough to trouble the monastery with a consideration vote, and it doesn't warrant pestering the Janitors.  I'll also maintain that when we appease the behavior we enable it, or at least, legitimize it.  I certanly wouldn't want to encourage what I consider to be a bad practice by obliging the author's request just because he forced a move by double-posting.  I still believe that for this reason, and because it's what we normally do with dupes anyway, the second post (the newer duplicate) should be the one to be removed.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for [tye]'s suggestion that the OP follow up to the anonymous post with a &quot;I wrote this&quot; message, I suppose I'm ok with that.  If I considered the anonymously posted message to be worth upvoting, I guess I would probably feel good about upvoting the &quot;I posted this&quot; instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2004-08-21&lt;br /&gt;
I agree with your original points.  It is my experience that we haven't made a habit of intentionally making dupicates when people forget to log in.  I find the mess and effort involved in dealing with duplicates way not worth it (plus the relative messiness of the end result).  The tradition is to reply saying that you wrote it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], 2004-08-21&lt;br /&gt;
Great points [castaway], this is why I presented the question here.  I agree that it's unlikely that someone will try to claim an AM post that isn't theirs.  Mostly I was concerned about the double posting as a means of dealing with forgetting to log in.  It's like mamma always said, &quot;Two wrongs don't make a right.&quot;  But if the precedent is that we oblige this approach to dealing with the problem, that's fine I guess, as long as we are on the same page.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I do like the idea of allowing someone from the same IP to claim AM posts.  That's a cool notion.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2004-08-21&lt;br /&gt;
While it's true that the general policy is to keep original versions of posts, and delete following ones, I think we can make some exceptions. While its true that it is possible someone else come along, copy the post, and consider an AM post for deletion, Id like to think that a) people that get to the level where consideration is possible, wouldnt (hopeful, I know), and b) That its pretty unlikely that happen in a such short span of time (ie the time gap between the two posts would be longer, if someone other than the author did it). In fact it was me that suggested [gaal] consider it. 
&lt;p&gt;
A better solution to this, would possibly be to allow anyone from the same IP, within say 1 minute of posting, to 'claim' an AM post. While it isnt 100% sure (yes, I know about NATing etc), Id like to think we can give people the benefit of the doubt here.
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[davido], 2004-08-20&lt;br /&gt;
[gaal] considered [id://384692] for deletion, stating he posted it without being logged in.  He then double-posted the same text in [id://384696], this time logged in.  I voted 'keep' on the original anonymously posted node because I believe: (1) Not being logged in is not a reason to double post.  (2) In the event of double-posts, the general rule of thumb is to delete the newer post (the one he posted after logging in).  (3) Though I doubt this is has happened in this case, if we reinforce this practice, what's to prevent someone from copycatting [Anonymous Monk] posts in an effort to XP grab?  (4) In general, we ought to reinforce the notion that the important thing is that help was given, even if it was mistakenly anonymous.  (5) A minimal XP gain that a user might experience by correcting a 'not logged in' issue by double posting is more than offset by the amount of work it creates for others by double-posting and requesting deletion of the original.  Let's not encourage people to create extra work just so they'll get a few extra XP.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stopped short of unconsidering the original node, and considering the duplicate, because I wanted to confirm that my argument is both sound and backed up by precedent.  I think the proper course of action should be to unconsider the original, consider the duplicate for deletion (even if the original was anonymous and the duplicate wasn't), and send a friendly reminder to the person mentioning that an easy way to provide a strong visual clue about login status is to use one of the PerlMonks CSS themes.  Comments?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[demerphq], 2004-08-19&lt;br /&gt;
Unfortunately there currently isn't a lot of emphasis on previews of wikis so its easy to think that you've hit update when in fact you've only hit preview. You can tell if you've updated ok becase when you do youll see &quot;All fields updated!&quot; at the top of the page. Really a successful update should result in returning to the display view but this hasnt been done yet as its a bit tricky. (Not hard, but fiddly.) Suggestions (that are theme/css freindly for improvements are welcome.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2004-08-18&lt;br/&gt;
(Rewriting an update that didn't take from hours ago)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It thwarts simple searching for nodes that contain &quot;addendum&quot; in their titles.  It also makes no sense anywhere except when viewing a parent node in that thread.  Not show stoppers but neither am I big proponent of users' &quot;creative control&quot; on node titles, especially when they start getting creative.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I'll probably /msg the author.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[castaway] 2004-08-19&lt;br /&gt;
Me too, I voted keep. I see no reason to force titles of replies whatsoever.
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ysth] 2004-08-18&lt;br /&gt;
re: [id://383692] consideration to retitle to &quot;Re: Re: Variable use lib with taint (FindBin problem)&quot;; is there any site usability issue here?  I'm inclined to unconsider it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Chady] 2004-08-11&lt;br /&gt;
[ysth], there was a &lt;code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/code&gt; in those &lt;code&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags. I removed them. As for why they don't appear in [Tutorials], it's probably because [Tutorials] is cleaning up the html before displaying, but I'm not sure cause I didn't look at the code.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ysth], 2004-08-10&lt;br /&gt;
I added [brian_d_foy]'s CGI Troubleshooting thang to [tutorials source], but in Firefox 0.9.3 it's rendering with a blank line after it (and the following tutorial is too) in [Tutorials] but not [tutorials source].  Can anyone explain?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[davido], 2004-08-08&lt;br /&gt;
[castaway]: Thanks for testing it.  I've tried it three times now.  Each time, it correctly retitles the parent node, and leaves the children alone.  I don't see any OS-dependant code in the retitler, so I doubt that it has anything to do with the fact that I'm using Windows.  The second and third time, I was very careful to turn it loose on threads that didn't have altered titles in the children.  Perhaps I'm just not following the instructions, but it seems fairly simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2004-08-08&lt;br /&gt;
[davido], I just an my copy of the noderetitler (dated 2003-12-10), against [id://380550] and it changed all the replies just fine. I can only imagine that you tried to retitle a node in which someone had changed the title subtly while replying.. Unless it happened several times? Anyway, theres been no PM change that would affect it, so it must be something else.. 
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[davido] 2004-08-06&lt;br /&gt;
Your one 'delete' vote is irrelevant, since the node has a strongly positive reputation, and only two delete votes against 13 or so 'edit' votes.  Votes, once cast, can't be changed, but at least you can rest assured that yours had no effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[larsen] 2004-08-06&lt;br /&gt;
I voted &quot;delete&quot; by accident on [id://380424]. The actual vote was meant to be &quot;edit&quot;.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[davido], 2004-07-30&lt;br /&gt;
Hi all, it's me (*gasp!*)...&lt;br /&gt;
Has something changed with the Monastery's HTML such that the Bulk Node Retitler no longer follows threads past the root node?  I just turned it loose on [id://378775], and it only retitled that parent node.  The rest of the nodes in the thread didn't get retitled.  ...perhaps I used it wrong, but I then had to just go manually update all the titles in the rest of the thread.  I'm pretty sure that's not what the retitler is meant to do. ;)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2004-07-30&lt;br /&gt;
Exactly.. There are several possible actions, when pondering considerations:&lt;br /&gt; 
1. Fix it as considered, I usually do this if I agree strongly, or the voting has gone that way enough for me to consider it a majority.. (Which depends on the action/consideration, so I cant give numbers). &lt;br /&gt;
2. Unconsider: If theres been little voting at all on an older consideration, or the results are tied, or I just plain disagree (like considerations to delete non-dupes, or edit for spelling etc), I unconsider, and if I remember, I make a note at the bottom of the node saying what it was considered as, the voting, and why I unconsidered.(with any luck this will be replaced by a consider-history some day ,)&lt;br /&gt;
3. Do nothing. Never forget this is always an option.. If I dont disagree/agree enough to edit/unconsider, then I leave it for someone else to ponder. Things in this category may jump into #2 if they stay around long enough..&lt;br /&gt;
Recently Ive been known to message considerers, if I see them repeatedly considering things with useless texts.. (One actually answered, that his opinion was, one should consider-away, and the editors would dump any considerations they dont like.. I managed to explain that just makes us a lot more work..)
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2004-07-29&lt;br /&gt;
I vote &quot;keep&quot;, /msg the considerer, and unconsiderer after a couple of days (if required).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth] 2004-07-29&lt;br /&gt;
I'm seeing a number of considerations recently for fairly minor stuff that somewhat improve the readability of nodes but aren't really site-usability issues (correcting spelling of title words that are unlikely to be searched for, code tags instead of &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;'d lines with no problem characters, removing &amp;lt;br&amp;gt; from within &amp;lt;code&amp;gt;, rescoping code tags to not include text paragraphs).  These feel overly intrusive to me, at least for
non-anonymous nodes; seems like just /msg'ing the author and leaving it up to them would be much preferred.  Anyone else have the same reaction?  If so, what can be done?  (Should my question be a PMD?)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Chady] 2004-07-28&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;...made no substantial changes to node content...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
I don't see that being a point either, since anyone (not only janitors) can edit their node &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; alter contents that would eventually influence the node rep.
&lt;p&gt;I don't think janitors can abuse their powers on their own nodes. They can, OTOH, abuse their power by editing other people's nodes. The only way power can be abused on one's nodes is probably deleting a node that's gaining lots of negative reputation, but since that requires the approval of 3(?) janitors, it's not even an issue. Or am I missing some hidden powers that janitors have? :)

&lt;p&gt;[ybiC] 2004-07-27&lt;br /&gt;
I see no problem with your action in this specific case, as you only corrected a problem in where your node was posted, and presumably made no substantial changes to node content and did nothing which would unfairly influence the node's reputation. &amp;nbsp; [ysth|/you]++ for full disclosure. &amp;nbsp; 8^)
&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], 2004-07-26&lt;br /&gt;
I did use editorial powers; I reparented it from where I'd accidentally created it to under the root node of the same thread.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[theorbtwo], 2004-07-26&lt;br /&gt;
I don't see a problem with applying your normal moderation powers to your own nodes.  I do see a problem with applying your editorial powers, but that's not what you did, so you're in the clear.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], 2004-07-25&lt;br /&gt;
In the ex post facto department:&lt;br /&gt;
I just posted a note in the wrong place and moved it myself; is there any procedural reason for not doing for myself what I would do on request for anyone else?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2004-07-23&lt;br /&gt;
For what it's worth, I approve.  Thank you, [ybiC].
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ybiC] 2004-07-23&lt;br /&gt;
For the record, I unconsidered the following nodes, as they've all been sitting in [nodes to consider|NTC]/[nodes requiring editing|NRE] for several days with significant vote dissention and relatively minor consideration causes. &amp;nbsp; Personally, I've become less inclined to retitle nodes when the original nodetitle is not completely offbase. &amp;nbsp; But that's just my opinion, worth exactly what you paid for it.
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[id://375347] &amp;nbsp; [cchampion] EDIT - change ownership to cchampion - I forgot to log-in :-( &amp;nbsp; edit:23 keep:9 del:0
  &lt;li&gt;[id://375245] &amp;nbsp; [arden] retitle: problems with PAR arguments &amp;nbsp; edit:25 keep:5 del:1
  &lt;li&gt;[id://374896] &amp;nbsp; [PodMaster] EDIT - retitle &quot;pl2bat and drag and drop&quot; &amp;nbsp; edit:26 keep:7 del:0
  &lt;li&gt;[id://374233] &amp;nbsp; [Arunbear] Edit title - mark as Off Topic &amp;nbsp; edit:40 keep:12 del:3
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2004-06-30&lt;br /&gt;
I'm a little surprised that a [janitor] is out of touch with the current workings of such things.  The author &lt;b&gt;does&lt;/b&gt; have access to update the node.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And I think the breach of protocol means that the pendulum must swing back and we must tread extra lightly in honoring your request.  In other words, you have brought this upon yourself and we'll now have to give due process &lt;b&gt;extra&lt;/b&gt; time to run its course.  So, I think you just need to sit and wait for a reply/reaction to come from the node author for a reasonable amount of time.  A day or two seems reasonable to me in normal situations.  I think we need to allow more time for this specific case, though I sincerely hope such won't be required.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;
Understood, and for which I now humbly apologize.  &lt;b&gt;Now&lt;/b&gt;, can we get back to the matter at hand?
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The second sentence makes the first sound like lip service.  I find the more important matter at hand to not be your minor embarrassment due to your e-mail becoming public.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And I can't let &quot;harboring criminals&quot; pass.  I'd think [merlyn|you] would have some awareness of the distinction of &lt;em&gt;criminal&lt;/em&gt; law and the difference between accusation and conviction.  Despite due process, some people still get wrongly convicted (which is what I believe happened to you).  I'd think your experience would make you shy to label someone a &quot;criminal&quot; without due process or to deny or rush that due process.  Let's give the author a chance to contribute their side to the story and probably resolve the problem without the need for administrative action.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I've got to get back to my day job, so I'll stop here, even though I think there much room for improvement as to clarity and completeness of my entry above.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[merlyn] 2004-06-30&lt;br /&gt;
Understood, and for which I now humbly apologize.  &lt;b&gt;Now&lt;/b&gt;, can we get back to the matter at hand?  Since I'm reclusing myself from actual edit, I beseech upon the &lt;i&gt;other&lt;/i&gt; MFWIC to please correct the manner in which I've been wronged, and edit the node to remove my private email content, recalling of course that the original poster does not have the power to do this himself, and yet has
already been informed of his direct violation of my copyright.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[dws] 2004-06-30&lt;br /&gt;
Janitors are somewhat akin to judges. Issues come before us, and we deal with them. Sometimes we take unilateral action, but that's mostly for formatting cleanup and title typo correction.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
To avoid a conflict of interest--which is what we seem to have here--Judges are expected to recuse themselves when they're a party to an action that comes before them. When a judge takes unilateral action on an issue to which they're a party, the process is corrupted, and people lose confidence in the process.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Absent explicit permission from the original poster to edit the post, this should have been punted to another editor. There are plenty of us.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[merlyn] 2004-06-30&lt;br /&gt;
I had already made the request directly of the person.  However, as the person is an initiate, they will not have the power to edit their own node immediately, nor probably understand that they can write the [editors] to have it changed.
&lt;p&gt;
The issue is not my email address. The issue is one of principal: taking private email and making it public.  I don't get to do that.  You don't get to do that.  He did that, and I raise issue with that.  In particular, my answer was meant for private consumption only, and looks weird in a public forum.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[demerphq] 2004-06-30&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As I am the newest god and essentially on probation I do not feel I have the authority to take the action you request. As soon as another god is online and we have something approaching a quorum a decision will be made.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I consider it disingenuous to complain about the email address as a search on google shows zillions of hits against it. Have you asked google to remove all of their cached copies of it? And not ever post it again? And frankly right now I think you are doing your reputation a lot more harm by your response and follow up than the OP did by posting the mail. I think you should rethink your position on this.  
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I originally made comments here about copyright that may have been construed as site policy. I am not entitled to make such comments based on my junior level and as such I removed them. Whether you hold copyright on this material is not for me to ascertain. However my highly personal feeling is that &lt;i&gt;if&lt;/i&gt; you do its the kind of scenario where the court would award a 1 cent award, with no costs.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Still on a personal level I really think the best solution is for you to retract your request and /msg the poster and ask him to remove it. It certainly would be the only way in my eyes for you to emerge from this situation with your dignity intact.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[merlyn] 2004-06-03&lt;br /&gt;
Well, not to quibble [castaway], but there &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a notion of &quot;compilation copyright&quot;.  If I republish materials from others, I can claim copyright to the resulting amalgamation.  Of course, if the material I re-use is challenged, I have no right to the compilation either, but that isn't the case here.
&lt;p&gt;
So, in this case, it is the expression of the entire mail to which I claim copyright.  The way I quoted
his remarks, the way I quoted &quot;perldoc -f sort&quot;, and the short answers that I gave.  I claim copyright 2004, Randal L Schwartz, republishing rights hereby NOT given, on that exact artistic expression, both as original material, and as a compilation copyright.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2004-06-30, &lt;br /&gt;
Can you detail which parts you are claiming copyright on, exactly? The entire email, as it was sent by you? the parts you wrote? As was said earlier, if a claim is made, it will be dealt with. I believe tye was referring to the quoted parts of the email, that the OP clearly orginally wrote, to which you cannot claim copyright, as they were merely quoted by you. (Just as he cannot claim any rights to the parts you wrote.)
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[merlyn] 2004-06-30&lt;br /&gt;
OK, I admit, bad judgement call.  But what is the precedent this is now setting?
We are going to permit blatent confirmed copyright violations &lt;i&gt;persist&lt;/i&gt; in a node?
So this site &lt;i&gt;now harbors criminals&lt;/i&gt;?  C'mon.  There's got to be a policy here that permits
such items to be dealt with swiftly.
&lt;p&gt;
And I don't agree with [tye] that the node holder holds a copyright as a right that trumps the
original copyright holder (me).  Otherwise, I could simply publish an MP3 here and say &quot;but &lt;i&gt;I&lt;/i&gt; now hold the copyright&quot;.  That's crazy talk.
&lt;p&gt;
So, I now make a plea to the MFWIC here.  That message is a copyrighted message, and is being
republished without my permission.  I request strongly that swift action be taken to preserve my
copyright before &lt;i&gt;more&lt;/i&gt; damage is created.  I have that right under the DMCA (as much as you might hate it, it's still the law).
&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion] 2004-06-30&lt;br /&gt;I'm in the Bad Judgement crowd here. The same reasons why nobody can/should approve/frontpage their nodes apply to editing nodes which &quot;relate&quot; to the janitor in question. &lt;i&gt;Don't do it&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2004-06-30&lt;br /&gt;
Ah, so it's like finding the failure reason in JCL output.  I didn't see the needle [merlyn] left behind in the haystack.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I expect janitors to respect other people's words.  I expect a janitor to respect other people's words &lt;b&gt;even more&lt;/b&gt; when those words are personally detrimental to that janitor.  A janitor deleting stuff that they shouldn't is a big deal to me, but it will happen from time to time.  A janitor deleting stuff due to a personal motivation is not something I think should be tolerated in the least.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
We don't even allow [merlyn] to approve his own nodes, because it is so easy to have a blind spot to your own words / issues.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And I agree with [theorbtwo] that copyright &lt;b&gt;(update:&lt;/b&gt;probably&lt;b&gt;)&lt;/b&gt; isn't a valid point in this.  If [merlyn] owns copyright to stuff he deleted (most of which was quoted bits [merlyn] merely copied in an e-mail), then the node author certainly owns copyright to the bits of [merlyn]'s e-mail that were quoted in the node, which is a creative work produced by the node author and one that [merlyn] selfishly defaced.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Had it not been [merlyn] self-enforcing his own perceived copyright, but someone else('s), then I'd think it was a serious matter to deal with.  But the extremely poor judgement (IMO, obviously) of censoring people for personal gain isn't something that I think is compatible with janitorial power.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I'm also tired of the mindset that any claim of copyright violation requires immediate janitorial removal of text.  If [merlyn]'s lawyer had sent a cease-and-desist order, then I'd support removing material pending the outcome of any legal action the &lt;b&gt;two sides&lt;/b&gt; chose to pursue.  The law certainly doesn't require anything more/faster than that (and I've repeatedly said that I think doing much more is likely to be worse from a legal standpoint for PerlMonks).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I think everyone will be better off if less swift, less decisive action were the rule.  In this case (as in most cases), complaining would be a good first step (/msg the author and/or reply).  When this has been done, content has almost(?) always been removed voluntarily.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth] 2004-06-30&lt;br /&gt;
[tye], [merlyn] &lt;b&gt;did&lt;/b&gt; leave a trace: he put in {copyrighted private email used without permission removed by merlyn} where the email had been.  The scenario as I see it: copyrighted material was inappropriately included in a node; the rightsholder got upset; an editor removed the material immediately and then left a note on this wiki inviting feedback.  I can see feeling things should have gone somewhat differently, but think you might be overreacting just a little.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Chady] 2004-06-30&lt;br /&gt;
regarding [id://370652], it's not very hard to edit. please look at [pad://Chady] I left out the email part until it is resolved.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2004-06-29&lt;br /&gt;
I find that the act shows a significant lack of understanding about what is and isn't proper for a janitor.  I'd rather [merlyn] undo it and resign from [janitors] and then ask someone else to make a more appropriate response to his complaint.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Single-handedly (without even consulting anyone, it appears) deleting a significant part of a node and &lt;b&gt;leaving no trace&lt;/b&gt; for the public to be able to figure what the heck happened...  Well, I just don't know what to say.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[theorbtwo] 2004-06-30 (can't sleep)&lt;br /&gt;
If we had gotten a copyright chalange from an outsider, one of us would have delt with it immediatly, yes... but we didn't.  We got one from you, or rather, we would have, if you hadn't delt with it yourself.  I'd have rather you asked another editor to do it, on the theory that you should never sit in judgement of yourself, but that's neither here nor there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Style note: It's normal to put, at the very bottom, your editors signature, so that it's obvious it's been edited, not to put gunk in the body of the node which lowers readablilty (which was horribly low to begin with).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a personal note, I'm appalled that you'd consider trying to yank this (and doing so -- I'm not going to override it).  It's the contents of perldoc -f sort, his text, and seven words of text by you.  It probably doesn't meet the minimum standard of copyrightability.  Not only that, but you removed significant parts of the text that you did not have copyright intrest in: the [doc://sort|sort docs] and the mail to which you replied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[merlyn] 2004-06-29&lt;br /&gt;
OK, I felt a little weird, but I removed &lt;b&gt;my private email published without permission&lt;/b&gt;
from [id://370652].  I figure if we'd gotten a copyright challenge from an outsider, one of us would
have had to deal with it immediately anyway.  This would have been the flow.  But yell at me if
you must.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2004-06-29&lt;br /&gt;
I don't think [id://370652] is a job for a janitor. I don't see much useful change to that node w/o major rewrite, which isn't something we should do.  The most I think makes sense is putting the whole thing in a READMORE with a note like &amp;quot;Unformatted node awaiting major revisions to be done by node author&quot;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It isn't like preview didn't show all of that garbage to them.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[castaway] 2004-06-24&lt;br /&gt;
Mission accepted.&lt;br /&gt;
293 nodes assimilated with missing /small tag.&amp;lt;br /&gt;
Update code written and deployed on pmdev server for test, results: good.&lt;br /&gt;
Deployment on perlmonks server imminent.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Petruchio] 2004-06-19&lt;br /&gt;
Greetings.  [Jenda] has, for some time now, had an unclosed 'small' tag in his signature.  He has now
fixed it, but many of his posts remain somewhat broken.  I'm looking for volunteers; your mission is:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send out a small reconnaissance team, and determine the extent of the damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploy an elite force, armed with &lt;code&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags for tactical insertion.
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surgical strike.  In, out, nobody notices until it's too late.  If you're caught, we deny knowledge
of your existence.  Good luck.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jeffa] 2004-06-14&lt;br /&gt;
I just unconsidered [id://366409] because, even though the title could be written better, it contains
the words PHP, perl, and faster ... that's plenty for searching. I feel that changing this title would
be the same as changing the content. The standings at time of unconsideration were 6 keep, 16 edit, and
one delete.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[castaway] 2004-06-13&lt;br /&gt;
Going by current standard policy, they should be restored. I assume it was an act of annoyance rather than they contained information he/she/it didnt want to be seen. One could ask, if possible. (Theres resuurection of nuked/reaped nodes, not of wiped ones I believe). Yes, the edit history currently ONLY tracks editors changes, not ones by the user themselves, as its only done as part of the displaytype=editors process. Its in the works to change it.. 
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Corion] 2004-06-13&lt;br /&gt;
[baruch] wiped all his nodes clean - what is the stance on this - should they be restored? My opinion is in favour of restoral, as [baruch] participated in some discussions and contributed some answers. If I am the one to do the restoration, I guess copying from [thepen]s cache would be the way to go for me, but I don't know if the [gods] have some technique of mass-ressurection for wiped nodes.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On a related note, the edit history for these nodes does not show edits by the owning user - is this intentional, a bug or a result of the Way Things Are? Should it be changed?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[vroom] 2004-06-03&lt;br /&gt;
[tye] I'm glad to hear you're working on an approval rewrite.  I think that will be a big help from a performance standpoint.  Any estimation on when you think that could be ready to roll out?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2004-06-02&lt;br /&gt;
I was thinking of something similar, was attempting to test/get moderation nodelet running, before actually expanding on it.
&lt;p&gt;
I don't see exactly what having nodes defaul to approved gets us, at least in terms of people considering them for reaping? Did you mean that'll just give them another thing to consider for, and they'll stop considering for reaping less? I'm not sure I agree that it'll have that effect. I didn't know there was a problem with nodes not gettign approved. It won't do any harm that I can think of though, either. (Any 'offensive'/illegal posts will then show up immediately on SoPW etc, but I cant say we've had all too many of those, anyway.
&lt;p&gt;
I like the idea of 'disapproval' for any and all nodes, where disapproved ones don't show up in sections, give warnings when answered, maybe are listed somewhere extra instead of [Newest Nodes], an explicit setting needs to be set to show disapproved replies.. etc. pp. hmm.. 
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2005-06-02&lt;br /&gt;
I'd just add a comment field to the approval history table.  I had already written the code so that approval, disapproval, and moves would get logged there.  It would be easy to add a record there when a consideration is resolved (and require editors to include some 'reason' text that gets logged there or else the 'unconsider' checkbox just complains -- and fill in some canned text for auto reaping).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Also, I'm convinced that we should just have nodes be &quot;approved&quot; by default and let people consider and vote if they want a note dis-/un-approved.  This will allow busybodies to &lt;b&gt;do something&lt;/b&gt; about off-topic or &lt;em&gt;whatever&lt;/em&gt; nodes they don't like without trying to have them reaped, it removes the problem of nodes not getting approved, might get more people paying attention to front-paging.  And disapproval would be an option for non-root nodes as well (where it would discourage people if they try to reply).  So, consider this a pre-announcement to get feedback before I consider writing a PMD on it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
FYI, a big reason for the approval rewrite (besides fixing just a ton of bugs -- and none of this is in use yet) was so that efficient SQL can be used to find the nodes to display on the front page and main section pages.  The section display pages are horribly inefficient right now (and only let you navigate back in time 300 nodes even though some of them load tens of thousands of records each time they run).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion] 2005-06-02&lt;br /&gt;
In absence of the Consideration History, I think this approach is good enough. The user could still edit that history by editing the node content, but such is life.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[castaway] 2005-06-02&lt;br /&gt;
Hey all! [id://356772|this node] gets the dubious honour of being guinea pig for something it just occured to me to do.. In the abscense of a 'unconsider reason' field, I've written the consider/unconsider reasons together with the voting at the time at the bottom of the node I unconsidered.
&lt;p&gt;
Any opinions on this?
&lt;p&gt;
In the meantime, Im still looking at getting the consideration code to do this, scratchpads distracted me a bit, as is figuring out [tye]s new Moderation Nodelet and surrounding code, but we'll get there, I hope.. In case anyones wondering, the Moderation Nodelet is a refactor of the existing consideration code, which changes the internal mechanism for marking nodes as Approved and Front-Paged. It also allows Editors to un-Approve, thus hopefully getting rid of the 'Un-Approve and move' problems..
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[castaway] 2005-05-18&lt;br /&gt;
I completely agree. Editor's delete, if used &lt;i&gt;at all&lt;/i&gt; should be reserved for 1) deleting absolute duplicates, although that also isnt really necessary, and 2) deleting &lt;strike&gt;offensive&lt;/strike&gt; illegal nodes. Nothing else. Also I get annoyed at people mentioning such in the CB at all. Theres no call for it, since there is hardly ever any hurry to get rid of a node at all. (The only exception being illegal ones)
&lt;p&gt;
Anyway, I'll be looking into considerations etc, with a view to implementing some of [Consideration overhaul?].. 
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Corion] 2005-05-18&lt;br /&gt;
[jdporter&amp;#93; rallied to get Editorial Delete votes on [id://354215]. Personally, I think that this node should be kept at least for the following formal reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The node has replies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is a consideration in process, and the voting does not indicate any preference yet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The node content also does not indicate direct harm to individuals, the website or other entities that janitors should protect in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The consideration itself seems wrong to me as well, but even a reaped node is just hidden from sight and thus the harm is small, relatively speaking, as a Editorial Delete seems still to erase the data from the database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussion of this topic is much wanted - maybe I'm completely off-base and the quality of the crack I found on the toilet was diminished by my lacing it with LSD...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[vroom] 2004-05-04&lt;br /&gt;
I've added [Steve_p] at his request to [janitors].  Please join me in welcoming him to the group.  I've pointed him to he Editor's Guidlines and this wiki to familiarize himself with how the group works.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2004-05-04&lt;br /&gt;
The HTML nesting patch fixes this problem.  It will eventually become manditory and you won't have to worry about this.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Petruchio] 2004-05-04&lt;br /&gt;
Something to keep in mind:  you should not put strings of hyphens inside HTML comments
([http://www.w3.org/TR/html401/intro/sgmltut.html#idx-HTML|reference]).  Consecutive hyphens in comments
should be construed as markup, and they tend to cause problems which you may not be apparent on your browser.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So when you're autographing an edit, remember not to say something like:
&lt;code&gt;&lt;!-- This may comment out the rest of the page. --Petruchio --&gt;&lt;/code&gt;.  
I noticed this in [Tutorials], by the way, where there remain numerous examples.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[BazB] 2004-05-03&lt;br /&gt;
Goto the [Editor's Hall of Mirrors and Trickery] - the &quot;ehomat&quot; link in the Editor's Nodelet and do the obvious :-)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter] 2004-04-03&lt;br/&gt;
According to [id://61460], it is possible for [janitors] to reparent notes.
Is this true?  I've read elsewhere that only [gods] can do it.
If [janitors] can do it, where is the process documented?&lt;br/&gt;
Thanks...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[castaway] 2004-03-31&lt;br /&gt;
Just for info, I just unconsidered [id://340870] despite the high 'edit' vote. [davido] expressly requested it not be tutorialised, and I was also of the opinion he would have written a faqlet, had he meant to. I'm wondering if 'promote to tutorials' shouldnt become a 'thing of the past', since tutorials can be created directly anyway.. (As I understand it)
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;/me waits for [tye]s new approval code... &lt;/i&gt; ,)
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[castaway] 2004-03-05&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks for the comments, I'll get to summarising/suggesting on PMD at the weekend.
&lt;p&gt;
Something slightly different, I realised that we still don't have anything resembling 'guide to editing for new editors' (oops, janitors, whatever), so I put together a little something. I'd appreciate feedback, anything I've forgotten, mis-represented, left unclear, etc. Note these are supposed to be guidelines only, not rules!
&lt;p&gt;
[http://desert-island.dynodns.net/perl/perlmonks/editorsguidelines.txt|Editor's guidelines] (No HTML formatting as yet..)
&lt;p&gt;
This'll hopefully end up as a faqlet, and get linked from the editors nodelet. 
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[dvergin] 2004-03-03&lt;br /&gt;
I find [castaway]'s suggestions about consideration quite interesting. What follows is all about usability (not ease of implementation).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Structuring things so that *informed* consideration is more likely has some real appeal. But we need not stop with dropping buttons and a snippet from the [Nodes to Consider] page. Imagine a &quot;Look at and Consider This Node&quot; link on the NTC page that took you to that page (as [castaway] suggests). While there you can use the Approval Nodelet to cast your vote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But wait! Why go back to [Nodes to Consider] to find the next considered node. What if there were a &quot;Next Considered Node&quot; link &lt;i&gt;right there in the Consideration Nodelet&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, we might even consider the [Nodes to Consider] page unnecessary. We could just always have a &quot;Next Consideration&quot; link in the Consideration Nodelet. If there were Considered nodes I had not voted on, there would be an asterisk next to those words (as happens with other Consideration/Editor/PmDev things that need my attention).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Every time I clicked that link it would take me to the next considered node. When I had voted on everything currently pending, the asterisk would disappear. I like it. But implementation may be non-trivial.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2004-03-03&lt;br /&gt;
Re: [id://333302] - Someone please tell me what is OT about using the [cpan://XML::XSL] module? I know the question is short, but.. I have a feeling some people are being far too hasty, and still think my suggestions below should be given some consideration ,) - In fact I'll probably post them to PMD, unless anyone objects. (And ponder an implementation)&lt;p&gt;
Addendum:&lt;br /&gt;
After a short discussion with [theorbtwo]: Our biggest problem in this seems to be peoples differing opinions on what constitutes OT, 'a perl question' and so on. He just suggested the criteria should not be 'perl or not perl' but 'interesting or not interesting', which is just as much a matter of personal opinion.&lt;p&gt;
Anyway, another suggestion from me: I think (anyone got any evidence?), that some people just go through [Nodes to Consider] and vote quickly, without looking if the consideration actually applies. So maybe the voting buttons there should disappear, maybe also the actual consideration text, to stop people being pre-.. whatsit, when they go to the actual node. (Or even not let people ever see at all, why it has been considered, just that it has. ) - make them go to the node, or, get rid of NTC altogether, and people then only vote on nodes they go to look at, either to read or consider themselves. NTC would then be just a list of IDs..
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[castaway], 2004-02-26&lt;br /&gt;
[tye]++ (If this were a node..)&lt;br /&gt;
We've had several suggestions to try and improve the amount of slightly off-topic nodes, the one I liked was a new header piece of some sort at the top of [The Monastery Gates] which points to what PM is about, where to post, links to the bottom of [Seekers of Perl Wisdom] etc.
&lt;p&gt;
The difficult bit is the anti-version of this, how to persuade considerers not to consider, or to think a while before doing so. One idea that just popped into my head is the 'think a while' method, which would consist of disabling the consideration box until a while after the node has been created. Editors could of course still edit directly. (This method is practiced in some army, I forget where, where any complaints against fellow soldiers are not allowed to be voiced on the same day, but need to be 'slept on', to see if they were really worth it.) an hour or two would probably do it. Another way would be to create consideration types, and just keep the text field for certain ones, like title change suggestions, dupes would just have a box in which a node id can be entered, and nothing else, etc. Types suggestions: delete, OT, duplicate, edit (formatting), retitle ... and then restrict certain ones to X hours after node creation (OT, delete). It's more complicated, and more restrictive, but would probably reduce the amount of unconsidering, and agonising over whether to actually do what has been considered.
&lt;p&gt;
Well, that was my inspiration for today - mebbe we should move it to PMD.
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[theorbtwo], 2004-02-26&lt;br /&gt;
Err... metoo?  Seriously, this would make very good [pmdiscuss] fodder.  (And I won't do it this time, even if you say &quot;go ahead&quot;.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2004-02-26&lt;br /&gt;
To me, reaping a node is a &lt;b&gt;big deal&lt;/b&gt; and not something that should be done unless there is a very good reason with a bright line marking off that reason.  Perhaps you (the reader) don't consider it censorship, but I'm sure many do.  It certainly has a lot in common with censorship.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
There is absolutely no reason to avoid reaping duplicates (and lots of good reasons to do it).  I have no problem even with *nuking* duplicates, provided sufficient time has passed since the duplicate become clearly labeled as a duplicate (probably by being reaped).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&quot;Is this a duplicate?&quot; is a pretty bright line.  The closest case to the line is an exact duplicate of a root node that happens with a wide separation of time and on purpose (to re-ask the question in hopes of getting a better response).  And I don't consider that a duplicate.  The wide separation in time means that the node should be preserved so that the context of the conversation makes sense.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Nearly everything else is something I don't want to reap except for rare and extreme cases.  Reaping was created in order to deal with abuse (and duplicates).  Using it for non-abuse is a bad idea.  It doesn't fit.  It is the wrong tool.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&quot;Off-topic&quot; is a very blury line.  Reaping should not be done based on blury lines.  It should be extremely rare for one person to see value in a node that got reaped.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The current moderation system doesn't have the right tool for off topic nodes.  &quot;Don't&quot; is a pretty good fit in many respects (don't approve such, don't reply to such, don't post such yourself, don't encourage others to...) but it isn't enough for several reasons.  One big reason is that people have a need to *do* something.  If you think a node is off-topic, it is very unsatisfying to deal with this via *lack* of action.  There are other reasons, as well.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Further, I find many nodes that were considered off-topic to be absolutely on-topic.  Not only is this line blury, but it is pretty easy for one person (or many people) to see absolutely no Perl in a node when another sees a whole lot of Perl.  This is especially true when people are going out *looking for* off-topic nodes.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If the hunt for off-topic nodes continues (which it probably will and I'm not saying this is a bad thing -- I find it a mixed blessing), then, IMO, there will be nodes that get voted by consensus as being off-topic that turn out to be *provably* on-topic.  Sometimes it is easy to overlook the Perl that really is in the question.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
PerlMonks is not usenet.  We don't have a sister site for SQL questions nor for algorithm questions, so it is more than fine to have questions on PerlMonks about using SQL with Perl or discussing generic algorithms in the context of Perl or even discussing the work environment that many Perl programmers deal with, etc.  I *want* to see these questions and I want to see them *here*.  PerlMonks is a great site for Perlers.  And most Perlers benefit from discussions of topics related to Perl that aren't just Perl.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Even a question that (appears, to you) to be *only* about SQL, is often a good question for PerlMonks.  It will often be interesting, informative, or otherwise helpful to no small number of members, will probably end up touching on Perl and explaining the SQL issue in the context of Perl.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Should we discourage such?  Certainly.  We don't want to become better at answering SQL questions than some SQL site and steal all of their traffic.  We want to keep our focus.  And it gets worse if it is an SQL question in the context of Java or PHP and not Perl.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So we need a way to discourage such. IMHO, it need only be (and should only be) a fairly nuanced shove:  a way for the community to vote that a node is off-charter and so can't be approved for any section and you get told why you shouldn't be replying to it if you try to reply to it.  It should also make such nodes less visible for those who haven't specifically asked to see such.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Until we get that, we'll limp along with &quot;don't&quot; and downvote and rant and consider (even though it probably won't get reaped in the end -- so far anyway and I hope that holds up; the fact that a node has been considered should have *some* chilling effect on it) and mark as 'OT' and the occasional reap...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I don't know what a &quot;useless rant&quot; is.  If someone feels strongly enough to rant, then there is a good chance that there is some use to it.  We've had *way* off-topic rants turn into fairly big, fairly flamey fests.  In such cases, reaping has often made things worse.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And I've seen a surprising number of what I considered pretty tame jokes get considered as trolls.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So I don't want to reap rants and I only want to reap *egregious* trolls that are also offensive.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And, to answer [ybiC]'s original question, I don't &quot;mind&quot; off-topic nodes on PerlMonks much because I hardly ever see any.  Usually the ones I see that I consider off-topic are replies, and I have little trouble ignoring them.  The degree of off-topicness in root nodes does not appear to be worsening to me.  And I don't notice any problematic repeat offenders posting off-topic questions repeatedly.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[dvergin] 2004-02-24&lt;br/&gt;
For me, the issue of how to handle OT nodes is informed by our notions of the social dynamics of PM. When I try to draw the line between acceptable OTality and posts that are over the line, I am helped by considering the issue in the light of PM's need for focus *and* friendliness. That seems to require on-going firm-but-gentle vigilence and sensitivity. I'm an old softy and I tend to be a bit permissive, but I readily admit that we need to keep focus and specificity so that we can fulfill our &quot;mission&quot; and not drift off to become EverythingMonks. I am satisfied that the &quot;hard liners&quot; and we &quot;softies&quot; do a pretty good job of keeping each other in check. We'll miss the mark from time to time and have to reconsider, but that goes with the territory.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter] 2004-02-24 0324Z&lt;br/&gt;
I'm certainly in favor of reaping nodes which are truly off topic; useless rants and trolls fall in
this category.  IMHO the gray area -- where &quot;reasonable monks can disagree&quot;, apparently -- is in the
permissibility of nodes which are not overtly perl related, but could latently be.  IMHO, it is not
OT for PM for a node to ask how to do a whois search (e.g.).  I don't believe an OP has to include
the &quot;perl&quot; buzzword in the post in order for the consequent thread to be perl-centric.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ybiC] 2004-02-23&lt;br /&gt;
I've heard, on occasion, other monks opine that they don't mind most OT posts. &amp;nbsp; I respect &lt;i&gt;(yet most often disagree)&lt;/i&gt; with these opinions. &amp;nbsp; But my point in wiki-ing this is that I've yet to hear *why* said monks feel the way they do. &amp;nbsp; In voiceing my own general opinion against OT posts here at PM, I strive to explain the rationale behind my thinking. &amp;nbsp; For those who feel that OT posts should not be actively discouraged, please share with us logical thought processes behind those feelings.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[theorbtwo] 2004-02-21 (His sister's birthday.)&lt;br/&gt;
I tend to disagree with many OT considerations as well, but that's my personal oppion, and not my editorial or godly oppinion -- take it as you will.  One important thing to remember about reaping such nodes is that the original author's /msgonreply setting no longer matters -- they are no longer the author of the node in question, [NodeReaper] is.  (They are also divorced from any ++s or --s on the node.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
IMnsHO, there is almost never a reason to reap a node for offtopicnes, only to modify it's title.  The exception is for nodes that aren't about perl and are about something strongly not-perl, and for nodes where the /poster/ clearly knew that it wasn't about perl.  For example, javascript questions fall in to both categories.  OTOH, questions that the poster thinks are about perl, but are really about apache, fall into neither, and probably should get a (OT) in the title, at  worst.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter] 2004-02-21&lt;br/&gt;
I am in agreement with [BazB]. It doesn't make sense to me to consider a node for deletion
but contribute to its thread anyway.  And in at least some cases, the node was (IMHO) not
as off topic as was suggested.  I have unconsidered in cases like this.  Beyond that, what
can be done?  I suppose [Abigail-II|Abigail]'s posts could be fed to the [NodeReaper|shredder] as trollish...
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ybiC] 2004-02-21&lt;br /&gt;
Hmmm... I tend to agree with m(any|ost) of [Abigail-II]'s &quot;not perl&quot; considerations, if not with his presentation or demeanor. &amp;nbsp; There's a literal plethora of other places on the 'Net to ask not-Perl questions, so I see no reason to accept them here at Perl monks. &amp;nbsp; Of course, as some monks see not-Perl posts as a problem, we must ensure that any &quot;solution&quot; doesn't generate greater problems than the orginal problem. &amp;nbsp; A key point to remember is that, unlike nuked nodes, reaped nodes *are* still accessible. &amp;nbsp; That is to say, undue censorship has not &lt;i&gt;(necessarily)&lt;/i&gt; taken place.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My thoughts, worth exactly what you paid for'em. &amp;nbsp; 8^)
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[BazB] 2004-02-20&lt;br /&gt;
I'm getting kinda bored of seeing [Abigail-II] leap in on off-topic posts, considering them and ranting at the OP.
In [id://180874], [footpad] suggests nodes should not be considered unless they are so offtopic there is no chance someone could implement some kind of solution in Perl.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

I've not msg'ed [Abigail-II] yet, but I'm tempted to just unconsider the posts and move on. Comments?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[Corion] 2004-02-07&lt;br /&gt;
I think what I meant is 25% of the cast votes:
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;edit&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;keep&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;delete&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Action by me&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;unconsider because of &quot;enough&quot; votes and keep votes&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;unconsider because of no direction and enough total votes&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
(I just updated the numbers and raised them by a factor of 1.5, as they seemed too low for my taste after I made them up)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2004-02-06&lt;br/&gt;
I haven't been able to decipher:

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;
&quot;enough&quot; means a factor three or ten keep votes
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Are you saying that if 30% of the votes cast are 'keep' votes, then you feel justified in unconsidering the node?  That sounds about right to me so long as enough votes have been collected.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter] 2004-02-06&lt;br/&gt;
I voted 'keep' on it, FWIW.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion] 2004-02-06&lt;br /&gt;
I went before looking here and cleaned out the nodes with &quot;too many&quot; keep votes from Nodes Requiring Editing, but didn't keep a list of what I unconsidered/marked done...&lt;br /&gt;
My policy is that enough &quot;keep&quot; votes will override any other voting, and currently &quot;enough&quot; means a factor three or ten keep votes. If you have differing opinions, please speak out here as I don't want to unconsider stuff against the consensus here :-)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ybiC] 2004-02-05&lt;br /&gt;
I concur with both [BazB] and [tye] that the post in question is informative but not actually a tutorial, so shouldn't be moved to the [Tutorials] section.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2004-02-05&lt;br /&gt;
I think we've already put too many non-tutorials in [Tutorials] and the habit of consideration has people trying to put their favorite nodes in there whether they fit the purpose of the section or not.  I think a very informative node should be rewritten as a tutorial if someone wants it in [Tutorials].  If it is a very informative non-tutorial, then put it somewhere else, such as a list of 'favorite nodes' on your home node.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If someone wants to write some extra voting system for selecting cool nodes (I think other forums have prior art for this), that'd be cool.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But in this case, I wouldn't put the node into [Tutorials] based on the vote, since I think a significant number of 'keep' votes is much more indicative than the number of 'edit' votes. *shrug*
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
[BazB] 2004-02-05&lt;br /&gt;
What's everyone's opinions regarding the consideration of [Abigail-II]'s [id://215675] for promotion to tutorials?&lt;br /&gt;
I'm not going to argue that the node isn't informative or interesting, but it isn't a tutorial in the strictest sense and it's a set of _personal_ rather than de facto (i.e. perlstyle) standards.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Update&lt;/b&gt;: [allolex] checked for and considers [id://317520] to be a good precedent in this case.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

This useless gibbering was brought to you by tired and confused [BazB] (tm).&lt;br /&gt;
Apologies.
&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;hr/&gt;
Continued in [id://331288]...



























</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>68046</type_nodetype>
  <node_id>405784</node_id>
  <author_user>979</author_user>
  <title>editors' wiki through 2004-10-31</title>
  <createtime>2001-07-14 06:15:20</createtime>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-02 09:45:07</nodeupdated>
</node>
