<node>
  <doctext>&lt;P&gt;[footpad], 25 Jun 01 - 21:25 PDT&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Personally, I'd like to see the &quot;Keeper of Tutorials&quot; role clarified.  Several good ones have been posted recently and it'd be nice for the authors to receive appropriate credit.  Also, would folks mind scrolling through the remaining nodes in [nodes to consider|ntc] and voting as appropriate?  I got the total down to fifty.  Next... &lt;I&gt;--f&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Petruchio] Mon Jun 25 16:16:26 EDT 2001:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks, [Adam], for the clarification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, what's been clarified is that the situation really is 
ambiguous.  Did [vroom|someone] make a choice, or was it an oversight?  
The only way to know is to ask. In the present case that's not a big deal, 
but this sort of thing is likely to come up again.  Somewhere down the 
line a more formal mechanism should probably be devised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Adam] localtime(993497932)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[Petruchio], [Tutorials] get listed for a short time when they get posted. Then [Vroom|someone] manually categorizes them. If they don't get categorized then the vanish into the ether.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2001-06-25 09:37 ET&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
For deleting nodes, I have several suggestions.  First, change the title of the node-to-be-deleted.  I usually use &quot;(duplicate) old title (to be deleted)&quot;.  This helps prevent people from replying to it and also makes it less likely that some idiot^Wwell-meaning monk will consider the other node without noting that this node has already been considered.  Also, make sure the doomed duplicate is not approved (and you may want to approve the non-doomed duplicated).  If you have the race condition where both duplicates get considered at the same time, then you may want to temporarilly change the title of the other to &quot;old title (please KEEP this one)&quot;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And, of course, probably the big idea:  Don't vote &quot;delete&quot; on a supposed duplicate unless you have looked at its duplicate, seen that it is really a duplicate and &lt;em&gt;that no one has voted &quot;delete&quot; on that one&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I think [vroom] can undelete one of them by hand if requested not long after the delete happens.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
We can already &quot;unconsider&quot; nodes as soon as two people have voted &quot;edit&quot; on a node.  I almost always vote &quot;edit&quot; in [Nodes to Consider], so others may want to do that as well.  Then you can go to [Nodes Requiring Editing] and check &quot;resolved&quot; to unconsider the node.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Sorry, [Petruchio], I don't know how [Tutorials] works.  I was hoping that [References Quick Reference] would eventually make it to that page.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Petruchio] Mon Jun 25 03:45:51 EDT 2001&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been asked by [grinder] to look into why his tutorial, 
[Parsing your script's command line], is no longer listed on the 
[Tutorials] page.  If you know, please let me know.  Then you can 
tell him or I can, either way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If no one knows, we might consider putting the link back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ar0n] 2001-06-25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Just a suggestion: an option to 'unconsider' nodes would be nice, for nodes that are unjustifiably considered. That'll probably have to wait until the [dev] group gets here, as I'm sure [vroom|El Presidente] is busy...
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2001-06-22 -- That is SOP, [Masem]. &lt;!-- &quot;Standard Operating 
Procedure&quot;, as in, &quot;yes, please do that; it is part of your job&quot; (: --&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
[Masem] on 21 Jun 2001 
&lt;P&gt;
In regards to [id://90425|this node regarding READMORE tags], would it seem to be an abuse or an appropriate use of editor power to add READMORE tags to nodes that don't already have it if only to reduce front page clutter?
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
[chromatic] on 19 June 2001.
&lt;p&gt;
In my mind, there's a difference between reaping a node that reasks a frequently asked question and just not replying to it.  For a technological solution, what about locking a thread?  (&quot;This question is answered in ... ... ..., please direct all replies there instead.&quot;)
&lt;p&gt;
As for giving new and anonymous users access to unmoderated content, maybe logged in users could have access to only those nodes they've created?  Hard to say.
&lt;p&gt;
I do think there's a possibility to go overboard on enforcing node purity.  When the database starts to run out of disk space, [vroom] will let us know.  Until then, I'm willing to let some stuff slide.
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ar0n] 2001-06-19 23:58 GMT +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I may or may not have voted delete on that node, though I don't think I have. My memory's a bit flakey right now, sorry. But I'll play devil's advocate here, just for the sake of argument.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Let's say I *did* vote delete on that node. Why? Because it was considered by a high-level monk (an [editors|editor], no less), and has been voted Delete on by at least 9 other people (if I recall correctly). Not only that, but at the time I looked at the node, there weren't any replies to it (this is a while after it's been posted). This says to me that there's a general consensus that the node is not worth replying to. Besides that, there are &lt;i&gt;at least&lt;/i&gt; 8 entire threads that handle the exact same topic. As much as I like proclaiming vim's superiority over all editors -- as The One True Editor -- I must say that it's a little much.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
On the other hand, now that somebody *has* replied to it, I no longer see a reason to delete it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Anyway, that's my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[vroom] 2001-06-19 15:00ET&lt;/P&gt;
I can show which editors voted to a delete a given node.  Nodes that 
have been delete are stored in a tomb table.  So a display of these 
nodes for accountability purposes wouldn't be too hard.  Reaped and
deleted nodes are stored in two different tables.  So the view
reaped node option wouldn't work in this case.  One other question
would it be good to turn on the view unmoderated flag for Anonymous
Monks and possibly new users by default so they feel their nodes
aren't disappearing within the system?

&lt;P&gt;[tye] 2001-06-19 14:35 ET&lt;/P&gt;
[neshura]++ (that's Perlmunkese for &quot;me too&quot;) on all points&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I'd love to see the proposed and promised access to the editors' log.  The /msg for purges is tempting but editor deletes wipe the node completely so I'm not sure what good it would do.  I wonder if we can view reaped nodes that we know the ID of using the &quot;view reaped node&quot; feature even when there is no placeholder to make it easy.  How about a reaper's log with pointers to reaped nodes and perhaps even nodes recently voted to be deleted but not reaped yet.  May have to wait for [developers] for this, eh?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[neshura] 2001/06/19 10:45 Pacific&lt;/P&gt;
Feel free to blame me for FP'ing the (1st but not 2nd) logged-in version of the @INC node. My convoluted reasoning was that there seemed to be quite a bit of lag between when the first post (as AM) was posted and when it was approved (which means the guy probably thought it got lost in the system). Since he *did* go to the trouble of making a nick for what was obviously an urgent question, I figured it wouldn't hurt to FP it so it could be easily found and we wouldn't get a 3rd copy. I don't think I'm wrong, and I'd do it again because I'd rather give the benefit of the doubt to the frustrated newbie and FP something than enforce spotlessly shiny Gates that nobody can get through. Of course, it's fine by me if another editor disagrees and un-FP's it. :)&lt;BR&gt;The site has plenty of good documentation, but until we've got a developers group goin' on who can fix this suX0ring though beloved UI, newbies are going to be muddling around with it and giving the [editors] headaches for a while.
&lt;P&gt;UPDATE: How about auto-generating a message to editors when a node gets 3 delete votes? Or would that be too much for one's message inbox?
&lt;p&gt;[Ovid] 2001/06/19&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pursuant to a request from [tye], I am saying 'mea culpa'.  I am one of the people whore quested that [id://89440|While I'm here - Perl Editors...] be deleted.  I regretted it after I did, but here's why I did it:  I was having a massive allergy attack and downed a bunch of Benadryl.  This made me very cranky.  I saw the 'what editor do you like' node and got disgusted with the rehash.  Clicking 'delete' was automatic, but I realized that I shouldn't have as soon as I did.  Ugh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2001-06-19 11:35 ET&lt;br&gt;
Heh.  I unapproved one of the @INC threads and changed its title to add &quot;(duplicate)&quot; and &quot;(to be deleted)&quot;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I don't want to have a discussion every time someone want to do something minor like unFP or unapprove a node.  What I do is first, doubt my assumption that it shouldn't be FP/approved since I know someone had to click for that to happen.  If I still feel it shouldn't be, then I undo it.  If I notice that is has gotten approved/FPed again and I'm strongly against it, then I'll try to start a discussion (and NTC isn't very useful for discussions so chatter, here, and/or a Discussion node).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Likewise, if I find a node got unapproved but I feel strongly that it should be approved.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[footpad] 19 Jun 2001, 07:05 am (PDT)&lt;BR&gt;

What's the general feeling regarding un-Approving and/or (especially) un-Frontpaging a node?  Should those be submitted to [nodes to consider|ntc], discussed via an editor's announcement, or just done?&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Case in point, one of the [id://89384|@INC] threads got front-paged and, without thinking too seriously about it, I un-FP'd it.  After doing so, I realized I should have brought it the rest of the team first.  So, I apologize for jumping the gun and wonder what the rest of you think about it.  (If someone disagrees with me, note that the node can be returned to the FP.)&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;As a side node on the dev group that [vroom] suggested, I would personally love to be able to view, though not edit, check-in, or otherwise muck with the source.  I'd find it instructive.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2001-06-18&lt;br&gt;
I'm against content revision.  I'd rather you just fix the formatting
and if you want to help others understand what you think his question
was, then post a reply.  &quot;Minor content revision&quot; is just too fuzzy of
a line, leading to a &quot;slippery slope&quot; situation.  I also don't want to
start seeing nodes submitted to [Nodes to Consider] for typo correction.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[Petruchio] 2001-06-18 5:32 EST&lt;br&gt;
Please let me know what you think of the way I've 
edited [Separation of content and code]. The fellow 
had much trouble with English. While I wanted to 
tread lightly, certain changes seemed likely to give 
him a better chance to get good answers.  The original 
is commented out, and may be restored wholly or in 
part.
&lt;p&gt;
[Petruchio] 2001-06-17 7:15 EST&lt;br&gt;
I'm honored to be here. *bow* :-)  Thanks for 
your trust.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As a possible remedy for a malicious downvoter, 
once he's identified by whatever means:  what 
about just giving him blanks to shoot?  You 
don't generally know the reputation of a node 

before you vote on it; it would take a very 
observant vandal to figure out that his 
downvotes weren't actually changing reputations.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
One advantage of such a strategy would be to 
waste the vandal's effort, while 
he thinks he's still working mischief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2001-06-16 17:10 ET&lt;br&gt;
Welcome new editors.  Feel free to prepend questions here.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2001-05-24 18:35 ET&lt;br&gt;
&lt;small&gt;I started posting this yesterday but it got lost...&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
First, on the [dev] group, I was definately interested in only having [vroom] check in changes and being very conscious of minimizing the impact on his time.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I came up with a simple change that may help many of these problems.  No XP changes for voter/votee after 3rd consecutive vote for/against the same person.  That is, if I vote (for or against) [Ovid] ten times in a row, then only the first three votes will have any chance of gaining me XP or of raising/lowering [Ovid]'s XP.  This would be another of the &quot;unwritten rules&quot; like how managing to vote for a node that you have already voted for doesn't do anything to XP or rep but does cost you a vote.  Eventually I'd like to have this same rule apply for obvious robot votes (where the resulting page doesn't reference the nodes voted on), but I'll leave that as a separate issue.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This change should reduce the &quot;Ack!&quot; messages (which I consider to be the largest, though not the only, problem with &quot;voting the person&quot;) and should make it harder to get robots advancing in power.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This would not change how votes affect node reputations at all.  I could still increase the rep of every single one of [Ovid]'s nodes consecutively.  This is in part to make this &quot;unwritten rule&quot; harder to notice and figure out so that robots aren't so likely to quickly work around it.  But this is also in part because there are legitimate reason to vote the same person more than 3 times in a row and I want the &quot;penalty&quot; for that to be quite minor.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
For the record, I don't really like my own previous proposal that much.  I would really like to drastically reduce the amount of robot voting.  I understand [vroom]'s reluctance to finding out who is doing it.  I've investigated malicious-user problems as a system admin before and I think my feelings on it are a bit unusual.  I don't want the identity to become public knowledge but I don't mind knowing.  I've caught my friends doing stupid things before and I've done my share of stupid things and I can deal with being friends and having respect for someone even though I know what they've done.  And I think that the current level of robot voting means that some people need to be confronted by a person who says &quot;I know what you've done.  It isn't appreciated.  Please stop or we'll stop you.&quot;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Also, regarding [jcwren]'s note that dropping 1000 XP from the guilty would make their guilt known to all pretty soon.  I vote for dropping the XP of any identified robots to 0 (and probably eventually changing their password).  For identified robot drivers, I'd like to punish them as well after they are confronted.  I think I'd probably take away their ability to vote for a 2-month period, or something.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Ovid] 2001-05-23&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like a lot of what I am seeing here, but I do have one concern:  dropping people to 0 XP with no notice.  My thought:  we attempt to reach some concensus on the issues that need to be addressed and then issue an official node regarding what the concensus is without going into specifics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Due to voting abuses, we are implementing systems to detect and eliminate problems from votebots, personality voting, and anyone who upvotes PHP posts...(that was a joke)&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than give the specifics that people &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; ask for, and panic about, simply let them know that this will be occurring.  This might scare abusers who aren't terribly creative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ugh... on second thought, I don't like that approach, either, but I'd like to at least give abusers a chance to clean up their acts before the boom is lowered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[vroom] 20001-05-22&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;B&gt;In regards to a possible dev group&lt;/B&gt;&lt;P&gt;
E2 has a group that is allowed to view the source to the htmlcodes, htmlpages, and superdocs used to generate pages etc... I wouldn't be against that.  Some
things to consider:&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;I want to avoid e-mails saying your code sucks... which it probably does in many cases.
&lt;LI&gt;I only want code fixes that are helpful where I define helpful.
&lt;LI&gt;I think for things to make sense I would be the only one to check in changes/ make actual changes.
&lt;LI&gt;I don't want my job as PM pumpking to take up a ton of time
&lt;LI&gt;I want to avoid everyone from coding up things that may be cool to them but
are of limited usefulness to the community at large.
&lt;HR&gt;
&lt;BR&gt;[vroom]-more on votebot detection&lt;BR&gt;
Good point on the ++ votebots that's something else to take into consideration.  The problem with many of these solutions is that sleeps or visiting each page before voting could make a votebot go undetected.  IP's is another good thing to log but that can be gotten around as well.  If the algorithm is open people will find ways around it... if it's closed people will question the results validity. 
&lt;HR&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye] 2001-05-22&lt;br&gt;
I could care less about &quot;voting the person&quot; right now.  I think the problem right now is automated voting and I don't want automated voting even if the votes are only ++ votes (especially since that is how vote robots get created).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I think most of the automated voting could be detected right now by noting when a form is submitted that contains vote requests but that results in a node that doesn't include all of the nodes just voted on.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Any solution will require &quot;voting logs&quot; so that when someone balks &quot;I didn't robot vote&quot;, there is evidence to review and prove to the accused that we really do know what has been going on.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I'd be happy to help write code to generate logs include the information about what nodes are included in the page that results from the &quot;vote form&quot; submission plus the software to analyse the logs (to be reviewed by humans -- if we ever have so many robot voters that a group like [editors] can't review the evidence before action, then we all need to find another site).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then I say we detect robots and collect their IDs and source IP addresses for a couple of weeks and then just drop them all to 0 XP with an announcement that robot voting is not appreciated.  I also say we track non-robot-voting-IDs that come from the same IP addresses (and who voted strongly for the robots) for tracking as possible facilitators in case we find tenacious repeat offenders.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Is that extreme enough for everyone?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I really think we need a [dev] group for helping with coding changes.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[jcwren] (22 May 2001)&lt;/p&gt;
I don't know about the severity of the problem, but [tilly] and [merlyn] seem to be the primary targets.  I did have 6 of my nodes with a rep of 0 get downvoted today, all within a 5 minute span.  I'm not sure what the point of that is...  But it happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[chromatic] (22 May 2001)&lt;br&gt;
I'm not convinced there's reason to do anything, mostly because I'm not convinced there's a problem.  I'm not convinced there's a way to prove there's a problem or not.
&lt;p&gt;
[vroom], is the essential structure of the voting stuff in the voting nodeball on EveryDevel?  If so, maybe a couple of us could take a look at it and see if there are any ways to detect &quot;personality voting&quot; within a reasonable doubt.
&lt;p&gt;
I doubt there are, but I'm willing to take a look if it'll put an end to the speculation.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[neshura]&lt;br&gt;
I think it is legitimate voting behavior to use downvotes exclusively yet conservatively. There are many people who never downvote anyone, and on the opposite side of the distribution, I see no problem with intelligent downvoting of nodes that...well...SUX0r. E.g. most of the poetry.
&lt;BR&gt;This might appear as personality voting on a lot of heuristics you design. What is required is to narrow down a definition for personality voting. This seems like an utterly arbitrary problem. I haven't been around enough to hear the &quot;proof&quot; of the systematic downvoting so I am really pretty skeptical that it is a big enough problem to warrant this kind of attention.
&lt;P&gt;It's a common enough pattern -- one starts with a free community, something is not to someone's liking, a law is passed, and over time, the community is eventually asphyxiated by regulation. 
&lt;BR&gt;Thus, I support Option 2 for the moment. And if people complain that systematic abuse is continuing, vroom SHOULD go into the database. He'll find one of two things.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abuse is occurring: knock the abuser(s) down 5 or more levels in XP. 
&lt;li&gt;Abuse is not occurring: knock the complainer(s) down 2 or more levels in XP.
&lt;/ul&gt;
Perhaps include the option to appeal to a small jury of Saints.
&lt;P&gt;The core of this problem is balancing Accountability versus Freedom. Full accountability means no private votes, no private votes means whoever wields the most power and influence controls the voting. 
&lt;BR&gt;The only people who could theoretically do damage with systematic voting are those with multiple registered logins or those who are high-level members. You could require that Saints vote publicly. It wouldn't solve the vote-bot problem, but [vroom] could easily look for logins with a lot of XP and a very small number of writeups over a fairly significant time period.
&lt;P&gt;I semi-support the idea of upper levels having to reveal their votes. They have the bulk of the votes and the power. For instance, the Supreme Court members have to answer for their votes because of the tremendous influence the Court has on Americans (relative to the individual citizen's vote on an individual issue in a single election). The analogy is imperfect, of course, because a single Saint vote has the same value as a single vote by an initiate.
&lt;P&gt;[Adam]&lt;br&gt;
I notice one big problem with your ++/-- ratio approach. It can generate false positives. I don't usually ++ vote on nodes written by higher level monks (like saints), unless I am really impressed by the node, mostly because I know the node will get a realistic rep without me, and because the author doesn't need the xp. On the other hand, I have no qualms about -- voting a node written by a saint. They (we) should know better! So I would look like a personality voter. Perhaps that is a form of personality voting, but there is nothing malicious about it. I thing we need a solid picture of undesirable voting behaviour before automating it. Particularly repeated offense, ie someone investing more then a day or two's worth of votes to downvote one other person.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
That said, what should we do about it? I think a &lt;tt&gt;msg&lt;/tt&gt; to the offender is a good response for a first offense, and could be done automatically (with the caveat of a better algorithm). A simple &lt;tt&gt;msg&lt;/tt&gt; isn't really a penalty, its just a note saying, &quot;Hey. We know about that, now knock it off.&quot; For repeat offenders, I think people will need to get involved. I'm wary of passing judgement without hearing both sides, and that requires contacting the person.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
And I disagree with [jcwren] about publishing the algorithm. A well crafted algorithm would not require hiding. I do agree with you though that the automated stuff has got to err towards the conservative.
&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jcwren]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I'd like to really hope that whomever is the problem, or part of the problem, is not an editor.  
&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure that if you develop a set of rules for determining voting habits that they should be published.  It might be one of those things best kept to yourself, so that the system can less effectively be defeated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, we've seen lots of opinions about how -- votes should be used.  Some feel that every -- should be explained at great length, other that the end of the world should occur sooner than making use of a --, or, people like me, that are fairly liberal with them when I don't like something (perl poetry, for example, generally sucks, and in my mind, is usually worthy of expending a --).  However, agree or disagree, my voting habits are not the subject of this discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can safely say that with exception of [discostu] and his alter ego, methodical downvoting is usually not my style, and I doubt that any rules that I can imagine would ever trigger on any voting I do.  The problem is that they cannot falsely trigger, or they will generate massive amounts of boring discussion, and will undermine the faith in how the monastery is run.  If anything, they need to error on the side of being conservative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While to some extent I agree with [vroom|Tim] that I don't want to know who the problem child is, I want it dealt with, and made clear that this won't be tolerated.  Unfortunately, for that to occur, Tim is going to need to know who it is.  I would personally elect for subtracting 1000 or more XP from whomever this is.  Perhaps resetting it to 0, even.  Sadly, doing so will become fairly evident to the inquisitive souls we have around here, and within a week, everyone will know who it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has put Tim in a really awkward position, as far as I'm concerned.  It forces him to make decisions that he doesn't want to make, and in all probability, learn information he doesn't want to know.  If you do have any idea who this is, and have some facts to back it up, I would suggest you drop a gentle note to the person in question.  Preferrably before the damage done is more severe than it has been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[vroom]
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Voting Issues/Abuse&lt;/B&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Obviously a lot of people have been talking about systematic downvoting etc.  The vote table can tell the tale but then what does one do with the information?
Some heuristics I've thought of for finding questionable voters:
&lt;LI&gt;Up to downvote ratio between a voter and a node author:&lt;BR&gt;
perhaps a ratio of 5 downvotes to 1 upvote or maybe a 10:1 ratio would be flagged as personality voting.  There would probably need to be a minimum number of nodes say 25 for this statistic to hold weight.  Also some users like DiscoStu would be seen as deserving of this systematic downvoting.
&lt;LI&gt;Downvote window-A sliding window of all the downvotes would be examined if 5 out of 10 say were between one voter and node_author this would look questionable.
&lt;P&gt;
The last heuristic can be easily side-stepped with generous sleep()'s in the vote bot.
&lt;P&gt;The next question is what to do with the information.
I don't necessarily want to know who is doing this stuff because I don't want to lose
respect for people I currently respect based on this info.  

&lt;LI&gt;Option 1: a script could send off /msg's from the [VoteMonitor] noting suspicious behavior and linking to
a Voting Ethics page.
&lt;LI&gt;Option 2: I could post a node saying the data is all there... I can find out who is doing what.  Don't make me cuz I don't want to.  Stop abusing the system yada yada.
&lt;BR&gt;Option 3: I could continue with the hands off approach and assume that at the end of the day good users will be able to withstand downvoting from one malicious user.
&lt;P&gt;Thoughts on the matter??



&lt;HR&gt;
[vroom]&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;permissions /should/ work now.  The creator of a wiki can set a
minimum level or a usergroup required for reading/writing to a wiki
&lt;LI&gt;This node /should/ be readable and writable only by editors
&lt;HR&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Necessary additions&lt;/B&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Update permission denied message to say what level/group requirement
is needed to view a given node
&lt;LI&gt;Need to decide who can create wikis and add a page for creating them
&lt;LI&gt;add [jcwren's] suggested shortcuts for adding usernames and timestamps
&lt;HR&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[mirod]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What should we do we nodes in [nodes requiring editing] that we cannot
      edit properly (like moving them to a different thread for
      example), should we remove them
      after a while?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- It should be fun to look at the various ways people tag this kind of
     node, XHTML vs &quot;if it looks good then it _is_ good ;--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The ones that need moving to a different thread I've been keeping around
in hopes that soon we'd be able to take care of that.  Most of the ones
that get requested to be deleted either don't get a negative rep (soon
enough) or get too many keep votes so I almost always vote &quot;edit&quot; on
those and then clear them out when someone else votes &quot;edit&quot; on them as
well.  Most non-troll requests for deletes (including simple duplicates)
are not handled well by the current reaping method and so should
probably be sent to [Editor Requests] instead (which is really &quot;[vroom]
requests&quot; at this point).  Editors probably need increased power to
delete.  That is, be able to delete nodes with a positive rep if 3
editors agree, for example.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[mirod]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree that duplicate (and the likes) deletion needs to be improved,
3 editor votes sounds reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[vroom]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;three editor delete votes will now take out a node.. is this acceptable?
&lt;BR&gt;what do people think about the possibility of editors voting to
unreap a node?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- $0.02: --&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[turnstep]
&lt;BR&gt;The power to &quot;undelete&quot; sounds feasible, although I cannot think 
of any node that has warranted it so far. Maybe make the threshhold 
a bit higher, say 5 editors? Maybe even bump up the three to delete 
figure - after all, most of the editors are very active, which makes 
us different from those with the power to consider.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye]&lt;br&gt;
I've already requested a couple of undeletes.  And I've seen nodes that
required deleting but took a long time to get 5 delete votes so I don't
think more than 3 editors should be required to delete.  3 (or 4)
[editors] to undelete makes sense to me.  I assume (and hope) that
deleting a node removes it from [Nodes to consider]. (:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I'm very tempted to retitle this node &quot;editors' wiki&quot;...
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Adam]&lt;br&gt;
I have to agree with [Tye] on the title... :-) also on the
delete/undelete discussion. 3 [editors] to delete seems like a good
number. 4 is pushing it, and 5 is too many. I think fewer votes should be
neccessary to undelete. After all, I would rather see crumy content then
not see good content. As such, 2 editor votes aught to be enought to undelete.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt;[turnstep]&lt;BR&gt;
Good points. I'll go with 3 and 3 then.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye]&lt;br&gt;
I think we should be updating this type of wiki in the other direction
(newest text at the top).  If you add a new subject here, I think you
should feel free to &quot;/msg editors&quot; to announce that fact.  But I'd rather
avoid starting new discussions in /msg land.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As for number of votes to unreap, the only reason I considered more than
3 was that, to get reaped, there had to be some small consensus involved,
so I didn't want us [editors] to take overruling that consensus too
lightly.  I still like 4 but 3 works for me as well.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As for seeing number of &quot;editor delete&quot; votes after you vote, well, sure,
there is &lt;b&gt;one&lt;/b&gt; case where you don't know: You were the first to vote
&quot;delete&quot; and the node is still there.  So an enhancement in that
direction certainly isn't worth much effort.  I'd rather spend that
effort on reducing the height of the editors' nodelet when the delete
button is present. (:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
([turnstep], how did you steal the lock from me??) ;)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Hmm. Now I wonder at the details of wiki locking.  I'm suspecting
something similar to [editors] node locking which is unlocked &lt;b&gt;only&lt;/b&gt;
when the 10-minute timer expires.  I assume the timer here is shorter. 
Ugh.  Anyone have the details?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt;[Adam]&lt;br&gt;
Say, are those checkboxes next to the keywords in the keyword nodelet
functional? If I check one and then hit submit, does that delete it? &lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;[vroom]&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Notes on wiki functionality:&lt;/B&gt; Currently the lock is one minute.  That can of course change.  Before an update it also checks to see if the MD5 digest for a field in the db matches what it was when you started the edit.  If your update is denied as a side effect of previewing stuff the text field will have the text you entered into it after it0.  You can then copy your changed text.  Go back to display mode, then back to edit mode (at this point the MD5 values passed along will be reupdated).  If you have or can gain the lock you can then paste the change in and submit.
&lt;P&gt;The delete checkboxes will now remove keywords.  How do people think keywords should be incorporated into the search?  Should a hit on a keyword or word in the title count the same? should they have different ratings/weights?  or should I make yet another search for searching only on keywords?

&lt;p&gt;[tye]&lt;br&gt;
I took the liberty of reversing the entries.  If someone minds, tell me soon!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I'm happy with the locking.  One enhancement would be for &quot;go back to the display view&quot; to immediately release the lock (and similarly for &quot;display&quot; when [editors] edit nodes).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I vote for a separate field for keywords to search on.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It would be neat if we could search for Cat Qs and As by a specific author and if we could search the missing code sections. (:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Regarding keywords&lt;/b&gt; (&lt;i&gt;I'm not sure if this warrants its own
node (yet). Once we have cooked this out, this should most likely go into
a public node with public discussion I think, but not yet&lt;/i&gt;) The
keyword search is a nice idea, but it needs two things :
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;People who index (their own and other) nodes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A semi-consistent scheme of keywords and keyword searches&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
Taking care of People Who Index Nodes isn't that hard, we already have
[editors|People Who Maintain Indexes]. The interesting part of making
keywords work is making the retrieval work. I have seen an interesting
approach during my admin time at [http://www.navicon.de|NaviCon GmbH]
(they do such stuff for a living, not on the web, but still) - they use a
thesaurus to make keyword searches better. You only add fine grained
keywords, and the search (or maybe a &lt;tt&gt;cron&lt;/tt&gt; job) consults the
thesaurus for other keywords. Opinions and links to thesauri or on how to
maintain our own thesaurus are welcome. I'm also prepared to take this
into its own node, but I guess before we talk that much about keywords,
keyword search should be in place to avoid the effect we had with [Nodes
To Consider] which filled up and there was nobody with the power to act
on them.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just had the idea of &quot;promoting&quot; such nodes from [Nodes Requiring
Editing] to [vroom|Editors Requests] - just having another button that
moves such nodes into a bucket that [vroom] sees over from time to time
would be enough IMO, maybe together with more concise instructions like
&lt;i&gt;Reparent to node xxx&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;HR&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[turnstep]
&lt;BR&gt;For the record, I know that [tye] meant well, but I really find it 
hard to read the node in reverse order when every other node on the site 
is ordered &quot;newest at the bottom&quot;. I also think that adding &amp;lt;HR&amp;gt; 
tags to separate sections works well too.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;!-- Ctrl-end is my friend! :) --&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;[tye]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Items unreversed, I hope.  I don't think this will scale well (I don't think it
scales well already).
&lt;/p&gt;
</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>68046</type_nodetype>
  <node_id>91826</node_id>
  <author_user>979</author_user>
  <title>editors' wiki through 2001-06-27</title>
  <createtime>2001-04-20 19:28:52</createtime>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-02 09:31:34</nodeupdated>
</node>
