<node>
  <doctext>&lt;!--

&lt;p&gt;&lt;wikihead&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[davido], &lt;a href=&quot;#2011-08-17 13:18:10&quot; name=&quot;2011-08-17 13:18:10&quot;&gt;[localtime://2011-08-17 13:18:10]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I just wanted to provide an explanation for an edit of [id://920659].&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;  Background: This was the OP's seventh post, and most of the previous ones had formatting problems.  He has been asked several times via /msg as well as by followups to his nodes to read [id://17558] and format accordingly. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now: When [id://920659] was posted I saw that it was gathering downvotes and &quot;please read this&quot; replies.  I /msg'ed the OP to let him know that he should read [id://17558] and edit his post accordingly.  Seven hours later it hadn't been done.  Someone considered the node for editing, and it gathered a vote of 0/11/1 (11 for edit).  I edited the node so that its formatting would match the original raw input from the OP, and sent him a message letting him know what was done, why, and where to learn how to format properly in the first place. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I left a small &lt;c&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;/c&gt; blurb at the bottom of his node identifying that the node had been edited.  I know we have sort of gotten away from doing that in general, but this time I did it for two reasons: First, because then he would see someone worked on it for him, and second, so that all the &quot;I can't read this node&quot; replies would have a contextual reference point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look back over old nodes here in the Monastery.  &quot;Back in the day&quot; it seems like there were fewer &quot;Please read xxxx, please read yyy&quot; followups.  I am afraid we (the Monks in general) have gotten in the habit of following up in public with what probably ought to be done in private.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[planetscape], &lt;a href=&quot;#2009-07-26 22:25:49&quot; name=&quot;2009-07-26 22:25:49&quot;&gt;[localtime://2009-07-26 22:25:49]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Unconsidered [id://783174] (&lt;c&gt;[moritz]: reap: not perl news 	keep:3 edit:0 reap:11 	2009-07-25
(1 day ago)&lt;/c&gt;) per discussion ~15 hrs ago in the CB between myself, [jdporter], and [Corion]. [Corion] stated he felt the consideration would have been more appropriate if a move (rather than a reap) had been indicated, and that [Corion|he] was disinclined to restore the [http://corion.net/perlmonks/783174.xml|original content]. And because of the 3 Keeps.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-11-28 08:38:37&quot; name=&quot;2008-11-28 08:38:37&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-11-28 08:38:37]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Can [id://726434] be unreaped please?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[planetscape], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-10-26 16:33:24&quot; name=&quot;2008-10-26 16:33:24&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-10-26 16:33:24]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
FWLIMBW, I agree that &lt;c&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;/c&gt; tags are &quot;freakin' ugly&quot;, but also concur with [GrandFather]'s read of the OP's intent: &quot;out with the old and in with the new&quot;. I do not think too much (censorship, editorial judgement, moral value) should be read into &lt;c&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;/c&gt; tags. It is also my understanding that [janitors] are not here to make nodes aesthetically pleasing. I further believe that it is the will of the [gods] that [janitors] not resort to &quot;Wikipedia-style dueling edits&quot;, if I recall the phrase correctly. I humbly suggest that done is done, further edits to a node may be considered by some to be further editorializing upon/brutalizing deceased horseflesh, and that if a standard for handling emptied and/or radically re-written nodes can be agreed upon, it should be applied to future [janitors|janitor]ial actions, and not be made retroactive (as I'm certain the dusty corridors of the Monastery hold many nodes [janitors|janitor]ed in fashions now long out-of-date).&lt;br&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;b&gt;Update:&lt;/b&gt; closed open paren&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[GrandFather], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-10-26 15:01:03&quot; name=&quot;2008-10-26 15:01:03&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-10-26 15:01:03]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
[Arunbear|You] may re-edit the node if you feel you must. The OP deleted his own words. I restored them, but in a fashion that indicates the OP's obvious intent - to delete the material. I do not consider that a judgemental action or to constitute censorship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do think however that restoring the original node content and giving it equal billing with the new content is in direct opposition to the OP's intent. That surely is more akin to censorship than the current state of the node.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-10-26 12:16:40&quot; name=&quot;2008-10-26 12:16:40&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-10-26 12:16:40]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
[GrandFather] and [McDarren], please correct your respective edits to [id://716992] and [id://716308] as discussed below.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-10-18 15:03:26&quot; name=&quot;2008-10-18 15:03:26&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-10-18 15:03:26]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Striking out someone else's words gives the impression of judging or censoring that content, so in my view is an editorial action (so is inappropriate and is also unnecessary given that there is an alternative I pointed out that lets the old and new coexist whilst not getting into editorial territory). I also think that content restoration is perhaps the only case in which a janitorial comment is helpful. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

[McDarren], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-10-18 01:07:02&quot; name=&quot;2008-10-18 01:07:02&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-10-18 01:07:02]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I'll put my hand up for the [id://716308] one. In this case, the OP had removed the original content entirely and replaced it with &quot;Thanks very much - that works!&quot;. After restoring the original content, this now seemed out of place, so I added the update to provide some context. It seemed the right thing to do at the time, but I do take [Arunbear|your] point about it being more editorial than janitorial. And so I'll happily take my slap on the wrist for that one, and not do it again. And just to be clear - does everyone agree that [davido]'s [id://503564|approach] is the preferred one? I seem to recall doing something similar in the past and being told at the time that the practice of &quot;dirtying&quot; nodes with janitorial comment was deprecated.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just to add a further comment regarding [GrandFather]'s case, whilst I agree that the strike looks fugly, I'm struggling to think of a better way to handle such a case, without leaving too much &quot;janitorial-intrusiveness&quot;. Perhaps put the original content inside some blockquotes and mark it as such? That doesn't seem right either...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[GrandFather], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-10-16 16:07:26&quot; name=&quot;2008-10-16 16:07:26&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-10-16 16:07:26]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I agree the strike is &quot;freakin' ugly&quot;, but restoring the original content of [id://716992] without removing the new content was appropriate. The OP completely rewrote the node and there are answers to both versions. In this somewhat unusual case strike seemed an appropriate way to restore the original content in a fashion consistent with the OP's intent (out with the old and in with the new).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-10-16 13:25:34&quot; name=&quot;2008-10-16 13:25:34&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-10-16 13:25:34]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Yes.  Strike tags for more than about one word are also freakin' ugly.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-10-16 12:50:10&quot; name=&quot;2008-10-16 12:50:10&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-10-16 12:50:10]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Adding strike tags as in [id://716992], and the word 'update' as in [id://716308] seem more editorial than janitorial (in the sense of putting words in the authors mouth) and I thought we weren't supposed to be doing that.  
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[davido]'s method of noting a restoration (e.g. [id://503564]) seems more innocuous by comparison - who did what is much more obvious. Any comments?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-07-31 11:53:36&quot; name=&quot;2008-07-31 11:53:36&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-07-31 11:53:36]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Who unconsidered [id://697364] and why?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-07-10 16:33:44&quot; name=&quot;2008-07-10 16:33:44&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-07-10 16:33:44]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

The secret node stash now officially lives at [http://corion.net/perlmonks/]. So the convenient
free nodelet entry would be:
&lt;c&gt;
[http://corion.net/perlmonks/`id`.xml|Original content of `id`]&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/c&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-07-03 16:51:11&quot; name=&quot;2008-07-03 16:51:11&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-07-03 16:51:11]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Just a heads up - the secret node stash has now &quot;most&quot; XML files compressed by gzip. Apache should work the necessary magic to serve up the files as both, &lt;c&gt;.xml&lt;/c&gt; or &lt;c&gt;.xml.gz&lt;/c&gt;, but I found that at least the LWP GET utility displays the compressed data instead of properly decoding the gzipped data before display. So if you run any automated tools against the node stash, you might need to check/change them.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-06-19 03:51:40&quot; name=&quot;2008-06-19 03:51:40&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-06-19 03:51:40]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Can [id://692662] be unreaped please?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-05-22 18:34:25&quot; name=&quot;2008-05-22 18:34:25&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-05-22 18:34:25]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://673882]. It was considered &lt;em&gt;[mr_mischief]: move to be a follow-up to [id://673757], where the problem was addressed?&lt;/em&gt; on 2008-03-13 (10 weeks ago).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[McDarren], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-05-05 03:09:01&quot; name=&quot;2008-05-05 03:09:01&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-05-05 03:09:01]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I probably wouldn't have bothered with the message to the [gods], except that it was specifically asked for ;)&lt;br/&gt;
Noted (and thanks) on the other - I guess I was erring on the side of caution in that regard.
&lt;br/&gt;
And now [tye|you] have another little star to ruin your day ;p&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-05-05 01:29:17&quot; name=&quot;2008-05-05 01:29:17&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-05-05 01:29:17]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The [gods] can see the little star by the &quot;wiki&quot; links just like other members of [janitors] (or whatever).  I personally find the duplicate notice, so that now I have two little indicators in nodelets, one telling me of a message that tells me about the other, just annoying.  FYI. :)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Also, usually no need to declare that you unconsidered a node unless you did it rather suddenly, which one usually shouldn't do, or perhaps if you had a question or comment related to it.  If the node has been considered for most of a week, then those interested in its disposition will have had a chance to see the direction the vote tally is going and likely won't be particularly suprised when it disappears from NTC.  The less clear-cut the failure of the consideration, the longer you should let it linger, generally.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[McDarren], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-05-04 20:59:48&quot; name=&quot;2008-05-04 20:59:48&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-05-04 20:59:48]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Original content of [id://684434] has been restored, and [Gods] have been messaged.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-05-04 17:38:38&quot; name=&quot;2008-05-04 17:38:38&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-05-04 17:38:38]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
[id://684453] was reaped as a dup of [id://684434].  But [id://684434] had had its contents overwritten by the author and the dup was of the new content.  If anyone digs up the original content of [id://684434], please restore it and /msg gods to have the other node unreaped.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[McDarren], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-05-02 12:51:06&quot; name=&quot;2008-05-02 12:51:06&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-05-02 12:51:06]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://683865]. Considered: [Erez]: reap: spam. (Keep: 9, Edit: 0, Reap: 17)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[McDarren], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-04-27 12:46:44&quot; name=&quot;2008-04-27 12:46:44&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-04-27 12:46:44]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://682719]. Considered: [grep]: reap: SPAM. (Keep: 5, Edit: 1, Reap: 3).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[McDarren], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-03-24 14:51:45&quot; name=&quot;2008-03-24 14:51:45&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-03-24 14:51:45]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I considered [id://675862] for code tags, and then shortly afterwards I noticed that the OP had included his mysql server password in the code. So I went ahead and immediately removed this, as well as adding the code tags while I was at it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[McDarren], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-03-24 14:24:37&quot; name=&quot;2008-03-24 14:24:37&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-03-24 14:24:37]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I have unconsidered [id://673851]. ([jarich]: &quot;delete. Not about Perl, valueless, off-topic&quot; - Keep: 11, Edit: 0, Reap: 8). As far as I can tell, this was not a valid consideration in the first place. (Is it customary to send a note to the considerer in such cases?)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Co-Rion], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-03-06 11:49:45&quot; name=&quot;2008-03-06 11:49:45&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-03-06 11:49:45]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Welcome [McDarren] to the ranks of the [janitors]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[g0n], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-12-27 06:19:40&quot; name=&quot;2007-12-27 06:19:40&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-12-27 06:19:40]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://656365] (Considered: [bart]: Fix markup: readmore tags, nesting code tags, final paragraph is in signature  - Keep: 4, Edit: 19, Reap: 0). The markup appears to be OK now.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[g0n], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-12-15 06:34:03&quot; name=&quot;2007-12-15 06:34:03&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-12-15 06:34:03]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://655541] (Considered: [ww]: amend title;add &quot;Regex to capture....&quot;). It looks like an inappropriate consideration, calling for the subthread to be retitled differently to the overall thread - either that or [ww] has considered this one rather than the root node (and the root node makes no reference to regex).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[GrandFather], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-12-12 08:43:00&quot; name=&quot;2007-12-12 08:43:00&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-12-12 08:43:00]&lt;/a&gt;
I restored content of [id://656305] and added code tags&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-12-08 20:38:58&quot; name=&quot;2007-12-08 20:38:58&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-12-08 20:38:58]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I unreaped [655360|it] and reparented it to [id://655317].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-12-08 11:52:54&quot; name=&quot;2007-12-08 11:52:54&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-12-08 11:52:54]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Could [id://655360] be unreaped please? It is not an exact duplicate of [id://655317].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[GrandFather], [localtime://2007-11-24 09:17:00]&lt;br/&gt;
The link would be more PerlMonkish as: ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;c&gt;
[http://corion.net.h1272824.stratoserver.net/perlmonks/`id`.xml|Original content of `id`]&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/c&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-11-23 12:09:49&quot; name=&quot;2007-11-23 12:09:49&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-11-23 12:09:49]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
[g0n] has graciously provided me with his Perlmonks XML scraper, which I'm now running every five minutes. The &quot;first impressions&quot; of nodes will be available under [http://corion.net.h1272824.stratoserver.net/perlmonks/nnnn.xml]. I have made the link into a [Free Nodelet] hack as well so I can visit the &quot;original Klingon&quot; of every (new) node:
&lt;c&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://corion.net.h1272824.stratoserver.net/perlmonks/`id`.xml&quot;&gt;xml copy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/c&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[yitzchak], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-07-25 02:47:55&quot; name=&quot;2007-07-25 02:47:55&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-07-25 02:47:55]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I unreaped [id://628558].  Consideration reason: &quot;[jdporter]: s/advertisement/perl_content/. Otherwise, reap.&quot;  Keep/reap/edit: 1/5/0.
&lt;p&gt;
I confess to not comprehending the consideration reason at all.  Perhaps it's just a little too terse for me?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-07-17 17:52:42&quot; name=&quot;2007-07-17 17:52:42&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-07-17 17:52:42]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Quoting myself, with emphasis added (and one typo fixed):
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;
Me, I'll only be tempted do that for a &quot;fast&quot; unconsideration such as blatantly bad considerations against nodes&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;that really need to be considered for a different reason&lt;/b&gt;&lt;i&gt;, I think.
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
to be clear.  [g0n] appears to have interpretted that part of my paragraph with the opposite sense.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[g0n], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-07-17 18:09:52&quot; name=&quot;2007-07-17 18:09:52&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-07-17 18:09:52]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
That was me. The consideration was something along the lines of 'remove haughty, sarcastic tone'. It was so blatantly not a valid consideration that I didn't think it was worth logging, and the node didn't seem to require reconsidering for anything else (ref [tye]s comment below).
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-07-17 15:43:03&quot; name=&quot;2007-07-17 15:43:03&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-07-17 15:43:03]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
[id://626643] was unconsidered a bit quickly (and not logged). Why??
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-07-08 01:40:58&quot; name=&quot;2007-07-08 01:40:58&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-07-08 01:40:58]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Perhaps log considerations where you feel a need to explain why you unconsidered it?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-07-06 02:06:31&quot; name=&quot;2007-07-06 02:06:31&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-07-06 02:06:31]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
A while back I complained about rash unconsiderations where I couldn't tell why the node got unconsidered.  My main point was that unconsideration should not happen too quickly.  But it seems that my mention of not having a log hit home even more.  Just to be clear, I personally don't care to see every unconsideration logged in this wiki.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I just unconsidered 10 nodes and I'm not documenting the details.  I wouldn't have even updated the wiki except I'm taking this as an opportunity to express a related point.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
All of the nodes I unconsidered had &quot;enough 'keep' votes&quot; or at least had languished long enough it NTC to make it clear that no janitor felt compelled to perform the described task (or I performed it before unconsidering or it appeared to have already been performed despite still being considered).  I don't need to document the details here because anyone curious about any of those has had plenty of time (over a week) to revisit the node and see how the vote was going before I unconsidered.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
To be clear, feel free to log unconsiderations in the wiki in cases where such seems appropriate to you.  Me, I'll only be tempted do that for a &quot;fast&quot; uconsideration such as blatantly bad considerations against nodes that really need to be considered for a different reason, I think.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thanks.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[GrandFather], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-06-27 14:57:48&quot; name=&quot;2007-06-27 14:57:48&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-06-27 14:57:48]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://623463], was considered by [Old_Gray_Bear]: &lt;i&gt;Please move to Meditations; not a discussion of how the Site works&lt;/i&gt;. at Keep: 11, Edit: 14
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-06-25 02:57:48&quot; name=&quot;2007-06-25 02:57:48&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-06-25 02:57:48]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://622511], was considered by [naikonta] for &lt;i&gt;Mark OT&lt;/i&gt; at Keep: 11, Edit: 19, Reap: 1
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-06-24 13:59:50&quot; name=&quot;2007-06-24 13:59:50&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-06-24 13:59:50]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered
[id://617685] at {keep:13 edit:0 reap:26}, which was considered on 2007-05-27 - &lt;em&gt;[Arunbear]: Reap: troll&lt;/em&gt;.


&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-06-12 03:50:18&quot; name=&quot;2007-06-12 03:50:18&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-06-12 03:50:18]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://619888], was considered by [Old_Gray_Bear] for &lt;i&gt;Retitle: &quot;I need help porting a script from Mac to Windows&quot;, perhaps.&lt;/i&gt; at Keep: 9, Edit: 18, Reap: 0
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-06-04 07:19:57&quot; name=&quot;2007-06-04 07:19:57&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-06-04 07:19:57]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

I've unconsidered [id://617742], was considered by [planetscape]: &lt;i&gt;Reap: troll&lt;/i&gt; at Keep: 11, Edit: 0, Reap: 26
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[g0n],[localtime://2007-05-31 11:39:00]&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
FYI, the 'node stash' is offline at the moment. The server it was on has blown a power supply, and since I'm planning on moving aboard my boat full time later in the summer there seems little point in fixing it urgently. I'm trying to migrate the data &amp; script to a hosted server I have some space on at the moment, so there'll be a new location for it when it comes back on line. Apologies for any inconvenience.&lt;p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-05-26 17:14:31&quot; name=&quot;2007-05-26 17:14:31&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-05-26 17:14:31]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[id://607124] at {keep:3 edit:34 reap:1}, which was considered on 2007-03-29 - &lt;em&gt;	[planetscape]: Please reparent under [id://607080], to which this is a follow-up.&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
and
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[id://607126] at {keep:2 edit:37 reap:0}, which was considered on 2007-03-29 - &lt;em&gt;	[planetscape]: Please reparent under [id://607080], to which this is a follow-up.&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[g0n],[localtime://2007-05-18 13:33:00]&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://615656] - considered by [TStanley] for code tags. Looks like the OP has added them in.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[castaway], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-05-16 08:17:33&quot; name=&quot;2007-05-16 08:17:33&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-05-16 08:17:33]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Maybe I mismade my point. As [tye] said, moving what appear to be trolling nodes into a special section just gives them the attention they are seeking, which encourages the poster, and indeed they will be likely to repost.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I've thought a bit about the perlishness (or not) of the post. And indeed in my opinion, off-topic is there for posts which are not about perl, this site, it's users, or in any way associated with any of those. My reaction to the actual content would probably be to treat it like any other discussion about the fate of perl, we've had many, why is it that the ones with normal tone get actually discussed, and the ones with a somewhat attacking tone, like this one, get labeled as trolls? Granted, that may be the intention, but if people could ignore the abrasiveness and discuss the issue as normal, we wouldn't have trolling problems.. Ok, now I've gone on way too long ;)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-05-15 02:21:41&quot; name=&quot;2007-05-15 02:21:41&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-05-15 02:21:41]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I was originally in support of moving the node to the off-topic section because it seemed a good alternative to the (currently imaginary) &quot;don't approve&quot; flag. But looking at the other off-topic nodes, the trollishness is not representative for off-topic nodes. I agree that handing out any special flags for trolls will be like an achievement badge, so just ignoring such posts likely will be the best course of &quot;action&quot;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-05-14 20:25:34&quot; name=&quot;2007-05-14 20:25:34&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-05-14 20:25:34]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I see three topics here; the trollishness, meditationness, and off-topicness of the post
in question:
&lt;p&gt;
I think taking extra action like moving to offtopic in response to trollishness is like
waving a red flag in front of a bull.  I'd really rather not see trolls go there.
&lt;p&gt;
I really don't want to get into the business of judging whether
something that claims to be a meditation is really a meditation.  I don't see anything productive coming of that.  If it were clearly not an attempt at a meditation, and didn't
fit under any other category, it might be a candidate for offtopic.  But this is far from such a case.  (AFAIK there isn't consensus about what to use offtopic for, but my inclination is to use it for things that are offtopic and are also not question/meditation/etc. sparingly, particularly when such a node gets moved multiple times and is creating a furor over what to do with it.)
&lt;p&gt;
I really don't want to get into the business of judging whether something that claims to be about perl is really about perl.  This particular node has me pretty much in the dark as to its actual point; this especially is a flag to me to just leave it alone.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-05-14 19:37:30&quot; name=&quot;2007-05-14 19:37:30&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-05-14 19:37:30]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I agreed with [castaway] before seeing what she wrote.  Arguments like &quot;The node isn't &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; about Perl; it is just &lt;em&gt;pretending&lt;/em&gt; to be about Perl&quot; can be used to justify anything so I don't think they are appropriate.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As for &quot;discouraging trolling&quot; the immediate reaction of the author in this case was to offer to repost it.  The best thing to do with trolls is to ignore them, not give them special status, something to shoot for or to rail against (or, as some would surely claim, to pretend to rail against).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I suspect that the consensus &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; that the node was not off topic and so it was inappropriate to designate as &lt;em&gt;completely&lt;/em&gt; off-topic by putting it into the non-section.  But others need to speak up either way.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I haven't seen the author complaining about the characterizations made about his node.  He certainly did complain about it being labeled as &quot;off topic&quot;, which of course he would if he isn't going to stop pretending.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
My response to the troll nodes is mostly to downvote replies, especially replies that go on-and-on about this troll and that troll.  Sometimes I notice someone who appears to have a problem with being able to ignore trolling and I /msg them.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-05-14 18:27:36&quot; name=&quot;2007-05-14 18:27:36&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-05-14 18:27:36]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Is&lt;/em&gt; it about Perl? Is it even a Meditation? IMHO, such posts where the intention is clearly to abuse or cry wolf, and the poster has a history of trolling are a good fit for the offtopic zone - this might even discourage trolling. It would be good if we could could come to a consensus on this one way or another.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[castaway], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-05-13 14:50:11&quot; name=&quot;2007-05-13 14:50:11&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-05-13 14:50:11]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I consider this quite inappropriate use of the offtopic section, since it was clearly about perl. Also Evan didn't seem to get a message that his node was moved. Even if things appear to be trolling, that's no reason not to be polite. I've moved it back.. any objections?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-05-13 13:57:28&quot; name=&quot;2007-05-13 13:57:28&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-05-13 13:57:28]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I've moved [id://615177] to the offtopic zone, because it is clearly a troll post, and not the first from this particular poster.
I was tempted to do the same with an earlier troll post [id://613233], but considered it instead as that's perhaps the more conventional way of handling such posts (though mabye not the most effective way - if there is one).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I realize this may not be considered an appropriate use of the offtopic zone - if you feel this is the case please say so, and I'll put it back where it was (Meditations).
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-05-13 09:05:05&quot; name=&quot;2007-05-13 09:05:05&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-05-13 09:05:05]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered 

[id://606563] {Keep: 2, Edit: 44, Reap: 0}, which was considered on 2007-03-26 - &lt;em&gt;[Joost]: edit: reparent under [id://606552]&lt;/em&gt;.

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-05-10 11:04:57&quot; name=&quot;2007-05-10 11:04:57&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-05-10 11:04:57]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://613047], was considered by [parv] for &quot;mark OT: OP is Perless, and is general enough to be done in any programming language&quot; at Keep: 7, Edit: 19, Reap: 3
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-05-07 09:47:22&quot; name=&quot;2007-05-07 09:47:22&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-05-07 09:47:22]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered 

&lt;p&gt;[id://610121] {keep:9 edit:0 reap:16}, which was considered on 2007-04-16 - &lt;em&gt;[ajt]: link spam?&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
and
&lt;p&gt;[id://609561] {Keep: 21, Edit: 24, Reap: 1}, which was considered on 2007-04-12 - &lt;em&gt;[Old_Gray_Bear]: Please mark as OT&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-05-01 02:48:33&quot; name=&quot;2007-05-01 02:48:33&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-05-01 02:48:33]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The consideration of [id://612713]:
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Edit: suggest retitle: &quot;How to use gzip from Perl under Win32?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
Keep: 2, Edit: 23, Reap: 1
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
is a terrific example of how taking a lousy title and fixing it up greatly
changes the meaning of the question (something that should be avoided even
when to a much lesser extent, IMO).
Agree or disagree?  Comments?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-04-27 05:26:57&quot; name=&quot;2007-04-27 05:26:57&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-04-27 05:26:57]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://607303], was considered by [adrianh] for 'reap = spam?' at Keep: 10, Edit: 1, Reap: 30
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-04-23 02:39:10&quot; name=&quot;2007-04-23 02:39:10&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-04-23 02:39:10]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://609561], was considered by [Old_Gray_Bear] for &quot;Please mark as OT&quot; at Keep: 15, Edit: 21, Reap: 1
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://609974], was considered by [shmem] for &quot;reparent to [Deprecating CPAN modules?], to which this is a reply it would seem&quot; at Keep: 3, Edit: 17, Reap: 0
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://609381], was 
considered by [ikegami] for &quot;Unapprove. Completely unrelated to Perl.&quot; Keep: 8, Edit: 12, Reap: 10
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://608919], was 
considered by [talexb] for &quot;Reap: I should have used a /msg, as per jdporter. Keep: 13, Edit: 1, Reap: 15&quot;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://608623], was
considered by[adrianh] for &quot;edit == Mark OT?&quot; Keep: 5, Edit: 19, Reap: 7
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-04-04 03:20:44&quot; name=&quot;2007-04-04 03:20:44&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-04-04 03:20:44]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://605578], was considered by [Joost] for 'edit: add formatting. (OP msg'd)' at Keep: 5, Edit: 36, Reap: 0. It had no visible &quot;real text&quot; formatting to be htmlified anyway.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-03-28 07:18:17&quot; name=&quot;2007-03-28 07:18:17&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-03-28 07:18:17]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://604767], was considered by [Old_Gray_Bear] for 'Please mark OT: There is no Perl question here. (Almost no question at all, really)' at Keep: 6, Edit: 26, Reap: 2
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-03-27 09:15:57&quot; name=&quot;2007-03-27 09:15:57&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-03-27 09:15:57]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://606103]. Was considered: [friedo] for 'fix code tag' (was done by author) at Keep: 4, Edit: 19, Reap: 0
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[Corion], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-03-27 04:24:06&quot; name=&quot;2007-03-27 04:24:06&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-03-27 04:24:06]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://606516]. Was considered: [Skeeve] for 'remove' at Keep: 28, Edit: 3, Reap: 9
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[g0n], [localtime://2007-03-22 09:26:00]&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://605702] (considered for 'tidy the code') and /msg'd the considerer.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2007-03-19 17:36:27]&lt;br/&gt;
Janitors have done &lt;c&gt;s/\n\n/\n&lt;p&gt;\n/&lt;/c&gt; or equivalent, but that is of minimal help in this case.  Janitors shouldn't &lt;em&gt;invent&lt;/em&gt; formatting, though.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[GrandFather], [localtime://2007-03-20 08:48:27]&lt;br/&gt;
Should we /msg [Joost] wrt the consideration on [id://605578] saying that Janitors don't do that?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], [localtime://2007-03-15 04:04:27]&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://603634], was considered by [NovMonk]: &lt;i&gt;move to discussion?&lt;/i&gt; at Keep: 8, Edit: 36, Reap: 1
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], [localtime://2007-03-13 06:29:08]&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://602145], was considered by [OfficeLinebacker]: &lt;i&gt;How about presenting the code with some linebreaks in there?&lt;/i&gt; at Keep: 20, Edit: 32, Reap: 0
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2007-03-06 17:01:03]&lt;br/&gt;
I went ahead and did this; it looks a little funny with no clear label for the checkbox, but if the box is left unchecked they'll get a cluestick error message.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2007-03-06 14:34:00]&lt;br/&gt;
So we need to move the checkbox for those who don't know that you are supposed to click it &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; you've finished composing your reasons (I don't have to worry much because I have my primary PM browser set to prompt me before submitting). :)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[yitzchak], [localtime://2007-03-06 14:16:11]&lt;br/&gt;

I /msg'd him too, he meant to type &quot;correct spelling in title&quot;, typed core and meant to hit backspace but hit enter instead :)

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], [localtime://2007-03-06 09:03:03]&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://603188] - it was considered for 'core' at Keep: 11, Edit: 3, Reap: 1. I've &lt;c&gt;/msg&lt;/c&gt;'ed [wazoox] for what he meant by that...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[g0n], [localtime://2007-03-01 12:52:00]&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://601998] - it was considered for 'abbreviate code listing' which seemed to me suggesting editing node content. The node has readmores anyway. I've /msg'd the considerer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], [localtime://2007-03-01 04:13:29]&lt;br/&gt;
I mentioned that as a &lt;c&gt;/msg&lt;/c&gt; but on second thought it's better to document it here &lt;c&gt;:)&lt;/c&gt; - I think it's completely acceptable to unconsider these nodes as they won't be reaped anyway.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[GrandFather], [localtime://2007-02-29 15:28:00]&lt;br/&gt;Is it acceptable to unconsider [id://600477] and [id://600749] (both considered for reapage a week ago) without vote annotation on the grounds that a week has gone by and reconsideration is unlikely to happen?&lt;br/&gt;
Update: unconsidered on advice.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], [localtime://2007-02-23 03:25:36]&lt;br/&gt;
IMO no change is necessary at all. The error, if you want, was that [GrandFather] used the thread retitler for retitling a single node, which was overkill. The thread retitler unconsiders rightly IMO, because retitling a thread should mostly be done via a consideration anyway. Retitling a single node can be done via editing it, and that doesn't reset the consideration...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], [localtime://2007-02-22 21:21:09]&lt;br /&gt;
Mark-as-OT &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; unconsider shouldn't it?  Many considerations are &quot;Mark as off topic&quot;, so it would be reasonable to unconsider them after the action is performed.  I'm just advocating the capability to override the default behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2007-02-22 13:33:55]&lt;br/&gt;
Or maybe a mark-as-dup checkbox (I hope the mark-as-OT checkbox doesn't unconsider?)
Or both.
&lt;p&gt;
On second thought, I think I'd rather have (dup) just be added on the one node, not a
whole (sub)thread.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], [localtime://2007-02-22 11:32:34]&lt;br /&gt;
That brings up a good point.  The retitling page automatically unconsiders the top level node being retitled.  There should be a check-box for unconsidering, where &quot;unconsider&quot; is the default.  Unchecking the box would prevent the automatic unconsidering.  &lt;small&gt;(This paragraph has really made Firefox's spell checker mad... apparently any version of the word 'unconsider' is misspelled. ;)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[GrandFather], [localtime://2007-02-22 22:06:00]&lt;br/&gt;
Apologies, I retitled [id://601513] to indicate it was a duplicate and that reset [Corion]'s consideration for reapage. Was adding &quot;(dup)&quot; to the start of the title appropriate?


&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2007-02-19 13:56:14]&lt;br/&gt;
I'm unconsidering a few old considerations that don't seem to be going anywhere.
There doesn't seem a lot of point in cluttering the doctext with &quot;unconsidered&quot; notes for these.
&lt;p&gt;[id://542185]&lt;br /&gt;
Considered: [adrianh]: edit = Move to PL/Perl - Oracle &quot;decode( )&quot; for Postgresql?&lt;br /&gt;
Keep: 11, Edit: 23, Reap: 2
&lt;p&gt;[id://599267]&lt;br /&gt;
Considered: [jdporter]: move to SOPW&lt;br /&gt;
Keep: 11, Edit: 21, Reap: 1
&lt;p&gt;[id://598346]&lt;br /&gt;
Considered: [Moron]: belongs as reply of main thread rather than to branch&lt;br /&gt;
Keep: 4, Edit: 19, Reap: 0
&lt;p&gt;[id://600215]&lt;br /&gt;
Considered: [lin0]: must fix link to the Python programming language. Currently it points to a porn site&lt;br /&gt;
Keep: 7, Edit: 21, Reap: 4
&lt;p&gt;[id://600246]&lt;br /&gt;Considered: [lin0]: should delete link in text: &quot;exposed breasts&quot; . It currently points to a porn site.&lt;br /&gt;
Keep: 8, Edit: 20, Reap: 4
&lt;p&gt;[id://600406]&lt;br /&gt;Considered: [BrowserUk]: Remove double spacing&lt;br /&gt;
Keep: 10, Edit: 14, Reap: 0
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2007-02-15 23:11:20]&lt;br /&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://598307], was &quot;Considered: [ww]: code tags, please, op msg'd&quot; (Keep: 2, Edit: 41, Reap: 0).  I don't see any real need to add code tags.  I did add p and br tags to make the output formatting match the input.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], [localtime://2007-01-30 16:04:03]&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://594923], was &quot;Considered: [Errto]: Delete - dup of Re^2: Question about eval which is more complete Keep: 3, Edit: 5, Reap: 29 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], [localtime://2007-01-24 07:40:36]&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://595222], was &quot;
Considered: [ww]: mark OT; OP /msgd for &quot;any Perl nexus?&quot;&quot; (Keep: 7, Edit: 19, Reap: 1).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[Corion], [localtime://2007-01-18 03:56:49]&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered [id://594768] (Keep: 8, Edit: 18, Reap: 5) - it was considered &quot;[Old_Gray_Bear]: OT: No real Perl content.&quot;. I've also messaged the considerer because of the consideration - the node even contains Perl content (or at least the word Perl).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2007-01-15 03:38:31]&lt;br/&gt;
IMO, considerations that say &quot;something like&quot; are fair game for unconsidering, even if what follows is reasonable and the voting is all positive.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], [localtime://2007-01-15 02:38:47]&lt;br/&gt;
I've unconsidered  [id://594694], because it now contains code tags, was
&lt;i&gt;Considered: [Tanktalus]: code tags, please&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], [localtime://2007-01-14 23:12:14]&lt;br /&gt;
I'm unconsidering [id://594516].  [bsdz] tried to consider it for title change, but the consideration was unclear, lacked an actionable title suggestion, and resulted in a vote of 15/10/0 in favor of keeps:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Considered: [bsdz]: title should be something like copying multidimensional arrays or list of array refs&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm sending [bsdz] a message to request that he try to make his considerations clearer.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[planetscape], [localtime://2007-01-13 02:46:54]&lt;br/&gt;
I unconsidered both 
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[id://304060] [Aristotle]: restore content 	keep:2 edit:5 reap:0 	2007-01-12
(16 hours ago) 	
&lt;li&gt;[id://304044] [Aristotle]: restore content 	keep:2 edit:6 reap:0 	2007-01-12
(16 hours ago)
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
as per discussion with [Aristotle], while the nodes had content inside sig tags, his custom CSS prevented him from seeing sigs; there was, therefore, no need to &quot;restore content&quot;; and when asked, he stated 
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;
I'd want to re-consider them as &quot;edit to move main content out of sig tags&quot;
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2007-01-09 18:54:06]&lt;br/&gt;
I unconsidered [id://592766] w/o waiting for many votes, because the requested edits were not something [janitors] should do (&quot;[ptum]: edit: reformat for readability, remove gratuitous double-space, integrate comments with code.&quot;).  I /msg'd [ptum] that [janitors] don't do such extensive editting and that the problems don't pose a hazard to navigation and therefore any changes would have to be requested of the author. (&lt;b&gt;Update:&lt;/b&gt; And I've recently unconsidered several inappropriate considerations after enough 'keep' votes arrived and /msg'd the considerers that their requests were in regard to relative trivia that didn't pose a hazard to navigation.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2007-01-07 01:38:44]&lt;br/&gt;
Such people cannot come back under the same name. I make sure of that, actually.  And coming back under a different name gives them no power to re-wipe the nodes that were reverted and so makes no difference on this point.  I meant &quot;user&quot; as in the authorization unit, not as in the person behind it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I guess I have  seen node contents restored and didn't see a scuffle break out.  In some cases, anyway, it may have been a wake-up call and worked out fine (in most cases it appears to have not obviously worked out badly).  But I still am uncomfortable with it conceptually and am usually uncomfortable with it in practice and so usually won't execute such requests.  I'm uncomfortable even with just some of the implications of the request being made.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In one case, there was a user having clear difficulty and they expressed difficulty with restoring the content and so janitorial assistance, though not explicitly and clearly requested, seemed appropriate.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So, I think such considerations are tollerable as a way to show the author how many people think the content should be restored.  But I'd rather the janitorial role be to ask the user to do the restoration themselves, pointing them to documentation about how to better deal with regret, or at least getting permission before restoring.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Unfortunately, I don't see a stellar method for a janitor to take up such tasks, preventing of piling-on of cajoling from janitors.  I guess a note in the wiki will do.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2007-01-07 00:59:04]&lt;br/&gt;
Re &quot;still-active&quot;, when do you (or others) think it would be appropriate?  I'm not sure why still-active makes a difference, unless you're thinking of the times folk have wiped several nodes and departed in a fit of pique.  But such people are pretty likely to come back, if not necessarily under the same name.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2007-01-06 13:57:55]&lt;br/&gt;
I've long puzzled over the concept of &quot;restore original content&quot; for a node of a still-active user.  Sounds like an invitation to a wiki-style revert war.  I just interpret the consideration as a request of the author.  Too bad they don't get a /msg notification of the consideration.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Corion], [localtime://2007-01-06 10:15:01]&lt;br/&gt;
I'm of two minds regarding the restoration of [id://592628] - I already looked into restoring its content, but as the content isn't really worthy of restoral and would only lead to further downvotes on the ill-advised post, I've refrained from it so far. I'm leaning towards leaving the node as is and unconsidering it. If you think otherwise, either restore it or discuss &lt;tt&gt;:)&lt;/tt&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

Continued in [id://593415]...
































































































































































</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>68046</type_nodetype>
  <node_id>74283</node_id>
  <author_user>979</author_user>
  <title>editors' wiki</title>
  <createtime>2001-07-14 06:15:20</createtime>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-15 10:15:34</nodeupdated>
</node>
