<node>
  <doctext>&lt;p&gt;Still updatable as of 2006-03-27&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[CowboyNeal] was here!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
testing -- vroom&lt;br&gt;
I have added a line to the Wiki test -- jcwren&lt;br&gt;
I have added a new line to the wiki test -- vroom&lt;br&gt;
I am adding another line -- jcwren&lt;br&gt;
Cool!  A wiki! :-) -- tilly&lt;br&gt;
But it's not made of Jellybeans... -- jcwren&lt;br&gt;
[vroom] wants to be [chromatic] when he gets old and cranky ... -- chromatic&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I had a couple different thoughts on this: Should only saints and saints-1 be allowed to create Wiki nodes?  Dunno, just a thought to prevent a massive amount being created.  There should definitely be a viewing level the creator can set.  We can use these for [editors] and [power users] discussions, etc.  Thoughts? Oh yea, and while AMs may have viewing rights, they definitely won't have editing abilities. You know what else would be cool in general?  Meta-variables.  Something like &amp;#091;%S&amp;#093; (for date/time), &amp;#091;%T&amp;#093; (for time only), and &amp;#091;%D&amp;#093; (for date only), which the engine would replace with the current date and time when the node is submitted.  One could add date/time stamps like at the end here.  -- jcwren 2001/03/29 01:08:00 EST&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;'If I heard a voice from heaven say &quot;live without loving&quot;,
    I'd beg off.  Girls are such exquisite hell.'
&lt;/code&gt;[Ovid] &lt;code&gt;quoting Ovid on 2001/03/30.&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oooh - [Ovid] using &lt;tt&gt;&amp;lt;pre&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt; tags. I changed them to &lt;tt&gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt; tags to remove this bad example &lt;tt&gt;:)&lt;/tt&gt; &lt;tt&gt;-- [Corion] 2001/03/30&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
The above begged the obvious question:  what's wrong with &lt;tt&gt;&amp;lt;pre&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/pre&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt; tags?  For poetry, format is often as important as the words, so I felt that I should preserve it, but it &lt;em&gt;isn't&lt;/em&gt; code.  The code tags that [Corion] put in there broke the link on &quot;Ovid&quot; (I switched it back from &lt;tt&gt;&amp;#91;Ovid&amp;#93;&lt;/tt&gt;, but kept the code tags).  If there's a reason not to use &lt;tt&gt;&amp;lt;pre&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/pre&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt; tags, I'd love to know and I'll avoid them.

&lt;p&gt;This raises another question:  barring a significant problem with someone else's words, should we change them or their code, HTML, etc? (though I will confess to closing a &lt;tt&gt;&amp;lt;tt&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt; tag that [Corion] missed :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Ovid] -- 2001/04/02&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I apologize &lt;font size=&quot;5&quot; color=&quot;red&quot;&gt;Plus,&lt;/font&gt; for messing up that &lt;font size=&quot;5&quot; color=&quot;red&quot;&gt;it's&lt;/font&gt; &amp;#91;Ovid&amp;#93; error. My personal &lt;font size=&quot;5&quot; color=&quot;red&quot;&gt;distressing&lt;/font&gt; stance
 on PRE &lt;font size=&quot;5&quot; color=&quot;red&quot;&gt;to&lt;/font&gt; tags is, that these &lt;font size=&quot;5&quot; color=&quot;red&quot;&gt;see&lt;/font&gt; break the (ridiculously low) limit &lt;font size=&quot;5&quot; color=&quot;red&quot;&gt;that&lt;/font&gt; that a
 user might have &lt;font size=&quot;5&quot; color=&quot;red&quot;&gt;your&lt;/font&gt; set for CODE, and thus I always changed PRE to CODE, as &lt;font size=&quot;5&quot; color=&quot;red&quot;&gt;work has been changed&lt;/font&gt;
 I think/thought that user-prefer &lt;font size=&quot;5&quot; color=&quot;red&quot;&gt;by&lt;/font&gt;ences have higher precedence than
 poster-preferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is OK for &lt;font size=&quot;5&quot; color=&quot;red&quot;&gt;someone&lt;/font&gt; normal code (and also provides a &lt;i&gt;download&lt;/i&gt; link),
 but with poetry, I see that [Ovid] has a point, as poetry is something where
 I'm willing to give the &lt;font size=&quot;5&quot; color=&quot;red&quot;&gt;else :)&lt;/font&gt; poster more rights than the user, because, as [Ovid]
 already stated, the form(at) is as important as the content.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;[Corion] &lt;font size=&quot;5&quot; color=&quot;red&quot;&gt;and [Ovid] ;)&lt;/font&gt;-- 2001/04/02&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Ovid] would also like everyone to know that he wouldn't dream of pulling this stunt on a &quot;non-test&quot; wiki :).  Also, if you're using a text-based browser, the above is probably garbage!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye]: I don't remove &lt;code&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags willy-nilly but I often find them being used with horrendously long lines (I'd put an example here, but that would just suck) and I yank those and &lt;b&gt;feel good about it&lt;/b&gt;.  If you keep your line length under 60, then &lt;code&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;/code&gt; is just fine.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I also remove gratuitous &lt;code&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags when they are used
as I'm using them here, that is, to break lines too infrequently so&lt;br&gt;
that the formatting done by your browser just gets
all defeated.  Like &lt;code&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags, I don't just
remove every &lt;code&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/code&gt; I find, but only the&lt;br&gt; ones that
are likely to render poorly for a large section of&lt;br&gt; the audience.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr size=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[OeufMayo] - Wow, wiki in the Monastery! What more can I expect of life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
[amelinda] - a bazillion dollars, a slave girl named &quot;Jemira&quot;, and a T1 plugged into the firewall in your skull?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size=-1&gt;[myocom] - Is that like a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tmbg.com&quot;&gt;Birdhouse in Your Soul&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;table border=1 cellspacing=0 cellpadding=6&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;
Dear Santa,
&lt;p&gt;
Just ask [amelinda].
&lt;p&gt;
Thanks - [epoptai]
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
-----BEGIN PGP SIGNED MESSAGE-----
Hash: SHA1

Murali Gana Lola Nanda Gopa Bala
Ravo Ravo Radha Lola Radha Lola
Thretha Yugamuna Sita Ramudai
Dvapari Yugamuna Radha Loludayi
Githanu Drapina Taraka Namudaiy
Yuga Yuga Manduna Tagu Rupa Dhairyai

    -- Sathya Sai Baba (sung), quoted by premchai21
-----BEGIN PGP SIGNATURE-----
Version: GnuPG v1.0.6 (GNU/Linux)
Comment: For info see http://www.gnupg.org

iD8DBQE7qjs41fuSPH+onEsRAmsVAKDJyFeWRcdVZNifn1xrO8rx9lkXFQCfaxgM
j5O2+QZL84ES/KqSGLcDtWA=
=CloY
-----END PGP SIGNATURE-----
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D'oh!&lt;br&gt;I thought it said &quot;Wiggi!&quot; -- Mr. Muskrat&lt;/p&gt;



</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>68046</type_nodetype>
  <node_id>68049</node_id>
  <author_user>979</author_user>
  <title>PerlMonks Sample Wiki</title>
  <createtime>2001-03-29 04:02:32</createtime>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-03 05:59:01</nodeupdated>
</node>
