<node>
  <doctext>Tomorrow, all the [gods] become [punsters] and all the [pirates] become [gods].  You have been Warned.

&lt;p&gt;

Write permission changed to level 10.  Deal.

&lt;p&gt;let &lt;tt&gt;x = x&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;I met this guy - and he looked like might have been a hat check clerk at an ice rink. Which, in fact, he turned out to be. And I said: Oh boy. Right again.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter|You] &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; [id://73988|home].

&lt;p&gt;[lucky://&quot;this is the time&quot; &quot;this is the record of the time&quot;|This is the time.  And this is the record of the time.] ([jdporter], 2004-08-11)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[grinder] just had to fiddle with the title (2004-06-02)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido] hands out Groucho Marx nose glasses and elasticized &quot;ball &amp; paddle&quot; toys to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[blokhead] wanders past without incident (2004-01-26)&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ybiC] thinks that now is the time for all good monks to come to the aid of their monastery. &amp;nbsp; (2004-01-22)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[barrd] gets a word in edgewise and waves hello to everymonk (2004/01/22)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ehrmm... One from Crete is a Cretan (in English, anyway); and one suffering from congenital idiocy is a cretin.  Let these corrections fall where they may... ([jdporter], 2004-01-18)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[TStanley] checks out the [id://73988|wiki] and leaves his mark (2004-01-17)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey, you misspelled Cretean, you cretan!  ([theorbtwo] is one, by ancestery.  Crete is a Greek island.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Limbic~Region], the Cretan, was fond of expounding on the fact that all Cretans are liars (2003-09-11)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jeffa] is reminded of the immortal words of Socrates, who said &quot;I drank what?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this is the hour, this is the place, this is this. &lt;i&gt;I.e.&lt;/i&gt; this is the place [grinder|I] was talking about [id://268305|here]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[BazB] makes his mark on da Wiki, just because he can. (2003-08-25)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[diotalevi] Loves Chotchkies! &lt;i&gt;2003-06-23&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[CowboyNeal] loves you too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[monkfan] PM meant so much to me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
One Wiki to rule them all, One Wiki to find them,&lt;br /&gt;
One Wiki to bring them all and in secret bind them,&lt;br /&gt;
In the Land of Vroomitude where the Monks go by.&lt;!--29008 :) happy new year --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;[The Mad Hatter] spraypaints &lt;/i&gt;&quot;Kilroy Was Here&quot;&lt;i&gt; across the wiki.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;first edit of 2003?! whooo ... [wil], 2003, sometime, maybe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;You see two pillars.  One is marked The Orb One, and is blank.  The second is marked [theorbtwo].  There is a small plaque, that says:&lt;/i&gt; [theorbtwo] 2002-12-29 15:05 EST&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A wiki is a terrible thing to waste... - [Mr. Muskrat] 2002-12-09 13:00:?? CST
&lt;p&gt;
On that node, he had a wiki - with a wiki, wiki here and a wiki, wiki there, here a wiki, there a wiki ... mighty [vroom] had a wiki of love - [rob_au] 2002-11-14 20:33 AEST
&lt;p&gt;
=head1 Holy Schnikes!!!!
&lt;p&gt;
I can't believe I missed this one ~ [podmaster] ~ Fri Sep  6 14:38:29 2002 GMT

&lt;p&gt;
Kilroy was here
&lt;p&gt;
vroom vroom vroom ya ya ya ya vroom-vroom-vroom-vroom [belg4mit] 2002-16-01
&lt;p&gt;
What wicked wikies we weave... [MeowChow] 2007-02-33
&lt;br&gt;
...when first we hack these to receive. - ([Petruchio], May 10th, 2001)
&lt;p&gt;
aren't you lucky you can read this?
&lt;p&gt;Um, I guess :) [Ovid] 2001-04-19.  I assume that this &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; to play with, right?&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;Out of curiousity, what are the restrictions on this one? ([tilly] 2001-04-19)
&lt;p&gt;I have heard the wikis singing each to each. I do not think they will sing to me. &lt;i&gt;Love Song of J. Garciuh Prufrock&lt;/i&gt; [jerrygarciuh] 2.02.02
&lt;p&gt;
I heard &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.everydevel.com&quot;&gt;EDC&lt;/a&gt; was planning on stranding [vroom] on a wiki with only the wickedest [Saints in our Book|companions] to keep him company.  BRUTAL!  ([chromatic])&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;font color=&quot;#750000&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;All your wiki are belong to us.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt; ([ar0n] - 2001-04-24)&lt;br&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
mmmm....special access...What kind of HTML tags are allowed in here. This should be a place for the higher level monks, like a paradise :) ([damian1301] 4-24-01)&lt;P&gt;
Almost as good as being able to teleport into the [45399|pool room]... &lt;br&gt;
Incidentally, since we're (almost) all grownups here: it sure looks like 
you could change the title of this node; that could get a little messy, eh? 
 - ([Petruchio], May 4th, 2001).
&lt;p&gt;cool, i can write here now. i couldn't earlier. wikis should be free for all! -[ailie]
&lt;p&gt;I second [ailie] on that one. Free Wikis for Everybody! Fresh Wikis for Everybody! Who wants the Fresh Wikis! - [OeufMayo] 20010509&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love EDB and his/her/its cousin, [NodeReaper]! -- [N-Wing]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shhh.... I'm hunting Wikis... ([Zoogie] Wed May 09 2001)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/me is not vewy quiet at all ... h-h-h-h-huh([arturo] May 14 2001)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;all the birds sing words and the flowers croon in the wiki wiki wiki wiki wiki room!  ([Vynce] December 13 2001)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;a little nonsense now and then is relished by the wisest men&quot; -- i'd say that's fitting for this crazy nizzode -- ([jrsmith] 04/03/2002)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Naturally, the common people don&#194;&amp;#8217;t want war, but after all, it is the leaders of a country who determine policy, and it is always a simple matter to drag people along whether it is a democracy, or a fascist dictatorship, or a parliament, or a communist dictatorship. Voice or no voice, the people can always be brought to the bidding of the leaders. This is easy. All you have to do is tell them they are being attacked, and denounce the pacifists for lack of patriotism and exposing the country to danger. It works the same in every country.&quot; &lt;br/&gt;
Hermann Goering, (1899-1946), Nazi Reich Marshall, Nuremburg Trials, 18 April 1946.&lt;br/&gt;

As related to Gustave Gilbert at the Nuremberg trials, from the book Nuremberg Diary.&lt;br/&gt;-- (added by [EdwardG] 20040602)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;(2005-07-21) [neshura]'s draft text on Editor Powers has been turned into a [id://475618|faqlet].&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
By the pricking of my thumbs, something Wiki'd this way comes.
&lt;br&gt; [Old_Gray_Bear|OGB]

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 
ARE YOU THREATENING ME? I AM CORNHOLIO!!! BRRRRRAAAAH!!!!
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[Dhoss]&lt;/i&gt;&amp;copy;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;i&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href=&quot;#2009-08-12 12:26:45&quot; name=&quot;2009-08-12 12:26:45&quot;&gt;[localtime://2009-08-12 12:26:45]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;











</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>68046</type_nodetype>
  <node_id>73988</node_id>
  <author_user>979</author_user>
  <title>q/&quot;vroom's phantasmagorically phreaky w-w-w-wiki of phunky love fandango (thunderbolts, lightning, and rain, Oh My!)&quot; is the new black/ considered harmful and door marked &quot;Beware of the Leopard&quot;... or so said your mama last night</title>
  <createtime>2001-04-19 20:42:33</createtime>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-10 03:54:07</nodeupdated>
</node>
