<node>
  <doctext>&lt;h3&gt;Resources for [QandAEditors]:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[id://1843]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[vroom]'s kick-off: [id://20057]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our faqlet: [id://20059]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[href://?node_id=48824;recipient=11732|Our message inbox]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An old (but interesting) [id://17060]. See the rest of the thread too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additional old PMDs and Quests: [id://11208], [id://11053], [id://11736], [id://13235], [id://16722]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;3rd Annual Great [id://1843] Cleanup is Under Way!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;[QandAEditors], Stake out your categories here:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;table border=1 cellspacing=0 cellpadding=0&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;th rowspan=2 valign=bottom&gt;Category&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;th colspan=2&gt;Acquired&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;th colspan=2&gt;Released&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;th rowspan=2 valign=bottom&gt;Status&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;th&gt;by user&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;th&gt;on date&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;th&gt;by user&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;th&gt;on date&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://1824|arrays]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://1830|CGI programming]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; [Russ] &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; 2007-01-11&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;started&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://1829|data formatting]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[jdporter]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;2006-11-02&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[jdporter]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;2006-11-17&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://1831|database programming]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;not started&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://1837|dates and times]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;not started&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://1834|debugging]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;not started&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://1840|directories]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;not started&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://1839|files]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;not started&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://15433|GUI Programming]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[jdporter]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;2006-12-21&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;started&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://1825|hashes]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;not started&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://1841|HTTP and FTP clients]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;not started&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://2661|input and output]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;not started&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://1875|mail and news]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;not started&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://1828|math]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;not started&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://1974|Data Structures]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;not started&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://1842|network programming]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;not started&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://1827|numbers]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;not started&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://1838|object-oriented programming]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;not started&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://1877|programs and processes]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;not started&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://1832|references]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[jdporter]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;2006-11-26&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[jdporter]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;2006-12-04&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://1835|regular expressions]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;not started&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://1836|sorting]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;not started&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://1826|strings]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;not started&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://1833|subroutines]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;not started&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;[id://369495|testing]&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;not started&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Above these lines, put important stuff, most important first.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Below these lines, put chronological updates, newest on top.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;!-- update template:

&lt;p&gt;&lt;wikihead&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

PLEASE leave some blank lines above your entry!
--&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;



&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href=&quot;#2010-04-29 13:29:14&quot; name=&quot;2010-04-29 13:29:14&quot;&gt;[localtime://2010-04-29 13:29:14]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The editor-oriented elements of the Categorized Question display page have been rearranged somewhat for greater convenience;
they are now all grouped together in a &quot;box&quot;, i.e. a &lt;c&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/c&gt; element.
However, this element has no default styling. I'd recommend something like the following (put in your [Display Settings]):
&lt;code&gt;
div.catqa-commandbox { border: thick solid black; padding: 5px; text-align: center; font-size: larger; }
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-07-18 13:55:40&quot; name=&quot;2008-07-18 13:55:40&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-07-18 13:55:40]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
It is now possible to SOPWify Categorized Answers (as well as Questions).
This fact is documented in [id://20059], but until recently (today) it was not actually true.
Please be very cautious in your use of this power.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-06-23 16:03:27&quot; name=&quot;2008-06-23 16:03:27&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-06-23 16:03:27]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The &quot;delete&quot; and &quot;kill&quot; buttons by each CatA listed under a CatQ
are now a radio button group (with a new &quot;nada&quot; option, checked by default), vice the old pair of checkboxes.
This prevents selecting both options... not that it was ever really a problem.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-05-07 09:53:56&quot; name=&quot;2008-05-07 09:53:56&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-05-07 09:53:56]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
OK, [Arunbear]. I was thinking it would have been a good CatQ. There does not seem to be a CatQ (nor Tutorial)
for this question yet.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Arunbear], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-05-06 17:41:39&quot; name=&quot;2008-05-06 17:41:39&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-05-06 17:41:39]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I archived it. I also requested [nirf1] to post the question in SOPW, which (s)he has [id://684561|done].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href=&quot;#2008-05-06 09:11:55&quot; name=&quot;2008-05-06 09:11:55&quot;&gt;[localtime://2008-05-06 09:11:55]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
On 2008-05-04, [QandAEditors|we] received a message in [href://?node_id=48824;recipient=11732|our inbox] 
from [nirf1] saying:
&lt;blockquote&gt;what are the best procedures to call c++ functions (in *.so) from perl ?&lt;/blockquote&gt;
The message has been moved to the Archive folder. Who moved it? Did anybody actually reply to [nirf1]?&lt;br&gt;
I suspect that he sent us this question per the [id://1843] directions, which say 
&lt;blockquote&gt;If you have a good idea for a Categorized Question but you're not
yet of [id://198665], or you don't know how to write the question
appropriately, feel free to &quot;submit&quot; it by sending a [/msg] to the
[QandAEditors].&lt;/blockquote&gt;
But I don't see a new Categorized Question.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], &lt;a href=&quot;#2007-07-17 10:10:11&quot; name=&quot;2007-07-17 10:10:11&quot;&gt;[localtime://2007-07-17 10:10:11]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Today, [ambrus] send us a message:
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;
I suppose you should delete [id://626953].
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
I replied with the following:
&lt;blockquote&gt;
We'd love to delete [id://626953] &#8212; but we do not have the power to delete notes (replies). We could delete the Answer to which it is a reply, and that would carry it into oblivion, mostly, but that's not desirable, obviously. Thanks, though.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;a name=&quot;20070112104322&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2007-01-12 10:43:22]&lt;br/&gt;
No. And as to your inquiry about that question appearing in two categories: That's a typical symptom of the problems afflicting CatQA. And that's why I've suspended my cleanup activities. At least, beyond editing individual posts.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Russ], [localtime://2007-01-11 14:20:02]&lt;br/&gt;
[jdporter]'s links don't seem to show successful resolution.  Any updates?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2006-12-22 12:34:02]&lt;br/&gt;
I don't know about you, but I've been seeing some problems when trying to 
clean up QandA. In particular, the &lt;u&gt;sopwify!&lt;/u&gt; link doesn't function
100% correctly. It changes the node to a sopw, but it doesn't remove the
node from the containing QA category.  Until this situation is fixed, my
QA cleanup activities are on hold.  [id://591317|more info]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2006-11-13 11:00:45]&lt;br/&gt;
Fellow [QandAEditors], I recently revised the text shown in the [id://1843] main page.
This is the essential doc for the section.  Please review, and /msg me any suggestions
for improvement. (Or if you're SDC, you can edit it [id://487795|directly].)
Thanks! 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], [localtime://2006-11-01 19:37:14] &lt;br /&gt;
Sounds good.  Q&amp;AEditors: Add to this list when you take over a category for cleanup, and mark it &lt;em&gt;done&lt;/em&gt; when you're ready to release your evil grip from the polished bones of its once rotten and decaying remains. ;) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;The master list has been moved to the top of this wiki -- [jdporter]&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And [jdporter] is right: be aggressive.  Make it count.  Questions should be good questions, answers should be good answers.  Rewording and rephrasing is fine.  SoPWify the lousy questions, or restate them if they're worth salvaging.    Delete unworkable and bad answers.  If you find the absence of a good question or answer, either ask it yourself, answer it yourself, or maybe post a node in [PerlMonks Discussion] with a list of possible questions and answers that others may wish to contribute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When in doubt, seek clarification here in our wiki.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more thing while I'm thinking about it.  There's no real good reason to attach editor attribution to the nodes you've worked on.  I would even go so far as to remove any you find, or better yet, put any existing attributions (and your own if you feel it's necessary) into &lt;c&gt;&lt;!-- comments --&gt;&lt;/c&gt;.  It's not that important to leave a fingerprint; [QandAEditors|we] own whatever happens here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2006-11-01 13:53:29]&lt;br/&gt;
O.k., so it's time once again to try another great [id://1843] cleanup.
We've got 25 categories, with 813 questions and almost 2500 answers.
We should figure out how to partition these. How about this: When you're
ready to do some work, take the next available section in the list and
starting going through its questions. Use this wiki to indicate what
you're working on and what you've completed.  Let's start by listing
what we've already cleaned up, so it doesn't get revisited needlessly.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
We also need to lay down some groundrules. I'm not sure what those should be. 
[davido] and [jdporter|I] seem to agree that agressive editing of stuff that's
salvageable and deleting of stuff that's totally wrong is acceptable.
Ownership of CatQA nodes is the source of (almost) all that's squirrelly
about this section, so it may be going away some time soon. ;-)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2006-10-31 11:21:57]&lt;br/&gt;
Re: &quot;[ysth], 2004-12-13&quot;, below:&lt;br/&gt;
There was a note from the OP later in the thread in which he clarified that he meant pasting the files column-wise, which is entirely not what most of the Answers were about. I took the liberty of re-writing the Question and deleting all the Answers that were off-track.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I considered that it might be nice not to lose all the work that people had put into answering the wrong question... but given that concatenating two files is trivial by any standard, I decided it would be no great loss.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2006-06-05 10:10:52]&lt;br/&gt;
Thanks, [ysth]; I appreciate your reply. The main reason I asked here, rather than just boldly making it so, is because I'm still trying to get a feel for how things are done in this group. Cheers...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2006-06-05 02:35:19]&lt;br /&gt;
That was me.  I only noticed your mention of it here after the fact, and posted a reply but apparently neglected the update button :), since I don't see it here now.  If it had been a good question, it might have been worth reformatting, but as it was, it seemed best just to SoPWify it.  In general, go ahead and fix things when there's a clearly best course of action, and bring it up here when there's not.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2006-05-22 23:45:40]&lt;br/&gt;
Well, once again, one of [QandAEditors|us] went and did the change without any discussion.
Is that how it works?  Help me out here...
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2006-05-22 10:10:42]&lt;br/&gt;
So, I suppose this is probably a typically border case:
[id://550896] was obviously (to me) written as a SoPW style question, and the first Answer it got wasn't even an answer, but a typical SoPW style reply. So as I see it, this could either be cleaned up into a &quot;good&quot; categorized Question and two Answers; or it &amp;mdash; the whole thread &amp;mdash; can be SoPWified. In fact, the only reason I can think of for doing the former rather than the latter is in case someone thinks &quot;an easy way to list prime numbers 1 to 100&quot; is the kind of information that ought to be presented in a Categorized Q&amp;amp;A style. Thoughts?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2006-05-02 16:52:18]&lt;br/&gt;
Well, it looks like that action has been taken.
Unfortunately, there's no way to tell when or by whom.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[jdporter], [localtime://2006-04-19 14:12:31]&lt;br/&gt;
There's a msg from [dvergin] in our inbox that says
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Can someone who knows something about socket programming filter out [id://6535]? I suspect there's a lot of duplication there
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
That node is actually very, very old. My feeling is that it should
be SOPWifified. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], [localtime://2005-09-07 22:22:33]&lt;br /&gt;
I agree that it is too soon for Perl6 answers to Perl5 questions in CatQ+A.  It may not be too soon for a &lt;b&gt;few&lt;/b&gt; Perl6 &lt;em&gt;questions&lt;/em&gt;, which, of course, should get Perl6 answers.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Eventually (probably pretty soon, since we have working implementations of much of Perl6) the specification for most of Perl6 will be finalized (it appears to still be fluxuating in interesting ways -- from my very-outside perspective), and it will be appropriate for Perl6 answers to appear for general questions.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As with the rest of the Monastery (and the Perl community), at first, Perl6 items should be clearly labeled as such.  Eventually, Perl5 items will also require clear labels.  And after that, Perl6 items will no longer require labels.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&quot;perl6&quot; and &quot;perl5&quot; (no spaces) are good markers.  Put them in brackets of some kind if desired.  &quot;use 6.0&quot; and &quot;use 5.0&quot; are also good markers in my book.  &quot;use v6&quot; and &quot;use 6&quot; are much less clear, in my book.  Even &quot;use v6.0&quot; is less clear to me.  I'd like &quot;use strict&quot; to be a Perl5 marker and asked Larry to make it so, but I never saw a response.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], [localtime://2005-06-15 06:58:44]&lt;br /&gt;
Sounds good to me.  Then [arrays] would just be for general questions that
could apply to any array.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[davido], [localtime://2005-06-15 01:36:22]&lt;br /&gt;
I propose changing [id://1974] to &quot;Data Structures&quot; (removing the word 'Nested').  This will open up the section to Q&amp;A on stacks, queues, linked lists, and heaps.  Yes, some of those are implemented in Perl as nested datastructures, but that point may not be obvious to someone new who is investigating traditional data structures.  This change would also satisfy the need in [id://466695], where the OP wishes to add a Q&amp;A on implementing a simple stack using an array, but believes that people looking to learn how to implement stacks may not immediately think, &quot;Oh, I need to look under Arrays to find my answer.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; it is possible (at least for the [gods] or [pmdev]) to change a Q&amp;A section heading name.  How do the other [QandAEditors] feel about this proposal?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[davido], 2005-03-03&lt;br /&gt;
I agree with [ysth] (again).  It's a useless Q&amp;A entry, in its existing form.  From what I can tell it's a rather awkward way of building some sort of linked list.  ...at least that's what the code seems to do.  On the other hand, the description of the code and its title lead one to think they're about to see a subroutine that could be better written as &lt;code&gt;@hash{@array}=()&lt;/code&gt;.  After pondering the code, this is clearly not the intent, but the description and the code are out of sorts from one another.  Anyway, that's all beside the point; it's not really a Q&amp;A in its current form, and doesn't belong in Q&amp;A.  If someone wanted to post a &quot;How are Linked Lists implemented in Perl?&quot; Q&amp;A that might be worthwhile though (unless there's one already there....off to check...) .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ysth], 2005-03-03&lt;br /&gt;
I'm inclined to encourage [EchoAngel] to repost [id://436280] as a snippet and nuke the existing post.  (Haven't figured out exactly what the code actually does yet.)
Agree or disagree?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ysth], 2004-12-13&lt;br /&gt;
Mostly a note to myself: [id://129969] askes a very confusing question; none of the answers seem to actually fit the question.  Rewrite the question to fit the answers and consolidate the answers?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ysth], 2004-11-29&lt;br /&gt;
re: [id://411099], I've /msg'd the author asking that the body of the question be posted as an answer instead.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[davido], 2004-10-26&lt;br /&gt;
I have long supported the policy of excluding [Anonymous Monk] from posting to [Catagorized Questions &amp; Answers].  Currently they can post answers (not questions).  I too am deleting a couple of AM garbage posts a week.  ...probably four this week already.  I think that [castaway] mentioned the other day that she agrees with such a policy change, though I really should let others speak for themselves.  If I remember correctly, the site documentation already states that Anonymous Monks cannot post to Q&amp;A.  So either the implementation or the documentation need to be changed.  I've held off on changing the documentation, out of a hope that it might be one more voice of support for an implementation change.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ysth], 2004-10-26&lt;br /&gt;
I've been deleting a lot of answers recently (3 or more a week? I've lost track) that are empty or garbage.  It's almost enough to make me think [Anonymous Monk] shouldn't be allowed to post answers.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], 2004-06-26 &lt;br /&gt;
Actually it's probably not appropriate as a Q&amp;A, as it is not presented in a FAQ-like Question and Answer format.  Q&amp;A stuff, to be good, ought to be specifically written with the intent of being a Q&amp;A, or FAQ answer, not just another question that happens to be on a topic covered in Q&amp;A.  We SoPWify good questions sometimes because they were not presented in a Q&amp;A-appropriate format.  Other times we re-work them to turn them into good Q&amp;A entries.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
My suggestion is that if you like the premise of the question, and also like the answers, that you go ahead and write your own post specifically for Q&amp;A covering the question, and presenting an answer.  In your answer, you might link to the SoPW question that you've mentioned, as additional reading material.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Of course we all just offer opinions here, and mine is only one opinion.  Check with some of the other active [QandAEditors] to see what they think too.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[McMahon] 2004-06-26 &lt;br /&gt;This would be perfect for the &quot;testing&quot; section: [id://369868].  But the OP wanted it in SoPW.  Is it rude to move it or dup it to Q&amp;A?&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ysth] 2004-06-24&lt;br /&gt;[demerphq] added it as &quot;testing&quot; (they are all lower case except for acronyms)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[McMahon] 2004-06-24&lt;br /&gt;I still like &quot;Testing&quot;.  Out in the world, there is a real effort to bring together &quot;user testing&quot; (*::GUITest) and &quot;unit testing&quot; (Test::*).  (Let me know if you want citations.)  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Most monks (but for now not me) are probably more interested in the Test::* part, but I don't want to exclude either camp.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ysth] 2004-06-23&lt;br /&gt;Not sure there's anything better than &quot;testing&quot;.  &quot;Software testing&quot;?  We have ways of dealing with the weird and off-topic.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[davido] 2004-06-23&lt;br /&gt;Aye.  But let's think about the category name.  'Testing' might attract some pretty wierd (and off-topic) questions.  Maybe &quot;Systematic Testing&quot; or something along those lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ysth] 2004-06-23&lt;br /&gt;
Straw poll re [id://368766]: who feels a testing section would be worthwhile?
I think it would be.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[davido] 2004-05-29&lt;br /&gt;
I went through each Q&amp;A section looking for questions that had zero responses.  Questions that had no responses after a reasonably long period of time were removed from Q&amp;A unless they contained an answer within the body of the question, or at very least, a link to an answer within the question.  I didn't want to remove anything that had any value, but a 3 year old question with no responses is of no value.  As it turns out, most of what has been removed was written prior to the &quot;Level 4 - Scribe&quot; requirement was put in place, presumably by people who thought they were posting to SoPW.  By &quot;remove&quot;, I mean I just SoPWified the questions involved; I didn't want to affect XP in any way.  All told, there were about ten zero-response questions removed.  The newest was from sometime in 2002.  Most were 1999 through 2000.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ysth], 2004-05-11&lt;br /&gt;
I've notified [swngnmonk] and [parv] that [id://352193] and [id://352198] will be going away.  I'll wait about a week to hear back from them.&lt;br /&gt;
I've made all the other changes.
&lt;p&gt;[davido], 2004-05-10&lt;br /&gt;
I agree with each of [ysth]'s proposals except that I think [id://352198|352198], while interesting, isn't an answer to the question posed in the thread.  Q&amp;A topic threads should be narrow and to the point.  This post is making some other point.
&lt;p&gt;
What to do with it is a different question.  The [parv] went to a little work posting it, and it's not &quot;bad information&quot;.  Perhaps he should be given the opportunity to repost it as a Snippet.  Or maybe someone with a different kind of voodoo could move it out of Q&amp;A.  Definately if it's going to get deleted [parv] should be informed so he understands why.  ...any comments?
&lt;p&gt;[ysth], 2004-05-10&lt;br /&gt;
Four answers were added to [id://17057] today; here are some proposed actions for [QandAEditors|peer] review:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;[17167] is a good answer and can be left alone.
&lt;li&gt;[232742] should have Time::Seconds and the stuff about ONE_MONTH and ONE_YEAR removed;
these won't result in months and years from this specific beginning date.
Also remove mention of DateTime at the bottom since there's a DateTime example later.
My inclination when there are so many answers is to also remove extraneous stuff like
the &quot;Cheers, Matt&quot;, but I'd like to hear other opinions on this.
&lt;li&gt;[17058] should be deleted since there is a Date::Calc example now
&lt;li&gt;[352190] Add link to DateTime module and maybe homepage.  Needs mention of
&quot;if $dt1 and $dt2 are DateTime objects&quot; and/or code initializing them.
&lt;li&gt;[352193] Upvote this, then delete it, since the objectionable part of the Time::Piece
answer will be removed.
&lt;li&gt;[352242] Good answer.  Remove extraneous comments and just leave code?
&lt;li&gt;[352198] Using floating point for this kind of calculation gives me the heebie-jeebies,
and it doesn't directly address the question; nevertheless I'm inclined to leave it (though
it really belongs as a root node in one of the code sections.)
&lt;/ul&gt;
Query: should [swngnmonk] be notified and given the opportunity to copy the stuff in [352193]
to a meditation before removing it?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[davido], 2004-05-10&lt;br /&gt;
Just wanted to welcome two new members to [QandAEditors]: [castaway] and [theorbtwo].  We're glad to have a couple more active Monks in our ranks.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ysth], 2004-01-28&lt;br /&gt;
That would be better, yes.  I was somehow assuming you couldn't do that with approved questions.
&lt;p&gt;
Am I correct in guessing it won't appear on Newest Nodes or the SoPW section (since it's a very old node)?  Or does it get a new node number?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2004-01-28&lt;br /&gt;
Don't nuke the whole thread, SoPWify it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;

[ysth] 2004-01-28:
&lt;p&gt;
Wondering about [id://6879].  The topic of nested delimiters is a good one;
the question as phrased is basically a vauge misplaced SoPW.  There would be
a lot of work to change it to ask a more general question and change all the
answers to suit.  Would it be better just to nuke the whole question and start
with a fresh one (asking about paired delimiters like &amp;lt; &amp; &amp;gt; rather than &quot;).
&lt;p&gt;
This comes up because of the recent answer [id://324397].  It seems to try to answer the question in a more general way, and so gives the basis for an answer to the actual question, but not a complete answer.
&lt;p&gt;
I added a descriptive comment to it (before it just had the regexes) and fixed a slight problem (changed: (&quot;)? to (&quot;?)) in the second one.  If the question stays, should it be further changed to actually capture the desired pieces of text?
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
[davido] 2004-01-18:
&lt;p&gt;
I agree that 'clever' answers often don't answer the actual question.  Perl 6-ish responses to Perl 5 questions are generally useless as &quot;Q and A Answers&quot; in a P5-centric forum.  They may be interesting fodder for discussion, but I feel that the QandA section's &quot;charter&quot; is to provide answers to common questions, not discussion.  A Perl 6 response to a Perl 5 question is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; an answer.  It is an unfortunate side-effect that it gets labled an Answer by our system.  It is the QandAEditors responsibility to see that answers in QandA are on topic, accurate, clean, and effective.
&lt;p&gt;
The Monastery has other areas more appropriate for open discussion.  SoPW, and Meditations come to my mind immediately as areas where the discussion of Perl 6 solutions to common Perl 5 questions might be on-topic.
&lt;p&gt;
As for how to ensure that P6-ish answers get listed after P5 answers, that's simply not possible, since QandA Answers are ordered by reputation, not by the nature of the content.
&lt;p&gt;
So for now, I oppose P6 answers in QandA, unless they are in direct response to P6 questions (of which I know of none).  P6 is not clearly defined, behaviors will change, such answers aren't applicable to the here-and-now of P5, they encourage discussion rather than resolution, and therefore, aren't QandA Answers.
&lt;p&gt;
I'm still open for comments.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
[ysth], 2004-01-18:
&lt;p&gt; The question of perl6 answers (in the absence of even an alpha perl6) I think leads to the more general question of &quot;clever&quot; answers.  I see a spectrum of answerss in the range practical..clever (eq impractical) to some questions.  A perl6 answer is just an extreme case of impracticality.  The case for leaving such answers in place is that they may lead readers to learn interesting things not directly related to the question at hand.  The challenge is making sure the practical answers are shown first, especially since a &quot;clever&quot; answer may draw more votes.  Is there a good mechanism in place for enforcing order?
&lt;HR&gt;
[davido], 2004-01-17:
&lt;p&gt;
A day or so ago [ysth] and I both pondered over the appropriateness of Perl-6ish &quot;Answers&quot; in the Q&amp;A section.  The node that prompted the discussion was [id://321712].  In my opinion, the answer does nothing for Perl 5.x.x users, and is speculative, since P6 has yet to be released (and may not come for quite awhile still).  Thus, the response has little or no value as an &quot;Answer&quot;, and thus, little or no place in the [Catagorized Questions and Answers] section.  Also, since P6 hasn't been finalized and released, it's doubtful that the [QandAEditors] themselves have devoted enough time to learning Perl 6 to be competant to verify the accuracy of Perl 6ish Answers.  I'm open to hear other opinions and thoughts.  For now, the node is left untouched, until I (we, including [ysth]) hear arguments supporting or opposing the deletion of this and similar nodes as they crop up.
&lt;HR&gt;
[davido], 2003-12-6:
&lt;p&gt;
I just realized that since the &quot;Vote&quot; button doubles as the &quot;Action&quot; button for deleting or killing bogus Q&amp;A Answers, if I am out of votes (and thus, the button isn't displayed), I'm unable to perform a Delete or a Kill on an answer.
&lt;HR&gt;
2003-04-28, moved from my wiki&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Corion: Louis Wu mentioned on the CB that he finds reaping of the mentioned node ([id://252763]) rather harsh, as he sees the Reaper mostly as the punitive instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I don't follow this completely, as I see the Reaper more as the tool of the Editors (and QandAEditors) to clean up stuff, but the XP loss that goes with a reaped node is not nice (not that it would really matter, but it's a symbolic action). &lt;/p&gt;
Comments / opinions ?
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-01-17&lt;br /&gt;
Now all [cabal] members can read each other's [wiki wiki|wikis].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
[crazyinsomniac], Fri Jun 28 21:32:47 2002 GMT &lt;br /&gt;
okay, he's back with yet another double post.  We'll see what happens (if he reads and such). Whohooooo!! He finally read it.  Apparently he thought it was ads and such, and didn't pay much attention.  Thank you tye (especially for approving &lt;b&gt;bolden&lt;/b&gt; in cb)
&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Russ], 2002-06-27&lt;br&gt;
If things get too bad, maybe we need the ability to Kill (not just SOPWify or Delete) Questions.&lt;br&gt;
On a side note: I submitted a patch to make  all questions show the number of answers, not just old ones.  Long time ago.  Some Q&amp;AEDitor/PMDev'er wanna find that and give me some feedback?
&lt;p&gt;[tye], 2002-06-26&lt;br /&gt;
I checked his inbox to make sure my /msg would be visible and I notice that [crazyinsomniac|your] /msgs to him did not actually tell him where to ask questions, just not to ask in Cat Q+A.  I sent my standard /msg ([tye|here]) with just a tiny bit extra punch.  We'll see what happens.
&lt;/p&gt;
[dvergin] Wed Jun 26 2002&lt;br /&gt;
I'm guessing s/he never looks at the ChatterBox. I remember it took me a long time to take an interest in it. Try posting your counsel in a response to the items themselves -- or better yet, as an update &lt;b&gt;in&lt;/b&gt; the offending post.&lt;p /&gt;
My guess is s/he is clueless rather than willfull.&lt;p /&gt;
And if the problem persists, hand it over to one of us other QAEds for a while.
&lt;HR&gt;
[crazyinsomniac] Wed Jun 26 23:31:52 2002&lt;br /&gt;
[dwatson06] has started treating the Q&amp;A section like SOPW.  I've messaged him extensively, but he's ignoring me (over 6 posts and over 10 messages).  How do I procede (i've cleaning up as I usually do, but it's starting to piss me off).
&lt;HR&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[chromatic] Mon Mar  4 04:56:36 UTC 2002&lt;br /&gt;
We can fix that by refraining from replying to categorized questions as I'm sopwifying them.  :)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[crazyinsomniac] -  Mon Mar  4 03:23:16 2002 &lt;BR&gt;
If you visit the 'perlanswer' [id://149011] you'll notice something weird, &lt;BR&gt;
&lt;CODE&gt;Q&amp;A &gt; &gt; IO::Socket should be readable, but isn't....&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
and if you click on [id://149008|IO::Socket should be readable, but isn't....],
you'll notice it's a 'perlquestion' aka SOPW post.
&lt;BR&gt;
Anyone have a clue as to how we can remedy this?&lt;BR&gt;
(yeah I know, I know, bug the [gods] )
&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;HR&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[tye] - 2001-12-27&lt;br&gt;
Only [vroom] can reparent nodes so far.  There is a tool for [editors] to reparent nodes but it doesn't work very well yet and likely won't work for Cat Q+A for quite a while after it works for regular nodes.  So I suggest someone just post an answer that contains the contents of the reply (or a combination of the previous answer and the reply, or update the existing answer to incorporate the reply, or whatever).  The point of Cat Q+A is that the answer should be &quot;the best&quot; answers so heavy editing is a good thing.  Then request [editors] purge the reply, then Q+A Editors can purge the original answer if needed.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The replies to Cat Q+A are not very visible and so you shouldn't worry about them much other than making sure that any important information in the reply gets incorporated into one of the answers.  If a cat Q+A generates lots of replies, then it might mean it should be SoPWified.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;P&gt;[crazyinsomniac] - Thu Dec 27 05:42:03 2001 GMT&lt;BR&gt;
The node
[id://134537]&lt;BR&gt;
is a reply to 
[id://134425]&lt;BR&gt;
and has been considered for reparenting to the original question.
Can [editors] reparent such nodes? (replies to QandA answers)

&lt;P&gt;
Why are replies to QandA answers possible?
&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
All your wikis are belong to us.
&lt;P&gt;
What's the most efficient way to implement a wiki in Perl?  Is there a script I can use?










































</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>68046</type_nodetype>
  <node_id>133122</node_id>
  <author_user>979</author_user>
  <title>QandAEditors' wiki</title>
  <createtime>2001-12-19 13:33:44</createtime>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-14 02:59:49</nodeupdated>
</node>
