<node>
  <doctext>&lt;h2&gt;Tidings: What's New at PerlMonks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Your [cabal|site maintainers] are constantly improving the appearance and functions of PerlMonks
to make your experience here the best it can be.  
To find out what has changed recently, or since the last time you logged in, peruse the headlines below.
Also browse recent [id://1040|PerlMonks Discussions] for a deeper view into what's in the pipeline for PerlMonks.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you have questions about anything you read here, you may ask about it in the Chatterbox.
If it's an issue of weightier import, you might consider posting a [id://1040|PMD].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;


&lt;!--
+ Remember, this is about announcing user-visible changes to the user community.
  Don't, for example, announce bug fixes to bugs that never impacted the general
  population, or changes that only a [Cabal] group would care about.
+ Announcements must be listed in STRICTLY chronological order, newest at the top.
+ Use the following template. (The format is likely to change to support RSS.)

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;ANCHOR&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;HEADLINE&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://ccyy-mm-dd hh:mm:ss]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
ARTICLE TEXT
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

+ The Headline should be a succinct, no-BS description of the change.
+ The argument string for localtime:// is server time by default so include the &quot;UTC&quot; suffix.
+ The article text should be short - about 1 paragraph; 2 max.
  Consider it OBLIGATORY that the text include links to any/all relevant
  PMD threads or other nodes. Just make sure they're PUBLIC nodes.
  Patches, unfortunately (for this purpose), aren't.
  (And don't forget about the [pmdev://...] shortcut type.)
+ Please leave some space above each entry.
--&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;GooglePlus&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;Google+ Page for Perlmonks&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2011-11-10 17:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Perlmonks now has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/105273906362552592638&quot;&gt;Google+ Page&lt;/a&gt;.  Add it to your circles, and it will add you back.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;InlineCodeClass&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;Inline code gets class&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2011-10-31 19:45:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Inline code (like in chatter) now gets the class &lt;c&gt;inlinecode&lt;/c&gt; applied to it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;PermissionDeniedDetails&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;&quot;Permission Denied&quot; now knows what it denied&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2011-07-31 14:30:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Now, when you receive a &quot;Permission Denied&quot; error, you may get additional information on the node to which access was not granted.
&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;OfferYourReply&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;&quot;Offer your reply&quot; is history&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2011-07-21 15:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
There have been some changes to the way posts are shown on &quot;aggregate&quot; pages, i.e. [id://131] and the various sections.
The header block above each post has been reorganized, so that the title and &quot;replies&quot; are on the left, and the author and date are on the right.
The &quot;replies&quot; text has been changed so that the link to the post is in separate text (&quot;Read more&quot;).
If &amp;mdash; and &lt;i&gt;only&lt;/i&gt; if &amp;mdash; there are no replies yet, an additional link is given, directly to the &quot;Comment on&quot; form.
The &quot;Offer your reply&quot; link, which used to be in a separate right-hand column in the table, has been eliminated.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
These changes were proposed and acclaimed in the discussion [id://886779].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;newipaddress&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;New IP address in DNS pool&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2011-01-08 21:19:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A new machine with a new IP address has joined the perlmonks.org, perlmonks.com and perlmonks.net IP pool:
&lt;c&gt;
perlmonks.org.          6622    IN      A       66.39.54.27
perlmonks.org.          6622    IN      A       209.197.123.153
perlmonks.org.          6622    IN      A       216.92.34.251   ;; This one is new
&lt;/c&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the changeover was not entirely smooth, you may have experienced pair.com placeholders
getting served while the DNS updated. The DNS should propagate within the next 48 hours.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;


&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;newlistmarkup&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lists of links receive new markup&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2010-12-15 16:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Some lists of links appearing commonly on the site have been formatted with new markup. 
&lt;br&gt;The so-called &quot;nav menu&quot;, which appears (by default) in the upper right corner of each page, is now coded as
&lt;br&gt;&lt;c&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;inline-list&quot;&gt;&lt;/c&gt;
&lt;br&gt;Many of the lists appearing in nodelets are now coded as 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;c&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;spacey-list&quot;&gt;&lt;/c&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you would like to customize the appearance of these lists, see what's done in [http://perlmonks.org/css/common.css|common.css] (look for &lt;c&gt;spacey-list&lt;/c&gt;), copy the css code into your [href://?node=Display Settings#On-Site-CSS|on-site css], and modify to suit.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
One known issue with the new markup is that MS Internet Explorer does not honor the &lt;c&gt;li:before{content:&quot;|&quot;}&lt;/c&gt; styling, so these lists appear without any bullet/separator in IE.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;canonical_url&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;index.pl is not the canonical URL anymore&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2010-11-30 16:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strike&gt;All URLs of the style &lt;c&gt;/index.pl?...&lt;/c&gt; now redirect permanently (301) to &lt;c&gt;/?...&lt;/c&gt;, as do all URLs
of the style &lt;c&gt;/index.pl/foo/bar/baz?...&lt;/c&gt;. This should reduce the double-crawling by bots.&lt;/strike&gt;
While that redirecting will sometime later still happen, the chosen tool, &lt;c&gt;mod_rewrite&lt;/c&gt;, created more problems than it solved. This change was backed out again.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;Can customize refresh rate for chat frames&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2010-09-28 16:30]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[Fullpage chat] is an example of a frameset that makes a convenient interface for chatting via PerlMonks.  You can also copy that and make your own custom frame set.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
One of the frames contains a link to [href:///?node_id=50772&amp;displaytype=raw], which shows (some of) your private messages.  This used to unconditionally refresh every 30 seconds.  It now defaults to refreshing only every 60 seconds and you can append &quot;;refresh=180&quot; to the URL to change the refresh rate (but not to less than 30 seconds).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;


&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;20100410150000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;&quot;Location&quot; field is HTML-escaped for anonymous users&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2010-04-10 15:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The &quot;Location&quot; field is now HTML escaped for anonymous visitors. This is unfortunate, but as that field has been
used to linkspam via the website, only registered users can now choose to have this field
output HTML.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;


&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;201004020038&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;Signatures now delineated by a thin line in CSS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2010-04-02 00:38:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Signatures are now delineated from the main post by a thin, CSS generated line. The other themes
may change that. If a &lt;c&gt;&lt;HR&gt;&lt;/c&gt; element is the first element in a signature, that
HR gets hidden. That way, old signatures look mostly the same as new signatures.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;


&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;20100321020000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;Scratchpads are only visible to logged-in users&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2010-03-21 02:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Scratchpad contents are not visible to [Anonymous Monk] and bots anymore. If you want to view
scratchpad contents, you need to be logged in.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;20100217230000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;New link shortcut type: wolframalpha&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2010-02-17 23:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A new shortcut has been added to link to [wa://]: &lt;c&gt;[wolframalpha://]&lt;/c&gt;, with the shorthand alias &lt;c&gt;[wa://]&lt;/c&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;c&gt;[wa://10 choose 3]&lt;/c&gt; in posts or chatter becomes the link [wa://10 choose 3].
See the [wa://] site for ideas of what is possible. It's very powerful, and very cool.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thanks to monk [repellent], who suggested the idea in PMD [id://823003].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;20091129183000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;Reply text size no longer hardcoded&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2009-11-29 18:30:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As foretold in [id://806834],
replies in threads are no longer being rendered with hard-coded &lt;c&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;/c&gt; HTML.
Replies will now appear in the same size font as the &quot;root&quot; node being viewed.
You are free to style replies however you wish, using your
&lt;a href=&quot;?node_id=450961#Stylesheet-Settings&quot;&gt;Display Settings: Stylesheet Settings&lt;/a&gt;.  Adding &quot;&lt;c&gt;td.reply-body { font-size: smaller; }&lt;/c&gt;&quot; there will likely come close to the previous formating.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;20091101102009&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;Snippets Section and Code Catacombs deprecated for new posting&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2009-11-01 10:20:09]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The [Snippets Section] and [Code Catacombs] have been closed for posting. 
These sections are now archival only. All new posting of &quot;substantial&quot; 
code should be done in the [Cool Uses For Perl] section.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
They are no longer listed in the &lt;b&gt;Sections&lt;/b&gt; nodelet, but have been 
moved to the &lt;b&gt;Leftovers&lt;/b&gt; nodelet, alongside the link to [Craft]. 
Also, the &quot;nav menu&quot; at the top of each PerlMonks page no longer 
contains links to these sections.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
See the original [id://803953|announcement and discussion].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;20090813000000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;RAT Settings Persisted&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2009-08-13 00:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A security-related patch made in February 2007 inadvertently caused [Recently Active Threads]
not to persist some of your configuration settings.
This has been fixed. Now all of your [Recently Active Threads|RAT] settings, such as &quot;View Mode&quot;,
will be remembered for the next time you load RAT.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;20090724143000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;Extra info in Other Users&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2009-07-24 14:30:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The user links listed in &quot;Other Users&quot; (both the nodelet and lower right pane of the [id://3184] 
have extra info (added via the &lt;tt&gt;'title'&lt;/tt&gt; attribute) which you can see in most browsers by
hovering over the link.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Until recently, this [wp://tooltip]-like info simply indicated that the link was to the user's
homenode. This info is now augmented with the user's group memberships, if any.
This makes it a little easier to determine if any of the users current active on-site (such as
in the chatterbox) are members of [janitors], for example.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;20090726143000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;Newest Nodes RSS feed now has dc:creator tag and validates&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2009-07-26 14:30:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The [link://node_id=30175;xmlstyle=rss|Newest Nodes RSS feed] now has the &lt;c&gt;dc:creator&lt;/c&gt; tag to
generate attributions to the author name. It also validates against [http://feedvalidator.org/]. The &lt;c&gt;dc:creator&lt;/c&gt; contents don't seem to have any effect on the FireFox 3.0 built-in RSS reader though.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;20090719080000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;tt&gt;perldoc://&lt;/tt&gt; shortcut now uses Google&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2009-07-19 08:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;c&gt;perldoc://&lt;/c&gt; [id://43037|shortcut type], which provides a general-purpose search
of [perldoc://|the Perl documentation], has been changed to use [google://|Google] to do
the search, rather than perldoc.perl.com's native search. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
See discussion under [id://781066] for background.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
(Note that &lt;c&gt;[doc://]&lt;/c&gt; is unaffected.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;20090629125700&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;Migratory changes in how threads are rendered&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2009-06-29 12:57:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The code for rendering a thread was split up into some more subroutines and a new
data structure that allows data fetching in larger bulk sizes. Potentially, some
off-by-one errors or other glitches have crept in.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;2009-06-21&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;Recently Updated Home Nodes fixed&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2009-06-21T19:20:19UTC]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[Recently Updated Home Nodes] is a listing (linked from [Newest Nodes]) which, as its name indicates, shows the users who have recently committed &quot;significant&quot; updates to their homenodes. For quite some time now, this list was defective in that all of the newly created users showed up on it, even if they hadn't touched their homenodes. Since there are usually far more newly created users than users (new or old) who have actually updated their homenodes, this list was practically unusable.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This list will now only show what it was intended to show: those homenodes which have actually had (significant) updates recently. New users will no longer be automatically added.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Note: The fix is not retroactive; new users who were created before 2009-06-17 will remain on this list until they are, eventually, displaced (i.e. &quot;scroll off the bottom&quot;).&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;2009-05-18&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;New shortcut type for [Message Outbox]: &lt;c&gt;[msg://]&lt;/c&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2009-05-18 18:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The [Message Outbox] (see &lt;a href=&quot;#2009-05-08&quot;&gt;preceding entry&lt;/a&gt;) was designed to make it easy to link to a &quot;send private message&quot; function.
Now you can make those links easily, with the new &lt;a href=&quot;?node_id=43037#outbox&quot;&gt;&lt;c&gt;[msg://]&lt;/c&gt;&lt;/a&gt; [id://43037|shortcut] type. 
Read the &lt;a href=&quot;?node_id=43037#outbox&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;2009-05-08&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;Message Outbox created&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2009-05-08 13:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
We now have a [Message Outbox] which is just for sending [id://17534|private messages] to another user. 
Similar functionality is embedded within the [Message Inbox], and accessible via the [/msg] command in the [Chatterbox FAQ|cb].
By having this function by itself on its own page, you can link to it, and send other people links to it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
All of the places on PerlMonks where a &quot;send /msg to user&quot; kind of link appears have been converted to utilize this new feature.
For example, when you are looking someone's writeup, the &lt;b&gt;Send private /msg to &lt;i&gt;user&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; link right below it (next to the &quot;Comment on&quot; link) now takes you to the Message Outbox. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;2009-04-26&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;strike&gt;Meditations&lt;/strike&gt; All Sections now have an RSS feed link&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2009-04-26 09:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strike&gt;The [Meditations] page&lt;/strike&gt; All of the Section pages now contain an embedded link to an RSS feed for that section's nodes so that the feed is automatically discoverable (e.g. by browsers such as Firefox).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Issue was raised in [id://759875].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;a name=&quot;2009-03-16 09:00:00&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;New link shortcut type: man&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2009-03-16 09:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A new shortcut has been added to link to UNIX-oid man pages: &lt;tt&gt;[man://|&amp;#91;man://&amp;#93;]&lt;/tt&gt;.
The target is normally just the name of a man page.
There are two options you can add as well: one to specify the &quot;section&quot;, and one to specify the particular UNIX-oid system.
Examples:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [man://passwd] &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [man://passwd(5)] &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [man://passwd/linux] &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [man://passwd(5)/linux] &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
Both &quot;options&quot; are suffixes, and if both are given, must be in the order shown in #4 above.
By default, the section is unconstrained. The default system appears to be &lt;tt&gt;FreeBSD&amp;nbsp;7.1-RELEASE&lt;/tt&gt; (currently).
To see what options are available, go [man://|here] (which is also where &lt;c&gt;[man://]&lt;/c&gt; (no target keyword) links to).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This was suggested (most recently) in [id://748618].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;20090105184500&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;Simple Search now falls through to Super Search&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2009-01-05 18:45:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The site's [id://237035|simple search] function now re-submits the query to [id://590032|Super Search] if no exact title matches are found.
Previously, in this case, a rather crude and computationally expensive title search was done. 
Using Super Search produces better results and places less load on the server.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The behavior of simple search when one or more exact title matches are found is unchanged:
If there is exactly one title match, you are taken directly to that node;
If there is more than one, you are presented a list of duplicates from which to choose.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;200812240000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;Vote buttons have no more font information&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-12-24 18:13:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;c&gt;&lt;tt&gt;&lt;/c&gt; tags around the vote buttons have been removed.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you would like these radio buttons or their labels to have specific styling,
note that they are enclosed in a &lt;c&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/c&gt; which has &lt;c&gt;class=&quot;vote&quot;&lt;/c&gt;. The magic incantation to put into the [Display Settings|Custom CSS] is:
&lt;c&gt;
div.vote center label {
    font-family: Monospace;
}
&lt;/c&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;


&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;20081215023000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tutorials Needed&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-12-15 02:30:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Tutorials are still needed. Please check out &lt;b&gt;[id://615833]&lt;/b&gt;
and see if you might be able to serve your PerlMonks community by
writing a [Tutorials|tutorial]. Some ideas may have been added
since the last time you checked.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Also, we are always soliciting ideas for new tutorials.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;20081129003000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;
History of your votes available, Homenode layout updated&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-11-29 00:30:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
We have updated the layout of homenodes to make it more obvious how you edit your user profile and to make boilerplate items easier to distinguish from user-entered content.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This also added a link that allows you to see what nodes you have previously voted upon.  If you go to your own homenode, then the &quot;Your votes&quot; link will show you your most recent 20 votes (and then you can request to see a different range of your votes).  If you go to some other user's homenode, then the &quot;Your votes&quot; link will only show you votes you have previously cast upon nodes authored by that user.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
See also [id://726730] and the nodes that it was in reply to.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;20081121184530&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;Poster now sees own post immediately&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-11-21 18:45:30]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In a move which should dramatically reduce the number of re-posts, registered
users now see their own posts immediately after posting in a section,
even before they've been approved. All of the other rules controlling
when a user sees unapproved posts remain unchanged.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A tip o' the biretta to [ccn] for the idea.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;20081106120000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;Categorized Question format change&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-11-06 12:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When viewing a [id://1843|Categorized Question], the Answers (if any) are shown below it in a table. The specific formatting of this table has changed somewhat; in particular, it now has the CSS class &lt;c&gt;&quot;paneled&quot;&lt;/c&gt;. Previously, it was a complicated arrangement of nested tables. This change affects those who may have had some custom styling in their [display settings] for this table.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;20081101200000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;New option for Nodelet display&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-11-01 20:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As part of our ongoing effort to give you, the monk, more control over the
look and feel of your PerlMonks experience, we have added an option for rendering the nodelets as &lt;c&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/c&gt; elements rather than as the traditional &lt;c&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;/c&gt;.  If you go to your [Display Settings], you'll see a new checkbox at the bottom: &lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt; Render nodelets as &lt;c&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/c&gt; instead of &lt;c&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;/c&gt;?&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br&gt;If this is unchecked, nodelets will be rendered in a table like so:
&lt;code&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;nodelet_container&quot; id=&quot;nodelet_container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;tbody class=&quot;nodelet&quot; id=&quot;XP_Nodelet&quot;&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;nodelet_head&quot;&gt;
          XP Nodelet
      &lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;nodelet_body&quot;&gt;
          (nodelet content)
      &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
    (and so on... Each nodelet is a &lt;tbody&gt; with two &lt;tr&gt;s)
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
If checked, nodelets will be rendered in &lt;c&gt;div&lt;/c&gt;s like so:
&lt;code&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;nodelet_container&quot; id=&quot;nodelet_container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;nodelet&quot; id=&quot;XP_Nodelet&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;nodelet_head&quot;&gt;
          XP Nodelet
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;nodelet_body&quot;&gt;
          (nodelet content)
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    (and so on... Each nodelet is a &lt;div&gt; with two &lt;div&gt;s inside)
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
We encourage you all to experiment with your [Display Settings|on-site css] to do interesting things with the Nodelet &lt;c&gt;div&lt;/c&gt;s, and to post your findings in [Perl Monks Discussion].

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;20081101120000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;Changes to Nodelet Style metadata&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-11-01 12:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you are interested in using CSS to style individual nodelets, or the header and/or body of individual nodelets, or if you're already doing so, please note that the &lt;c&gt;id&lt;/c&gt; attributes of the &lt;c&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;/c&gt;, &lt;c&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;/c&gt;, and &lt;c&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/c&gt; have recently changed &amp;mdash; that is, simplified.  The pattern is now as shown here: (XP nodelet example)
&lt;code&gt;
    &lt;tbody class=&quot;nodelet&quot; id=&quot;XP_Nodelet&quot;&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;nodelet_head&quot;&gt;
          XP Nodelet
      &lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;nodelet_body&quot;&gt;
          (nodelet content)
      &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
View your page source to see the exact IDs of the nodelets you use.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;


&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;20081010120000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Number of Replies clarification&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-10-10 12:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In [id://131] and the posting sections ([id://479], etc.),
the metadata shown for each node includes the count of replies.
This can be either the &lt;i&gt;total&lt;/i&gt; number of replies (all &quot;descendents&quot;)
or just the number of &lt;i&gt;direct&lt;/i&gt; replies (immediate &quot;children&quot;).
You select which in your [User Settings] &amp;mdash; a checkbox labeled
&quot;Show count of all replies&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When you have selected showing only the count of direct replies
(the option is unchecked), then [id://131], etc. will show counts
labeled as &quot;&lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;direct&amp;nbsp;replies&quot;.  Previously it said
&quot;&lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;replies&quot;, just as in the other case.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Migration to new database machine completed&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-09-27 16:28]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[id://714052|The database backing the website was switched to a new machine.]
The site at least feels faster. [id://713488|Previous discussion of the changeover].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Font color styling issue in No Theme fixed&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-09-09 12:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Some users of the &quot;No Theme&quot; theme may have noticed that the
&quot;Comment On&quot; link, shown just below the top node on a thread
display page, was invisible due to a white-on-white font color
styling bug. This has been fixed, and few other minor CSS-related
improvements have been made as well.
If you find that these links now look strange, or are illegible,
you may need to refresh your cached CSS files.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Author's level title hidden by default&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-09-08 00:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The site's default CSS has been updated to cause the recently included name of the author's level title to no longer be visible above each node.  If you would like to (again) see each author's level title listed in their node by-lines, then go to [Display Settings] and add the below line to your &quot;On-Site CSS Markup:&quot;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;c&gt;
.attribution-title { display: inline; }
&lt;/c&gt;&lt;p&gt;
as noted in slightly more detail at [id://709707], part of the thread where you can read more about the history behind this.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;New link shortcut type: xkcd&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-08-30 05:06:56]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A new shortcut has been added to link to the popular geeky comic strip xkcd: &lt;c&gt;[xkcd://224]&lt;/c&gt; in posts or chatter now becomes the link [xkcd://224].  This is described in [href://?node_id=43037#xkcd|What shortcuts can I use for linking to other information?]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;a name=&quot;2008-07-30 22:30:00&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Character set now Windows-1252&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-07-30 22:30:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The site character set has been changed from Latin-1 to Windows-1252, a superset of Latin-1.  Many browsers already permitted the extra characters usefully defined by Windows-1252 despite the character set being declared (in our HTTP headers) as Latin-1, so for many this change has no direct impact.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The most visible impact should be preventing some browsers from converting super-set characters (such as separate left- and right-tilted single- and double-quote characters) into HTML entities when replying to nodes.  The browsers that silently permitted these superset characters would allow posters to include them in node titles with no sign of a problem.  When someone with a stricter browser replied, the browser might replace them with HTML entities (strangely half-honoring Windows-1252 by using HTML entities of Windows-1252 characters or replacing the characters with '?' or something else).  So a node titled &quot;Perling McDonald&#8217;s&#8482;&quot; might get a reply titled &quot;Re: Perling McDonald&amp;amp;#8217;s&amp;amp;#8482;&quot;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Now the following characters can all be used (directly) in PerlMonks with full legitimacy &amp;#91; &#8364; &#8218; &#402; &#8222; &#8230; &#8224; &#8225; &#710; &#8240; &#352; &#8249; &#338; &#381; &#8216; &#8217; &#8220; &#8221; &#8226; &#8211; &#8212; &#732; &#8482; &#353; &#8250; &#339; &#382; &#376; &amp;#93; using their 0x80 through 0x9f code points.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;New shortcut type for user writeups: &lt;tt&gt;by://&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-07-18 12:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A new [id://43037|shortcut] type, &lt;b&gt;&lt;c&gt;[by://...]&lt;/c&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, has been introduced. 
This allows to link to any user's writeups.
It is conceptually much like &lt;c&gt;[pad://...]&lt;/c&gt; but instead of linking to
the user's (or your own) scratchpad, it links to the [Perl Monks User Search]
page for that user (or yourself).
&lt;br/&gt;For example:
&lt;c&gt;[by://vroom]&lt;/c&gt; &amp;rArr; [by://vroom].&lt;br&gt;
If you omit the username, it defaults to yourself (the author).&lt;br&gt;
Like other shortcut types, it provides a reasonable default for the link text.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Author attribution now usually includes author level&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-07-10 14:24:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Where posts or replies are attributed to an author (e.g. &quot;by [paco]&quot;), 
the author's &lt;em&gt;current&lt;/em&gt; monk [id://509805|level] name may be appended, in parentheses. 
This attribution is enclosed in a &lt;c&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/c&gt; with css class &lt;c&gt;&quot;attribution-title&quot;&lt;/c&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Super Search links to thread root&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-06-28 15:34:51]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When you do a search with [Super Search], the last column of the table of nodes found shows the section of the node, or &quot;Re:&quot; followed by the section for notes (replies).  This short section name used to be a link to the section.  Now it's a link to the section only for root nodes: for notes it links to the root node of the thread the note is in.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;New XML Generator: Node Navigator Ticker&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-06-24 12:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A new [id://72241|XML Generator] is available: the
[href://?node_id=72241#navigator|Node Navigator ticker].
Its concept of operation is just like that of the 
[id://590097|Node Navigator nodelet].
It is primarily of interest to those who write PerlMonks
automation clients.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;!-- This patch was reverted; so the announcement is backed out:
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Delete Messages in Chatterbox Sidebar&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-05-18 12:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The [Chatterbox Sidebar] now has a submit button so you can clear messages from within the sidebar instead of having to use (e.g.) [Message Inbox].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
--&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Newly available Community Ads nodelet&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-04-17 02:49:58]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[Nodelet Settings] now allows anyone to enable the Community Ads nodelet, which delivers informational, non-commercial ads from the [http://adserver.szabgab.com/|Perl community adserver].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;HTML filtering of homenodes now the default&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-04-17 02:49:58]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Filtering of HTML on monk's homenodes to a restricted list of elements/attributes
is now the default.  Note that the ability to disable filtering via a [User Setting] is likely a short-term option. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;CSS change to the Chatterbox&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-03-31 12:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Alternate lines in the (on-site) Chatterbox are now given
the &lt;c&gt;odd-row&lt;/c&gt; and &lt;c&gt;even-row&lt;/c&gt; CSS classes, for those
who would like to highlight the lines in some way.
Previously, every other line was
given the &lt;c&gt;highlight&lt;/c&gt; class.
(Most users would not have noticed this, since it 
requires custom CSS in [Display Settings].)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lots of Theme/Style Tweaks&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-03-27 12:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A large number of very small tweaks have been made to the site's styling,
mostly geared toward replacing hard-coded styles (colors, font sizes, etc.)
with CSS-based style controls.  Hopefully, these changes are all transparent,
i.e. resulted in no or insignificant visible differences to the user. However,
just to be sure, we ask that you keep an eye out as you visit all your usual nodes,
and if you find anything odd/broken/ugly, please [/msg|report] it to [pmdev].
Thank you.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you're interested in customizing the appearance of your chosen theme,
you can go to your [Display Settings] and add CSS in the
&lt;b&gt;Stylesheet&amp;nbsp;Settings&lt;/b&gt; section. Refer to 
[href://?node_id=17642#theme|theme and CSS configuration].
Also check out [shmem]'s [id://597524].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Voting rules and homenode button alert&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-03-26 20:38:45]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This is a reminder that the only approved method of voting on nodes is via the form interface provided on the node display pages.  Penalties, automatic or otherwise, may apply to voting via other methods.  Note that buttons on some homenodes will cast votes in violation of these rules.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Message Inbox now shows folder sizes&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-03-17 12:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The &quot;Showing messages&quot; configuration form at the top of [Message Inbox]
now shows the count of messages in each folder next to the folder name,
in parentheses.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;The [id://3184|FPC] Titlebar Now Uses Text+Styles instead of Images&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-02-25 12:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Users of the [id://3184|Full-Page Chat]terbox client will notice that the image buttons
in the titlebar have been replaced with text buttons. Color and font of these text buttons
are controlled by CSS. If the titlebar buttons look like actual buttons to you, it means you
need to refresh/invalidate your CSS cache.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Code no longer spoiled in Perl-Blue Theme&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-02-15 12:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The [pmdev://668160|Perl-Blue Theme] had a non-black color for &lt;tt&gt;&lt;[href://?node_id=17558#codetags|code]&gt;&lt;/tt&gt; text, which kind of defeated the purpose of &lt;tt&gt;&lt;[href://?node_id=17558#spoiler|spoiler]&gt;&lt;/tt&gt; tags. (Was only a problem for those who had [Display Settings|opted] to 
render &amp;lt;spoiler&amp;gt; tags as 'table'.)
This has been fixed; code text is now black.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Many thanks to [Argel] for [id://668073|noticing]!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Some CSS Conversions; Feedback Needed&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-01-11 12:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As part of a long-term conversion of the site's theme control to CSS,
certain pages have had certain specific elements converted from 
hard-coded style to CSS style.  We are asking all interested monks
to look for any anomalies as they use the site, and [/msg|report] them to
[pmdev].  Specific areas affected include any nodes and nodelets which
display lists of nodes, such as &quot;best nodes&quot; and &quot;other users&quot; type lists.
Also affected is [id://28877].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Added &quot;Send &lt;tt&gt;/msg&lt;/tt&gt; to user&quot; link to home nodes&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2008-01-05 17:30:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The home nodes of users now have a link to the [Message Inbox]
with the name of the home node owner filled in already. Thanks to [bart]
for suggesting the feature.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;


&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bug fixed with below item&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2007-12-22 20:50:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A bug in the implementation of the next item prevented the possibility of loss of XP until now.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;One can now lose XP for casting mostly down-votes&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2007-12-17 14:35:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[id://656189] has passed.  The chance of losing 1 XP or gaining 1 XP (depending on whether one's recent votes have been mostly up-votes or down-votes) each time one casts a down-vote is now in effect.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Many more XP quips added due to demands from [runrig]&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2007-11-30 14:30:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Turn on &quot;XP quips&quot; in [User Settings] and see [id://5938] for ways to gain (or lose) XP if you want to occassionally see some of them.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;XP Nodelet shows when down-voting may cost you XP&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2007-11-30 14:30:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The feature described in [id://654038] has been implemented.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Adjustments made to how XP is awarded due to voting&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2007-11-18 15:40:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
See [id://651535] for more information.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Negative XP hidden in home nodes&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2007-10-18 10:38:07]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Negative XP now result in 'requires penance' displayed on home nodes,
since negative XP isn't interesting but for trolls to brag about. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;New shortcut type for Urban Dictionary: &lt;tt&gt;ud://&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2007-10-10 10:10:10]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A new [id://43037|shortcut] type, &lt;b&gt;&lt;c&gt;[ud://...]&lt;/c&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, has been introduced. 
This allows to link to entries in the [ud://].
&lt;br/&gt;For example:
&lt;c&gt;[ud://troll]&lt;/c&gt; &amp;rArr; [ud://troll].
&lt;br/&gt;
(Users are cautioned that many [ud://] pages are [ud://NSFW].)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;New &lt;tt&gt;mathworld://&lt;/tt&gt; link short-cut&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2007-08-29 16:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You can now use &lt;c&gt;[mathworld://]&lt;/c&gt; to get a link to Wolfram's MathWorld ([mathworld://]), &lt;c&gt;[mathworld://convolution]&lt;/c&gt; to search that site ([mathworld://convolution]), or &lt;c&gt;[mathworld://Convolution.html]&lt;/c&gt; to link to a specific page there ([mathworld://Convolution.html]; the trailing &quot;.html&quot; is what causes the link to not be generated as a search).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;In the Chatterbox, &lt;tt&gt;/em&lt;/tt&gt; is now an alias for &lt;tt&gt;/me&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2007-08-09 12:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A new [id://236794|Chatterbox] &quot;command&quot;, &lt;b&gt;/em&lt;/b&gt;,
has been added as an alias for &lt;b&gt;/me&lt;/b&gt;.
This is not to fix what could be a typo; rather, &lt;b&gt;/em&lt;/b&gt;
(for &lt;i&gt;emote&lt;/i&gt;) is the equivalent command on some 
instant messaging systems.
&lt;br/&gt;
Relevant PMD: [id://631430]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;New shortcut type for CPAN RT: &lt;tt&gt;rt://&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2007-07-31 12:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A new [id://43037|shortcut type] for linking to a module's page
in the [rt://|CPAN RT system] has been introduced: 
&lt;b&gt;&lt;tt&gt;rt://&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;
CPAN RT nominally wants a distribution name, so the canonical form
is &lt;b&gt;&lt;tt&gt;[rt://Module-Build]&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.  However, module names
also work, at least for now: &lt;b&gt;&lt;tt&gt;[rt://Module::Build]&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;
Relevant PMD: [id://629698]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pedagogues Request Volunteers to Write Tutorials&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2007-06-27 12:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In an effort to improve the breadth and depth of the articles in
the [Tutorials] section, the [id://591017|Pedagogues] have created
a permanent &quot;bulletin board&quot; where they post requests for new
tutorials: &lt;b&gt;[id://615833]&lt;/b&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;
New topic ideas can be submitted via &lt;tt&gt;[/msg]&amp;nbsp;[Pedagogues]&lt;/tt&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Handy Parent and Root Links When Replying&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2007-06-15 12:34:56]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
When you're replying to a node, you will now see links to both the
parent node and the thread's root node at both the initial
&quot;Comment&amp;nbsp;on&quot; stage and the Preview stage.
When the parent and the root are the same, only the parent is linked.
These links are accompanied by links to their corresponding authors.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;More Free Nodelet Macros for Thread Info&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2007-05-30 12:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Several new [id://590089|Free Nodelet macros] have been added,
which provide information on the thread context of the current
node, when the current node is in a user-postable section
([id://480], [id://479], etc.) They are:
&lt;code&gt;
`root_type_title`
`root_type_id`
`root_ss_type`
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
One of the cool things you can now do with these is make a
[id://616580|Mini Super Search] form in your 
[id://590089|Free Nodelet] which knows which section you're
reading in.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;List Nodes By Users with Node Type constraint&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2007-05-02 12:58:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It is now possible to constrain the nodes listed on [id://6364] by type,
a handy enhancement to list e.g. the obfuscations or meditations of a

user, especially when coming from their homenode.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Since a node's reputation is the secret of its author, which you can see
only after voting on it, sorting by reputation is (silently) disabled 

when you list another monk's nodes with this type constraint feature. 
Instead, the nodes will be ordered chronologically, newest first.
(Ordering your own nodes by reputation, with type constraint, works just fine.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ordering Notes 'Newest First' Now Works Correctly&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2007-05-01 01:41:28]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In your [User Settings], you can indicate to show notes (replies) in a thread 
ordered 'Newest First' (in addition to a couple of other possibilities).
This setting didn't work; instead, notes were ordered oldest first.
This has been fixed.  If you had this setting set to 'Newest First', you 
should now expect to see a difference in how notes are ordered in threads.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Replies in a Thread have Link Anchors&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2007-05-01 01:41:28]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It is now possible to link to a reply within a thread.
This is handy if you want to link to a reply but within the context of its
containing thread.  The syntax is:
&lt;code&gt;
    [href://?node_id=rootID#nodeID]
&lt;/code&gt;
(Note that the &quot;root&quot; node need not be the actual root of the thread; it
can be any ancestor of the selected node.)&lt;br/&gt;
Example:
&lt;c&gt;[href://?node_id=590141#590154]&lt;/c&gt; ([href://?node_id=590141#590154|try it now])
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Show Reaped Nodes User Setting now affects section listings&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2007-04-25 22:34]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The &quot;Show Reaped Nodes&quot; [Newest Nodes Settings|Newest Nodes Setting] now affects
other section listings besides [Newest Nodes] and [Recently Active Threads]. Also,
reaped nodes cannot be viewed anymore by [Anonymous Monk] (and thus, search engine crawlers).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Anti-Spam Measures in Place&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2007-04-24 18:41:27]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[Anonymous Monk|Anonymous] posting from certain domains is being blocked
to prevent spam, which is now on the rise due to PerlMonks' increased
visibility, which is due to....
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Search engines index PerlMonks&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2007-03-06 20:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
We've removed the restrictions against search engine spiders indexing PerlMonks ([id://601658]) and enough time has passed so using Google (for example) to search PerlMonks is useful.  [Super Search] now includes a link to Google's advanced search with the restriction to only search www.perlmonks.org preloaded.  And if you do a simple search (that doesn't match only one node exactly) your results will include a link that does the same search via Google.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
How PerlMonks is indexed is better than it was in the past (all spiders now only index www.perlmonks.org instead of 6 different valid PerlMonks host names along with a few less valid URLs).  It isn't as good as we would like it to be (we would prefer that chatter was not indexed, for example) but this is a good short-term solution until the spider-specific features are finished.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Preferred WikiMedia language setting added&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2007-01-28 13:19]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
There is now a [id://450961|setting] to define your preferred language for
WikiMedia [id://43037|shortcuts] (wp, wb, wq, and ws). 
This won't help you with all linked English words,
but if you prefer [http://hu.wikipedia.org] over [http://en.wikipedia.org] you can now
set this.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;


&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Newest Nodes can now be sorted by title&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2007-01-28 13:19]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
There is now a [id://492848|setting] to define the order in which nodes are listed in each section of [Newest Nodes]. 
As an alternative to the default ordering, which is chronological,
you can choose to order by title or by author. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;


&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Super Search generates Links for sharing/bookmarking searches&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-12-28 18:30:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Now, when you submit a query in [id://590032|Super Search], you not only get back
the results but also a link which will execute the same query again. 
You can copy this link and paste it in nodes, in the [id://17989|Chatterbox], 
or in your [id://590101|Personal Nodelet].
The link will be an 
[href://?node_id=43037#general|&lt;tt&gt;&amp;#91;href://...&amp;#93;&lt;/tt&gt; style shortcut].
Note that the link, when clicked, does not execute a [Super Search] immediately,
but simply loads the [Super Search] form with the given parameters pre-loaded.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;New FAQ Goes Live&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-12-17 12:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The [PerlMonks FAQ] has been upgraded to a fully hierarchical structure.
This makes it much easier to link to sections within the FAQ and to specific questions.
Note that this involved switching the FAQ to a different node: [483072], vice [237040].
Please update your bookmarks accordingly.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;New shortcut type for JavaJunkies: &lt;tt&gt;jj://&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-11-28 12:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A new [id://43037|shortcut type] has been added, for linking to 
PerlMonks' Java-related sister site, [jj://|JavaJunkies]: 
&lt;c&gt;[jj://login]&lt;/c&gt; &amp;rArr; [jj://login]. It accepts node IDs and
node title terms, just like on PerlMonks.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lost node content restored from backup&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-11-14 21:41:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Some node contents were lost due to MySQL table problems, most notably
in the 252000 range. They were all restored except for some
[NodeReaper] messages.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Main CSS now served from relative URL&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-11-14 18:53:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The main PerlMonks CSS was served from the hardcoded absolute
URL &lt;c&gt;http://perlmonks.org/&lt;/c&gt;, which caused problems
whenever DNS resolved differently for any of the other
domains used and one of the two servers was unreachable.
Now it is served with a relative URL and hence will use the
same server and connection as the rest of the page.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Posting [Tutorials] Limited to Registered Users&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-11-14 11:30:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Due to a recent spate of spam postings in the [Tutorials] section,
[Anonymous Monk]s can no longer post there.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;[Cabal] can view [id://481721|alphafaqlets]&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-11-10 14:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[id://560179] has been effected.  [Cabal] members,
expect that the [SiteDocClan] may occasionally ask
you to review [id://481721|alphafaqlets].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;[Timezone settings] works again&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-11-08 14:30:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
On 2005-09-17, the links to change your timezone at [Timezone settings] stopped having an effect and the support for using the backward-compatability timezones was removed from [User settings].  The links now work again to set your timezone and at the bottom of [Timezone settings] you can select a &quot;backward&quot; timezone (though, why would you?).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Font size for node id for replies is now adjustable&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-11-03 22:48:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The node id text added in the spirit of [id://581651] is now
within a &lt;c&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;attribution&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/c&gt; and can be styled
by adjusting the CSS accordingly.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;


&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;The &quot;Nodes requiring editing&quot; list includes the date/time of each consideration&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-11-03 22:48:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
[id://59481] now has an additional column that
shows when a node was considered.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;


&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;CSS pages now cached for 24 hours&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-10-30 18:41:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The CSS pages for the themes are now cacheable for
24 hours instead of 1 hour as previously.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;


&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;All shortcuts now link usefully with no arguments&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-08-28 15:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Per the discussion [id://567465], all shortcut types now link usefully
even if given with no arguments. (Certain shortcut types, such as
&lt;c&gt;[pad://]&lt;/c&gt;, &lt;c&gt;[c2://]&lt;/c&gt;, and &lt;c&gt;[apc://]&lt;/c&gt;, already had this
behavior.) In most cases, the link created will lead to the main page
or search form of the relevant site.
In cases where this does not make sense, such as &lt;c&gt;[http://]&lt;/c&gt;,
the link will go to the usage documentation.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
See [id://43037|full details on PerlMonks shortcuts].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;[href://?node_id=30175;xmlstyle=rss|Newest Nodes RSS Feed] now is more RSS 2.0 compliant&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-08-21 19:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;c&gt;pubDate&lt;/c&gt; element of the generated RSS contained the node creation timestamp in the user-specified format instead of the [rfc://822|RFC822] format as mandated by the RSS 2.0 standard. Now the element is output RFC822 compliant.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;New &lt;tt&gt;RFC822&lt;/tt&gt; user time format&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-08-21 19:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The &quot;Format for date-times&quot; field in [User Settings] now accepts the string
&lt;b&gt;&lt;tt&gt;RFC822&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/b&gt; as a convenient alias for&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;%a, %d %b %Y %H:%M:%S %z&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
(This parameter controls how timestamps on nodes and various other
things are displayed to you.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;


&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Newest Nodes timestamp format now respects your format for date-times&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-08-09 12:19:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The timestamp in [id://3628] and [id://16902] was incorrect and not
respecting the user formats. Now it does.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Happy MonkDay Message&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-08-01]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A frivolous little message has been added to the [href://?node_id=239623#xp|XP Nodelet] to wish users a Happy MonkDay on their anniversary.  Select &quot;Show quips on XP loss/gain messages&quot; in [id://1072] to enable additional quips.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;New shortcut type for perl source code: &lt;tt&gt;apc://&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-07-11 11:22:33]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A new [id://43037|shortcut] type, &lt;b&gt;&lt;c&gt;[apc://...]&lt;/c&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, has been introduced.  This allows to link to files and patches in the perl source code base. There are three variants:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Link to a specific file: &lt;tt&gt;&amp;#91;apc://&lt;i&gt;file&lt;/i&gt;]&lt;/tt&gt;, e.g. &lt;tt&gt;[apc://perl.c|&amp;#91;apc://perl.c&amp;#93;]&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Link to a specific patch: &lt;tt&gt;&amp;#91;apc://&lt;i&gt;patchNum&lt;/i&gt;]&lt;/tt&gt;, e.g. &lt;tt&gt;[apc://1575|&amp;#91;apc://1575&amp;#93;]&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Link to a specific file at a specific patch number: &lt;tt&gt;&amp;#91;apc://&lt;i&gt;file@patchNum&lt;/i&gt;]&lt;/tt&gt;, e.g. &lt;tt&gt;[apc://perl.c@1575|&amp;#91;apc://perl.c@1575&amp;#93;]&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Link to the perl code repo browser: &lt;tt&gt;&amp;#91;apc://]&lt;/tt&gt;, e.g. &lt;tt&gt;[apc://|&amp;#91;apc://&amp;#93;]&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Note: this is ActiveState's perl code repository.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Search and Talk entry fields are stylable&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-06-05 10:30:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The text entry field at the top of each page now has an HTML ID,
&lt;c&gt;search_text&lt;/c&gt;. This allows to style it in CSS (e.g. in your [id://450961]), for example
&lt;code&gt;
input#search_text { width: 40em; }
&lt;/code&gt;
Similarly, the text entry field in the Chatterbox nodelet now has ID &lt;c&gt;talkbox&lt;/c&gt;; so you could do (for example)
&lt;code&gt;
input#talkbox { width: 20em; }
&lt;/code&gt;
Scripting (e.g. via javascript in your [id://492700|Free Nodelet]) of these elements is thus facilitated as well.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Filter Out CB Messages Based on Content&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-05-12 12:15:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A new filter feature lets you avoid seeing messages with &quot;offensive&quot; content in the Chatterbox. To set it up, go to your [id://16082|Ignored Users Settings]. For details on how it works, see the [href://?node_id=17642#ignored_users|help for that page].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;'ISO' date/time format now acceptable&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-04-28 08:30:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The &quot;Format for date-times&quot; field in [User Settings] now accepts the string
&lt;b&gt;&lt;tt&gt;ISO&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/b&gt; as a convenient alias for&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;%Y-%m-%d&amp;nbsp;%H:%M:%S&amp;nbsp;%Z&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
(This parameter controls how timestamps on nodes and various other
things are displayed to you.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Some bots banned from back door&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-04-26 23:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
User agents matching &lt;c&gt;m/msnbot/&lt;/c&gt; have been banned from &quot;back-door&quot; accessing the site (through http://alternate-hostname/~monkads/index.pl?...) as they were mildly suspected of contributing to the 'A' web server locking up for an extended time periodically.  Other user agents (probably all) will likely be banned (will get an HTTP 403 response, &quot;Forbidden, use http://perlmonks.org/ instead&quot;) in future.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;RAT prefers user-selected colors&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-04-25 23:00:00]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The colour key for [Recently Active Threads] has been altered so that is shows user selected colours if they have been supplied using [id://492690].&lt;br/&gt;
Relevant PMD: [id://545757]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;New shortcut type for Everything2&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-04-20 12:14:08]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
To facilitate linking to articles on [http://everything2.com/|Everything2],
the &lt;tt&gt;e2://&lt;/tt&gt; shortcut type has been created.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
See [id://43037]&lt;br/&gt;
Relevant PMD: [id://529682]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;'View Scratchpad' now defaults to Public&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-04-17 11:47:57]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Previously, the 'View scratchpad' link on homenodes would lead to either public or private pads, depending on your last explicitly selected one. This had its purpose, but was counterintuitive to most people.  It now DWYM, and goes to public pad everytime.&lt;br/&gt;
Relevant PMD: [id://543815]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Newest Nodes Settings Consolidated&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-04-13 17:00:44]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As a result of earlier, incomplete, reorgs, [Newest Nodes Settings] had most but not all [Newest Nodes] related settings.
The last few were moved, mostly from [User Settings].
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;wikipedia:// is now an alias for wp://&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-04-13 16:31:40]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
'wp' has been a [id://43037|shortcut type] for quite some time, but some people were expecting
wikipedia:// to work. Therefore, it has been added as an alias.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;module:// shortcut now goes straight to the docs&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-04-13 16:28:10]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The 'module' [id://43037|shortcut type] previously used a CPAN search feature 
which was not optimized for documentation. This has been rectified.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;Timezone selection removed from User Settings&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-04-11 11:19:38]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The timezone selection widget in [User Settings] was redundant with [Timezone Settings],
and in fact not as powerful. It has been removed. Use [Timezone Settings] instead.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;


&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;perlmonk.org back on line&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;[localtime://2006-03-11 07:18:49]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;
After some lengthy downtime, [http://perlmonk.org] is back up.

One consequence is that long-time cherished services such as
[http://mojotoad.perlmonk.org/cbs/index.html|CB Stats] are available again.&lt;br/&gt;
See relevant PMD [id://535931]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;

&lt;/dl&gt;





































































































</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>68046</type_nodetype>
  <node_id>545862</node_id>
  <author_user>321667</author_user>
  <title>Tidings</title>
  <createtime>2006-04-26 16:08:34</createtime>
  <nodeupdated>2006-04-26 12:08:34</nodeupdated>
</node>
