<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="1223" title="perlman:IPC::Open2" created="1999-12-22 19:52:28" updated="2005-08-14 02:40:14">
<type id="119">
perlfunc</type>
<author id="113">
root</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
</field>
<field name="name">

&lt;P&gt;
IPC::Open2, open2 - open a process for both reading and writing

&lt;P&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
</field>
<field name="synopsis">

&lt;P&gt;
&lt;PRE&gt;    use IPC::Open2;
    $pid = open2(\*RDR, \*WTR, 'some cmd and args');
      # or
    $pid = open2(\*RDR, \*WTR, 'some', 'cmd', 'and', 'args');
&lt;/PRE&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
</field>
<field name="description">

&lt;P&gt;
The 
&lt;CODE&gt;open2()&lt;/CODE&gt; function spawns the
given &lt;CODE&gt;$cmd&lt;/CODE&gt; and connects &lt;CODE&gt;$rdr&lt;/CODE&gt; for reading and
&lt;CODE&gt;$wtr&lt;/CODE&gt; for writing. It's what you think should work when you try

&lt;P&gt;
&lt;PRE&gt;    open(HANDLE, &amp;quot;|cmd args|&amp;quot;);
&lt;/PRE&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
The write filehandle will have autoflush turned on.

&lt;P&gt;
If &lt;CODE&gt;$rdr&lt;/CODE&gt; is a string (that is, a bareword filehandle rather than a glob or a reference) and it begins with ``&amp;gt;&amp;amp;'', then the child will send output directly to that file handle. If &lt;CODE&gt;$wtr&lt;/CODE&gt; is a string that begins with ``&amp;lt;&amp;amp;'', then 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;WTR&lt;/FONT&gt; will be closed in the parent, and the child will read from it directly. In both cases, there will be a 
&lt;CODE&gt;dup(2)&lt;/CODE&gt; instead of a 
&lt;CODE&gt;pipe(2)&lt;/CODE&gt; made.

&lt;P&gt;

&lt;CODE&gt;open2()&lt;/CODE&gt; returns the process 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;ID&lt;/FONT&gt; of the child process. It doesn't return on failure: it just raises an exception matching
 &lt;CODE&gt;/^open2:/&lt;/CODE&gt;.

&lt;P&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
&lt;H1&gt;&lt;A NAME="WARNING"&gt;WARNING&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
It will not create these file handles for you. You have to do this
yourself. So don't pass it empty variables expecting them to get filled in
for you.

&lt;P&gt;
Additionally, this is very dangerous as you may block forever. It assumes
it's going to talk to something like &lt;STRONG&gt;bc&lt;/STRONG&gt;, both writing to it and reading from it. This is presumably safe because
you ``know'' that commands like &lt;STRONG&gt;bc&lt;/STRONG&gt; will read a line at a time and output a line at a time. Programs like &lt;STRONG&gt;sort&lt;/STRONG&gt; that read their entire input stream first, however, are quite apt to cause
deadlock.  

&lt;P&gt;
The big problem with this approach is that if you don't have control over
source code being run in the child process, you can't control what it does
with pipe buffering. Thus you can't just open a pipe to
&lt;CODE&gt;cat -v&lt;/CODE&gt; and continually read and write a line from it.

&lt;P&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
&lt;H1&gt;&lt;A NAME="SEE_ALSO"&gt;SEE ALSO&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
See [perlman:IPC::Open3|Open3] for an alternative that handles 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;STDERR&lt;/FONT&gt; as well. This function is really just a wrapper around 
&lt;CODE&gt;open3().&lt;/CODE&gt;

&lt;HR&gt;
</field>
</data>
</node>
