<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<node id="202" title="perlfunc:write" created="1999-08-24 18:42:03" updated="2005-08-13 00:37:25">
<type id="119">
perlfunc</type>
<author id="114">
gods</author>
<data>
<field name="doctext">
</field>
<field name="name">

&lt;P&gt;
write - print a picture record

&lt;P&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
</field>
<field name="synopsis">

&lt;P&gt;
write 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;FILEHANDLE&lt;/FONT&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
write 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;EXPR&lt;/FONT&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
write

&lt;P&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
</field>
<field name="description">

&lt;P&gt;
Writes a formatted record (possibly multi-line) to the specified 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;FILEHANDLE,&lt;/FONT&gt; using the format associated with that
file. By default the format for a file is the one having the same name as
the filehandle, but the format for the current output channel (see the [perlfunc:select|select()] function) may be set explicitly by assigning the name of the format to the &lt;CODE&gt;$~&lt;/CODE&gt; variable.

&lt;P&gt;
Top of form processing is handled automatically: if there is insufficient room on the current page for the formatted record, the page is advanced by writing a form feed, a special top-of-page format is used to format the new page header, and then the record is written. By default the top-of-page format is the name of the filehandle with 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;``_TOP''&lt;/FONT&gt; appended, but it may be dynamically set to the format of your choice by assigning the name to the
 &lt;CODE&gt;$^&lt;/CODE&gt; variable while the filehandle is selected. The number of lines remaining on
the current page is in variable &lt;CODE&gt;$-&lt;/CODE&gt;, which can be set to &lt;CODE&gt;0&lt;/CODE&gt; to force a new page.

&lt;P&gt;
If 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;FILEHANDLE&lt;/FONT&gt; is unspecified, output goes to the current default output channel, which starts out as 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;STDOUT&lt;/FONT&gt; but may be changed by the

[perlfunc:select|select()] operator. If the 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;FILEHANDLE&lt;/FONT&gt; is an 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;EXPR,&lt;/FONT&gt; then the expression is evaluated and the resulting string is used to look up the name of the 
&lt;FONT SIZE=-1&gt;FILEHANDLE&lt;/FONT&gt; at run time. For more on formats, see
 [perlman:perlform|the perlform manpage].

&lt;P&gt;
Note that write is &lt;EM&gt;NOT&lt;/EM&gt; the opposite of [perlfunc:read|read()]. Unfortunately.

&lt;HR&gt;
</field>
</data>
</node>
