<node>
  <doctext>&lt;b&gt;Downloading your modules:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
To download modules, please check [http://search.cpan.org|search.cpan.org].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

To install onto a web server always check before hand if it's compiled in C or if it's strictly .pl files.  On cpan near the download link you will find a browse button, click that to view the contents of the module.  If all you see are folders and .pl files, download it.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

When downloading from this site more often than not you will be download in a .tar format, which is ok for both *nix and Windows.  Windows users may have to unzip the file twice.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

Unzip the contents as you would any file.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
On your server in your home directory (often /www/) create the folder 'lib' in lowercase letters.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

Open your folder with your module and look for the 'lib' directory.  Depending what module you downloaded there might be a single folder or a huge list of folders here.  Behind these folders are the modules themselves, each are broken down into their own folder.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Make web directory 'lib'&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Connect to your site via FTP (if you need to connect via the browser, you will need to transfer each file into their respect folder EXACTLY as you downloaded them) and transfer all the FOLDERS with their contents into your 'lib' directory on your server.  Use ASCII as perl files are text.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Using your modules:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Near the top of your script, 
use:     &lt;code&gt;use lib &quot;/location/lib/&quot; ;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Testing:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
If your script isn't working and you want to be sure your modules are installed correctly and your script and locate them, use the line (if you have CGI::Carp): &lt;code&gt;use CGI::Carp qw(fatalsToBrowser);&lt;/code&gt;</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>956</type_nodetype>
  <node_id>216644</node_id>
  <author_user>115576</author_user>
  <title>Installing Modules on a Web Server</title>
  <createtime>2002-11-30 05:30:57</createtime>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-15 10:16:33</nodeupdated>
</node>
