<node>
  <doctext>I just started out with ncurses for the first time. It is
hard enough to use the manuals/tutorials written for C. To
make it worse, some functions have been renamed or might
simply be nonexistant. I have only scratched the surface of
the ncurses module, but I have a few pointers, that will
save the ones new to CPANs Curses module some time.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
1) The functions to read from STDIN are (as usual) blocking.
This means, the program will halt on fx. getch() until
input is recieved. There are a few ways to make it nonblocking
according to the manual. I have found only one that does
not cause problems: Use the function halfdelay(ms). The
function will wait for ms milliseconds on a getch(), and
if no input is recieved, getch() will return &quot;-1&quot;.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
2) To use color, simply use start_color and define a few
color pairs with the function init_pair(pairnr, fg, bg)
where fg is the foreground and bg is background. Colors are
from 0 to 7. (Black, Red, Green, Yellow, Blue, Magenta, Cyan,
White). To use the colors, I have found only two supported
functions: attron(ATTR) and attroff(ATTR). &quot;man attr&quot; will
show what attributes can be toggled with the functions. To
print a line in green, on yellow, you simply use the ATTR COLOR_PAIR(n). Do like this:
&lt;CODE&gt;init_pair(1,2,3);  # Initiate pair. Pair 0 reserved for mono.
attron(COLOR_PAIR(2));   # Start color.
addstr(15, 30, &quot;MOOOO!&quot;);# print string at 30,15. Always use (y,x).
attroff(COLOR_PAIR(2));  # End color.&lt;/CODE&gt;&lt;BR&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
3) The above is also a good example for this point: Some
functions have been slightly renamed. attron/attroff is
named attr_on/attr_off in C and therefore in all manuals. This can make it difficult to find
the correct manpages.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
4) I am still looking for a way to hide the cursor. The C
man pages have the function curs_set(&lt;mode&gt;). Unfortunately
the CPAN Curses seems unable to support this. If anyone finds
a way, please let me know. =)&lt;BR&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
As I said, I barely even scratched ncurses surface, but I
hope this will save the ones new to both ncurses and C ( like
me ) a few hours of agony.</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>956</type_nodetype>
  <node_id>32154</node_id>
  <author_user>31586</author_user>
  <title>Tips and Pointers using ncurses with perl</title>
  <createtime>2000-09-12 18:23:52</createtime>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-15 11:47:56</nodeupdated>
</node>
