<node>
  <doctext>&lt;b&gt;CPAN LINK: &lt;/b&gt;[cpan://Acme::Comment]&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;b&gt;CPAN ABSTRACT:&lt;/b&gt; This module allows for  multi-line comments which are filtered out. Unlike the pseudo multi-line comment if (0) {}, the code being commented.
&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Introduction:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
Roaming about the monastery I came upon the following node:
&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.perlmonks.org/index.pl?node_id=304458&quot;&gt; Block Commenting&lt;/A&gt;, a fellow monk essentially searching for advise on the possibilty of multi-line commenting.  A few replies down mentioned in passing the module Acme::Comment, it's claim was to allow multi-line comments which are filtered out.  I became curious so I downloaded the module and checked it out for myself.&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Functionality:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
Acme::Comment, in a nutshell, allows for multi-line and single line commenting in several different language styles.  Some of the multi-line comment language styles are: C++, HTML, Pascal and Java to name a few.  In total, both single and multi line together there were a total of 43
different programming languages represented.  I tested it out in &quot;HTML&quot; mode
using multi-line comments with ActivePerl 5.8.0 on WinXP,
and it proved to be quite easy to use. The distribution itself contains fairly straight forward documentation.&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Generic Example:&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
#!/usr/bin/perl -w

use strict;
use Acme::Comment  type=&gt;'HTML';

&lt;!--
Multi-line comments here.
Everything enclosed in the html
style comment braces is ignored.
--&gt;
my $a=1;
my $b=2;
my $c=$a + $b;
print &quot;$a + $b = $c\n&quot;;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Final Thoughts:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
For implementation of multi-line comments in various language formats I found this module to be quite useful.
The only drawback that I can immediately see is that this module is not yet widely known.  I think multi-line commenting
(a single format of) would be great implemented as a standard
feature in a future version of Perl; perhaps in Perl6? (it can't hurt to hope)
</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>31663</type_nodetype>
  <author_user>243154</author_user>
  <createtime>2003-11-05 22:07:52</createtime>
  <itemdescription>Allows multi-line comments which are filtered out.</itemdescription>
  <identifier></identifier>
  <node_id>304932</node_id>
  <usercomment></usercomment>
  <title>Acme::Comment</title>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-13 23:34:52</nodeupdated>
</node>
