<node>
  <doctext>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;font size=&quot;+2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Acme::Don't&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;p&gt;
This module, from the warped mind of [theDamian|Damian Conway], provides only one export, the &lt;code&gt;don't&lt;/code&gt; command.  This command is used in exactly the same way as the &lt;code&gt;do BLOCK&lt;/code&gt; function except that, instead of executing the block it controls, to quote the module POD, &amp;quot;&lt;i&gt;it...well...doesn't&lt;/i&gt;&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;The result of wrapping a code block by the &lt;code&gt;don't&lt;/code&gt; command is a no-operation which, regardless of the contents of the block, returns &lt;code&gt;undef&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;p&gt;
Why review this module?  Well, in contrast to many of the other modules which have found their way into the [cpan://Acme::] namespace, I can actually see a use for this module in development.  How many time have you been working on some code and wanted to comment out a section of it to test specific code components?  With [cpan://Acme::Don't], it is as simple as adding the surrounding &lt;code&gt;don't&lt;/code&gt; block!  The only caveat with this debugging and development approach is that code within the &lt;code&gt;don't&lt;/code&gt; block must be syntactically valid, providing compile time-syntax checks without execution.  Additionally, it should be recognised that this statement is not all encompassing with &lt;code&gt;BEGIN&lt;/code&gt; blocks placed within a &lt;code&gt;don't&lt;/code&gt; block still being executed - For example:&lt;p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;code&gt;
use Acme::Don't;

don't {
    BEGIN {
        print &quot;foo&quot;;
    }
    print &quot;bar!\n&quot;;
}

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The above code still produces the output of &amp;quot;&lt;code&gt;foo&lt;/code&gt;&amp;quot; as a result of the &lt;code&gt;BEGIN&lt;/code&gt; block execution.&lt;p&gt;
Other caveats of this interesting module are included in the module documentation and while this module resides within in the [cpan://Acme::] namespace it might just be something more than a gimmick and an interesting use for Perl4 module pragma :-)
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;p&gt;</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>31663</type_nodetype>
  <author_user>65703</author_user>
  <createtime>2002-05-09 23:16:55</createtime>
  <itemdescription>The opposite of do</itemdescription>
  <identifier></identifier>
  <node_id>165585</node_id>
  <usercomment>Something more than just a gimmick and an interesting use for Perl4 module pragma</usercomment>
  <title>Acme::Don't</title>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-12 10:07:01</nodeupdated>
</node>
