<node>
  <doctext>Review Synopsis: Good for viewing variables and data structures, and for remote debugging&lt;p&gt;

[CPAN://Devel::ptkdb] is a graphical debugger using the Tk toolkit.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;What's good?&lt;/h1&gt;
The documentation is good.&lt;br&gt;
It's easy to use, much easier than the normal perl debugger.&lt;br&gt;
You can follow the flow of your program and choose if you want to step in or step over subroutine calls.&lt;br&gt;
You can set and maintain breakpoints easily.&lt;br&gt;
You can watch arbitrary expressions, variables and complex data structures during the run.&lt;br&gt;
You can debug remote running programs and cgi scripts.&lt;br&gt;
You can even debug Tk programs.
&lt;h1&gt;What's bad?&lt;/h1&gt;
Though you can debug Tk programs, it is not always possible to do that.&lt;br&gt;
It is a bit slow.&lt;br&gt;
You need perlTk.&lt;br&gt;
It is so nice, you might end up using it for debugging simple problems, where it is just overkill.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What's missing?&lt;/h1&gt;
A regex debugger would be nice, but i think this will come with perl 6.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Bottomline&lt;/h1&gt;
Devel::ptkdb is a full featured graphical debugger for perl written in perl by Andrew Page.&lt;p&gt;
Though most of the time a simple print statement in the right place will tell you what's wrong, it's good to have a tool like this at hand.&lt;br&gt;
The 'step in', 'step over' and 'return' buttons make it easy to follow the flow of the running program as you like.&lt;br&gt;
You can see the values of needed expressions all the time, sometimes even inside of one statement, which is not possible for a print statement.&lt;br&gt;
With very few changes to your program you can debug cgi scripts and cron tasks, a feature that comes more with the XWindow infrastructure than with ptkdb, but is nevertheless very useful.&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Many thanks to Andrew Page for his work!&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;
There has been much controversy about debugging lately in the Monastery and I'd rather put dozens of print statements in a program than starting the debugger, but sometimes it can be VERY handy.&lt;p&gt;
For more thoughts on perl debugging have a look at the following nodes:&lt;p&gt;
[id://48495|Are debuggers good?]&lt;br&gt;
[id://76174|Are debugging skills atrophying?]&lt;br&gt;
[id://64424|Book Review: Debugging Perl]&lt;br&gt;
[id://14606|Easy, elemental, but cool debug trick] (read the comments)</doctext>
  <type_nodetype>31663</type_nodetype>
  <author_user>61798</author_user>
  <createtime>2001-05-07 08:13:13</createtime>
  <itemdescription>Graphical debugger for perl</itemdescription>
  <identifier></identifier>
  <node_id>78455</node_id>
  <usercomment></usercomment>
  <title>Devel::ptkdb</title>
  <nodeupdated>2005-08-05 13:19:32</nodeupdated>
</node>
